<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792254</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2023(01)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792254</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Huaier Granule in Patients With Stage I Primary Ovarian Fallopian Tube Cancer After Peritoneal Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Safety of Huaier Granule in Patients With Stage I Primary Ovarian Fallopian Tube Cancer After Peritoneal Cancer: a Single-center Prospective Single-arm Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ruijin Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ruijin Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is an exploratory, single-center, prospective single-arm study to explore the&#xD;
      efficacy of Huaier granules in the treatment of stage Ⅱ-Ⅳ primary ovarian cancer, fallopian&#xD;
      tube cancer, and peritoneal cancer after satisfactory tumor reduction (R0/R1). Twenty-five&#xD;
      patients with FIGOⅡ-Ⅳ ovarian cancer, peritoneal cancer or tubal cancer confirmed by&#xD;
      histopathology were enrolled and treated with Huaier granules. During the study period, the&#xD;
      patients were followed up once at 3 months, and the medication was continued until&#xD;
      progression or intolerability of toxicity. This is an exploratory, single-center, prospective&#xD;
      single-arm study to explore the efficacy of Huaier granules in the treatment of stage Ⅱ-Ⅳ&#xD;
      primary ovarian cancer, fallopian tube cancer, and peritoneal cancer after satisfactory tumor&#xD;
      reduction (R0/R1). Twenty-five patients with FIGOⅡ-Ⅳ ovarian cancer, peritoneal cancer or&#xD;
      tubal cancer confirmed by histopathology were enrolled and treated with Huaier granules.&#xD;
      During the study period, the patients were followed up once at 3 months, and the medication&#xD;
      was continued until progression or intolerability of toxicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the efficacy of Huai er granule in the treatment of stage I primary ovarian&#xD;
      cancer, fallopian tube cancer and peritoneal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To analyze the safety of Huaier granule in the treatment of ovarian fallopian tube&#xD;
           cancer and peritoneal cancer after operation;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To analyze the influence of Huaier granule on the quality of life of postoperative&#xD;
           patients with ovarian fallopian tube cancer and peritoneal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the efficacy of Huaier granule in patients with BRCA mutation and BRCA wild-type&#xD;
      ovarian cancer&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year progression-free survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 years from start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The time from study entry to the time of disease progression as determined by the investigator (by clinical, radiological or pathological means) or death from any cause</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 3 month until 2 years from start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>PFS according to the RECIST 1.1 criteria, based on the investigator's assessment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1 year overall survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
    <description>Observed length of life from entry into the study to death; or for living patients, the date of last contact regardless of whether or not this contact is on a subsequent protocol.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life score（FACT-O）</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 3 month until 2 years from start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The FACT-O questionnaire consists of a Physical Well-Being Section, Social/Family Well-Being Section, Emotional Well-Being Section, Functional Well-Being Section, and Additional Concerns Section</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 3 month until 2 years from start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>In the Visual Analog Score to be used as the pain measurement criterion, '0' indicates no pain, while '10' defines the most severe pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the Rates of AE and SAE</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 3 month until 2 years from start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>frequency of adverse events according to MedDRA terms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Fallopian Tube Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Peritoneal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Huaier granule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Huaier granule is supplied as 20-g granule. Huaier granule will be administered as 20 g orally tid x 28 days (continuous). One cycle = 28 days. There is no planned treatment interruption between cycles. In the absence of intolerable toxicity, a patient may continue to receive treatment with Huaier granule until disease progression, or until 24 months have elapsed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Huaier granule</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral Huai Er granules, 20 g once, 3 times a day, continued to progress or intolerance toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Huaier granule</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ≥18years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histopathologically confirmed FIGO II-IV stage primary ovarian cancer peritoneal or&#xD;
             fallopian tube cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who underwent primary tumor reduction or intermediate tumor reduction with&#xD;
             satisfactory results (R0/R1) within 15 days after surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. After tumor reduction, the physician assessed that chemotherapy was not suitable or&#xD;
             the patient was unwilling to receive chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Life expectancy is 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Liver and kidney function :&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. AST and ALT 3 times the upper limit of normal value or 5 times the upper limit of&#xD;
                  normal value in the presence of liver metastasis; T&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. he upper limit of total bilirubin 3 times normal value;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum creatinine is 3 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No other tumors, no history of other malignant tumors (except non-melanoma skin cancer&#xD;
             in situ cervical cancer or other cancers that have received curative treatment and&#xD;
             have no signs of disease for at least 5 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Voluntarily participate in the study and sign the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Breastfeeding women during pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Recurrent ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known allergy to the study drug;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Central nervous system diseases or brain metastases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of abdominal/pelvic radiotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of organ transplantation history of immune deficiency disease requiring&#xD;
             systemic steroid therapy or other immunosuppressive therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Hiv-ag /AB test result is positive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Complicated with serious cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases or other serious&#xD;
             diseases affecting follow-up treatment of subjects: such as myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             unstable angina, stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months; Uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension after antihypertensive therapy (systolic ≥140 or diastolic ≥90 mmHg);&#xD;
             Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (HbA1c&gt;8.0%) etc&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participate in other clinical study patients within 1 month&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Poor compliance is estimated to be difficult to complete the follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. In addition to the above, the investigator determined that the patients were not&#xD;
             suitable for the clinical trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 19, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

