<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05799339</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2105008584_ViiV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05799339</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Optimizing CAB-LA as PrEP for Women Who Inject Drugs</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring Engagement and Opportunities to Optimize CAB-LA as Pre-exposure Prophylaxis (PrEP) for Women Who Inject Drugs</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alexis Roth</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ViiV Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Miami</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Michigan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Drexel University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to elicit information crucial for designing strategies to support&#xD;
      engagement in cabotegravir, a long-acting injectable form of pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP)&#xD;
      to reduce HIV risk among women who inject drugs (WWID), a population with high unmet need&#xD;
      that has been understudied in all phases of PrEP research. The main questions this study aims&#xD;
      to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. How do WWID perceive long-acting injectable cabotegravir (CAB-LA) as a HIV prevention&#xD;
           tool?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. If and how their decisions to initiate CAB-LA as PrEP are informed by their experiences&#xD;
           with other long-acting medications, experience with daily oral medications, and their&#xD;
           personal circumstance (e.g., like housing or addition severity)?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Do PrEP outcomes (e.g., adherence) and engagement in care over time differ between WWID&#xD;
           prescribed CAB-LA versus daily oral PrEP?&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample for this study will be derived from and ongoing prospective trial of &quot;TIARAS,&quot; a&#xD;
      multi-component behavioral intervention designed to reduce HIV acquisition risk among women&#xD;
      who inject drugs (see NCT05192434).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This open-label community demonstration project draws from parent study TIARAS (NCT05192434),&#xD;
      a multi-component behavioral intervention designed to reduce HIV acquisition risk among women&#xD;
      who inject drugs (WWID). Participants are prescribed PrEP prior to enrollment based on&#xD;
      consultation with their medical provider. They then simultaneously enroll in TIARAS and this&#xD;
      observational study. Over six months, we will use data extracted from participant's&#xD;
      electronic medical records to (1) describe CAB-LA and daily oral PrEP uptake among WWID and&#xD;
      (2) assess for differences in adherence and persistence among WWID prescribed CAB-LA versus&#xD;
      daily oral PrEP. All quantitative analyses will control for random group assignment in the&#xD;
      TIARAS trial (NCT05192434). To understand uptake (primary outcome), we will purposively&#xD;
      sample 20 WWID who were prescribed CAB and 20 prescribed daily oral PrEP. Participants will&#xD;
      complete a semi-structured interview designed to explore their decision to initiate PrEP and&#xD;
      the product-related attributes that influenced their decision, accounting for previous PrEP&#xD;
      experience or use of long-acting injectable medications (e.g., birth control or MOUD), and&#xD;
      examining how structural factors, like homelessness or medical mistrust influence&#xD;
      decision-making. To understand persistence and adherence, at endline (six-months) we will&#xD;
      purposively recruit 10 women who initiated CAB-LA who remained actively engaged in care and&#xD;
      10 who did not. We will also purposively recruit 10 women who initiated daily oral PrEP who&#xD;
      remained actively engaged in care and 10 who did not. All participants will complete a&#xD;
      semi-structured interview that explores facilitators and barriers to adherence and&#xD;
      persistence (secondary outcomes). We will focus on strategies to increase engagement in care.&#xD;
      Because previous research highlights the important influence of seasons of risk on PrEP&#xD;
      outcomes (i.e., women are less interested in PrEP during periods of low perceived HIV risk&#xD;
      such as during drug abstinence), we will examine how individual and structural factors&#xD;
      influence PrEP persistence. Finally, should we find that &gt;10% of the sample switches or&#xD;
      discontinues a PrEP formulation over time, we will recruit a subset (n=15) to understand&#xD;
      their decision-making process about switching.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 13, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP Uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months</time_frame>
    <description>PrEP uptake will be operationalized as the number of participants who are prescribed (1) CAB-LA AND receive their first injection OR (2) daily oral tenofovir-based PrEP AND receive their first week of medication, as verified in the patient's electronic medical record (EMR).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CAB-LA adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess PrEP adherence in women initiating long-acting injectable cabotegravir (CAB-LA), we will extract the dates of CAB-LA injections from participants' electronic medical records and will determine whether each follow-up CAB-LA injection occurred within recommended dosing windows according to Apretude prescribing information (+/- 7 days). In primary analysis, any injection occurring within the recommended dosing window will be considered adherent. Injections outside this dosing window will be considered non-adherent.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP persistence</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months</time_frame>
    <description>To describe PrEP persistence, we will calculate the proportion of days covered by a PrEP prescription over the 12-month study period, among those who initiate PrEP (see PrEP uptake). Dates and number of pills dispensed and/or date of each CAB-LA injection will be extracted from the EMR. Persistence will be operationalized as: (sum of days with an &quot;active&quot; PrEP prescription) ÷ (365 days) × 100.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Late injection</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months</time_frame>
    <description>Any CAB-LA injection occurring outside of the dosing window (+/- 7 days of each scheduled injection) will be considered late. Dates of each injection will be extracted from the patient's electronic medical record.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CAB-LA restart (reinitation)</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months</time_frame>
    <description>A restart (reinitation) will be defined as any CAB-LA injection occurring more than 4 weeks from when it was scheduled/due but within the 12-month study timeframe. Dates for each CAB-LAI injection will be extracted from the patient's electronic medical record.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP product switching</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months</time_frame>
    <description>We will describe patterns of switching between PrEP modalities over time among those who initiate CAB-LA (see PrEP uptake). For example, we will assess the number/proportion of women switching from daily oral PrEP to CAB-LA (or vice versa), the timing of when switching occurred (e.g., after one month of PrEP uptake), and the average number of switches per participant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">144</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Use</condition>
  <condition>Trauma, Psychological</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women who inject drugs&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV-negative cisgender female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  speaks/reads English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  reporting past 6 months day non-prescription injection drug use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  enrolled in the TIARAS trial (NCT05192434)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Unable to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Cisgender females eligible</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alexis M Roth, PhD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Drexel University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alexis M Roth, PhD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>317-213-3960</phone>
    <email>amr395@drexel.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Erin C McDowell, MA</last_name>
    <phone>248-345-8237</phone>
    <email>ecm88@drexel.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prevention Point Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amy Jessop, MD</last_name>
      <phone>610-220-7473</phone>
      <email>amy@ppponline.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Rachel Holbert, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>215.510.3599</phone>
      <email>rholbert@ppponline.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05192434?term=Alexis+Roth&amp;cond=HIV&amp;draw=1&amp;rank=2</url>
    <description>Link to TIARAS ClinicalTrials.gov protocol and results description</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 23, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 4, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 4, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 4, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Drexel University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alexis Roth</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PrEP</keyword>
  <keyword>Preexposure Prophylaxis</keyword>
  <keyword>WWID</keyword>
  <keyword>Women who inject drugs</keyword>
  <keyword>CAB-LA</keyword>
  <keyword>Long-acting injectable cabotegravir</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psychological Trauma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

