<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05616975</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OU IRB 14031</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05616975</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SWAY Mobile Application Assessments in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>Reliability, Validity, Normative Data, and Accuracy of SWAY Mobile Application Assessments in Healthy Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oklahoma</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>SWAY Medical, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>College of Medicine Alumni Association</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Harvard Medical School (HMS and HSDM)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oklahoma</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SWAY Medical, Inc. (SWAY) has developed a mobile application that assesses balance,&#xD;
      functional performance, and cognitive function. Clinical reliability, validity, and normative&#xD;
      data have been studied extensively in individuals aged 5 to 20. The accuracy of the SWAY&#xD;
      Mobile Application in assessing conditions associated with head injury has also been well&#xD;
      established. The objectives of this study are to examine the reliability and validity, and&#xD;
      establish normative data, for SWAY balance, functional, and cognitive assessments in healthy&#xD;
      adults aged 21-90. The SWAY smartphone app will be used to record balance, simple reaction&#xD;
      time, impulse control, inspection time, working memory, reverse number counting, flanker&#xD;
      task, modified Stroop, and 30 second chair stand test results. The following tests will be&#xD;
      administered to participants: Test of Premorbid Functioning, WAIS-IV Logical Memory, WMS-IV&#xD;
      Older Adult Logical Memory, Animal Fluency, Boston Naming Test, D-KEFS Color Word&#xD;
      Interference Test, WMS-IV Symbol Span, WAIS-IV Coding, Auditory Consonant Trigrams, Verbal&#xD;
      Fluency (FAS), and Flanker Inhibitory Control and Attention Test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Specific Aims The objectives of this study are to examine the reliability and validity, and&#xD;
      to establish normative data, for SWAY balance, functional, and cognitive assessments in&#xD;
      healthy adults aged 21-90.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1, Hypothesis 1: Sway balance, functional, and cognitive test scores collected at&#xD;
      baseline and 30 days will show acceptable test-retest reliabilities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2, Hypothesis 2: Sway balance, functional, and cognitive test scores will have medium&#xD;
      correlations with psychometrically supported neuropsychological tests of similar constructs&#xD;
      (convergent validity) and small correlations with psychometrically supported&#xD;
      neuropsychological tests of disparate constructs (discriminant validity).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3, Hypothesis 3: Sway balance, functional, and cognitive normative test scores will vary&#xD;
      significantly across age, education, sex, and race.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance Assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>&lt;15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>i. Modified balance error scoring system protocol (mBESS) in individuals less than 55 years of age ii. CDC 4-stage Balance test for individuals greater than or equal to 55 years of age</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>&lt;15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>i. SWAY 30 Second Chair Stand Test (functional)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive Assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>i. SWAY Memory (visual working memory) ii. SWAY Modified Erikson Flanker Task (visual scanning) iii. SWAY Simple Reaction Time (visual simple RT) iv. SWAY Impulse Control (visual go/no-go) v. SWAY Inspection Time (visual processing speed/reaction time) vi. SWAY Number Counting (visual processing speed) vii. SWAY Modified Stroop Test (executive function)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">700</enrollment>
  <condition>Reliability</condition>
  <condition>Validity</condition>
  <condition>Normative Data</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>reliability</arm_group_label>
    <description>Assessing the test-retest reliability of SWAY Balance, Functional, and Cognitive tests</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>validity</arm_group_label>
    <description>Investigating the construct validity of SWAY Balance, Functional, and Cognitive tests</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>normative</arm_group_label>
    <description>Collection of normative SWAY Balance, Functional, and Cognitive data</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>test-retest reliability</intervention_name>
    <description>Assessing the test-retest reliability of SWAY Balance, Functional, and Cognitive tests.</description>
    <arm_group_label>reliability</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>construct validity</intervention_name>
    <description>Investigating the construct validity of SWAY Balance, Functional, and Cognitive tests.</description>
    <arm_group_label>validity</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>normative data</intervention_name>
    <description>Collection of normative SWAY Balance, Functional, and Cognitive data.</description>
    <arm_group_label>normative</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Not less than seven hundred (700) and up to one thousand (1000) men and women from the&#xD;
        University of Oklahoma. OU students, residents, staff, faculty, and patients will be&#xD;
        recruited through flyers posted and distributed on campus, in clinics, on social media and&#xD;
        through emails. Additional participants will be recruited from the community as needed via&#xD;
        flyers distributed at local hospitals, clinics, senior living facilities, and through&#xD;
        newspaper and radio advertisements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncorrected visual or hearing impairment that interferes with testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol or drug intoxication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe, untreated psychiatric illness (e.g., schizophrenia, bipolar disorder,&#xD;
             depression)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment (e.g. dementia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Motor impairments that may interfere with testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have a self-reported history of falling or are believed to be at-risk&#xD;
             of falling may be excluded from the balance testing portion of the study but will&#xD;
             remain eligible to participate in the functional and cognitive assessment portions of&#xD;
             the study. Participants over the age of 50 will complete a short fall risk screening&#xD;
             assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have a musculoskeletal injury affecting functional movement and&#xD;
             balance may be excluded from the balance testing portion of the study but will remain&#xD;
             eligible to participate in the cognitive assessment portions of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteers may also be excluded from portions of this study if they do not have the&#xD;
             necessary technology to maintain a Zoom connection required for remotely administered&#xD;
             follow-up assessments, and a smart-device capable of downloading and operating the&#xD;
             SWAY application.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lamont Cavanagh, MD</last_name>
    <phone>918-619-4701</phone>
    <email>Lamont-Cavanagh@ouhsc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>reliability</keyword>
  <keyword>validity</keyword>
  <keyword>normative data</keyword>
  <keyword>balance assessments</keyword>
  <keyword>functional assessments</keyword>
  <keyword>cognitive assessments</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

