<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05075694</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>09.07.2021/46</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05075694</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cukurova University Faculty of Medicine Non-interventional Clinical Research Institutional Ethics Committe</brief_title>
  <official_title>the Effect of Therapeutic Touch on Sleep Quality and Fatigue in Menopausal Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cukurova University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cukurova University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research was carried out to determine the effect of therapeutic touch on sleep quality&#xD;
      and fatigue in menopausal women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Methods: This randomized controlled experimental study was conducted with 48 (24 in the&#xD;
      intervention group and 24 in the control group) women who sought treatment in the&#xD;
      gynecological outpatient clinic of a public hospital. According to the study procedure, while&#xD;
      the intervention group received therapeutic touch, the control group received SHAM&#xD;
      therapeutic touch for 10 minutes a day for five consecutive days. Data were collected through&#xD;
      the Personal Information Form, the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index, and the Piper Fatigue&#xD;
      Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results: The median post-test total sleep quality score was significantly lower in the&#xD;
      intervention group than in the control group (p=0.010). However, the mean total fatigue&#xD;
      scores did not differ significantly between the groups (p=0.917).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conclusions: The results of this study showed that therapeutic touch was effective in&#xD;
      improving sleep quality, but it did not affect fatigue in menopausal women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This study was conducted as a parallel randomized-controlled, single-blind, single-centered, interventional study with a pre-test and post-test design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>In this study, while the intervention group was administered Therapeutic Touch , the control group was administered Sham Therapeutic Touch (STT). The interventions in the study were implemented using the literature information as well as the Therapeutic Touch Practice Procedure (TTPP) and Sham Therapeutic Practice Procedure (STPP). To administer the TT practice, the researcher received a certificate by participating in the first and second-level courses held by the International Therapeutic Touch Association.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Quality</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Turkish version of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), which was developed by Buyssee et al. (1989), was used for the assessment of sleep quality. It is a self-report scale that makes a quantitative assessment of sleep quality and sleep disorders over a one-month time interval [30]. Turkish reliability and validity of the scale were performed by Ağargün et al. in our country (1996) [31]. The scale is composed of 18 items and seven sub-scales, which include Subjective Sleep Quality, Sleep Latency, Sleep Duration, Habitual Sleep Efficiency, Sleep Disorders, Use of Sleeping Drugs, and Daytime Dysfunction. Each item is scored between 0 and 3. The total score of the seven sub-scales gives the PSQI score. Scores to be obtained from the scale range between 0 and 21. A total score greater than 5 indicates &quot;poor sleep quality.&quot; Cronbach's alpha reliability coefficient of the PSQI was reported 0,804 in the Turkish adaptation of the scale [31].</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Turkish version of the Piper Fatigue Scale (PFS) was utilized to assess fatigue. PFS was developed by Barbara F. Piper et al. in 1987 [32]. Turkish reliability and validity of the scale were performed by Can et al. (2001) [33]. The scale responded on a 5-point Likert scale has 22 items and four sub-scales and it aims to assess individuals' subjective perceptions about fatigue. The sub-scales are Behavioral/Severity, Affective Meaning, Sensory, and Cognitive /Mood. Calculation of the sub-scale scores is done by summing all the items in that sub-scale and dividing it by the number of items. Higher scores indicate higher fatigue levels. Total Cronbach's alpha value was reported to be 0,99 in the Turkish reliability and validity of the scale [33].</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Menopause</condition>
  <condition>Sleep</condition>
  <condition>Fatigue</condition>
  <condition>Therapeutic Touch</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experiment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Therapeutic touch (TT) is a treatment that takes an average of 15-20 min, in which energy in the universe is transferred through the hands of the practitioner to eliminate the imbalance in the individual's energy field and facilitate healing. The intervention group (TT group) received therapeutic touch for 10 minutes a day for five consecutive days. The practice was implemented in line with Therapeutic Practice Procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo: Sham Therapeutic Touch (STT) The control group was administered STT instead of TT for 10 minutes for successive 5 days. The practice was implemented in line with Sham Therapeutic Touch Practice Procedure (STTPP).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Therapeutic Touch</intervention_name>
    <description>Therapeutic Touch performed in line with the Therapeutic Touch Practice Procedure included the following steps: centering, assessing, rebalancing, reassessing, reexamining, grounding, and closure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experiment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham Therapeutic Touch</intervention_name>
    <description>The control group was administered STT instead of TT for 10 minutes for successive 5 days. The practice was implemented in line with STTPP. The practice was implemented by not centering or intending to help to heal, by moving at a longer distance, and by imitating the TT practice protocol visually.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The study included women who agreed to participate in the study, lived in the city center,&#xD;
        were at least literate, were in the natural premenopausal (irregular menstrual cycle within&#xD;
        the last three months), perimenopausal (amenorrhea for 3-11 months or increased irregular&#xD;
        menstruation), or postmenopausal (amenorrhea for more than 12 months) periods, were open to&#xD;
        communication and cooperation, and could speak Turkish.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The women who received hormone replacement treatment, used drugs for sleep problems and&#xD;
        depression, were diagnosed with a medical psychiatric disease, and had sensitivity or&#xD;
        problems about touching were excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ebru GOZUYESIL, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Cukurova University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ozlem Yalcinkaya</name>
      <address>
        <city>Adana</city>
        <state>Saricam</state>
        <zip>01330</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 14, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 14, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cukurova University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ozlem Yalcinkaya</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Msc Student</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Menopause</keyword>
  <keyword>Sleep</keyword>
  <keyword>Fatigue</keyword>
  <keyword>Therapeutic touch</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

