<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796271</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CTMS# 22-0016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796271</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial of Roflumilast Added to Standard Chemoimmunotherapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Trial of Roflumilast Added to Standard Chemoimmunotherapy for High-risk Diffuse Large B-cell Lymphoma (CTMS# 22-0016)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is an investigator-initiated, phase II, single arm, open label clinical trial that&#xD;
      will enroll subjects with untreated diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLCBL) at moderate or high&#xD;
      risk for poor outcome, defined as an NCCN-IPI score of 2 or higher. All subjects will receive&#xD;
      investigational drug, and outcomes will be compared to historical controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-tumor efficacy: progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured every 3 weeks for 21 day cycles for the duration of study treatment, from Baseline to approximately one year</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the change in anti-tumor efficacy of Roflumilast in combination with R-CHOP in subjects with previously untreated high-risk DLBCL who are appropriate for treatment by estimates of progression-free survival (PFS).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Lymphoma, B-Cell</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>R-Chop and Roflumilast</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All subjects will receive R-CHOP therapy at standard doses according to the standard preparation and infusion procedures of each investigational site, which is to be repeated every 21 days (+/- 3 days) for a total of 6 cycles. All subjects will receive a fixed oral dose of one 500 microgram (μg) tablet of roflumilast per day with or without food for all 21 days of each cycle, which will amount to a total of 126 doses. Subjects will be asked to keep a drug diary to record the days and times when Roflumilast is taken. The first dose will be given on the day of the first R-CHOP treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>R-Chop and Roflumilast</intervention_name>
    <description>All subjects will receive R-CHOP therapy at standard doses according to the standard preparation and infusion procedures of each investigational site, which is to be repeated every 21 days (+/- 3 days) for a total of 6 cycles. All subjects will receive a fixed oral dose of one 500 microgram (μg) tablet of roflumilast per day with or without food for all 21 days of each cycle, which will amount to a total of 126 doses. Subjects will be asked to keep a drug diary to record the days and times when Roflumilast is taken. The first dose will be given on the day of the first R-CHOP treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>R-Chop and Roflumilast</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Daliresp</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Men and women 18 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pathologically proven diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No prior systemic therapy for lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient has provided informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient is willing and able to comply with clinic visits and procedure outlined in the&#xD;
             study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Life expectancy of ≥3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Ann Arbor stage II-IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. NCCN-IPI risk score of ≥ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Measurable disease, meaning at least 1 lymph node or other lymphomatous lesion with a&#xD;
             long axis of ≥1.5 cm by CT imaging, and at least one FDG-avid lesion by FDG-PET scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Left ventricular ejection fraction of at least 45% by either echocardiography or&#xD;
             radionucleotide angiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Ability to swallow oral tablets without difficulty.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. All subjects with preserved reproductive potential must agree to practice abstinence&#xD;
             or employ contraceptive measures for the duration of treatment and for 4 weeks&#xD;
             following final dosing. All male subjects are considered to have reproductive&#xD;
             potential. Female subjects of reproductive potential are those who: 1) are not at&#xD;
             least 50 years old and have no menses for 24 consecutive months; or 2) have not been&#xD;
             rendered surgically sterile (having undergone hysterectomy and/or bilateral&#xD;
             salpingo-oophorectomy). Female subjects of reproductive potential must have a negative&#xD;
             serum pregnancy test (minimum sensitivity 25 IU/L or equivalent units of human&#xD;
             chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) within 7 days of first day of drug dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Meet the following clinical laboratory requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine clearance ≥30 ml/min by Cockcroft-Gault formula;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN) (unless indirect bilirubin is&#xD;
                  elevated due to Gilbert's syndrome or hemolysis);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST and ALT≤ 3 × ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 50,000/μL, with or without transfusion support;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ANC ≥ 1000/μL, with or without chronic granulocyte growth factor support;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥8 g/dL, with or without transfusion support.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Any active malignancy other than DLBCL 3. High grade B Cell Lymphoma with rearrangements&#xD;
        of MYC and BCL2, MYC and BCL6, and /or MYC and BCL2/BCL6 (&quot;double-hit&quot; or &quot;triple-hit&quot;&#xD;
        DLBCL) 4. Current participation in another interventional clinical study 5. Prior&#xD;
        allogeneic bone marrow transplant within 12 months of screening date. 6. Prior autologous&#xD;
        stem cell transplant within 6 months of screening date. 7. Immunotherapy, chemotherapy,&#xD;
        radiotherapy, or investigational therapy within 6 months prior to drug dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Active central nervous system (CNS) involvement by lymphoma, including untreated&#xD;
        symptomatic epidural disease 9. Active uncontrolled infection. 10. Poorly controlled&#xD;
        depressive symptoms and/or currently under management for depression that is poorly&#xD;
        controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
        11. Significant disease or medical conditions, as assessed by the Investigator and Sponsor,&#xD;
        that would substantially increase the risk-benefit ratio of participating in the study.&#xD;
        This includes, but is not limited to, acute myocardial infarction within the last 6 months,&#xD;
        unstable angina, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, significant active infections, and&#xD;
        congestive heart failure New York Heart Association Class III-IV.&#xD;
&#xD;
        12. Second malignancy, except treated basal cell or localized squamous skin carcinomas,&#xD;
        localized prostate cancer, or other malignancies for which subjects are not on active&#xD;
        anti-cancer therapies and have had no evidence of active malignancy for at least 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        13. History of major surgery within 3 weeks or minor surgery within 1 week of roflumilast&#xD;
        administration. Major surgery includes, for example, any open or laparoscopic entry into a&#xD;
        body cavity, or operative repair of fracture; minor surgery includes, for example, open&#xD;
        surgical biopsy of palpable/superficial lymph node, or placement of vascular access device.&#xD;
&#xD;
        14. Other medical or psychiatric illness or organ dysfunction, which in the opinion of the&#xD;
        investigator, would either compromise the subject's safety or interfere with the evaluation&#xD;
        of the safety of the study agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        15. Corrected QT interval (QTc) prolongation (defined as a QTc &gt;450 ms for males and &gt;470&#xD;
        ms for females Fridericia's correction) or other clinically significant ECG abnormalities&#xD;
        as assessed by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        16. Baseline serum troponin above the upper limit of normal. 17. Baseline serum BNP above&#xD;
        the age-adjusted upper limit of normal. 18. Baseline amylase above the upper limit of&#xD;
        normal. 19. Subjects known to be HIV-positive must not have multi-drug resistant HIV&#xD;
        infection, CD4 counts &lt; 150/μl or other concurrent AIDS-defining conditions. Serologic&#xD;
        screening for HIV is required within the 6 months prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        20. Subjects positive for Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or Hepatitis C-virus&#xD;
        ribonucleic acid (HCV RNA), unless both AST and ALT≤1.25 x ULN and there is no known&#xD;
        history of chronic active hepatitis. Serologic screening for hepatitis B and C testing is&#xD;
        required within the 6 months prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        21. Subjects with moderate or severe liver impairment, as defined by a Child-Pugh class of&#xD;
        B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
        22. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding. 23. Current use of any of the following&#xD;
        medications: boceprevir, carbamazepine, ciprofloxacin, cobicistat, conivaptan,&#xD;
        enzalutamide, fluvoxamine, itraconazole, ketoconazole, mitotane, phenytoin, posaconazole,&#xD;
        rifampin, ritonavir, St. John's Wort, telaprevir, voriconazole, or zafirlukast.&#xD;
&#xD;
        24. Current use of non-nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors (NNRTI) including&#xD;
        efavirenz, rilpivirine, etravirine, delavirdine, nevirapine, and lersivirine.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Epp Goodwin</last_name>
    <phone>210-450-5798</phone>
    <email>goodwine@uthscsa.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mays Cancer Center, UT Health San Antonio</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All collected IPD that underlie results in publication will be shared at the end of the study.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>At study end upon approval for publication</ipd_time_frame>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

