<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612633</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PU-H71-OS-0204</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612633</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Zelavespib (PU-H71) in Subjects With AP-MPN or BP-MPN</brief_title>
  <acronym>AP-MPN</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Open-label Study of Zelavespib (PU-H71) in Subjects With Accelerated Phase Myeloproliferative Neoplasm (AP MPN) or Blast Phase Myeloproliferative Neoplasm</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Samus Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Samus Therapeutics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, Phase 2 Simon 2-Stage study designed to assess the safety,&#xD;
      tolerability, PK, and efficacy of oral zelavespib (PU-H71) administered daily in adults with&#xD;
      accelerated phase (10% to 19% blasts in peripheral or bone marrow) myeloproliferative&#xD;
      neoplasm, with or without ongoing concomitant treatment with ruxolitinib.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Oral zelavespib 1501050 mg will be administered once daily (QD), in the morning ≥ 1 hour&#xD;
      before eating breakfast, for each day of a 21-day cycle, for 6 cycles. Subjects who derive&#xD;
      clinical benefit may continue treatment until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity,&#xD;
      death, or study termination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Stage 1, up to 2317 subjects will be enrolled and will complete 6 cycles of treatment. If&#xD;
      fewer than 2 subjects achieve &lt;CR?/PR?/CBR?/PBR?&gt; in Stage 1, the trial will be stopped for&#xD;
      futility. If 2 or more subjects achieve &lt;CR?/PR?/CBR?/PBR?&gt;a response , an additional 33&#xD;
      subjects will be enrolled, enrollment will begin in Stage 2 for a total of 56 subjects. . If&#xD;
      fewer than 2 subjects achieve a response in Stage 1, the trial will be stopped for futility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Cycle 1, subjects will attend 3 clinic visits (Day 1, Day 8, and Day 15) and will be&#xD;
      contacted by phone by the site at approximately Day 4 . In subsequent cycles, subjects will&#xD;
      attend a clinic visit on Day 1 onlyand will be contacted by phone on Days 8 and 15 so the&#xD;
      site staff can inquire about changes in concomitant medications and potential AEs. On days of&#xD;
      clinic visits, subjects will arrive at the clinic without eating anything in the morning or&#xD;
      taking the study drug. Predose biological samples will be collected for safety laboratory&#xD;
      tests and other clinical assessments, and subjects will undergo physical examinations and&#xD;
      ECGs. Subjects will receive the study drug at the clinic and at least 1 hour after dosing,&#xD;
      breakfast will be provided. On some clinic days, subjects may be required to remain in the&#xD;
      clinic for up to 8 hours for additional ECGs and collection of samples for PK testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will participate in the study for approximately 6.5 months , which includes a&#xD;
      28-day screening period, 6 cycles of treatment, and a final follow-up visit 30 days after the&#xD;
      final dose of study treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Samus Therapeutics Closure&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 15, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 23, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>In Stage 1, up to 2317 subjects will be enrolled and will complete 6 cycles of treatment. If fewer than 2 subjects achieve &lt;CR?/PR?/CBR?/PBR?&gt; in Stage 1, the trial will be stopped for futility. If 2 or more subjects achieve &lt;CR?/PR?/CBR?/PBR?&gt;a response , an additional 33 subjects will be enrolled, enrollment will begin in Stage 2 for a total of 56 subjects.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the MTD and safety of PU-H71 in subjects with AP-MPN and BP-MPN</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the safety profile by measuring Incidence and severity of adverse events (AEs), changes in physical examinations, electrocardiograms (ECGs), vital signs, and clinical laboratory evaluations</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Accelerated Phase MPN</condition>
  <condition>Blast Phase MPN</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral zelavespib 100 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral zelavespib 100 mg will be administered once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>zelavespib</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral zelavespib 100 mg will be administered once daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oral zelavespib 100 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able to provide signed informed consent and willing to comply with the requirements&#xD;
             and restrictions listed in the informed consent form and in this protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Confirmed diagnosis of accelerated phase (10% to 19% blasts in peripheral blood or&#xD;
             bone marrow) MPN arising on the background of previous PMF, PV, or ET&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients taking ruxolitinib must have been taking it for at least 3 months, with a&#xD;
             stable dose at least 1 month before Cycle 1 Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 1 to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Acceptable organ function at screening, defined by the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 500/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. platelet count ≥ 50,000/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2 × the&#xD;
                  upper limit of normal (ULN )&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. total serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. creatinine clearance &gt; 25 mL/min/1.73 m2 based on the Cockcroft-Gault equation&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Women of childbearing potential (defined as premenopausal or within 2 years of the&#xD;
             onset of menopause, and not surgically sterile) must meet both the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. negative urine or serum pregnancy test at screening and within 72 hours before&#xD;
                  the first dose of zelavespib&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. agree to use one of the following acceptable method of highly effective&#xD;
                  contraception for the duration of the study and for 13 weeks after the final dose&#xD;
                  of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Men must agree to the following requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. men who are sexually active with women of childbearing potential must agree to the&#xD;
             following requirements for the duration of their participation in the study and for 13&#xD;
             weeks after the final dose of study treatment: i. if the method of contraception is&#xD;
             abstinence from penile vaginal intercourse as a usual and preferred lifestyle&#xD;
             (abstinent on a long-term and persistent basis), men must agree to remain abstinent&#xD;
             ii. if having penile vaginal intercourse with a nonpregnant, non-breastfeeding woman&#xD;
             of childbearing potential, men must use a male condom, and their female partner must&#xD;
             use a highly effective contraceptive method with a failure rate &lt; 1% per year iii. men&#xD;
             with a pregnant or breastfeeding partner must agree to remain abstinent from penile&#xD;
             vaginal intercourse or use a male condom during each episode of penile penetration iv.&#xD;
             men must refrain from donating sperm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known active liver disease, including viral hepatitis or cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known or suspected infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or other active&#xD;
             infection requiring acute or chronic treatment with systemic antibiotics (conditions&#xD;
             requiring topical antibiotics are not exclusionary)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Positive for HIV 1 or 2, hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), or anti-hepatitis C&#xD;
             virus (HCV) antibodies at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous treatment with a hypomethylating agent&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Corrected QT interval using Fridericia's formula (QTcF) &gt; 480 ms at screening or&#xD;
             baseline ECG based on the median value of ECGs&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Personal or family history of long QT syndrome or taking any medication within 1 week&#xD;
             or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer) before Cycle 1 Day 1 that carries a risk of&#xD;
             Torsades de Pointes&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Left ventricular ejection fraction ≤ 50% or below the institution's lower limit of&#xD;
             normal (whichever is lower) by echocardiogram or multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Coronary artery disease with an ischemic event within 6 months before screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of a second primary malignancy within 6 months before screening that requires&#xD;
             treatment with systemic antineoplastic agents, except for the following, if&#xD;
             appropriately treated and considered cured: Stage 1 endometrial cancer, surgically&#xD;
             treated cervical or prostate carcinoma, and nonmelanoma skin cancer Note: Subjects who&#xD;
             are receiving adjuvant or preventive therapy for indolent cancers may be eligible, and&#xD;
             the investigator should discuss with the medical monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any significant uncontrolled medical condition, as determined by the investigator,&#xD;
             within 6 months before screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Planned use of antineoplastic agents (chemotherapy or cytotoxic drugs), immunotherapy,&#xD;
             experimental therapy, or biologic therapy for treatment of MPN, with the exception of&#xD;
             ruxolitinib&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Use of systemic corticosteroids (ie, prednisone &gt; 20 mg/day or equivalent within 2&#xD;
             weeks before Cycle 1 Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Planned or current use of strong cytochrome P450 (CYP)3A4/5, CYP2D6, or CYP2C19&#xD;
             inhibitors or inducers within 1 week or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer, for a&#xD;
             maximum of 4 weeks) before Cycle 1 Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Planned or current use of herbal preparations/medications within 7 days before Cycle 1&#xD;
             Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Previous exposure to zelavespib (PU-H71)&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any other condition or laboratory abnormality or receiving any other treatment that,&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator, may increase the risk associated with study&#xD;
             participation or that may interfere with interpretation of the study results&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Active ocular condition (eg, ocular inflammatory disease that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, may worsen during the course of the study, or a history or anticipation&#xD;
             of major ocular surgery (eg, cataract extraction or other intraocular surgery) during&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Currently pregnant or breastfeeding, or planning to become pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of gastrointestinal surgery or current gastrointestinal condition that could&#xD;
             affect the absorption of oral medication&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>myeloproliferative neoplasm</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Blast Crisis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

