<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05614037</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>YYKQ-202207</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05614037</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets and Felodipine Sustained Release Tablets in Healthy Subjects Under Fasting State Comparative Pharmacokinetic Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets and Felodipine Sustained Release Tablets in Healthy Subjects Under Fasting State: Single Dose, Randomized, Open, 2-treatment，2-period，Crossover Comparative Pharmacokinetic Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Guangzhou Kangqi Medical Technology Co., LTD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets and Felodipine Modified-release Tablets in Healthy&#xD;
      Subjects Under Fasting State: Single Dose, Randomized, Open, 2-treatment，2-period，Crossover&#xD;
      Comparative Pharmacokinetic Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main research objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets(strength: 5 mg) developed by Overseas Pharmaceuticals,&#xD;
      Ltd., and Felodipine Modified-release Tablets (strength: 5 mg) produced by AstraZeneca AB.,&#xD;
      trade name: The pharmacokinetic parameters of the test preparation and the reference&#xD;
      preparation in healthy subjects under fasting state were investigated and compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary research objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To observe the safety of test preparation and reference preparation in healthy subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The subjects were randomly assigned in a 1:1 ratio to one of two sequential administration&#xD;
      groups (group T-R, group R-T). In the first cycle, 8 subjects took the test formulation (T) 5&#xD;
      mg/tablet by fasting, and the other 8 subjects took the reference formulation (R) 5 mg/tablet&#xD;
      by fasting, with about 240 mL warm water. The drug was crossed over after 14 days. Phase I&#xD;
      trial site pharmacists assigned study drugs to each phase according to the randomization&#xD;
      list.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sixteen healthy subjects were randomly divided into two groups, T-R group and R-T group, with&#xD;
      8 cases in each group. The enrolled subjects entered the phase I observation room one day&#xD;
      before the administration of each cycle, and were required to fast for more than 10 hours&#xD;
      from the day before to the morning of the administration. After a blank blood sample was&#xD;
      collected on the morning of administration, the study drug was administered in the fasting&#xD;
      state. The standard meal was taken 4 hours after administration. Each week was performed at 0&#xD;
      h before administration (within 1.5 h before administration) and 0.5 h, 1.0 h, 1.5 h, 2.0 h,&#xD;
      2.5 h, 3.0 h, 3.5 h, 4.0 h, 4.5 h, 5.0 h, 5.5 h, 6.0 h, 6.5 h, 7.0 h, 7.5 h, 8.0 h, 8.5 h,&#xD;
      9.0 h, 10.0 h, 12.0 h, 24.0 h, 48.0 h, 72.0 h, a total of 24 blood sampling points were&#xD;
      collected from the upper limb vein.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vital signs (including body temperature (frontal temperature), pulse and blood pressure) were&#xD;
      measured at 0 h before administration (within 1.5 h before administration) and 4.0± 0.5 h,&#xD;
      8.0± 0.5 h, 24.0± 1.0 h, 48.0± 1.0 h and 72.0± 1.0 h after administration. The operation&#xD;
      procedure of the second cycle is the same as that of the first cycle. In the second cycle,&#xD;
      the subjects were required to take physical examination, vital signs examination,&#xD;
      electrocardiogram and laboratory examination on the day after the end of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a subject has an AE during the trial, the investigator should try to follow the subject&#xD;
      until the adverse event resolves, or returns to the screening level, or the subject's&#xD;
      condition is stable.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 28, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 20, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Test preparation (T) : Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets Specification: 5 mg Batch number: 22090301 Content: 100.8% Valid until: September 2024 Storage conditions: sealed, room temperature (10~30℃) Manufacturer: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Supplier: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Reference preparation (R) :Felodipine Modified-release tablets(trade name: plendil ®) Specification: 5 mg Batch number: 2204 a11 Content: 99.1% Valid until March 2025 Storage conditions: below 25℃ Manufacturer: AstraZeneca AB Supplier: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve from time zero to the time of the last quantifiable plasma concentration of the period (AUC0-last)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The 90% CI for the geometric mean ratios (i.e., antilog-transformation for 90% CI of difference with log transformation) of AUC0-last within [0.8, 1.25] range will be used to determine the result of bioequivalence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve from time zero to infinity (AUC0-inf)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The 90% CI for the geometric mean ratios (i.e., antilog-transformation for 90% CI of difference with log transformation)of AUC0-inf within [0.8, 1.25] range will be used to determine the result of bioequivalence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak concentration at each treatment period (Cmax,tp)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The 90% CI for the geometric mean ratios (i.e., antilog-transformation for 90% CI of difference with log transformation)of Cmax,tp within [0.8, 1.25] range will be used to determine the result of bioequivalence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak concentration of the first dosing (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Individual felodipine plasma concentration-time profile for each treatment period will be established.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to reach peak concentration of the first dosing (Tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Individual felodipine plasma concentration-time profile for each treatment period will be established.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal half-life (T1/2)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Individual felodipine plasma concentration-time profile for each treatment period will be established.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean residence time (MRT)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Individual felodipine plasma concentration-time profile for each treatment period will be established.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Test preparation (T) :Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets Specification: 5 mg Batch number: 22090301 Content: 100.8% Valid until: September 2024 Storage conditions: sealed, room temperature (10~30℃) Manufacturer: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Supplier: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Usage: Oral, 1 tablet at a time, once a day. Take it before bed and swallow it with water. Do not break, press or chew the pill.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Felodipine Modified-release Tablets (trade name:plendil ®)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Reference preparation (R) : Felodipine Modified-release Tablets (trade name:plendil ®) Specification: 5 mg Batch number: 2204 a11 Content: 99.1% Valid until March 2025 Storage conditions: below 25℃ Manufacturer:AstraZeneca AB Supplier: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Usage: Oral, 1 tablet at a time, once a day. Take it before bed and swallow it with water. Do not break, press or chew the pill.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Felodipine sustained release tablets (trade name: plendil®)</intervention_name>
    <description>Reference preparation (R) : Felodipine sustained release tablets (trade name: plendil ®) Specification: 5 mg Batch number: 2204 a11 Content: 99.1% Valid until March 2025 Storage conditions: below 25℃ Manufacturer: AstraZeneca AB Supplier: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Usage: Oral, 1 tablet at a time, once a day. Take it before bed and swallow it with water. Do not break, press or chew the pill.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>Test preparation (T) :Felodipine Controlled Release Tablets Specification: 5 mg Batch number: 22090301 Content: 100.8% Valid until: September 2024 Storage conditions: sealed, room temperature (10~30℃) Manufacturer: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Supplier: Overseas Pharmaceuticals, Ltd. Usage: Oral, 1 tablet at a time, once a day. Take it before bed and swallow it with water. Do not break, press or chew the pill.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Felodipine Modified-release Tablets (trade name:plendil ®)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The subject is fully aware of the purpose, nature, method and possible adverse&#xD;
             reactions of the study, voluntarily acts as a subject, and signs informed consent&#xD;
             prior to the commencement of any study procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Healthy subjects (male or female) aged 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Male weight ≥50.0 kg, female weight ≥45.0 kg; Body mass index (BMI) was in the range&#xD;
             of 19.0 to 26.0 kg/m2 (including the critical value).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. From the signing of informed consent to 6 months after the end of the study, they had&#xD;
             no fertility plan, voluntarily took appropriate and effective contraceptive measures,&#xD;
             and had no sperm and egg donation plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subjects were able to communicate well with the researchers and understood and&#xD;
             complied with the requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Allergic disposition or a history of food or drug allergy or other allergic diseases&#xD;
             (asthma, urticaria, eczema dermatitis, etc.) that researchers deem clinically&#xD;
             significant; Or allergic to any component of felodipine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with poor vascular puncture conditions, or who cannot tolerate venipunction,&#xD;
             or who have a history of fainting needles and fainting blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with gingivitis and periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous history of compensatory heart failure, acute myocardial infarction, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. lactose intolerance, or galactose intolerance, lactase deficiency, glucose-galactose&#xD;
             malabsorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with confirmed hypotension or history of postural hypotension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The presence of cardiovascular, blood, liver, kidney, endocrine, respiratory,&#xD;
             digestive, nervous, psychiatric, immune, skin, metabolic disorders and other systemic&#xD;
             diseases considered clinically significant by researchers, or a chronic or severe&#xD;
             history of these diseases; Or a history of surgery that may affect drug absorption and&#xD;
             metabolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Physical examination, vital signs examination, 12-lead electrocardiogram and&#xD;
             laboratory examination were abnormal and clinically significant as judged by the study&#xD;
             physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody, hepatitis B virus surface&#xD;
             antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody, or treponema pallidum antibody&#xD;
             (Anti-TP).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Pregnant women, breastfeeding women, or women of childbearing age who have unprotected&#xD;
             sex or pregnancy test positive within 14 days before the planned dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Those who received vaccines (other than COVID-19 vaccine) within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             screening, or who received COVID-19 vaccine within 1 week prior to screening, or who&#xD;
             plan to receive any vaccines during the trial or within 1 week after the study ends;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Those who have donated blood/lost blood ≥400 mL in the 3 months prior to screening or&#xD;
             who have received blood transfusions or used blood products, or who intend to donate&#xD;
             blood (including blood components) during or 3 months after the end of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Previous drug use:&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Those with a history of drug abuse or who have tested positive for drugs and used&#xD;
             drugs in the six months prior to screening, including methylenedioxymethamphetamine&#xD;
             (ecstasy), methamphetamine (meth), ketamine, morphine, and THC (marijuana).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Drugs that inhibit or induce liver metabolism of drugs (such as inducers:&#xD;
             barbiturates, carbamazepine, phenytoin, rifampicin, St. John's wort, etc.) were used&#xD;
             within 28 days before the initial administration; Inhibitors: cimetidine,&#xD;
             cyclosporine, pyrrole antifungal drugs (itraconazole, ketoconazole), macrolides&#xD;
             antibiotics (erythromycin), HIV protease inhibitors, etc.); Or any other medication&#xD;
             including prescription drugs, over-the-counter drugs, functional vitamins, health&#xD;
             products, or Chinese herbs used in the 14 days prior to administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Diet and smoking and alcohol consumption:&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. People who have difficulty swallowing or have special requirements for diet and cannot&#xD;
             accept unified diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Habitual long-term consumption of excessive (more than 8 cups a day, 1 cup =250 mL) of&#xD;
             food or drink containing caffeine (such as coffee, strong tea, cola, chocolate, etc.),&#xD;
             or ingestion of food or drink containing caffeine within 72 hours before the first&#xD;
             medication, or can not be interrupted during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. People who consumed purine-rich foods (such as anchovies, sardines, beef liver, beef&#xD;
             kidney, etc.) or products containing grapefruit, grapefruit juice, grape juice,&#xD;
             menthol within 48 hours before administration, or planned intake or could not be&#xD;
             interrupted during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Those who had started a significantly abnormal diet (e.g., diet, low sodium) within 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Excessive smoking within 6 months prior to screening (mean ≥5 doses/day) or within 48&#xD;
             hours prior to the first dose, or unable to stop using any tobacco products during the&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. those who have a history of alcoholism or are regular drinkers in the six months prior&#xD;
             to screening, that is, drinking more than 14 units of alcohol per week (1 unit =360 mL&#xD;
             beer with 5% alcohol by volume or 45 mL spirits with 40% alcohol by volume or 150 mL&#xD;
             wine with 12% alcohol by volume), Or consumed alcohol or food or beverages within 48&#xD;
             hours before the first dose, or tested positive for alcohol on the day of the first&#xD;
             cycle check-in, or were unable to stop alcohol consumption during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Other:&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Participants who had participated or were participating in clinical trials of other&#xD;
             drugs (defined as having used investigational drugs) in the 3 months prior to&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Subjects who were assessed by the investigator for other factors unsuitable for&#xD;
             participation in this clinical study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Trial Centre of Dongguan Kanghua Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dongguan</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <zip>523000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Felodipine</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
  <keyword>morning surge</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Felodipine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

