<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798429</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>compassion in nursing</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798429</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Compassion Education on Compassion Adequacy and Moral Sensitivity in Nursing Students</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Compassion Education on Compassion Adequacy and Moral Sensitivity in Nursing Students</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aliye Yıldırım</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Suleyman Demirel University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this thesis study is to determine the effect of compassion education on compassion&#xD;
      adequacy and moral sensitivity in nursing students. The sample of the descriptive study&#xD;
      consists of the first year nursing students studying at Süleyman Demirel University in the&#xD;
      2022-2023 academic year. The research will be carried out between October 2022 and September&#xD;
      2023. Research data will be collected from nursing students who volunteered to participate in&#xD;
      the research by using the Personal Information Form, which includes the demographic&#xD;
      characteristics of the students, the Compassion Adequacy Scale and the Modified Moral&#xD;
      Sensitivity Scale for Nursing Students.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Values have an important place in the nursing profession. In this context, it is necessary to&#xD;
      know the concept of compassion, which is among the values of health care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since the concept of Compassion-Compassion takes place in many disciplines, it has many&#xD;
      definitions. According to the Turkish Language Association, it is defined as 'the feeling of&#xD;
      sadness and pity for the bad situation that a person or another living thing encounters'&#xD;
      (TDK). In the Dictionary of Bioethics Terms, it is defined as &quot;an emotion directed towards a&#xD;
      person or group (sometimes other than human beings) in a difficult or worse situation&quot; .&#xD;
&#xD;
      When compassion is considered in the nursing profession, it is seen as an ethical obligation.&#xD;
      The ethical codes and declarations of the American Nurses Association and the International&#xD;
      Council of Nurses are also based on compassion .&#xD;
&#xD;
      While talking about care in Roach, he suggested that the concept of compassion is one of the&#xD;
      characteristics that a caregiver should have . Cummings and Bennett defined the features&#xD;
      required for the formation of a care culture with the concept of 6 Cs and emphasized that&#xD;
      compassion is important here .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compassion can be learned and developed from the environment and conditions. The purpose of&#xD;
      education is to provide individuals with certain behaviors. Explaining compassion education&#xD;
      to students not only increases compassion towards other individuals, but also allows them to&#xD;
      have positive emotions, integrating the coping methods they have gained into their own lives,&#xD;
      increasing their feelings of compassion towards themselves.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The concept of compassion adequacy was defined by Lee and Seomun as &quot;the capacity of a person&#xD;
      to successfully fulfill the responsibilities expected from him within the norms of society&quot;.&#xD;
      Nurses should not only have the care that meets the physical needs, but also have the&#xD;
      adequacy of the skills that meet the psychosocial needs. Moral sensitivity has an important&#xD;
      place in this holistic care provided by nurses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moral sensitivity is seeing the existence of ethical problems. It is also defined as the&#xD;
      personal capacity to identify ethical problems in specific events in the relationship between&#xD;
      patients and nurses. A nurse who does not have compassion for her patient cannot realize the&#xD;
      situation of the patient and does not have moral sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Generation Z, who will be in the nursing profession in the coming years, will have weak&#xD;
      family ties, underdevelopment of their emotional intelligence, more narcissistic&#xD;
      personalities, love to work independently, have high individuality and are less loyal than&#xD;
      other generations. causes a low sense of compassion and therefore negatively affects their&#xD;
      moral sensitivities. Since the Z generation is usually an only child and prevents&#xD;
      socialization with people, their interpersonal relationships are weaker than other&#xD;
      generations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this context, although there are studies in the literature stating that compassion has an&#xD;
      important place in nursing education, no study has been found that examines the effect of&#xD;
      compassion education on nursing students' compassion efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this thesis is to examine the effect of compassion education on compassion&#xD;
      proficiency in nursing students.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The aim of this study is to examine the effect of compassion training on compassion proficiency in nursing students.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It will be collected from nursing students who volunteered to participate in the research by using the Compassion Adequacy Scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The aim of this study is to examine the effect of compassion training on compassion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It will be collected from nursing students who volunteered to participate in the research by using the Modified Moral Sensitivity Scale for Nursing Students&quot;.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Compassion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>compassion education</intervention_name>
    <description>6 weeks of compassion training</description>
    <arm_group_label>experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  - voluntarily agree to participate in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuing to work as an administrator in undergraduate places of Süleyman Demirel&#xD;
             University&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being able to understand and speak Turkish,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No hearing and speech problems&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not voluntarily participating in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Does not understand Turkish&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 4, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 23, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 23, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Suleyman Demirel University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aliye Yıldırım</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Nurse</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nursing Students</keyword>
  <keyword>compassion</keyword>
  <keyword>Compassion Competence</keyword>
  <keyword>Moral Sensitivity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

