<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05794815</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UKMPPI/111/6/JEP-2023-074</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05794815</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Modulation of Gut Microbiota by Probiotic in Children With Respiratory Symptoms</brief_title>
  <official_title>Modulation of Gut Microbiota by Probiotic in Children With Respiratory Symptoms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Min-Tze LIONG</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National University of Malaysia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universiti Sains Malaysia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This project aims to study the benefits of probiotics namely Bifidobacterium infantis&#xD;
      YLGB-1496 in modulating gut microbiota of children with respiratory symptoms, among&#xD;
      pre-school children in Malaysia aged &gt;12 months old, &lt;7 years old.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Probiotic can be defined as &quot;live microorganisms that grant health effects to the host if&#xD;
      consumed in sufficient amounts&quot;. Probiotic bacteria, which beneficially affect the host by&#xD;
      improving the intestinal microbial balance, may affect the immune response, thus boosting the&#xD;
      body system to combat against diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Respiratory illnesses are the most common acute diseases in children where no virtually&#xD;
      effective treatments or prophylaxes are available for these infections. Probiotics on the&#xD;
      other hand have gained increasing evidences as an effective therapy in preventing respiratory&#xD;
      tract infections. Children attending day care are especially at risk for acquiring&#xD;
      respiratory illness, as close physical contact among children in day care favour the&#xD;
      transmission of infectious diseases. When studying children receiving either probiotic in&#xD;
      milk and control milk, the number of absences from day care because of illness is&#xD;
      significantly lesser in probiotic group when compared with control group. In addition,&#xD;
      children in the probiotic group had fewer respiratory tract infections with complications&#xD;
      (otitis media, sinusitis, bronchitis and pneumonia) and less prescribed antibiotic&#xD;
      treatments. The time without respiratory symptoms was also significantly longer in the&#xD;
      probiotic group compared with the control group. When the effects of probiotics were studied&#xD;
      on nasopharyngeal carriage of bacterial pathogens, the number of human bocavirus was reduced&#xD;
      significantly in the nasopharynx of these children, indicating that probiotics may be more&#xD;
      effective against respiratory tract infections of viral origin. While the precise mechanisms&#xD;
      of using probiotics in management of respiratory infections are largely unknown, speculations&#xD;
      include: probiotics compete against pathogens; increase the barrier function in respiratory&#xD;
      epithelium; immunostimulatory effects by enhancing cellular immunity with increased activity&#xD;
      of natural killer cells and macrophages in airways. Hence, probiotics may offer safe means of&#xD;
      reducing the risk of early respiratory related illnesses, common cold and antibiotic use, and&#xD;
      the risk of recurrent respiratory infections, thereby represent a simple, safe, effective,&#xD;
      available and affordable method for preventing respiratory infections in children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In worldwide, it is estimated that 5.2 million of children under five of age die every year&#xD;
      due to preventable disease such as diarrhea, malaria and pneumonia. Up to date, diarrhea&#xD;
      still remains as global health issues, even in developing countries, with 1 million of&#xD;
      children deaths reported to be attributed to diarrhea. In Malaysia, reported cases of&#xD;
      diarrhea and acute gastroenteritis have been observed to occur throughout the year, with&#xD;
      rotavirus-associated diarrhea being the most prevalently identified gastrointestinal&#xD;
      disorder. One of the most common gastrointestinal disorders in young children, is diarrhea.&#xD;
      Diarrhea is commonly defined as three or more loose or watery stools in the last 24 hours.&#xD;
      For clinical studies employing oral administration of probiotics, the probiotics were&#xD;
      administered directly to the participants or mixed with a variety of fluids and foods. In&#xD;
      studies on probiotic prevention of acute diarrhea in daycare centres worldwide, probiotics&#xD;
      tested such as Lactobacillus GG, Bifidobacterium lactis (alone or in combination with&#xD;
      Streptococcus thermophiles), and Lactobacillus reuteri, Lactobacillus casei and Lactobacillus&#xD;
      acidophilus showed a clear evidence of efficacy to reduce diarrhea-related symptoms in a&#xD;
      strain-dependent and dose-dependent manner. Probiotics administration reduces duration of&#xD;
      diarrhea, indicating the efficacy of probiotics not only in preventing occurrence of&#xD;
      diarrhea, as well as to treat episodes of diarrhea. Probiotics Lactobacillus acidophilus,&#xD;
      Lactobacillus rhamnosus, Bifidobacterium longum and Saccharomyces boulardii also showed&#xD;
      decreased time of vomiting in the intervention groups as compared with controls during the&#xD;
      probiotics treatment of acute rotavirus diarrhoea. The rationale for using probiotics in&#xD;
      infectious diarrhoea is that they act against enteric pathogens by competing for available&#xD;
      nutrients and binding sites, making the gut contents acid, producing a variety of chemicals,&#xD;
      and increasing specific and non-specific immune responses. Probiotics reduced infectious&#xD;
      diarrhoea in children and adults in various settings but a mechanism common to most&#xD;
      probiotics, for example, colonization resistance, is effective against a wide range of gut&#xD;
      pathogens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Probiotic bacteria, which beneficially affect the host by improving the intestinal microbial&#xD;
      balance, may affect the immune response, thus boosting the body system to combat against&#xD;
      diseases. Probiotics have been studied extensively for their effects in preventing and&#xD;
      treating a multitude of conditions, including the treatment of lactose intolerance,&#xD;
      traveller's diarrhoea and the prevention and treatment of nosocomial diarrhoea. In acute&#xD;
      diarrhoea, a reduction in the frequency of diarrhoeal symptoms has been reported in adults&#xD;
      and children treated with probiotics. Among the beneficial microbes, Bifidobacterium is one&#xD;
      of the best-known probiotic genus in the world, and it is widely applied in the dairy&#xD;
      industry as a probiotic. Evidences from in vitro, in vivo, and clinical studies and long&#xD;
      consumption history support the safety and health benefits of Bifidobacterium strains. The&#xD;
      ingestion of yogurt fortified with B. longum reduced harmful bacteria such as&#xD;
      Enterobacteriaceae, Streptococcus and C. perfringens, while at the same time alter the&#xD;
      microbiota gut profile of volunteers with a significant increase of beneficial microbes&#xD;
      Bifidobacterium and Lactobacillus species. Additionally, putrefactive substances in the&#xD;
      intestinal environment were also reduced in the presence of the probiotic supplement. Such&#xD;
      findings suggest that Bifidobacterium strains are safe and could be used further to evaluate&#xD;
      its effect in preventing diarrhea and/or respiratory-related illness prevalence in young&#xD;
      children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Probiotic (Bifidobacterium infantis YLGB-1496) adheres to probiotic properties such as&#xD;
      excellent tolerance to gastric acid, intestinal fluid and bile salt of the digestive system.&#xD;
      Both probiotic and placebo products are manufactured under HACCP conditions. All products do&#xD;
      not contain any animal-origin ingredients. The probiotic product contains probiotic and&#xD;
      carrier while placebo contains only carrier. Sachets of products containing probiotic and&#xD;
      placebo appear as light yellow powder. Both probiotic and placebo products are kept at&#xD;
      storage temperature range below 30oC according to the condition recommended by the&#xD;
      manufacturer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiota profiles of fecal samples in children with respiratory tract infections upon administration of probiotic as assessed via pyrosequencing</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in microbiota abundance in fecal sample of children with respiratory tract infections upon administration o probiotic compared to placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical respiratory symptoms duration and frequency in children with respiratory tract infections upon administration of probiotic as assessed using the Monthly Health Questionnaire (as used in ClinicalTrials.gov (identifier number NCT02434042)</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in duration and frequency of respiratory illnesses symptoms from children on probiotic or placebo after 12-weeks, via the use of questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical gastrointestinal symptoms in children with respiratory tract infections upon administration of probiotic as assessed using the Monthly Gastrointestinal Questionnaire as used in ClinicalTrials.gov (identifier number NCT02434042)</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in duration and frequency of gastrointestinal symptoms of children upon administration of probiotic compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunity profiles in children with respiratory tract infections upon administration of probiotic via the use of oral swabs</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in concentrations of proteins such as interleukins (IL-10, IL-4, IL-6, Tumour Necrosis Factor-alpha, Interferon gamma) in swab samples (ug/mL) of children upon administration of probiotic compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Infection (for Example, Pneumonia, Bronchitis)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Probiotic</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Bifidobacterium infantis YLGB-1496 at 1x10 log CFU/day for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention consists of daily administration of 2g of maltodextrin, administered daily for 12-weeks)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Probiotic</intervention_name>
    <description>Bifidobacterium infantis YLGB-1496 at 1x10 log CFU/day for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Probiotic</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Intervention consists of daily administration of 2g of maltodextrin, administered daily for 12-weeks)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preschool children (&gt;12 months old, &lt;7 years old).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having respiratory symptoms (having at least two of the following signs and symptoms:&#xD;
             fever (even if only reported not measured), nasal obstruction, chills, sore throat,&#xD;
             headache, cough, runny nose, olfactory disturbances, or taste disturbances;&#xD;
             Pucarelli-Lebreiro et al., 2022).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy with current weight of P20-P80 percentile chart of children&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infant formula powder does not contain probiotics; prebiotics FOS is not allowed, GOS&#xD;
             &lt;2g/ 100g is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to commit throughout the experiment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Long term medication &gt;6 months for any diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deformity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mothers with metabolic and/or chronic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or previous diseases, conditions or interventions that may interfere with the&#xD;
             study (such as tolerance and/or growth and development), such as gastrointestinal&#xD;
             malformations, chronic diarrhea, malabsorption syndromes, malnutrition, congenital&#xD;
             immunodeficiency or surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Oral antibiotics within 2 weeks before the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nutritional supplements containing probiotics and prebiotics (except infant formula)&#xD;
             within 2 weeks before the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Foods for special medical purposes or non-standard formula powders for lactose&#xD;
             intolerance and galactosemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Probiotic allergies or possible food allergies (milk, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participated in other clinical studies 4 weeks before the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to participate for any particular reason&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adli Ali, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National University of Malaysia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adli Ali, MD</last_name>
    <phone>603 8921 5555</phone>
    <email>adli.ali@ppukm.ukm.edu.my</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Min Tze Liong, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6046532114</phone>
    <email>mintze.liong@usm.my</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UKM Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cheras</city>
        <state>Kuala Lumpur</state>
        <zip>56000</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adli Adli, MD</last_name>
      <phone>603 8921 5555</phone>
      <email>adli.ali@ppukm.ukm.edu.my</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fahisham Taib, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Intan Juliana Abd. Hamid, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Min Tze Liong, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universiti Sains Malaysia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Min-Tze LIONG</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>probiotic</keyword>
  <keyword>respiratory tract infections</keyword>
  <keyword>Bifidobacterium</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bronchitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Signs and Symptoms, Respiratory</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

