<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798858</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>438/21</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798858</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Pilot Study for Implementation of First Trimester Screening of Aneuploidies in Campania Region</brief_title>
  <acronym>PISTA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study for Implementation of First Trimester Screening of Aneuploidies in Campania Region</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Federico II University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Federico II University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study aims to compare two different protocols for first trimester screening of&#xD;
      aneuploidies, one based on nuchal translucency and NIPT and another one based on the&#xD;
      integration between combined test and NIPT, in order to identify which is the most adequate&#xD;
      for the Campania region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In particular, a cost-benefit comparison will be made which will take into account for each&#xD;
      method:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Actual costs;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Percentage of patients who agree to undergo the proposed screening and number of&#xD;
           patients who undergo extra tests not included in the screening protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Post-invasive procedure miscarriage rate;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  False positives (fetuses undergoing an invasive procedure for a positive screen, which&#xD;
           have a normal karyotype).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION Aneuploidies are pathologies characterized by an alteration in the number of&#xD;
      chromosomes. They represent the most common form of fetal abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The prenatal diagnosis of aneuploidy is currently based both on invasive diagnostic&#xD;
      procedures (amniocentesis and CVS) and on non-invasive screening tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Invasive procedures are diagnostic tests, but they are burdened by quite high costs and by a&#xD;
      risk of miscarriage, which is estimated at around 0.5-1%. For these reasons, these procedures&#xD;
      can not offered to all pregnant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Bindi Decree in 1988 defined advanced maternal age (&gt;35 years) as a sufficient indication&#xD;
      to offer an invasive procedure. However, screening based on maternal age alone demonstrated&#xD;
      very low sensitivity (about 35%) with a very high false positive rate (about 15%).&#xD;
      Furthermore, if we consider the progressive increase in maternal age in the first pregnancy,&#xD;
      we realize that the number of patients who fall into the high-risk group according to&#xD;
      maternal age is extremely high. According to Cedap data 2013, around 25% of pregnant women&#xD;
      were aged &gt;35; this means that invasive procedures were offered to about 1 in 4 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Over the years, aneuploidy screening has improved, first thanks to the introduction of&#xD;
      biochemical markers (tri-tests and quadruple-tests) and, then, with the revolutionary advent&#xD;
      of combined screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This screening is based on anamnestic data (maternal age, previous fetuses affected by&#xD;
      aneuploidies), ultrasound data (measurement of nuchal translucency and fetal heart rate),&#xD;
      biochemical data (dosage of free beta-hCG and PAPP-a: &quot;DUO test&quot; ) with a sensitivity of 90%&#xD;
      and a false positive rate of about 4%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, cell free Dna testing has been introduce; this is a non-invasive test demonstrating&#xD;
      high accuracy (99.7%) for Down syndrome and over 90% accuracy also for Trisomy 13 and 18. The&#xD;
      main limitations of thus test are the high costs and the fact that without a good ultrasound&#xD;
      screening, it does not allow the identification of severe fetal anomalies, easily detectable&#xD;
      already in the first trimester of pregnancy (eg: anencephaly).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2017, the new Essential Levels of Assistance (LEA) have been approved subverting the now&#xD;
      outdated Bindi Decree and introducing the combined test among the procedures that will be&#xD;
      offered by the National Health System free of charge. Moreover, They underlined that access&#xD;
      to invasive procedures should not based on maternal age alone, but on combined risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Campania Region, a regional protocol for first trimester screening of aneuploidy has never&#xD;
      been approved and patients can access both combined screening and cell free fetal DNA only in&#xD;
      private settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our project has as main objective the implementation of the screening for aneuploidies in&#xD;
      Campania Region; moreover, we aim to compare two screening methods to define which one allows&#xD;
      a better identification of the high-risk population to be destined for invasive procedures.&#xD;
      In both cases, the nuchal translucency (NT) ultrasound is performed first, that is a service&#xD;
      provided by the NHS; if this shows a value &lt; 3.5 mm (99th percentile), one of the two&#xD;
      possible procedures will be randomly offered:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In one group, the fetal DNA test (NIPT) is carried out; if this is positive, an&#xD;
           indication is given for the invasive test (villocentesis/amniocentesis).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In the other, the combined test, financed by the research fund, is carried out first; if&#xD;
           this highlights an intermediate risk, we proceed with NIPT, which if positive, directs&#xD;
           us to amniocentesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIAL AND METHODS Patients referred to the Mother &amp; Child Department of theUniversity&#xD;
      Hospital. Federico II of Naples to perform first trimester screenining ultrasound scan, will&#xD;
      be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria: maternal age &lt;18 years, lack of consent to participate in the study, twin&#xD;
      pregnancy, ultrasound finding of a crown rump length &gt;84 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited at the time of the first trimester screening ultrasound (nuchal&#xD;
      translucency-NT), between 11+3 and 13+6 weeks of gestation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the patient decides to participate in the study, she will be asked to sign an informed&#xD;
      consent. We will then proceed with the collection of all the anamnestic data necessary for&#xD;
      the evaluation of the risk of aneuploidies which will be recorded in a dedicated database, in&#xD;
      compliance with the privacy. In particular, the following information will be collected:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age of the patient;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Previous fetuses affected by aneuploidy;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Weight, height, ethnicity, presence of diabetes, type of conception (spontaneous, after&#xD;
           the use of ovulation-inducing drugs, with intrauterine insemination, after&#xD;
           homologous/heterologous medically assisted fertilization techniques).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients who decide to participate in the study will be counseled by a geneticist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomized into two groups according to a 1:1 randomization scheme:&#xD;
&#xD;
      GROUP A: NT+ NIPT (n=200) Group A patients will undergo NT between 11+3 and 13+6 weeks. This&#xD;
      scan will be performed by accredited operators according to the standards set by the Fetal&#xD;
      Medicine Foundation (FMF) and by the Italian Society of Obstetrics and Gynecological&#xD;
      Ultrasound (SIEOG).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ultrasound examination is performed with transabdominal and/or transvaginal ultrasound,&#xD;
      through the use of a real-time ultrasound equipped with a transabdominal and transvaginal&#xD;
      transducer. During this examination, the following parameters will be evaluated, which will&#xD;
      be used to calculate the combined risk:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Crown rump length (CRL): this measurement is obtained from a sagittal scan of the fetus,&#xD;
           which must assume a neutral position, with the head in line with the column (not&#xD;
           hyperflexed or hyperextended). CRL measurement is used to redate pregnancy according to&#xD;
           ultrasound gestational age; this re-dating is not carried out for pregnancies obtained&#xD;
           after medically assisted fertilization in which the dating of the pregnancy is certain.&#xD;
           NT ultrasound can only be performed for CRLs between 45 and 84 mm. In the case of CRL&#xD;
           &lt;45 mm, a new appointment will be scheduled for the patient, while, in the case of CRL&#xD;
           &gt;84 mm, the patient will be excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fetal heart rate (FHR), obtained from a cross-sectional scan of the fetus at the level&#xD;
           of the tricuspid valve.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nuchal translucency (NT): the measurement of NT is obtained in sagittal scan of the&#xD;
           fetus which must appear horizontally on the screen, with obtaining the image of the&#xD;
           fetal profile (reference points: visualization of the nose, the palate must have a&#xD;
           rectangular shape and the frontal process of the maxilla should not be visualised,&#xD;
           visualization of the diencephalon). Ideal images should include only the fetal head and&#xD;
           upper chest. The magnification of the image must be such that each movement of the&#xD;
           caliper produces a change in the measurement of 0.1 mm. Measurements should be taken&#xD;
           with the inner edge of the horizontal line of the calipers positioned on the line&#xD;
           defining the thickness of the nuchal translucency. The horizontal bar of the calipers&#xD;
           should not protrude into the anechoic space of the nuchal translucency. It is necessary&#xD;
           to distinguish the fetal skin from the amnion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Minor ultrasound markers (nasal bone, ductus venosus, tricuspid regurgitation) will not be&#xD;
      included in the combined risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All ultrasound data and images will be saved in a special program dedicated to ultrasound&#xD;
      storage and reporting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the NT is &gt;3.5 mm (99th centile), the patient will be offered an invasive procedure&#xD;
      (amniocentesis or CVS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If, on the other hand, the NT is &lt;3.5 mm, the patient will be offered to continue the&#xD;
      screening with NIPT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A dedicated midwife will complete a specific request and collect a blood sample that will be&#xD;
      sent to the laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If NIPT comes back as positive result, the result will be confirmed by an invasive procedure&#xD;
      (amniocentesis/villocentesis); if, on the other hand, the NIPT will give a negative result,&#xD;
      the screening is concluded and the patient will not undergo further tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GROUP B: Combined test + NIPT (n=200) The patients of group A will undergo NT between 11+3&#xD;
      and 13+6 weeks, according to the same protocol foreseen for Group A.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the NT is &gt;3.5 mm (99th centile), the patient will be offered an invasive procedure&#xD;
      (amniocentesis or CVS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the NT is &lt;3.5 mm, the patient will be offered continuation of the screening using the&#xD;
      combined test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The execution of this test involves the compilation of a special form by a dedicated midwife,&#xD;
      who will also take a blood sample from the patient. The sample will be send to the DAI of&#xD;
      Laboratory and Transfusion Medicine of the AOU Federico II.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The test involves the dosing of two placental products, free beta-hCG and PAPP-a, which will&#xD;
      be carried out through the use of accredited equipment, already available at the DAI of&#xD;
      Laboratory and Transfusion Medicine of AOU Federico II . The patient will be notified of a&#xD;
      risk calculated according to the algorithm proposed by the FMF, which brings together the&#xD;
      patient's basic risk (maternal age, previous affected fetus), ultrasound data (NT, CRL, FHR)&#xD;
      and the two biochemical markers (free beta -hCG and PAPP-a).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High risk (1:2-1:100), the patient will be offered an invasive procedure&#xD;
           (amniocentesis/villocentesis)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intermediate risk (1:101-1:1000), the patient will be offered NIPT, according to the&#xD;
           protocol already described for Group A. In the event of a positive result, the patient&#xD;
           will undergo an invasive procedure (amniocentesis/villocentesis ); in the case of&#xD;
           negative NIPT, the screening is concluded and the patient will not undergo further&#xD;
           tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Low risk (&gt;1:1000), screening ends and the patient will not undergo further tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome collection The collected data will include the outcome of the pregnancy (spontaneous&#xD;
      abortion, voluntary termination of pregnancy, intrauterine fetal death, live birth) and the&#xD;
      cases of aneuploidies found (by karyotype in patients undergoing amniocentesis or CVS or&#xD;
      direct postnatal assessment if prenatal karyotype is not known). All those that occur within&#xD;
      seven days following the procedure will be considered post-procedure abortions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STATISTIC ANALYSIS The statistical analysis will be conducted through the SPSS 27.0&#xD;
      statistical analysis program (Chicago Inc.) All data relating to descriptive analysis will be&#xD;
      reported as median (interquartile range-IQR) for continuous variables, and absolute frequency&#xD;
      (percentage) for categorical variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The comparison between continuous variables will be performed through the parametric test&#xD;
      T-Student and the non-parametric test of Mann-Whitney. The comparison between categorical&#xD;
      variables will make use of the Chi-squared test and Fisher's exact test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlations between parameters will be evaluated through the Pearson correlation&#xD;
      coefficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ETHICAL CONSIDERATIONS The study has been approved by local ethical committee (IRB 438/21)&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPECTED RESULTS AND IMPACT We expect this study to clarify which method is more feasible in&#xD;
      terms of diagnostic accuracy and costs, in order to provide the basis for the identification&#xD;
      of a screening method to be implemented in Campania Region.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 11, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>compliance to the screening</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of patients not performing test not included in arm protocol</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>spontaneous abortions</measure>
    <time_frame>up to seven days</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of post-procedure spontaneous abortions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>sensitivity and specificity of two protocols</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>sensitivity and specificity of two protocols</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>total costs</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>cost- effective analysis of two protocols</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Aneuploidy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A: NT+ NIPT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group A patients will undergo NT between 11+3 and 13+6 weeks. If the NT is &lt;3.5 mm, the patient will be offered to continue the screening with NIPT.&#xD;
If NIPT comes back as positive result, the result will be confirmed by an invasive procedure (amniocentesis/villocentesis); if, on the other hand, the NIPT will give a negative result, the screening is concluded and the patient will not undergo further tests.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combined test + NIPT (n=200) The patients of group A will undergo NT between 11+3 and 13+6 weeks, according to the same protocol foreseen for Group A.&#xD;
If the NT is &lt;3.5 mm, the patient will be offered continuation of the screening using the combined test.&#xD;
In case of:&#xD;
High risk (1:2-1:100), the patient will be offered an invasive procedure (amniocentesis/villocentesis) Intermediate risk (1:101-1:1000), the patient will be offered NIPT, according to the protocol already described for Group A. In the event of a positive result, the patient will undergo an invasive procedure (amniocentesis/villocentesis ); in the case of negative NIPT, the screening is concluded and the patient will not undergo further tests.&#xD;
Low risk (&gt;1:1000), screening ends and the patient will not undergo further tests.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NIPT</intervention_name>
    <description>universal nipt in group a, NIPT for intermediate risk in Group B</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A: NT+ NIPT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  all patients referred to our hospital for first trimester screening scan&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  maternal age&lt;18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  twin pregnancies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of a signed consent form&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Federico II</name>
      <address>
        <city>Naples</city>
        <zip>80131</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laura Sarno, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+390817462966</phone>
      <email>laura.sarno@unina.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 21, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 2, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Federico II University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Laura Sarno</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator, Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>aneuploidy</keyword>
  <keyword>screening</keyword>
  <keyword>combined test</keyword>
  <keyword>non invasive prenatal testing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aneuploidy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

