<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796427</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2023-5814</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796427</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing &quot;SupporT for ADHD and Related Treatment&quot; (START) for Families of Children With ADHD</brief_title>
  <acronym>START</acronym>
  <official_title>Testing a Novel ADHD Engagement Intervention &quot;START&quot; to Improve Access to Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ann &amp; Robert H Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ann &amp; Robert H Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Our randomized control trial (RCT) study includes 2 aims; one being to test whether START&#xD;
      increases access to treatment for ADHD. We believe our intervention group will demonstrate&#xD;
      improved treatment engagement and access to all treatments compared to controls. Our second&#xD;
      aim is to explore whether START leads to functional improvements across home, social and&#xD;
      academic domains for the child and family. We believe the intervention group will show better&#xD;
      functioning including improved family and peer relationships and reduced parent stress&#xD;
      compared to controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before taking part in our study all participants will undergo a psychiatric evaluation.&#xD;
      Eligible participants will be randomized to START while controls receive a pamphlet with ADHD&#xD;
      information. Students and staff with related experience who are not mental health&#xD;
      professionals will be trained to deliver START. START includes 6 modules, typically delivered&#xD;
      over 6 sessions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ADHD Treatment Utilization</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Items from the National Survey of the Diagnosis and Treatment of ADHD and Tourette Syndrome (NS-DATA). Centers for Disease Control (CDC) survey used to evaluate treatment use among children with ADHD and Tourette syndrome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ADHD Symptoms and Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Vanderbilt ADHD Diagnostic Rating Scale (VADRS). 55-item, parent-report questionnaire that assesses symptoms of ADHD and comorbidities as well as functional impairment in multiple domains (academics, family and peer relationships).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Engagement Objectives</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>ADHD Treatment Engagement Questionnaire. Developed by the PI for the pilot trial to assess engagement objectives directly corresponding to the conceptual model.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent ADHD Treatment Preferences</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>ADHD Preference and Goal Instrument (PGI). Validated measure used in ADHD engagement studies that assesses parent perceptions of treatment feasibility, acceptability, and adverse effects for medication and therapy separately, as well as overall treatment goals.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ADHD Knowledge</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>ADHD Content Knowledge Questionnaire. 10-item parent quiz developed by the PI for the pilot trial and showing an increase in ADHD knowledge post-intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent Activation</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Parent-Patient Activation Measure (P-PAM). 13-item, parent-report measure adapted from the well-validated Patient Activation Measure (PAM) with acceptable reliability and validity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Family Relationships</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>NIH PROMIS® Pediatric Family Relationships Short Form. Created for the NIH PROMIS® using mixed methods, estimates the quality of the child's relationship with family in 8 items on a 5-point Likert scale with strong internal consistency and retest-reliability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parenting Stress</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Parenting Stress Index-Short Form (PSI-SF) Brief, 36-item version of the full 120-item PSI, and one of the most common instruments used to measure parenting stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Social Risk</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Child Healthwatch Vital Signs (food, housing, utilities)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent Stigma</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Parents' Self Stigma Scale (PSSS)&#xD;
11-item scale assessing Parents' stigma</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent Stigma</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Parent Perceived Stigma of Services Seeking Scale (PPSSS)&#xD;
17-item scale assessing stigma toward seeking services for mental health resources</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Child Education</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Education Activation&#xD;
10-item scale assessing parents' involvement in child's education</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">106</enrollment>
  <condition>ADHD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>START Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the experimental group will be part of a 6-module weekly intervention where they will learn more about ADHD and its treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Educational Brochure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the control group will receive an educational brochure by Children and Adults with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (CHADD).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SupporT for ADHD and Related Treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Intervention will include 6 modules typically taught over 6-7 weeks. Participants will have up to 3 months to complete the intervention. Modules will provide more knowledge on ADHD, discuss stigma around ADHD, address barriers in receiving care, encourage communication with physician and child, and empower caregivers. Overall, the goal being to improve engagement in ADHD treatment for newly diagnosed or unengaged families. This intervention is mostly targeted towards primary caregivers. However, the last module explicitly includes the child.</description>
    <arm_group_label>START Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The child is greater than or equal to 6 years old and less than or equal to 12 years&#xD;
             old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The child has a diagnosis of ADHD confirmed based on clinical psychiatric evaluation&#xD;
             with an expert child psychiatrist on the study team (PI or Co-I)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The diagnosis of ADHD is either new (defined as made for the first time by the study&#xD;
             psychiatrist OR made for the first time within the prior 3 months by a medical or&#xD;
             mental health provider) OR the child has been previously diagnosed but untreated&#xD;
             either since diagnosis or for at least the prior 12 months. &quot;Untreated&quot; is defined as&#xD;
             having received no therapeutic, medication, or school accommodations specifically for&#xD;
             ADHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. They can understand and complete informed consent and study procedures in English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Children who have received treatment for other psychiatric conditions may be included&#xD;
             if the treatment was specifically for a condition other than ADHD, to be confirmed by&#xD;
             the study psychiatrist at enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1) Children with most comorbid (i.e., co-existing) psychiatric conditions with be included,&#xD;
        but children with intellectual disability/cognitive impairment or psychotic symptoms will&#xD;
        be excluded because these conditions would substantially change the focus of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        B.5 2) Children under 6 and over 12 will be excluded because the intervention was&#xD;
        specifically designed for school age children in this age group. Developmental, adolescents&#xD;
        and preschoolers are considerably different than school age children and may require a&#xD;
        different approach for engaging them and their parents in ADHD care. Children under 6 with&#xD;
        ADHD symptoms may not yet be diagnosed and may not have the same treatment access or&#xD;
        options as children 6 and over. Adolescents over 12 are more independent and an&#xD;
        intervention may need to be more focused on the adolescent than our current intervention&#xD;
        which is primarily parent-focused. 3) Children who were diagnosed over 3 months ago and&#xD;
        already received treatment for ADHD will be excluded since our primary outcome is treatment&#xD;
        engagement. 4) Because this is an intervention only available in English at this time,&#xD;
        participants who are not able to complete study procedures in English will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrea E Spencer, MD</last_name>
    <phone>3122273402</phone>
    <email>aspencer@luriechildrens.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kryztal Pena, BA</last_name>
    <phone>3122271599</phone>
    <phone_ext>71599</phone_ext>
    <email>kpena@luriechildrens.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Visser SN, Danielson ML, Bitsko RH, Holbrook JR, Kogan MD, Ghandour RM, Perou R, Blumberg SJ. Trends in the parent-report of health care provider-diagnosed and medicated attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: United States, 2003-2011. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2014 Jan;53(1):34-46.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.jaac.2013.09.001. Epub 2013 Nov 21.</citation>
    <PMID>24342384</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cherkasova MV, Roy A, Molina BSG, Scott G, Weiss G, Barkley RA, Biederman J, Uchida M, Hinshaw SP, Owens EB, Hechtman L. Review: Adult Outcome as Seen Through Controlled Prospective Follow-up Studies of Children With Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder Followed Into Adulthood. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2022 Mar;61(3):378-391. doi: 10.1016/j.jaac.2021.05.019. Epub 2021 Jun 8.</citation>
    <PMID>34116167</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shaw M, Hodgkins P, Caci H, Young S, Kahle J, Woods AG, Arnold LE. A systematic review and analysis of long-term outcomes in attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: effects of treatment and non-treatment. BMC Med. 2012 Sep 4;10:99. doi: 10.1186/1741-7015-10-99.</citation>
    <PMID>22947230</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Coker TR, Elliott MN, Toomey SL, Schwebel DC, Cuccaro P, Tortolero Emery S, Davies SL, Visser SN, Schuster MA. Racial and Ethnic Disparities in ADHD Diagnosis and Treatment. Pediatrics. 2016 Sep;138(3):e20160407. doi: 10.1542/peds.2016-0407. Epub 2016 Aug 23.</citation>
    <PMID>27553219</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shi Y, Hunter Guevara LR, Dykhoff HJ, Sangaralingham LR, Phelan S, Zaccariello MJ, Warner DO. Racial Disparities in Diagnosis of Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder in a US National Birth Cohort. JAMA Netw Open. 2021 Mar 1;4(3):e210321. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.0321.</citation>
    <PMID>33646315</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Geneva, WHO. Patient Engagement: Technical Series on Safer Primary Care. Published online 2016. Accessed January 7, 2022. https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/252269/9789241511629-eng.pdf</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spencer AE, Sikov J, Loubeau JK, Zolli N, Baul T, Rabin M, Hasan S, Rosen K, Buonocore O, Lejeune J, Dayal R, Fortuna L, Borba C, Silverstein M. Six Stages of Engagement in ADHD Treatment Described by Diverse, Urban Parents. Pediatrics. 2021 Oct;148(4):e2021051261. doi: 10.1542/peds.2021-051261. Epub 2021 Sep 16.</citation>
    <PMID>34531290</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Paidipati CP, Brawner B, Eiraldi R, Deatrick JA. Parent and Family Processes Related to ADHD Management in Ethnically Diverse Youth. J Am Psychiatr Nurses Assoc. 2017 Mar/Apr;23(2):90-112. doi: 10.1177/1078390316687023. Epub 2017 Jan 11.</citation>
    <PMID>28076687</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Epstein JN, Kelleher KJ, Baum R, Brinkman WB, Peugh J, Gardner W, Lichtenstein P, Langberg J. Variability in ADHD care in community-based pediatrics. Pediatrics. 2014 Dec;134(6):1136-43. doi: 10.1542/peds.2014-1500. Epub 2014 Nov 3.</citation>
    <PMID>25367532</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brinkman WB, Epstein JN. Promoting productive interactions between parents and physicians in the treatment of children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Expert Rev Neurother. 2011 Apr;11(4):579-88. doi: 10.1586/ern.10.151.</citation>
    <PMID>21469930</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

