<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05622071</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UC-GIG-2003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05622071</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing Immunotherapy for Patients With Liver Cancer and Moderately Altered Liver Functions</brief_title>
  <acronym>HESTIA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multicentric National Phase II Trial Assessing TIslelizumab in Monotherapy for Patients With Hepatocellular Carcinoma Child-Pugh B and ALBI Grade 1 or 2 Liver Function Score</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UNICANCER</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UNICANCER</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Liver cancer is the third leading cause of cancer-related deaths worldwide. The majority of&#xD;
      primary liver cancers occur as hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), the incidence of which is&#xD;
      increasing in many parts of the world. The vast majority of HCC cases occur in the setting of&#xD;
      liver cirrhosis, usually due to chronic viral infections with hepatitis C or hepatitis B,&#xD;
      alcohol consumption, non-alcoholic fatty liver disease or diabetes. The degree of underlying&#xD;
      liver disease, as well as the stage of the tumour and the general condition of the patients,&#xD;
      should therefore be taken into account when deciding on the treatment of HCC. Most patients&#xD;
      with HCC have advanced disease at the time of diagnosis, or have recurrent disease after&#xD;
      potentially curative treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tislelizumab showed enhanced cellular functional activities by blocking PD-1-mediated reverse&#xD;
      signal transduction and activating human T cells and primary peripheral blood mononuclear&#xD;
      cells in vitro.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on this preliminary safety profile, and knowing that there is antitumour activity, we&#xD;
      can offer tislelizumab as a single agent in patients with unresectable HCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HESTIA study is a multicentric French national phase II trial assessing tislelizumab in&#xD;
      monotherapy for patients with Hepatocellular Carcinoma Child-Pugh B and ALBI grade 1 or 2&#xD;
      liver function score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is planned to include 50 patients in the study. All patients will be recruited in France.&#xD;
      The study will be presented to eligible patients at participating centres and an information&#xD;
      note will be provided. No advertising material is planned for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To be eligible, patients must meet all the following criteria to be ≥18 years old, with&#xD;
      histologically proven Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC), pre-treated or not with a tyrosine&#xD;
      kinase inhibitor and Child-Pugh B cirrhosis, ALBI (Albumin-Bilirubin) grade 1 or 2 and BCLC&#xD;
      (Barcelona Clinic Liver Cancer Group) B or C and with no more than 50% liver invasion of&#xD;
      tumour disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to assess efficacy of anti-PD1 (in terms of Objective Response Rate&#xD;
      [ORR] based on Best Overall Response across all time-points as defined by RECIST v1.1) in the&#xD;
      Child-Pugh B / ALBI grade 1/2 population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess safety of anti-PD-1&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess efficacy in terms of:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Objective Response Rate based on best overall response across all time-point&#xD;
                according to mRECIST and iRECIST tumor response evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Overall survival (OS)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Progression-free survival (PFS)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Time to progression (TTP)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess Quality of Life according to EORTC QLQ-C30 and HCC-18.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to confirm the eligibility of patients, a clinical examination, biological blood&#xD;
      tests, ECG, CT scan and a urine or blood pregnancy test for women of childbearing age will be&#xD;
      performed. A quality of life questionnaire will be administered to patients. Patients will&#xD;
      also be asked to agree to a full eye examination by an ophthalmologist prior to the start of&#xD;
      treatment to determine that there is no risk of worsening the patient's visual acuity with&#xD;
      treatment with tislelizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After enrolment in the study, the patient will be required to visit the hospital every 3&#xD;
      weeks to receive intravenous treatment for up to 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the treatment is completed, the patient will be seen at follow-up visits for 2 years,&#xD;
      initially every 3 months for the first year and then every 6 months for the second year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of tumour response by CT or MRI will be done after the start of treatment at weeks&#xD;
      9, 18, 27, 54 and every 12 weeks until disease progression and throughout the treatment&#xD;
      period. Tumour assessment by CT or MRI will be performed 2 years after the start of treatment&#xD;
      or upon disease progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be asked to consent to the use of a collected tumour sample, as well as to the&#xD;
      collection of blood samples, for future scientific research which includes, but is not&#xD;
      limited to, the detection of DNA, RNA and protein biomarkers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An independent Study Monitoring Board (DSMB), with expertise and experience in the pathology,&#xD;
      and without direct involvement in the conduct of the study, will be set up specifically to&#xD;
      ensure optimal safety monitoring during the early phase of the study and the feasibility of&#xD;
      at least 2 treatment injections (6 weeks from inclusion), an early stopping rule has been&#xD;
      defined for the first 20 patients included. This method was chosen for the evaluation of&#xD;
      serious adverse events (SAEs), which may occur relatively early in this trial. A high&#xD;
      frequency of occurrence may necessitate early termination of the trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 4, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 4, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 4, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Multicentre, national, monotherapy, open-label, phase II single-arm study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Tislelizumab will be administered every 3 weeks IV for a maximum of 2 years</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Objective response rate (ORR) is the percentage of patients with a best response during treatment being either complete response (CR) or partial response (PR).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of limiting toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>From inclusion, up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of limiting toxicity is defined as any adverse event related to the experimental drug, and leading to definitive treatment discontinuation according to the investigator, before the second injection.&#xD;
The National Cancer Institute-Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 5 (NCI-CTCAE v5) is widely accepted in the community of oncology research as the leading rating scale for adverse events. This scale, divided into 5 grades (1 = &quot;mild&quot;, 2 = &quot;moderate&quot;, 3 = &quot;severe&quot;, 4 = &quot;life-threatening&quot;, and 5 = &quot;death&quot;) determined by the investigator, will make it possible to assess the severity of the disorders.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of related and not related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From inclusion, up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of all adverse events occurring during the treatment period and until 3 months after treatment discontinuation.&#xD;
The National Cancer Institute-Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 5 (NCI-CTCAE v5) is widely accepted in the community of oncology research as the leading rating scale for adverse events. This scale, divided into 5 grades (1 = &quot;mild&quot;, 2 = &quot;moderate&quot;, 3 = &quot;severe&quot;, 4 = &quot;life-threatening&quot;, and 5 = &quot;death&quot;) determined by the investigator, will make it possible to assess the severity of the disorders.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From inclusion to death from any cause, up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>The overall survival (OS) is the length of time from randomization that patients enrolled in the study are still alive.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From inclusion to disease progression or death, up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>The progression-free survival (PFS) is the length of time during and after the treatment of a disease that a patient lives with the disease but it does not get worse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression</measure>
    <time_frame>From inclusion to radiographic disease progression, up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time to progression is the length of time patients leave without radiological disease progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life questionnaire - Core 30 (QLQ-C30)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, every 6 week for 1 year, then every 4 months, up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>Developed by the EORTC, this self-reported questionnaire assesses the health-related quality of life of cancer patients in clinical trials.&#xD;
The questionnaire includes five functional scales (physical, everyday activity, cognitive, emotional, and social), three symptom scales (fatigue, pain, nausea and vomiting), a health/quality of life overall scale, and a number of additional elements assessing common symptoms (including dyspnea, loss of appetite, insomnia, constipation, and diarrhea), as well as, the perceived financial impact of the disease.&#xD;
All of the scales and single-item measures range in score from 0 to 100. A high scale score represents a higher response level.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life questionnaire - Hepatocellular Carcinoma (QLQ-HCC-18)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, every 6 week for 1 year, then every 4 months, up to 52 months</time_frame>
    <description>This EORTC hepatocellular carcinoma specific questionnaire is intended to supplement the QLQ-C30.&#xD;
The QLQ-HCC18 contains 18 items to assess symptoms hepatocellular-related symptoms. These items are grouped into 6 domains: fatigue, body image, jaundice, nutrition, pain, and fever. Two single items address abdominal swelling and sex life. All items are rated on a four-point Likert-type scale (1 = &quot;not at all&quot;, 2 = &quot;a little&quot;, 3 = &quot;quite a bit&quot;, and 4 = &quot;very much&quot;), and are linearly transformed to a 0-100 scale; a higher score represents a more severe symptom or problem.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma by BCLC Stage</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SINGLE ARM</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Tislelizumab 200 mg will be administered every 3 weeks IV. Treatment will be continued until progression or limiting toxicities, for a maximum duration of 2 years and with an average duration of 4 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tislelizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Tislelizumab 200 mg will be administered every 3 weeks IV for a maximum of 2 years</description>
    <arm_group_label>SINGLE ARM</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BGB-A317</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient presenting with histologically-proven Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pretreated or not by tyrosine kinase inhibitors (e.g., sorafenib, lenvatinib,&#xD;
             regorafenib, cabozantinib)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Child-Pugh B cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. ALBI (Albumin-Bilirubin) grade 1 or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. BCLC (Barcelona Clinic Liver Cancer Group) B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Availability of biopsy specimen at study enrolment (taken within 3 months of&#xD;
             enrolment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. ECOG Performance status ≤2&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate organ function as indicated by the following laboratory values:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients must not have required a blood transfusion or growth factor support ≤14&#xD;
                  days before sample collection at screening for the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5 x 10⁹/L&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Platelets ≥75 x 10⁹/L&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hemoglobin ≥90 g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Serum creatinine ≤1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or estimated Glomerular&#xD;
                  Filtration Rate ≥60 mL/min/1.73 m²&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum total bilirubin ≤3 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Liver function: ASAT and ALAT ≤5 ULN, albumin &gt;2.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Presence of measurable and evaluable disease according to RECIST v1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Women of childbearing potential must be willing to use a highly effective method of&#xD;
             birth control for the duration of the study, and ≥120 days after the last dose of&#xD;
             tislelizumab, and have a negative urine or serum pregnancy test ≤7 days of first dose&#xD;
             of study drug. In case of a urine pregnancy test, it must be a highly sensitive urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Non-sterile males must be willing to use a highly effective method of birth control&#xD;
             for the duration of the study and for ≥120 days after the last dose of tislelizumab. A&#xD;
             sterile male is defined as one for whom azoospermia has been previously demonstrated&#xD;
             in a semen sample examination as definitive evidence of infertility. Males with known&#xD;
             &quot;low sperm counts&quot; (consistent with &quot;sub-fertility&quot;) are not to be considered sterile&#xD;
             for purposes of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients must have provided consent for the study by signing and dating a written&#xD;
             informed consent form prior to any study specific procedures, sampling, or analyses.&#xD;
             When the patient is physically unable to give their written consent, a trusted person&#xD;
             of their choice, independent from the investigator or the sponsor, can confirm in&#xD;
             writing the patient's consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient consent to the use of their collected tumour specimen, as well as blood&#xD;
             samples as detailed in the protocol for future scientific research which includes but&#xD;
             not limited to DNA, RNA, and proteinbased biomarker detection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patient affiliated to a social security regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Men and women patients must consent to not donate or bank sperm or ova during&#xD;
             treatment and for 120 days after treatment stop&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. No more than 50% of the liver is affected by the HCC (according to investigators&#xD;
             evaluation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Fibrolamellar HCC, sarcomatoid HCC, or mixed cholangiocarcinoma and HCC&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous treatment with immunotherapy (anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, or anti-CTLA-4 agents)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of active autoimmune disease. Note: Patients with the following diseases are&#xD;
             not excluded and may proceed to further screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Type I diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Hypothyroidism (provided it is managed with hormone replacement therapy only)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Controlled celiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Skin diseases not requiring systemic treatment (e.g., vitiligo, psoriasis,&#xD;
                  alopecia)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Any other disease that is not expected to recur in the absence of external&#xD;
                  triggering factors&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of interstitial lung disease, non-infectious pneumonitis or uncontrolled&#xD;
             diseases including pulmonary fibrosis, acute lung diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any of the following cardiovascular risk factors:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cardiac chest pain, defined as moderate pain that limits instrumental activities&#xD;
                  of daily living, ≤28 days before first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Pulmonary embolism ≤28 days before first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Any history of acute myocardial infarction ≤6 months before first dose of study&#xD;
                  drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Any history of heart failure meeting New York Heart Association (NYHA)&#xD;
                  Classification III or IV ≤6 months before first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Any event of ventricular arrhythmia ≥ Grade 2 in severity ≤6 months before first&#xD;
                  dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Any history of cerebrovascular accident ≤ 6 months before first dose of study&#xD;
                  drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Uncontrolled hypertension: systolic pressure ≥160 mmHg or diastolic pressure ≥100&#xD;
                  mmHg despite anti-hypertension medications before first dose of drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Any episode of syncope or seizure before first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with untreated chronic hepatitis B or chronic hepatitis B virus (HBV)&#xD;
             carriers whose HBV DNA is &gt;500 IU/mL or patients with active hepatitis C virus (HCV)&#xD;
             should be excluded. Note: Inactive hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) carriers,&#xD;
             treated and stable hepatitis B (HBV DNA &lt;500 IU/mL), and cured hepatitis C patients&#xD;
             can be enrolled&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known primary immunodeficiency or active HIV&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Immunosuppression, including subjects with a condition requiring systemic treatment&#xD;
             with either corticosteroids (&gt;10 mg/day prednisone equivalent) ≤14 days before&#xD;
             inclusion. Note: Patients who are currently or have previously been on any of the&#xD;
             following steroid regimens are not excluded:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Adrenal replacement steroid (dose ≤10 mg daily of prednisone or equivalent)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Topical, ocular, intra-articular, intranasal, or inhaled corticosteroid with&#xD;
                  minimal systemic absorption&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Short course (≤7 days) of corticosteroid prescribed prophylactically (e.g., for&#xD;
                  contrast dye allergy) or for the treatment of a non-autoimmune condition (e.g.,&#xD;
                  delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction caused by contact allergen)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Live vaccine within 4 weeks of first dose of study drug. Note: Seasonal vaccines for&#xD;
             influenza are generally inactivated vaccines and Covid vaccination with non-live&#xD;
             vaccine are allowed. Intranasal vaccines are live vaccines, and are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Transplanted liver, or patient with intent for transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Received locoregional therapy to the liver (TACE, transcatheter embolization, hepatic&#xD;
             arterial infusion, radiation, radioembolization or ablation) in the 4 weeks before&#xD;
             inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Prior malignancy active within the previous 3 years of inclusion except for locally&#xD;
             curable cancers considered cured or successfully resected, such as basal or squamous&#xD;
             cell skin cancers, superficial bladder cancer, or gastric cancers, or carcinoma in&#xD;
             situ of the prostate, cervix, or breast carcinomas. Any oncological concomitant&#xD;
             treatment are not allowed during the treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Has received any herbal medicine used to control cancer with immunostimulant&#xD;
             properties that may interfere with liver function within 14 days of the first study&#xD;
             drug administration&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Pregnant woman or breast-feeding women or patient with no adequate contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Participation in another therapeutic trial within the 30 days prior to study inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patients deprived of their liberty or under protective custody or guardianship&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Patients unable to adhere to the protocol for geographical, social, or psychological&#xD;
             reasons&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients eligible for treatment by TACE or SIRT are not allowed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Julien Edeline, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CLCC UNICANCER EUGENE MARQUIS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Veronica Pezzella</last_name>
    <phone>+ 33 (0)1 44 23 04 04</phone>
    <email>v-pezzella@unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laure Monard</last_name>
    <phone>+ 33 (0)1 44 23 04 04</phone>
    <email>l-monard@unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Eugene Marquis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rennes</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 17, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 17, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 18, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>tislelizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>monotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Child-Pugh B</keyword>
  <keyword>ALBI grade 1 or 2 liver function score</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

