<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612854</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CDT in pulmonary embolism</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612854</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Catheter Directed Therapy in Intermediate Risk Pulmonary Embolism Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Catheter Directed Therapy for Intermediate Risk Pulmonary Embolism Patients Guided by Prediction Model for Impending Shock</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim of the work:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To compare conventional medical therapy versus catheter-directed therapy in intermediate&#xD;
           high risk acute pulmonary embolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To define predictors of progression from intermediate to high-risk in medically-treated&#xD;
           patients for ideal timing for intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Based on history, physical examination, surface 12-lead ECG, bed-side echocardiography,&#xD;
      patients with a high probability of acute pulmonary embolism are selected and subjected to CT&#xD;
      pulmonary angiography to confirm the diagnosis and calculate the pulmonary artery obstruction&#xD;
      score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Routine labs are withdrawn, including cardiac troponin.Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Detailed TTE will be done with emphasis on the following indicators of RV strain and/or&#xD;
      dysfunction:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Echocardiography findings that are indicative of RV dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  tricuspid annular plane systolic excursion (TAPSE)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  S' Velocity&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  the McConnell's sign&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. RV dilation&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. interventricular septal flattening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. elevated right ventricular pressures&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. plethoric inferior vena cava&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. tricuspid regurgitation&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Direct visualization of thromboembolic in the RT heart and PA&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. RV stroke volume measured by RVOT VTI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. LV stroke volume measured by LVOT VTI Intermediate-high risk patient will be identified&#xD;
           (based on the calculated pulmonary embolism severity index, RV dysfunction on TTE and/or&#xD;
           CT, cardiac troponin), and then randomized to either receiving conventional medical&#xD;
           treatment or catheter-directed interventional therapy if the patient consents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7. Catheter directed therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. Mechanical embolectomy:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mechanical fragmentation will be done using a 6 F pigtail catheter inserted inside the&#xD;
      thrombus guided by the CTPA images.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hydro-mechanical defragmentation (HMD) is one of the CDT modalities for high-risk PE&#xD;
      patients, in which rapid pigtail rotation is combined with heparinized saline injection for&#xD;
      thrombus fragmentation.(4)&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. Suction embolectomy:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suction embolectomy was one of the earliest techniques for transcatheter treatment of PE, and&#xD;
      was introduced by Greenfield et al, using a 12-Fr catheter with a cup on its distal end.&#xD;
      Suction was applied manually to the catheter hub with a large syringe. (13) The Penumbra&#xD;
      Indigo aspiration system (Penumbra Inc., Alameda, CA, USA) that will be used, is an 8-Fr&#xD;
      device and its associated tubing, pump, and separator, has the flexibility for placement in&#xD;
      segmental branches of the pulmonary arteries. The Indigo aspiration system is indicated for&#xD;
      use in the peripheral arterial system and the pulmonary arteries, receiving U.S. Food and&#xD;
      Drug Administration 510(k) clearance for PE in December 2019.(14)&#xD;
&#xD;
      C. Catheter directed thrombolysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Catheter-directed thrombolysis allows delivery of the thrombolytic agent directly to the area&#xD;
      of highest embolic burden via a catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intermediate-high risk patient will be identified (based on the calculated pulmonary embolism&#xD;
      severity index, RV dysfunction on TTE and/or CT, cardiac troponin), and then randomized to&#xD;
      either receiving conventional medical treatment or catheter-directed interventional therapy&#xD;
      if the patient consents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled, open-label, parallel-assignment, prospective study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1.comparison between conventional medical therapy and catheter-directed therapy in intermediate high risk acute pulmonary embolism patients</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>comparison in intermediate high risk acute pulmonary embolism patients between conventional medical therapy and catheter-directed therapy as regarding safety and efficacy of the therapy by clinical assessment of occurrence of major adverse cardiac events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1.comparison between conventional medical therapy and catheter-directed therapy in intermediate high risk acute pulmonary embolism patients</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>comparison in intermediate high risk acute pulmonary embolism patients between conventional medical therapy and catheter-directed therapy as regarding safety and efficacy of the therapy by echocardiographic assessment of right ventricular function by TAPSE (mm) , RV/LV diameter ratio ,TR peak gradient (mmHg)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1.comparison between conventional medical therapy and catheter-directed therapy in intermediate high risk acute pulmonary embolism patients</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>comparison in intermediate high risk acute pulmonary embolism patients between conventional medical therapy and catheter-directed therapy as regarding safety and efficacy of the therapy by CT pulmonary angiography to asses embolus size and Pulmonary artery obstruction index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>predictors of progression from intermediate to high-risk acute pulmonary embolism patients</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>identifying predictors for ideal timing for intervention in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients who are medically-treated by new echocardiographic parameters (LVOT velocity time integral and RVOT velocity time integral)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation of pulmonary embolism response team at Assiut university hospitals</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>institutional reconstruction and communication between different departments (chest, cardiology, radiology and clinical pathology departments) aiming to implement a pulmonary embolism response team with clear structure and operational levels for decision making</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulmonary Embolism Subacute Massive</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>catheter directed therapy group in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>in this arm, intermediated risk pulmonary embolism patients is treated by intervention in the form of:&#xD;
A. Mechanical embolectomy: by hydromechanical defragmentation by pigta&#xD;
B. Suction embolectomy: using The Penumbra Indigo aspiration system&#xD;
C. Catheter directed thrombolysis:</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>medical therapy group in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>in this arm, intermediated risk pulmonary embolism patients is treated by routine anticoagulation only.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mechanical embolectomy: by hydromechanical defragmentation by pigtail</intervention_name>
    <description>Hydro-mechanical defragmentation (HMD) is one of the CDT modalities for high-risk PE patients, in which rapid pigtail rotation is combined with heparinized saline injection for thrombus fragmentation</description>
    <arm_group_label>catheter directed therapy group in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>medical therapy group in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Suction embolectomy by the Penumbra Indigo aspiration system</intervention_name>
    <description>The Penumbra Indigo aspiration system (Penumbra Inc., Alameda, CA, USA) that will be used, is an 8-Fr device and its associated tubing, pump, and separator, has the flexibility for placement in segmental branches of the pulmonary arteries.&#xD;
510(k) Number :K160449 FOIA Releasable 510(k) K160449 Device Name:Penumbra System, Penumbra Pump MAX</description>
    <arm_group_label>catheter directed therapy group in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>medical therapy group in intermediate risk pulmonary embolism patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute pulmonary embolism patients (confirmed by CT pulmonary angiography [CTPA])&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  symptoms started within 15 days of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intermediate-high risk pulmonary embolism patients , i.e., who have all of the&#xD;
             following risk indicators combined :(2) i.Pulmonary Embolism Severity Index (PESI)&#xD;
             class III-V or sPESI ≥1, ii.AND RV dysfunction on TTE or CTPA, iii.AND elevated&#xD;
             cardiac troponin levels&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with none of the following high-risk presentations: cardiac arrest, systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure &lt;90 mmHg, or vasopressors required to achieve a BP ≥90 mmHg despite an&#xD;
             adequate filling status, or end-organ hypoperfusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  high risk patients who are hemodynamically unstable (cardiogenic shock, SBP &lt;90 mmHg,&#xD;
             or use of intotropic support).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  low risk patients with no RV dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of CTEPH (or previous acute PE)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients known to have other pulmonary hypertension, apart from group IV (CTEPH).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with sever kidney injury (eGFR &lt;30 mg/dl/1.7m2).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shrouk K Ali, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shrouk K Ali, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+0201225134030</phone>
    <email>shrouk31@aun.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ayman Kh Hassan, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+0201094438055</phone>
    <email>Aymankhairy11@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Konstantinides SV, Torbicki A, Agnelli G, Danchin N, Fitzmaurice D, Galie N, Gibbs JS, Huisman MV, Humbert M, Kucher N, Lang I, Lankeit M, Lekakis J, Maack C, Mayer E, Meneveau N, Perrier A, Pruszczyk P, Rasmussen LH, Schindler TH, Svitil P, Vonk Noordegraaf A, Zamorano JL, Zompatori M; Task Force for the Diagnosis and Management of Acute Pulmonary Embolism of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). 2014 ESC guidelines on the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism. Eur Heart J. 2014 Nov 14;35(43):3033-69, 3069a-3069k. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu283. Epub 2014 Aug 29. No abstract available. Erratum In: Eur Heart J. 2015 Oct 14;36(39):2666. Eur Heart J. 2015 Oct 14;36(39):2642.</citation>
    <PMID>25173341</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Giri J, Sista AK, Weinberg I, Kearon C, Kumbhani DJ, Desai ND, Piazza G, Gladwin MT, Chatterjee S, Kobayashi T, Kabrhel C, Barnes GD. Interventional Therapies for Acute Pulmonary Embolism: Current Status and Principles for the Development of Novel Evidence: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2019 Nov 12;140(20):e774-e801. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000707. Epub 2019 Oct 4.</citation>
    <PMID>31585051</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hassan AKM, Ahmed H, Ahmed Y, Elfadl AA, Omar A. Efficacy and safety of hydro-mechanical defragmentation in intermediate- and high-risk pulmonary embolism. Egypt Heart J. 2021 Sep 25;73(1):84. doi: 10.1186/s43044-021-00204-2.</citation>
    <PMID>34564780</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kroupa J, Buk M, Weichet J, Malikova H, Bartova L, Linkova H, Ionita O, Kozel M, Motovska Z, Kocka V. A pilot randomised trial of catheter-directed thrombolysis or standard anticoagulation for patients with intermediate-high risk acute pulmonary embolism. EuroIntervention. 2022 Oct 7;18(8):e639-e646. doi: 10.4244/EIJ-D-21-01080.</citation>
    <PMID>35620984</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ayman khairy Mohamed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>catheter directed therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>intermediate risk pulmonary embolism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Embolism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

