<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619458</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ULethbridge</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619458</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of a Mindfulness Program on Emotion Regulation Among Youth Attending an Alternative School</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of an Adapted Version of the Learning to BREATHE Program on Emotion Regulation Among Youth Attending an Alternative High School: Rationale and Design for a Single-arm Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Lethbridge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Lethbridge</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main goal of this single-arm pre-post intervention study is to see if an adapted&#xD;
      mindfulness program can improve emotion regulation among youth aged 15-19 years who attend an&#xD;
      alternative school. Participants will complete a baseline survey package using an iPad. They&#xD;
      will then receive an adapted version of the 6-session Learning to BREATHE Program as part of&#xD;
      a course they are taking at their school. Students will again complete a survey package&#xD;
      within 2 weeks of completing the program. The investigator will compare baseline and&#xD;
      post-intervention survey responses to see if the program improved emotion regulation, as well&#xD;
      as several secondary psychosocial and behavioral outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND: The purpose of this study is to use a single-arm trial to assess the&#xD;
      effectiveness of a 6-week mindfulness-based intervention (MBI) on the emotional, social, and&#xD;
      behavioural well-being of adolescents attending an alternative school in Lethbridge, Alberta.&#xD;
      Mindfulness focuses on cultivating present-moment awareness in a non-reactive and&#xD;
      non-judgmental way. A 2017 meta-analysis found MBIs have a moderate effect on increasing&#xD;
      mindfulness among youth in controlled studies. A 2020 meta-analysis found MBIs have an&#xD;
      overall small effect size over a broad range of samples and mental health outcomes among&#xD;
      youth. The review found that in clinical samples of youth the effect size for mental health&#xD;
      outcomes is in the moderate range, and nearly three times the magnitude found of non-clinical&#xD;
      samples. MBIs also improve the mental health of at-risk youth including those in foster care,&#xD;
      prison, and those who are survivors of interpersonal trauma. The goal of the present study is&#xD;
      to build upon emerging evidence suggesting MBIs may be a useful addition to the curriculum&#xD;
      within an alternative school environment. Alternative schools, also called outreach schools&#xD;
      in Alberta, address the interpersonal, social, and learning needs of teens that cannot be met&#xD;
      in regular school settings. Alternative schools offer a flexible learning environment with&#xD;
      innovative programming designed to provide academic, social and emotional supports and skill&#xD;
      building. Youth who attend alternative schools experience more psychosocial problems,&#xD;
      including adverse childhood experiences (ACEs), and health risk behaviours; and thus may&#xD;
      benefits from MBIs. Learning how to regulate emotions in a socially adaptive and appropriate&#xD;
      manner is an important part of healthy psychological development. Emotion regulation allows&#xD;
      an adolescent greater autonomy, strengthens self-esteem and improves self-efficacy. The poor&#xD;
      regulation of emotions is implicated in the diagnostic criteria of many mental health&#xD;
      disorders. It is generally agreed in the literature that emotion regulation processes can be&#xD;
      conscious or unconscious, and automatic or effortful. It is also generally agreed that&#xD;
      emotion regulation involves both reducing the intensity and frequency of negative emotional&#xD;
      states, as well as developing the ability to create and maintain positive emotions. While&#xD;
      MBIs have been shown to strengthen emotion regulation in regular public high schools, the&#xD;
      extent to which MBIs strengthen emotion regulation within alternative schools is not well&#xD;
      understood, and the primary focus of the present study. The investigator will also explore&#xD;
      the impact of an MBI intervention on mindfulness, psychological outcomes, social connection,&#xD;
      and behaviour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTERVENTION: In this study, the investigator will use the six-week, evidence-based Learning&#xD;
      to BREATHE Program as the primary intervention. Learning to BREATHE teaches emotion&#xD;
      regulation and stress-reduction in relatable ways for teens. The program is delivered&#xD;
      flexibly and adaptively rather than as a manualized curriculum, which fits the learning&#xD;
      environment and goals of alternative schools. To date, two studies have examined the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the Learning to BREATHE program in alternative schools. The first study,&#xD;
      based in the US, used a pre-post design and found significant improvements in self-esteem and&#xD;
      perceived stress. The second study used a randomized controlled design with an active&#xD;
      comparator to assess Learning to BREATHE against a program designed to reduce substance use.&#xD;
      The team reported many intervention delivery problems within an alternative school, including&#xD;
      youth who were disinterested and disruptive during sessions. Changes were made to the&#xD;
      intervention throughout the trial to address these problems, including involving teachers and&#xD;
      school support staff in the sessions as youth were more familiar and comfortable with them.&#xD;
      They also shortened activities that youth found difficult (sitting meditation), and&#xD;
      lengthening others that youth enjoyed (body scan meditations and restorative yoga exercises).&#xD;
      At study end, the Learning to BREATHE program intervention was more effective at reducing&#xD;
      depression than active control. However, the small sample size (N = 14 intervention, N = 13&#xD;
      active control) and changes to the intervention throughout the trial made it difficult to&#xD;
      assess impacts. To address these problems before the present study began, the investigator&#xD;
      worked with social workers, school administrators, and community stakeholders in 2018-2019 to&#xD;
      adapt the Learning to BREATHE Program for delivery within an alternative school environment.&#xD;
      Suggested adaptions for program delivery were pilot tested in 2019-20 in a small sample of&#xD;
      junior high students (N = 17) in the Lethbridge Alternative School Program. Sessions were&#xD;
      delivered by three facilitators with mindfulness training certification. Due to the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic intervention effectiveness could not be assessed. The investigator was limited to&#xD;
      analyzing post-intervention data collected before government-mandated school closures in&#xD;
      March 2020 (N = 6 of 17 students who took part in the program). Fidelity and observational&#xD;
      data collected during each session was also analyzed, and used in a student MSc thesis. The&#xD;
      findings suggest youth were engaged in the adapted version of the program, that their&#xD;
      understanding of mindfulness as a tool for stress and coping increased, and that&#xD;
      incorporating digital technology (apps) to deliver segments of the intervention promoted&#xD;
      independent use of the digital tools by youth outside the sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS: This intervention study will begin November 28, 2022, at a single location -&#xD;
      Victoria Park High School in Lethbridge, AB. The study will be led by Dr. Cheryl Currie in&#xD;
      the Faculty of Health Sciences at the University of Alberta in Alberta, Canada. The study is&#xD;
      expected to end January 31, 2023. It is estimated that from time of first contact during&#xD;
      student enrolment in the study each participant will be engaged in the study for nine weeks,&#xD;
      excluding time away during the December holiday break. This includes one week to complete the&#xD;
      pre-intervention data collection meeting with school staff, six weeks to take part in the&#xD;
      intervention, and up to two weeks to complete a post-intervention data collection meeting&#xD;
      with a school staff member. This study will recruit a school-based sample of approximately 35&#xD;
      youth that meet eligibility criteria to achieve 31 participants. Participants will be&#xD;
      students registered in two specific classes in Victoria Park High School. These courses were&#xD;
      chosen by school administration for participation in the program. A low (5%) loss to&#xD;
      follow-up is expected given the program will be offered as part of two combined courses that&#xD;
      students have chosen to enroll in. Students will complete the baseline survey immediately&#xD;
      after completing the informed consent process by clicking the second Qualtrics tab that will&#xD;
      be open on their iPad browser. The survey will be administered using the Qualtrics survey&#xD;
      platform on iPads provided by the University of Lethbridge study team and will take&#xD;
      approximately 20 minutes. Within two weeks of completing the intervention, participants will&#xD;
      complete the same survey package they answered at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ANALYSIS STRATEGY: Data will be analyzed using Stata 17.0 and R software. The investigator&#xD;
      will use frequencies and percentages to summarize participant age, grade, genders, Indigenous&#xD;
      status (identify as Indigenous - yes or no), immigrant status (born in Canada - yes or no),&#xD;
      and who participants currently live with. The purpose of collecting this data is to create a&#xD;
      broad, general description of the sample in dissemination documents. For prediction of&#xD;
      emotion regulation pre- and post-intervention, participants will be included in the analysis&#xD;
      if they have completed 50% of the intervention and completed follow-up data collection.&#xD;
      Missing data for participants who meet these criteria will be addressed using multiple&#xD;
      imputation. A repeated-measures, mixed-model approach will be used to identify significant&#xD;
      changes in each of the primary and secondary outcomes pre-post intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 21, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in emotion regulation on the 18-item Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale - Short Form (DERS-SF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>The DERS-SF has excellent psychometric properties regardless of age and gender variation. A 5-point Likert scale from 1 (almost never) to 5 (almost always) is employed, with higher scores indicating greater emotion regulation impairment or dysregulation (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in emotion regulation on the 1-item Emotion Regulation Questionnaire for Children and Adolescents (ERQ-CA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>The ERQ-CA assesses use of two emotion regulation strategies: cognitive reappraisal where a person attempts to change how they think about a situation to change its emotional impact, and expressive suppression where a person attempts to inhibit the behavioural expression of their emotions. A 5-point Likert scale from 1 (almost never) to 5 (almost always) is employed, with higher scores indicating greater emotion regulation impairment or dysregulation (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in mindfulness on the 10-item Child and Adolescent Mindfulness Measure (CAMM).</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>The CAMM has good internal reliability in a variety of adolescent populations, with Cronbach's alpha scores reported between 0.80-0.84, and no significant gender differences. The measure uses a 5-point Likert scale with higher scores indicated greater mindfulness (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in anxiety and depression symptoms on the 4-item Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-4).</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>The PHQ-4 is a reliable measure of anxiety (α = 0.82) and depression (α = 0.81) separately and in composite (α = 0.85). Items are measured on a 4-point Likert scale, with options ranging from &quot;Not at all&quot; to &quot;Nearly every day&quot;, with higher scores indicating more frequent anxiety/depression symptoms (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in self-esteem on the 5-item Brief Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief Rosenberg Self-Esteem Scale assesses self-esteem by asking participants to reflect on the feelings they have about themselves using a 4-point scale ranging from strongly agree to strongly disagree, with higher scores indicating higher self-esteem (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in school connectedness on an adapted version of the the National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Health School Connectedness Scale (NLSAH-SCS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>The version of the NLSAH-SCS that will be used in this study was developed by investigators of the COMPASS Study - a prospective cohort study that collects longitudinal data from a sample of grade 9-12 in Canada. The adapted measure predicts reduced health risk behaviour in Canadian high school students. Consistent with the original measure, response options range from 1=strongly disagree to 4=strongly agree, with higher scores indicating stronger feelings of school connectedness (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in home connectedness on an adapted 5-item version of the National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Health School Connectedness Scale (NLSAH-SCS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>We have adapted the 5-item measure of school connectedness to measure an adolescent's sense of connectedness within their home (e.g., I feel close to people in my home, I feel safe in my home, I feel the adults in my home treat me fairly). Consistent with the original measure, response options range from 1=strongly disagree to 4=strongly agree, with higher scores indicating stronger feelings of connectedness at home (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in substance use on the Screen for Substance-Related Risks and Problems in Adolescents (CRAFFT) 2.1+N</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 10</time_frame>
    <description>CRAFFT scores are strongly correlated with diagnostic classifications for substance use among adolescents. We will use the new 2.1+N version of the CRAFFT which also assess tobacco use and vaping. All questions have yes/no responses, with higher scores indicating more significant substance use and problems (Week 10 Score - Baseline Score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Substance Use</condition>
  <condition>Mindfulness</condition>
  <condition>Adolescent Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Emotion Regulation</condition>
  <condition>Social Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Self Esteem</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention will consist of 6 one-hour sessions delivered once per week in a classroom at an alternative high school during normal school hours.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>6-week mindfulness intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness intervention</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Learning to Breathe Program</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 15-19 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in two specific courses offered at Victoria Park High School&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to give consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack capacity to provide informed consent as determined by the educational assistant&#xD;
             who will complete the informed consent process with each potential participant.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cheryl Currie, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Lethbridge</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mahala Swisterski, BHSc</last_name>
    <phone>403-332-4499</phone>
    <email>mahala.morris@uleth.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Victoria Park High School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lethbridge</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T1J 2M4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cayley King</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 5, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Lethbridge</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Cheryl Currie</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

