<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05613699</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>YOUEX_S932</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05613699</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exercise for Young Adults With Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>YOUEX</acronym>
  <official_title>Implementation and Evaluation of Physical Exercise Services for Young Adults With Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Heidelberg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Clinic Cologne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Clinic Essen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Heidelberg</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Over the past decade, importance of supportive care in cancer treatment of young cancer&#xD;
      patients has increased. However, most common cancer-related side effects, such as physical&#xD;
      deconditioning, psychological problems, infertility, and cancer-related fatigue, are&#xD;
      particularly problematic for young adults (AYA). Short- and long-term side effects result in&#xD;
      impaired quality of life, social life, and physical activity levels. While there is growing&#xD;
      evidence that physical exercise is effective in reducing disease- or treatment-related side&#xD;
      effects, programs are generally not tailored to the unique needs of young adults. In&#xD;
      addition, social media or web-based programs are rarely structurally integrated into existing&#xD;
      care programs. The objective of the Your Exercise Program (YOUEX) study is therefore to&#xD;
      address these specific needs and to improve physical exercise services for young people in&#xD;
      Germany. To this end, this pilot study presents three approaches to physical activity&#xD;
      enhancement, with a particular focus on web-based and cross-regional programs. All three&#xD;
      approaches will be evaluated for their feasibility and effectiveness on fatigue, distress,&#xD;
      quality of life, and activity levels, as well as sustained effects over 24 weeks. The YOUEX&#xD;
      study is an exploratory intervention study in the form of a 12-week exercise program for&#xD;
      patients aged 18 to 39 years who currently have or have had a cancer diagnosis within the&#xD;
      past 5 years. Eligible patients can choose from three support programs: Social Media Exercise&#xD;
      Program, Online Exercise Platform, Supervised Exercise Program. The goal is to recruit 70 to&#xD;
      80 patients over an 8-month period. Evaluation questionnaires will be sent at three time&#xD;
      points (T0: start of exercise program, T1: after 6 weeks; T2: after 12 weeks; T3: after 24&#xD;
      weeks) with a short weekly questionnaire between T0 and T2 to assess weekly adherence and&#xD;
      changes in fatigue. YOUEX study will collect detailed information on the acceptability and&#xD;
      feasibility of different physical activity programs for young people and their lasting&#xD;
      effects on fatigue, quality of life and physical activity. Should these be positive, the&#xD;
      findings can directly inform health care practice, which would be highly relevant especially&#xD;
      in light of the COVID pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the three exercise interventions</measure>
    <time_frame>During 12 week of the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Participants ability to follow the exercise prescription (measured by % of training frequency as well as type of the exercise)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical activity level</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks and 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Physical activity levels were determined by the standardized Godin-Shephard Leisure-Time Questionnaire. The questionnaire was used to ask for pre-diagnosis-, post-diagnosis- and pre-post-intervention physical activity levels within three categories: light, moderate and vigorous physical activity in minutes per week. Participants were categorized in an active and inactive subgroup with a threshold of 150 minutes moderate or 75 minutes vigorous physical activity per week (or the combination of both) based on the American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) guidelines.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Module Selection and preferences</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The individual module selection and preferences were queried and documented at the first three time points (Baseline, after 6 week and after 12 weeks). Reasons for any module selection and why other modules have not been selected were collected through open answer questions while multiple answers were possible. The subgroups of the initial module selection were analyzed according treatment and employment status. Further, we asked for module preferences under COVID-19 free conditions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of COVID-19 pandemic</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks, 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The questionnaire about the impact of COVID-19 has been self-developed, but internal validated in other studies at the National Center of Tumor Diseases (NCT) Heidelberg. The COVID-19 questionnaire consisted of six items and surveyed the impact of COVID-19 on patient´s current job situation, leisure-time activities, physical activity levels, self-efficacy, anxiety and mental health. Further we asked for, whether COVID-19 had any effect on the participants module selection. The COVID-19 questionnaire was submitted later during the ongoing study due to COVID-19-lockdown in November 2020. Therefore, not all participants completed the COVID-19 questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks, 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized questionnaire used: European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC) FA (Fatigue) 12</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks, 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life (QoL) will be assessed with the validated 30-item self-assessment questionnaire of the European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC QLQ-C30, version 3.0). It includes five multi-item functional scales (physical, role, emotional, cognitive, and social function), three multi-item symptom scales (fatigue, pain, nausea/vomiting), and six single items assessing further symptoms (dyspnea, insomnia, appetite loss, constipation, diarrhea) and financial difficulties.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Distress</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks, 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized questionnaire used: National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) Distress-Thermometer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks, 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized questionnaire used: Zufriedenheit (ZUF)-8 Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Social Support</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks, 12 weeks, 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized questionnaire used: German translation of the questionnaire by Sallis (1987)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue Thermometer</measure>
    <time_frame>Daily till week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized questionnaire used: Style of NCCN Distress-Thermometer. Dimensions: Physical, emotional and mental Fatigue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">106</enrollment>
  <condition>Fatigue</condition>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Physical Activity</condition>
  <condition>Exercise</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>supervised, group-based, online-social media exercise program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>unsupervised individual home-based training with an online-training app</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>supervised, in-person exercise program close to place of residence</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise - Social Media</intervention_name>
    <description>The supervised online-social media exercise intervention took place once per week at a fixed, pre-scheduled time, via an online video conference platform. The training sessions lasted for 60 minutes and included a holistic workout with different focuses (e.g. resistance training for lower extremities, sensorimotor training, home-based endurance training). Patients were further recommended independent physical activity like walking or cycling, 1-2 times per week or to maintain the current volume of physical activity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>supervised, group-based, online-social media exercise program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise - App</intervention_name>
    <description>Exercise program in the online-app were personalized and focused on a combination of endurance and resistance training, 2-3 times a week, depending on patient's needs. Additional types of exercise (e.g. sensorimotor training) were added if therapy-related side effects were present. If necessary, exercise trainers conducted one introductory training session as video conference to check for exercise techniques and answer any individual questions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>unsupervised individual home-based training with an online-training app</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise - closed to patients residence</intervention_name>
    <description>The supervised exercise program close to patient's home was executed in a certified exercise facility of the network OnkoAktiv and supervised by special qualified exercise trainers. The weekly recommendation was to participate in a personalized in-person exercise program 1-2 per week, plus independent physical activity (or to maintain current level of physical activity)</description>
    <arm_group_label>supervised, in-person exercise program close to place of residence</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cancer diagnosis within the past five years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cancer-related cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of sports clearance from the attending oncologist (e.g. in case of fragile bone&#xD;
             metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  current participation in another exercise intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  insufficient German language skills&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joachim Wiskemann, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Heidelberg University Hospital / National Center for Tumor Diseases</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Center for Tumor Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <state>Baden-Wuerttemberg</state>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 17, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Hospital Heidelberg</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Joachim Wiskemann</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head Exercise Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>social media</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>virtual training</keyword>
  <keyword>app</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

