<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796583</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PSWT SofPulse</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796583</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pulsed Shortwave Therapy for Postoperative Analgesia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pulsed Electromagnetic Fields for Postoperative and Post-Amputation Analgesia: A Randomized, Participant- and Observer-Masked, Sham-Controlled Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pulsed shortwave (radiofrequency) therapy is a possible method of pain control involving the&#xD;
      application of electromagnetic energy (also termed pulsed electromagnetic fields). Food and&#xD;
      Drug Administration-cleared devices have been in clinical use for over 70 years. For decades,&#xD;
      available devices consisted of a large signal generator and bulky coil applicator that were&#xD;
      not portable and produced significant electromagnetic interference, making them impractical&#xD;
      for common use. However, small, lightweight, relatively inexpensive, noninvasive, Food and&#xD;
      Drug Administration-cleared devices that function for 8 days are now available to treat acute&#xD;
      and chronic pain, decrease inflammation and edema, and hasten wound healing and bone&#xD;
      regeneration. Therefore, it has the potential to concurrently improve analgesia and decrease&#xD;
      or even negate opioid requirements, only without the limitations of opioids and peripheral&#xD;
      nerve blocks. The purpose of this study is to explore the possibility of treating acute&#xD;
      postoperative pain with nonthermal, pulsed shortwave (radiofrequency) therapy, optimize the&#xD;
      study protocol, and estimate the treatment effect.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study will be a randomized, participant- and observer-masked, sham-controlled,&#xD;
      parallel-arm, human participants study with two primary aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1: To determine the feasibility and optimize the protocol for subsequent&#xD;
      clinical trials that will compare the addition of nonthermal, pulsed shortwave therapy to&#xD;
      usual and customary analgesia following moderate-to-severely painful surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 2: To estimate the treatment effect of adding nonthermal, pulsed shortwave&#xD;
      therapy to usual and customary analgesia on pain and opioid consumption following&#xD;
      moderate-to-severely painful surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1 (primary): Nonthermal, pulsed shortwave therapy decreases pain in the 7 days&#xD;
      following moderate-to-severely painful surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 2: Nonthermal, pulsed shortwave therapy decreases opioid use in the 7 days&#xD;
      following moderate-to-severely painful surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a single-center (University of California San Diego), randomized, participant-&#xD;
      and observer-masked, sham-controlled, parallel-arm human subjects study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment. Participants will be consenting adults undergoing various surgical procedures&#xD;
      usually resulting in moderate-to-severe postoperative pain. Study inclusion will be proposed&#xD;
      to eligible presurgical patients. If an individual desires study participation, written,&#xD;
      informed consent will be obtained using a current University of California San Diego&#xD;
      Institutional Review Board-approved informed consent form. The study population of interest&#xD;
      includes adult women and men of all races, ethnicity, sexual identity, and socioeconomic&#xD;
      status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures. Following written, informed consent, we will record baseline anthropometric&#xD;
      information (age, sex, height, weight, amputation details and current pain levels).&#xD;
      Participants will receive any standard peripheral nerve block(s) administered using&#xD;
      bupivacaine or ropivacaine 0.5% with epinephrine (standard at University of California San&#xD;
      Diego) prior to undergoing their surgical procedure per standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment Group Assignment. Each participant will be randomized to one of two treatment&#xD;
      groups: Active or Sham treatment. Randomization will be stratified by surgical procedure in&#xD;
      block sizes of 2. The computer-generated randomization lists will be created by the&#xD;
      University of California San Diego Investigational Drug Service in a 1:1 treatment group&#xD;
      ratio. An Investigational Drug Service pharmacist will provide the investigators with the&#xD;
      appropriate device. Upon completion of data collection for a specific subgroup (e.g., total&#xD;
      knee and hip arthroplasty; cholecystectomy), the pharmacist will provide the investigators&#xD;
      with a masked list of the treatment groups (e.g., &quot;Treatment A&quot; and &quot;Treatment B&quot;), and the&#xD;
      active/sham lists only following analysis for that subgroup, resulting in a triple-masked&#xD;
      study (investigators, participants, statistician).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study intervention. The pulsed shortwave device will be affixed over the primary wound&#xD;
      area(s) using tape and activated prior to recovery room discharge. The optimal location to&#xD;
      treat phantom pain is currently unknown and will partially informed by the results of this&#xD;
      study, and patients will be encouraged to move the devices to a new anatomic location until&#xD;
      relief is optimized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Supplemental analgesics. In addition to the pulsed shortwave device, participants will&#xD;
      receive standard-of-care supplemental analgesics. Therefore, all patients of this&#xD;
      study-regardless of the treatment arm they are randomized to-will continue to receive current&#xD;
      usual and customary analgesia: all will receive the same combination of supplemental&#xD;
      analgesics they would regardless of study participation. Participants (and their caretakers)&#xD;
      will be provided with verbal and written instructions, and the telephone and pager numbers of&#xD;
      an investigator available during business hours throughout the treatment period. Participants&#xD;
      cannot shower or submerge the device, as advised by the manufacturer; but will be allowed to&#xD;
      remove it to bathe, and subsequently replace the device following bathing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be discharged with their pulsed shortwave device in situ and a prescription&#xD;
      for immediate-release oral opioid, preferably oxycodone 5 mg tablets, taken for breakthrough&#xD;
      pain (surgeons occasionally prefer a different type of opioids such as hydrocodone, which is&#xD;
      why we analyze the data using oral oxycodone equivalents). The pulsed shortwave devices will&#xD;
      be removed by participants at home following Day 8 when the battery is exhausted. Removing&#xD;
      the devices encompasses tape removal and discarding (these are disposable, single-use&#xD;
      devices).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measurements (end points). We have selected outcome measures that have established&#xD;
      reliability and validity, with minimal inter-rater discordance, and are recommended for&#xD;
      pain-related clinical trials by the Initiative on Methods, Measurement, and Pain Assessment&#xD;
      in Clinical Trials (IMMPACT) consensus statement. All data collection will be through&#xD;
      standard UCSD EPIC notes and patient interviews in-person during hospitalization or via a&#xD;
      telephone call for outpatients. Postoperatively, surgical endpoints will be recorded such as&#xD;
      surgical duration. All pain scores will be measured using the Numeric Rating Scale (0: no&#xD;
      pain, 10: worst imaginable pain).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical plan and sample size estimation. there will be a total of 70 surgical&#xD;
      participants, and these patients will be analyzed separately from Phase I surgical and&#xD;
      amputation patients. Sample size calculations are based upon the hypothesis that pulsed&#xD;
      electromagnetic field therapy decreases pain in the 7 days following moderate-to-severely&#xD;
      painful surgical procedures. The primary outcome calculated as follows: for each participant&#xD;
      all of the &quot;average&quot; and &quot;worst&quot; daily pain scores collected within the first 7 postoperative&#xD;
      days will be summed. We will use these summed scores from participants having cholecystectomy&#xD;
      (n=30), and hip and knee arthroplasty (n=40) to estimate a probable sample size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will consider a 33% reduction in pain scores to be the minimal clinically important&#xD;
      difference [Farrar et al. J Pain Symptom Management 2003; 25: 406-11]. Based on values from&#xD;
      patients receiving sham in an (as-of-yet) unpublished pilot study, we anticipate the sham&#xD;
      group to have an anticipated mean (SD) of 23.9 (12.3). Assuming a two-sided type I error&#xD;
      protection of 0.05 and a power of 0.80, approximately 25 patients in each group are required&#xD;
      (ClinCalc.com, accessed 2/23/23). To allow for a higher degree of variability than&#xD;
      anticipated we will enroll a total of 70 participants: cholecystectomy (n=30), and hip and&#xD;
      knee arthroplasty (n=40).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Continuous, normally-distributed data will be reported as mean ± standard deviation.&#xD;
      Nonparametric continuous or categorical data will be reported as median [10th-90th&#xD;
      percentiles] or precents, as appropriate. Comparisons of independent samples will be&#xD;
      performed using Student's t-test for parametric continuous variables or Mann-Whitney U test&#xD;
      for nonparametric or categorical variables. The Chi Square test and Fisher's Exact test will&#xD;
      be used for differences in proportions, as appropriate. P&lt;0.05 will be considered&#xD;
      statistically significant for the primary outcome. Results of comparisons in secondary&#xD;
      outcomes will be interpreted as suggestive, requiring confirmation in a future trial before&#xD;
      considering them as definitive.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 4, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Parallel Assignment: Randomized, Triple-Masked, Placebo-Controlled, Parallel-Arm Human Subjects Clinical Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The Investigational Drug Service will create the randomization tables and provide the investigators with the appropriate device (active or sham), leaving all participants, investigators, and the statistician masked to treatment group assignment with the exception of the study coordinator who receives the study device from the Investigational Drug Service.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>First postoperative week</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale. The primary outcome calculated as follows: for each participant all of the &quot;average&quot; and &quot;worst&quot; daily pain scores collected within the first 7 postoperative days will be summed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 2</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 3</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 180</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median AVERAGE pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Median value of the average daily pain measured on postoperative days 1, 2, 3, and 7</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale. The outcome will the mean value of daily average pain scores measured with the Numeric Rating Scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Median value of the worst daily pain measured on postoperative days 1, 2, 3, and 7</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale. The outcome will the mean value of daily worst pain scores measured with the Numeric Rating Scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 2</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 3</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WORST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 180</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LEAST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LEAST pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CURRENT pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CURRENT pain measured with the Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The numeric rating scale is a 0-10 Likert scale measuring pain level with 0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total OPIOID consumption from recovery room discharge until the data collection phone call on postoperative day 7 (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>Cumulative opioid consumption queried on postoperative days 1, 2, 3, and 7</time_frame>
    <description>Total opioid consumption from recovery room discharge until the data collection phone call on postoperative day 7 (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 2</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 3</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 180</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption of the previous 24 hours (measured in oral oxycodone equivalents)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief pain Inventory, short form (interference subscale)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief pain Inventory (short form) is an instrument specifically designed to assess pain and its impact on physical and emotional functioning. The brief Inventory is comprised of three domains: (1) pain, with four questions involving &quot;worst&quot;, &quot;average&quot; and &quot;current&quot; pain levels using a 0-10 numeric rating scale;(2) percentage of relief provided by pain treatments with one question [reported score is the percentage divided by 10 and then subtracted from 10: 0=complete relief,10=no relief] and, (3) interference with 7 questions involving physical and emotional functioning using a 0-10 Likert scale [0=no interference;10=complete interference]: general activity, mood, walking ability, normal work, relations with other people, sleep and enjoyment of life. This outcome will include the interference subscale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief pain Inventory, short form (interference subscale)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief pain Inventory (short form) is an instrument specifically designed to assess pain and its impact on physical and emotional functioning. The brief Inventory is comprised of three domains: (1) pain, with four questions involving &quot;worst&quot;, &quot;average&quot; and &quot;current&quot; pain levels using a 0-10 numeric rating scale;(2) percentage of relief provided by pain treatments with one question [reported score is the percentage divided by 10 and then subtracted from 10: 0=complete relief,10=no relief] and, (3) interference with 7 questions involving physical and emotional functioning using a 0-10 Likert scale [0=no interference;10=complete interference]: general activity, mood, walking ability, normal work, relations with other people, sleep and enjoyment of life. This outcome will include the interference subscale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Awakenings due to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>The number of times the participant awoke the previous night due to pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Awakenings due to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 2</time_frame>
    <description>The number of times the participant awoke the previous night due to pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Awakenings due to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 3</time_frame>
    <description>The number of times the participant awoke the previous night due to pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Awakenings due to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The number of times the participant awoke the previous night due to pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Awakenings due to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The number of times the participant awoke the previous night due to pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization duration measured in days</measure>
    <time_frame>First postoperative week</time_frame>
    <description>Day relative to the day of surgery that patient was discharged from the hospital (e.g., same day is postoperative day 0, while the day following surgery is postoperative day 1)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical start as recorded using military time format</measure>
    <time_frame>intraoperative (within the operating room)</time_frame>
    <description>The time of the surgical incision as recorded using military time format</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical stop as recorded using military time format</measure>
    <time_frame>intraoperative (within the operating room)</time_frame>
    <description>The time of the final suture insertion as recorded using military time format</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical duration</measure>
    <time_frame>intraoperative (within the operating room)</time_frame>
    <description>The time from surgical start to surgical stop measured in minutes and hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device location changes</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>If a patient moves the anatomic location of one or both of the intervention devices (and where the device is moved to) since the last phone contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device location changes</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 2</time_frame>
    <description>If a patient moves the anatomic location of one or both of the intervention devices (and where the device is moved to) since the last phone contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device location changes</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 3</time_frame>
    <description>If a patient moves the anatomic location of one or both of the intervention devices (and where the device is moved to) since the last phone contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device location changes</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 7</time_frame>
    <description>If a patient moves the anatomic location of one or both of the intervention devices (and where the device is moved to) since the last phone contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device location changes</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>If a patient moves the anatomic location of one or both of the intervention devices (and where the device is moved to) since the last phone contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Passive joint flexion</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>The number of degrees the patient can flex their knee or hip (for these procedures only; cholecystectomy excluded)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Postoperative Pain, Acute</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Pulsed Shortwave Treatment with SofPulse</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Application of 8 days of nonthermal, pulsed shortwave (radiofrequency) therapy with Endonovo Therapeutics SofPulse</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Application of 8 days of sham device</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Active Pulsed Shortwave Treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of 8 days of nonthermal, pulsed shortwave (radiofrequency) therapy with Endonovo Therapeutics SofPulse</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active Pulsed Shortwave Treatment with SofPulse</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>non thermal, pulsed shortwave (radio frequency) therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>pulsed electromagnetic fields therapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham Treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of 8 days of a nonfunctional sham device</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sham Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Placebo treatment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients of at least 18 years of age undergoing one of these primary surgical&#xD;
        procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  primary knee arthroplasty&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  primary hip arthroplasty&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cholecystectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  concurrent use of an implanted pulse generator (e.g., cardiac pacemaker)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  incarceration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic opioid/tramadol use (daily use within the 2 weeks prior to surgery and&#xD;
             duration of use &gt; 4 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neuro-muscular deficit of the surgical area/limb&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a planned postoperative perineural local anesthetic infusion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 24, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Brian M. Ilfeld, MD, MS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Anesthesiology, In Residence</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

