<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05617599</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>rEpic05 - Multiflex</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05617599</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SUPRAFLEX CRUZ PMCF Study ( rEpic05 )</brief_title>
  <acronym>Multiflex</acronym>
  <official_title>SUPRAFLEX CRUZPost-Market Clinical Follow-up Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación EPIC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación EPIC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multicenter, prospective, non-randomized, post-market clinical follow-up (PMCF) study to&#xD;
      confirm and support the clinical safety and performance of Medical Device Regulations (MDR)&#xD;
      with multivessel coronary disease requirements in all the CONSECUTIVE patients treated with&#xD;
      (SUPRAFLEX CRUZ).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this multicenter, prospective, non-randomized, post-market clinical&#xD;
      follow-up (PMCF) study is to confirm and support the clinical safety and performance of the&#xD;
      SUPRAFLEX CRUZ in a NON-SELECTED, Real World population under daily clinical practice when&#xD;
      used as intended by the manufacturer to meet EU Medical Device regulation requirements for&#xD;
      post-market clinical follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Target Lesion Failure (TLF)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of target lesion failure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Device-oriented Composite Endpoint (DoCE)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Device-oriented Composite Endpoint (DoCE) defined as the composite of: Cardiovascular death, target vessel myocardial infarction, clinically indicated repeat revascularization of the target lesion at 12 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major Adverse Cardiovascular Event (MACE)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Composite event of cardiovascular (CV) death, non-fatal myocardial infarction (MI) and non-fatal stroke</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) measured by echocardiography</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>In the subgroup of patients with reduced Ejection Fraction, Change from baseline in left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) measured by echocardiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Global Longitudinal Strain measured by strain-rate echocardiography</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>In the subgroup of patients with reduced Ejection Fraction, Change from baseline in Global Longitudinal Strain measured by strain-rate echocardiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of segmental movement of the territory revascularized measured by echocardiography</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>In the subgroup of patients with reduced Ejection Fraction, Change from baseline segmental movement of the territory revascularized measured by echocardiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) from baseline and from 1 month post-procedure/pre-hospital discharge as assessed by echo in the subgroup of ventricular dysfunction</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">508</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease (CAD)</condition>
  <condition>Ischemic Heart Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Coronary Artery Disease (CAD)</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SUPRAFLEX CRUZ</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in whom treatment with SUPRAFLEX CRUZ has been attempted</description>
    <arm_group_label>Coronary Artery Disease (CAD)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients treated with MULTIFLEX PMCF according to routine hospital practice and following&#xD;
        instructions for use&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 18 years old and;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated with SUPRAFLEX CRUZ according to routine hospital practice and&#xD;
             following instructions for use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with multivessel coronary artery disease (understood as that which affects&#xD;
             more than one territory of the major epicardial coronary arteries - anterior&#xD;
             descending, circumflex, right coronary artery) who is treated with more than 1 stent&#xD;
             under study in lesions located in more than 1 of the aforementioned arteries.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substudy: Patients with Ejection Fraction &lt;45% by Echocardiography&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent signed&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not meet inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication for antiplatelet treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient life expectancy less than 12 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bruno Garcia, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0034932746155</phone>
    <email>brunogb51@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>FUNDACION EPIC</last_name>
    <phone>0034987225638</phone>
    <email>iepic@fundacionepic.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bangalore S, Toklu B, Patel N, Feit F, Stone GW. Newer-Generation Ultrathin Strut Drug-Eluting Stents Versus Older Second-Generation Thicker Strut Drug-Eluting Stents for Coronary Artery Disease. Circulation. 2018 Nov 13;138(20):2216-2226. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.118.034456.</citation>
    <PMID>29945934</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lemos PA, Chandwani P, Saxena S, Ramachandran PK, Abhyankar A, Campos CM, Marchini JF, Galon MZ, Verma P, Sandhu MS, Parikh N, Bhupali A, Jain S, Prajapati J. Clinical outcomes in 995 unselected real-world patients treated with an ultrathin biodegradable polymer-coated sirolimus-eluting stent: 12-month results from the FLEX Registry. BMJ Open. 2016 Feb 17;6(2):e010028. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2015-010028.</citation>
    <PMID>26888727</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Modolo R, Chichareon P, Kogame N, Asano T, Chang CC, de Winter RJ, Kaul U, Zaman A, Spitzer E, Takahashi K, Katagiri Y, Soliman OII, van Es GA, Morel MA, Onuma Y, Serruys PW. A prospective multicentre randomised all-comers trial to assess the safety and effectiveness of the thin-strut sirolimus-eluting coronary stent SUPRAFLEX: rationale and design of the Thin Strut Sirolimus-eluting Stent in All Comers Population vs Everolimus-eluting Stent (TALENT) trial. EuroIntervention. 2019 Jul 20;15(4):e362-e369. doi: 10.4244/EIJ-D-18-00499.</citation>
    <PMID>30066672</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zaman A, de Winter RJ, Kogame N, Chang CC, Modolo R, Spitzer E, Tonino P, Hofma S, Zurakowski A, Smits PC, Prokopczuk J, Moreno R, Choudhury A, Petrov I, Cequier A, Kukreja N, Hoye A, Iniguez A, Ungi I, Serra A, Gil RJ, Walsh S, Tonev G, Mathur A, Merkely B, Colombo A, Ijsselmuiden S, Soliman O, Kaul U, Onuma Y, Serruys PW; TALENT trial investigators. Safety and efficacy of a sirolimus-eluting coronary stent with ultra-thin strut for treatment of atherosclerotic lesions (TALENT): a prospective multicentre randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2019 Mar 9;393(10175):987-997. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32467-X. Epub 2019 Feb 28.</citation>
    <PMID>30827782</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CE-MDR (Medical Device Regulations)</keyword>
  <keyword>PMCF (Post-Market Clinical Follow-up)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

