<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618171</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020/08-03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618171</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Patient's Risk Profile Using the Peri-implantitis Risk Diagram</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Patient's Pre- and Post-treatment Risk Profile Using the Peri-implantitis Risk Diagram</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Berceste Guler</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kutahya Health Sciences University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Various risk factors defined in the literature should be eliminated in order for the patient&#xD;
      to be able to use implant-supported prostheses for a longer period of time. In the&#xD;
      literature, such a diagram for peri-implant risk factors was first described by&#xD;
      Heitz-Mayfield in 2020. The scheme that will determine the peri-implant risk diagram is&#xD;
      called &quot;Implant Disease Risk Assessment (IDRA)&quot;. This tool provides evaluation of various&#xD;
      risk factors on a single diagram. In this study, peri-implant risk diagrams will be&#xD;
      determined by calling the patients who have previously completed implant treatment in Kütahya&#xD;
      University of Health Sciences Faculty of Dentistry Department of Periodontology, and the&#xD;
      change in the risk profile assessment will be re-evaluated after the risk factors that can be&#xD;
      eliminated are eliminated. In this study, it is aimed to predict the risk of inflammation and&#xD;
      alveolar bone loss of the tissues around the implant that may occur in the future in patients&#xD;
      who have undergone dental implant treatment, and to evaluate the risk profiles.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nowadays, dental implants are increasingly applied worldwide for the restoration of lost&#xD;
      teeth. It is known that the survival rates of dental implant treatments are quite high, but&#xD;
      in recent studies, the maintenance of the health of the peri-implant tissues and the&#xD;
      satisfaction of the patient play a more important role in the success of the dental implant,&#xD;
      not the survival. Various risk factors defined in the literature should be eliminated in&#xD;
      order for the patient to be able to use implant-supported prostheses for a longer period of&#xD;
      time. In the literature, a Spider Web scheme named &quot;Perio-tools&quot; has been defined, which&#xD;
      evaluates the risk profile of the patient by determining the risk factors for periodontal&#xD;
      diseases. However, such a diagram for peri-implant risk factors in the literature was first&#xD;
      described by Heitz-Mayfield in 2020. The scheme that will determine the peri-implant risk&#xD;
      diagram is called &quot;Implant Disease Risk Assessment (IDRA)&quot;. This tool provides evaluation of&#xD;
      various risk factors on a single diagram. In this study, peri-implant risk diagrams will be&#xD;
      determined by calling the patients who have previously completed implant treatment in Kütahya&#xD;
      University of Health Sciences Faculty of Dentistry Department of Periodontology, and the&#xD;
      change in the risk profile assessment will be re-evaluated after the risk factors that can be&#xD;
      eliminated are eliminated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      By using &quot;IDRA&quot;, a tool specially developed for patients who have had dental implants in our&#xD;
      clinic, patients will be grouped as &quot;low-medium-high&quot; risk according to their initial status&#xD;
      in terms of the risk of developing peri-implantitis. Again, these patients will be&#xD;
      re-evaluated using the &quot;IDRA&quot; tool 1 year after applying Phase I treatment. During this whole&#xD;
      process, clinical and radiographic evaluations will be carried out simultaneously. Periapical&#xD;
      radiographs will be taken from the implant periphery of the patients with the parallel long&#xD;
      cone technique. According to the periodontal disease classification made in 2017, the&#xD;
      diagnosis of the patients will be evaluated through panoramic radiographs and clinical&#xD;
      measurements. Patients will undergo periodontal examination at their first visit. Keratinized&#xD;
      gingival width, plaque index, gingival index, attachment loss, bleeding indices on probing&#xD;
      will be taken. Peri-implant mucosa will be examined. Peri-implant health status will be&#xD;
      recorded according to the following criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The state of being healthy of peri-implant tissues; No bleeding on probing, no swelling, no&#xD;
      hyperemia, no signs of inflammation Peri-implant mucositis; Inflammatory lesion limited to&#xD;
      the soft tissues surrounding the dental implant and no bone loss Peri-implantitis; Bleeding&#xD;
      on probing, presence of bone loss, distance between the most coronal part of the implant in&#xD;
      the bone and the bone level ≥ 3mm, pocket depth ≥ 6mm on probing&#xD;
&#xD;
      Plaque index and gingival index are obtained by measuring 4 regions of a tooth (mesial,&#xD;
      distal, buccal and lingual) with Williams periodontal probe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Attachment loss: It is the value of the distance between a tooth and the free gingiva, based&#xD;
      on the enamel-cementum junction, measured using a Williams periodontal probe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bleeding index in probing: In this index, probing is performed by gently walking around the&#xD;
      pocket. As a result of probing, the evaluation is made by looking at the presence or absence&#xD;
      of bleeding in the gingiva. If bleeding occurs within 10-15 seconds after probing in the&#xD;
      mesial, distal, buccal and lingual gingival parts of all teeth, a positive value is given.&#xD;
      The ratio of the bleeding area to the examined area is expressed as %.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keratinized gingival width: It is the distance from the free gingival margin to the&#xD;
      mucogingival junction line.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Modified plaque index and modified sulcus bleeding index will be used for implants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral hygiene motivation will be given after the periodontal indexes of the patients are&#xD;
      recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the periodontal pocket depth is excessive, routine Phase I treatment will be applied for&#xD;
      its elimination. Likewise, risk factors related to prosthetic restoration (occlusal trauma,&#xD;
      cement residue) will be eliminated. After all the risk factors that can be eliminated in our&#xD;
      clinic have been eliminated, the patient will be called for a repeat risk profile evaluation&#xD;
      1 year later. In the follow-up of the patient 1 year later, clinical and radiographic routine&#xD;
      evaluations will be performed again and the results will be compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IDRA is a functional risk assessment diagram specially developed for patients with dental&#xD;
      implants. Evaluated data;&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Evaluation of whether the patient has a history of periodontitis (inflammatory disease&#xD;
           of the teeth and surrounding tissues). Studies have shown that patients with a history&#xD;
           of periodontitis are at high risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Percentage of bleeding in periodontal probing (measurement in the gingival pocket with a&#xD;
           periodontal probe). It has been emphasized in studies that as the percentage of bleeding&#xD;
           on probing increases, tissue destruction increases and therefore the risk of implant&#xD;
           loss increases.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Peri-implant pocket depth ≥5 mm. It is emphasized that the risk of inflammation of the&#xD;
           tissues around the tooth and implant increases as the number of teeth or implants with a&#xD;
           pocket depth of more than 5 mm increases.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Evaluation of the relationship between age and periodontal bone loss (bone loss/age).&#xD;
           Studies emphasize that significant statistical values emerge when bone loss is compared&#xD;
           to age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Evaluation of periodontal susceptibility according to the renewed periodontal disease&#xD;
           classification by reaching Consensus in 2017&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Evaluation of participation in supportive periodontal therapy. Studies have emphasized&#xD;
           the positive effects of patients' regular visits to control appointments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Evaluation of the relationship between the restoration margin and the bone level. It is&#xD;
           emphasized that the risk of inflammation of the tissues around the implant increases as&#xD;
           the restoration margin approaches the bone crest.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Factors associated with dental prosthetic restoration (cleanability, evaluation of&#xD;
           restoration compliance, etc.). It is emphasized in studies that the risk of implant loss&#xD;
           decreases in cases where the prosthetic restorations on the implant are cleanable,&#xD;
           well-fitted, screwed or in the absence of excessive cementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, it is aimed to predict the risk of future inflammation of peri-implant tissues&#xD;
      and alveolar bone loss in patients who have undergone dental implant treatment and to&#xD;
      evaluate the risk profiles.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 28, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 5, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of pre- and post-treatment peri-implantitis risk profiles of patients who underwent dental implant treatment at the patient level.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after phase 1 treatment</time_frame>
    <description>By using &quot;IDRA&quot;, a tool specially developed for patients who have had dental implants in our clinic, patients will be grouped as &quot;low-medium-high&quot; risk according to their initial status in terms of the risk of developing peri-implantitis. Again, these patients will be re-evaluated 1 year after applying Phase I treatment using the &quot;IDRA&quot; tool. Evaluation will be at the patient level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of pre- and post-treatment peri-implantitis risk profiles at implant level in patients who have undergone dental implant treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after phase 1 treatment</time_frame>
    <description>By using &quot;IDRA&quot;, a tool specially developed for patients who have had dental implants in our clinic, patients will be grouped as &quot;low-medium-high&quot; risk according to their initial status in terms of the risk of developing peri-implantitis. Again, these patients will be re-evaluated 1 year after applying Phase I treatment using the &quot;IDRA&quot; tool. Evaluation will be at the implant level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">170</enrollment>
  <condition>Peri-Implantitis</condition>
  <condition>Peri-implant Mucositis</condition>
  <condition>Dental Implant Failed</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Evaluation of the patient's pre- and post-treatment risk profile using the peri-implantitis risk diagram</intervention_name>
    <description>By using &quot;IDRA&quot;, a tool specially developed for patients who have had dental implants in our clinic, patients will be evaluated as &quot;low-moderate-high&quot; risk in terms of the risk of developing peri-implantitis, according to their initial status. Again, these patients will be re-evaluated 1 year after applying Phase I treatment using the &quot;IDRA&quot; tool. During this whole process, clinical and radiographic evaluations will be carried out simultaneously.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who underwent dental implants in Kütahya Health Sciences University, Faculty of&#xD;
        Dentistry, Department of Periodontology&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be over 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The condition of making dental implants in Kütahya Health Sciences University, Faculty&#xD;
             of Dentistry, Department of Periodontology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Finding radiographic documentation of dental implants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Functioning of the implants in the mouth for at least 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antibiotic use in the 3 months before the first examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have not received regular implant maintenance therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mentally retarded patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Berceste Güler</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Kütahya Health Sciences University Faculty of Dentistry</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kütahya Health Sciences University Faculty of Dentistry, Department of Periodontology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kütahya</city>
        <zip>43100</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Heitz-Mayfield LJA, Heitz F, Lang NP. Implant Disease Risk Assessment IDRA-a tool for preventing peri-implant disease. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2020 Apr;31(4):397-403. doi: 10.1111/clr.13585. Epub 2020 Feb 20.</citation>
    <PMID>32003037</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dalago HR, Schuldt Filho G, Rodrigues MA, Renvert S, Bianchini MA. Risk indicators for Peri-implantitis. A cross-sectional study with 916 implants. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2017 Feb;28(2):144-150. doi: 10.1111/clr.12772. Epub 2016 Jan 11.</citation>
    <PMID>26754342</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 13, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kutahya Health Sciences University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Berceste Guler</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>IDRA</keyword>
  <keyword>Peri-implantitis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peri-Implantitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>It will be shared if the principal investigator is contacted.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>1 year after the research was published</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The principal investigator should be contacted.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

