<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612451</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20180112</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612451</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Outcome of Regenerative Endodontic Procedures</brief_title>
  <official_title>Outcome of Regenerative Endodontic Procedures for Necrotic Immature Permanent Teeth, Using Two Different Protocols: A Prospective Randomized Clinical Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King Abdullah University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King Abdullah University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Clinical management of immature non-vital (necrotic) permanent teeth is challenging, due to&#xD;
      inherent structural weakness. Earlier management of such teeth relied on the traditional&#xD;
      calcium hydroxide (Ca(OH)2) apexification procedure or the application of apical barriers&#xD;
      However, neither procedure allows for promoting root dentin maturation. In 2004, a novel&#xD;
      management technique for treating immature, non-vital teeth called regenerative endodontic&#xD;
      procedures (REP; also known as revascularization) was introduced. This procedure allowed for&#xD;
      continued root maturation presented in an increase in root length and dentin wall thickness.&#xD;
      The key points of REP include minimal or no instrumentation of the dentinal walls,&#xD;
      disinfection with irrigant solutions and intracanal medicaments, provocation of bleeding into&#xD;
      the canal space for creation of a blood clot, capping with calcium silicate-based material,&#xD;
      and an effective coronal seal to prevent reinfection of the root canal system. Several case&#xD;
      reports and clinical studies reported promising results for REP treatment. However, studies&#xD;
      widely varied in their treatment methods, hence the search for an optimal REP protocol is&#xD;
      still ongoing. A recent review reported that the methodological quality of REP clinical&#xD;
      trials available to date, was low with a moderate to high risk of bias. To date, only few&#xD;
      studies evaluated the outcome of REPs based on different types of intracanal medicaments.&#xD;
      These studies either presented a retrospective design, low sample size and/or short follow up&#xD;
      period. Hence, the need for randomized, controlled clinical studies to provide persuasive&#xD;
      evidence on the efficacy of different intracanal medicaments in REP is of utmost importance.&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to prospectively assess and compare the clinical and radiographic&#xD;
      outcomes of REP in non-vital immature permanent teeth using an intracanal medicament modified&#xD;
      TAP or non-setting Ca(OH)2 paste. Forty-five patients yielding a total of 50 anterior and&#xD;
      posterior non-vital immature teeth were randomly divided into 2 groups. REP utilizing either&#xD;
      non-setting calcium hydroxide (Ca(OH)2) (n=25) or modified triple antibiotic paste (TAP)&#xD;
      (n=25), as intracanal medicaments were performed. NeoMTA Plus was applied for coronal&#xD;
      sealing. Cases were followed up clinically and radiographically for 24 months. Survival rate,&#xD;
      success rate, and clinical outcome measures were analyzed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 20, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 27, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This randomized clinical trial aimed to assess and compare the clinical and radiographic outcomes of Regenerative Endodontic Procedures (REP) in treating non-vital immature permanent teeth using two intracanal medicaments.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>treatment success</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>disappearance of clinical signs and symptoms including tenderness to percussion or palpation, a swelling or sinus tract, or spontaneous pain, and absence or reduction in the size of periapiacl radiolucency</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>root elongation</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>increased root length</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>root maturation</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>increased root dentin thickness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>root completion</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <description>apical closure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Endodontic Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>non-setting calcium hydroxide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Regenerative Endodontic Procedure utilizing non-setting calcium hydroxide as intracanal medicament</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>modified triple antibiotic paste</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Regenerative Endodontic Procedure utilizing modified triple antibiotic paste as intracanal medicament</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Regenerative Endodontic Procedures</intervention_name>
    <description>Regenerative Endodontic procedures were performed by one operator following similar protocols according to the clinical considerations for a regenerative procedure advised by the American Association of Endodontists and European Society of Endodontology</description>
    <arm_group_label>modified triple antibiotic paste</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>non-setting calcium hydroxide</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>non-setting calcium hydroxide</intervention_name>
    <description>non-setting calcium hydroxide</description>
    <arm_group_label>non-setting calcium hydroxide</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>modified triple antibiotic paste</intervention_name>
    <description>modified triple antibiotic paste</description>
    <arm_group_label>modified triple antibiotic paste</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Anterior or posterior tooth diagnosed with necrotic pulp (as a result of trauma,&#xD;
             caries or anomaly) in the presence or absence of apical periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. an immature apex or open apex(an apical diameter wider than 1 mm and is&#xD;
             radiographically visible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pulp space not needed for post and core restoration&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. A cooperative and Compliant patient/ parent&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients not allergic to medicaments necessary to complete the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. medically compromised patient,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. teeth with vertical fractures,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. periodontally involved teeth,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. non-restorable teeth,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. teeth when bleeding could not be induced.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aladdin A Al-Qudah, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Jordan University of Science &amp; Technology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jordan University of Science &amp; Technology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irbid</city>
        <zip>22110</zip>
        <country>Jordan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Jordan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Duggal M, Tong HJ, Al-Ansary M, Twati W, Day PF, Nazzal H. Interventions for the endodontic management of non-vital traumatised immature permanent anterior teeth in children and adolescents: a systematic review of the evidence and guidelines of the European Academy of Paediatric Dentistry. Eur Arch Paediatr Dent. 2017 Jun;18(3):139-151. doi: 10.1007/s40368-017-0289-5. Epub 2017 May 15. Erratum In: Eur Arch Paediatr Dent. 2017 Jun;18(3):153.</citation>
    <PMID>28508244</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Saoud TM, Zaazou A, Nabil A, Moussa S, Lin LM, Gibbs JL. Clinical and radiographic outcomes of traumatized immature permanent necrotic teeth after revascularization/revitalization therapy. J Endod. 2014 Dec;40(12):1946-52. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2014.08.023. Epub 2014 Oct 16.</citation>
    <PMID>25443280</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>European Society of Endodontology (ESE) developed by:; Krastl G, Weiger R, Filippi A, Van Waes H, Ebeleseder K, Ree M, Connert T, Widbiller M, Tjaderhane L, Dummer PMH, Galler K. European Society of Endodontology position statement: endodontic management of traumatized permanent teeth. Int Endod J. 2021 Sep;54(9):1473-1481. doi: 10.1111/iej.13543. Epub 2021 Jun 20.</citation>
    <PMID>33934366</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sponchiado-Junior EC, Vieira WA, Frozoni M, Herkrath FJ, de-Jesus-Soares A. CONSORT Compliance in Randomized Clinical Trials of Regenerative Endodontic Treatments of Necrotic Immature Teeth: A Scoping Review. J Endod. 2021 Nov;47(11):1751-1766. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2021.07.017. Epub 2021 Aug 3.</citation>
    <PMID>34352304</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chan EK, Desmeules M, Cielecki M, Dabbagh B, Ferraz Dos Santos B. Longitudinal Cohort Study of Regenerative Endodontic Treatment for Immature Necrotic Permanent Teeth. J Endod. 2017 Mar;43(3):395-400. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2016.10.035. Epub 2017 Jan 19.</citation>
    <PMID>28110920</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>ElSheshtawy AS, Nazzal H, El Shahawy OI, El Baz AA, Ismail SM, Kang J, Ezzat KM. The effect of platelet-rich plasma as a scaffold in regeneration/revitalization endodontics of immature permanent teeth assessed using 2-dimensional radiographs and cone beam computed tomography: a randomized controlled trial. Int Endod J. 2020 Jul;53(7):905-921. doi: 10.1111/iej.13303. Epub 2020 Apr 30.</citation>
    <PMID>32249441</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Endodontic regeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Immature teeth</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Pulp Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Calcium</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>all IPD that underlie results in a publication will be shared</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>starting 12 months after publication</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>will be sent by email, upon request</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

