<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05622487</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Istanbul Universty FMS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05622487</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neural Therapy and Kinesio Taping Effectiveness in Fibromyalgia</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of Neural Therapy and Kinesio Taping on Pain, Functional Status, and Quality of Life in Fibromyalgia Patients: A Prospective Randomized Double-Blind Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study; to investigate the effects of neural therapy and kinesio taping&#xD;
      treatments on pain, functional status and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Fibromyalgia is a chronic disorder characterized by widespread pain, fatigue, sleep&#xD;
      disturbance, cognitive impairment, and other physical symptoms that negatively affect&#xD;
      physical and sensory functions and impair quality of life. Neural therapy and kinesio taping&#xD;
      are treatments for musculoskeletal diseases. In this prospective, randomized controlled,&#xD;
      double-blind, interventional study, 64 patients aged 18-55 years who met the eligibility&#xD;
      criteria will be included in the study. Eligible participants will be randomly assigned to&#xD;
      one of two groups using computer generated random numbers. Segmental neural therapy and sham&#xD;
      kinesio taping will be applied to the first group. In the second group, kinesio taping with&#xD;
      inhibition technique will be applied to bilateral trapezius and erector spina muscles and&#xD;
      sham neural therapy will be added. Treatments will be applied once a week for a total of 6&#xD;
      weeks. Both groups will be given a home exercise program consisting of stretching exercises&#xD;
      and will be checked every week. During the follow-up period, patients will be asked not to&#xD;
      make changes to their current medical treatment. Participants will be evaluated for pain by&#xD;
      Visual Analogue Scale (VAS), Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire (FIQ), Central Sensitisation&#xD;
      Inventory (CSI), Beck Depression Inventory (BDI), Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI), Health&#xD;
      Assessment Questionnaire (HAQ), Short Form-36 (SF-36), manual algometer measurements and&#xD;
      number of tender points, as well as post-treatment and post-treatment 3 month control data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue Scale pain (0-10 point).</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire (0-100 point)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>The Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire was developed to assess the current functional status of women with FMS. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain measurement with manual algometer</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>18 tender points in 1990 ACR FMS criteria will be evaluated with a manual algometer. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck Depression Inventory (0-63 point)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>Beck Depression Inventory (BDI) is a frequently used evaluation criterion as a diagnosis and follow-up parameter in evaluating the state of depression. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck Anxiety Inventory (0-63 point)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>The scale aims to determine the frequency and severity of anxiety symptoms experienced by individuals. The highest score that can be obtained from the 21-item scale is 63. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Central Sensitisation Inventory (0-100 point)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>Central sensitization scale; It is a scale used to detect central sensitization conditions such as fibromyalgia, migraine, myofascial pain, temporomandibular disorder. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Assessment Questionnaire (0-60 point)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>The health assessment questionnaire shows the extent of the participant's functional ability, is sensitive to change, and is a good predictor of future cost and disability. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Short Form-36 (0-100 point)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 month</time_frame>
    <description>Short Form-36 is one of the commonly used scales in which health concepts such as functional status and well-being are evaluated. This scale examines health in 8 dimensions: physical function, physical role limitations, emotional role limitations, social function, mental health, vitality (energy), pain and general perception of health. Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">65</enrollment>
  <condition>Fibromyalgia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Neural Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Segmental neural therapy will be administered with intradermal 0.5% lidocaine from cervical 1st to sacral 1st vertebra and upper trapezius region with quaddel injections.. Sham kinesio taping will be applied to the bilateral arms of the patients. Home exercise program; trapezius stretching, cervical, thoracic and lumbar paravertebral muscle stretching exercises will be required to be performed 10 times and every day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Kinesio Taping</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Kinesio taping will be applied with muscle inhibition technique by stretching from the origin to the insertion of the upper trapezius, cervical thoracic and lumbar paravertebral muscles. Sham neural therapy will be applied to the bilateral arms of the patients. Home exercise program; trapezius stretching, cervical, thoracic and lumbar paravertebral muscle stretching exercises will be required to be performed 10 times and every day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neural Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Neural therapy is a form of treatment that aims to act on the autonomic nervous system, by injecting local anesthetics into certain parts of the body.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Neural Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Kinesio taping</intervention_name>
    <description>Kinesiotape is used for injury prevention, rehabilitation and performance enhancement. It has been shown to be clinically effective in increasing joint movements, increasing muscle activity, inducing muscle maximum torque earlier, and improving functional performance</description>
    <arm_group_label>Kinesio Taping</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To be diagnosed with fibromyalgia according to the ACR 2016 diagnostic criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being a woman between the ages of 18 and 55.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No change in the medical treatment he received for fibromyalgia syndrome during the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To be able to come to treatment 1 day a week for 6 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of known central nervous system or peripheral nervous system disease,&#xD;
             progressive neurological deficit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripheral venous insufficiency, coagulopathies and anticoagulant drug use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Loss of sensation, loss of position sense, unhealed fracture or open surgical wound&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension and uncontrolled diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be in major depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment that causes difficulty following simple commands&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be in menopause&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to local anesthetics and kinesio taping&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Open wound or infection at the application site&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ayşegül Ketenci, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Study Director</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul University Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <state>Fatıh</state>
        <zip>34034</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul University</name>
      <address>
        <city>İstanbul</city>
        <zip>3409</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sinan GOK</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Fibromyalgia</keyword>
  <keyword>Neural Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Kinesio Taping</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

