<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05627245</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2022-05327</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2022-05327</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10500</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>10500</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186689</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05627245</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing the Safety of the Anti-cancer Drugs Tazemetostat and Belinostat in Patients With Lymphomas That Have Resisted Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1/Expansion Study of Tazemetostat Plus Belinostat for the Treatment of Relapsed or Refractory Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial tests the safety, side effects, and best dose of combination therapy with&#xD;
      tazemetostat and belinostat in treating patients with lymphomas that have returned (relapsed)&#xD;
      or resisted treatment (refractory). Tazemetostat is in a class of medications called EZH2&#xD;
      inhibitors. The EZH2 gene provides instructions for making a type of enzyme called histone&#xD;
      methyltransferase which is involved in gene expression and cell division. Blocking EZH2 may&#xD;
      help keep cancer cells from growing. Belinostat is in a class of medications called histone&#xD;
      deacetylase inhibitors. Histone deacetylases are enzymes needed for cell division. Belinostat&#xD;
      may kill cancer cells by blocking histone deacetylase. It may also prevent the growth of new&#xD;
      blood vessels that tumors need to grow and may help make cancer cells easier to kill with&#xD;
      other anticancer drugs. There is some evidence in animals and in living human cells that&#xD;
      combination therapy with tazemetostat and belinostat can shrink or stabilize cancer, but it&#xD;
      is not known whether this will happen in people. This trial may help doctors learn more about&#xD;
      treatment of patients with relapsed or refractory lymphoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and dose limiting toxicities (DLTs) of&#xD;
      tazemetostat and belinostat in combination in patients with relapsed or refractory lymphoma&#xD;
      (Phase I: Dose escalation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Evaluate the safety and toxicity of the combination tazemetostat and belinostat (Phase I:&#xD;
      Dose escalation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Assess the safety and tolerability of tazemetostat and belinostat in patients with&#xD;
      germinal-center derived aggressive B-cell lymphoma (transformed disease, diffuse large B-cell&#xD;
      lymphoma germinal center B-cell type [GC-DLBCL] defined by Hans criteria) (Phase I: Dose&#xD;
      expansion).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Assess the impact of EZH2, CREBBP, and EP300 mutations on response to dual epigenetic&#xD;
      targeting (Phase I: Dose expansion).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To observe and record anti-tumor activity. II. To evaluate the pharmacokinetic profile for&#xD;
      tazemetostat and belinostat when given as a combination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Define the overall response rate (ORR), progression free survival (PFS), and duration of&#xD;
      response (DOR) in patients with relapsed or refractory EZH2 mutated and EZH2 wild-type&#xD;
      aggressive germinal-center derived B-cell lymphoma (transformed disease, GC-DLBCL defined by&#xD;
      Hans criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To describe the maximum number of cycles received, the number of dose reductions and&#xD;
      delays at the MTD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine a biomarker for response by assessing the basal mutation and gene expression&#xD;
      status of key epigenetic regulators and correlating this signature with the response to the&#xD;
      combination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Determine the change in gene expression in tumor tissue following exposure the combined&#xD;
      epigenetic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Determine the effect of combination epigenetic therapy on modulation of acetylation and&#xD;
      methylation of histone K27.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Determine the effect of combination epigenetic therapy on modulation of the immune&#xD;
      response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a phase I dose-escalation study of tazemetostat and belinostat followed by a&#xD;
      dose-expansion study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive tazemetostat orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 2-21 of cycle 1 and days&#xD;
      1-21 of subsequent cycles, and belinostat intravenously (IV) over 30 minutes on days 1-5 of&#xD;
      each cycle. Cycles repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable&#xD;
      toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients may undergo a tumor biopsy during screening and on study (dose-expansion only).&#xD;
      Patients undergo blood sample collection while on study and positron emission&#xD;
      tomography/computed tomography(PET/CT) scan throughout the study. Patients may also undergo&#xD;
      computed tomography (CT) scan alone throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 4 weeks, then every 3 months&#xD;
      for a year or until they begin a new treatment for their disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) (Dose escalation)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to end of cycle 1 (Cycles = 21 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the highest dose level at which &lt; 33% of the dose cohort (0 of 3 or 1 of 6) experience a dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) in the first cycle.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease response</measure>
    <time_frame>Following cycle 2 and 6, and every 3-6 cycles, assessed up to 1 year after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) scan following cycle 2 and 6, and then every 3-6 cycles. Response will be defined by the Lugano Classification.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as complete response + partial response. Will be estimated and the exact 95% confidence interval will be constructed based on binomial distribution.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From time to enrollment to progression or death, assessed up to 1 year after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated by the Kaplan-Meier method and compared by the log-rank test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From time to enrollment to death, assessed up to 1 year after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated by the Kaplan-Meier method and compared by the log-rank test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first response to relapse or death, assessed up to 1 year after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated by the Kaplan-Meier method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of cycles</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The mean and range will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of dose delays</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The mean and range will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of dose reductions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The mean and range will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic profile for tazemetostat and belinostat</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, day 1 (C1D1) (belinostat only) and C2D1</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma concentrations of both tazemetostat and belinostat using area under the &quot;concentration time&quot; curve (AUC), maximum concentration (Cmax), time to maximum concentration Tmax, and half-life (T1/2) will be calculated for the two study drugs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 weeks after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>National Cancer Institute (NCI) toxicity Grade 3 and Grade 4 laboratory abnormalities will be listed. Summary statistics will be provided for all laboratory values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Modulation in immune function</measure>
    <time_frame>During cycle 1</time_frame>
    <description>Will be presented in descriptive terms.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Histone acetylation and methylation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed separately for the wild type (WT) and the mutant (MUT) groups and will be compared using a two-sample Wilcoxon rank-sum test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Gene signature biomarker for response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be evaluated next generation sequencing (NGS) and presented in descriptive terms. Gene signature biomarker data analysis will be completed using Lasso-based elastic net method.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Modulation of histone acetylation and methylation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will be presented in descriptive terms.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent B-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma Germinal Center B-Cell Type</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Primary Cutaneous T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Transformed Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory B-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma Germinal Center B-Cell Type</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Primary Cutaneous T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Transformed Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive tazemetostat PO BID on days 2-21 of cycle 1 and days 1-21 of subsequent cycles, and belinostat IV over 30 minutes on days 1-5 of each cycle. Cycles repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
Patients may undergo a tumor biopsy during screening and on study (dose-expansion only). Patients undergo blood sample collection while on study and PET/CT scan throughout the study. Patients may also undergo CT scan alone throughout the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Belinostat</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Beleodaq</other_name>
    <other_name>PXD 101</other_name>
    <other_name>PXD101</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biopsy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo biopsy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BIOPSY_TYPE</other_name>
    <other_name>Bx</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biospecimen Collection</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo blood sample collection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Biological Sample Collection</other_name>
    <other_name>Biospecimen Collected</other_name>
    <other_name>Specimen Collection</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Computed Tomography</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo CT scan</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CAT</other_name>
    <other_name>CAT Scan</other_name>
    <other_name>Computed Axial Tomography</other_name>
    <other_name>Computerized Axial Tomography</other_name>
    <other_name>Computerized axial tomography (procedure)</other_name>
    <other_name>Computerized Tomography</other_name>
    <other_name>CT</other_name>
    <other_name>CT Scan</other_name>
    <other_name>tomography</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pharmacokinetic Study</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmacokinetic study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PHARMACOKINETIC</other_name>
    <other_name>PK Study</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Positron Emission Tomography and Computed Tomography Scan</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo PET-CT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PET-CT Scan</other_name>
    <other_name>PET/CT SCAN</other_name>
    <other_name>Positron Emission Tomography/Computed Tomography</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tazemetostat</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (tazemetostat, belinostat)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>E7438</other_name>
    <other_name>EPZ-6438</other_name>
    <other_name>EPZ6438</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DOSE ESCALATION PHASE: Patients with relapsed or refractory non-Hodgkin lymphoma&#xD;
             including both B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL) and T-cell NHL. Refractory cutaneous&#xD;
             T-cell lymphoma (CTCL) will be allowed if greater or equal to stage 1B and have&#xD;
             previously failed two systemic therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DOSE EXPANSION PHASE: Patients with relapsed or refractory transformed lymphoma or&#xD;
             germinal center B-cell diffuse large B-cell Lymphoma (GCB-DLBCL) as defined by Hans&#xD;
             criteria. Equal numbers of patients will be enrolled onto one of 2 arms: (1) mutated&#xD;
             EZH2 or (2) wild-type EZH2. EZH2 mutations will be identified by polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction (PCR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not be eligible for, or have refused, stem cell transplantation or&#xD;
             chimeric antigen receptor T-cell (CAR T-cell) therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have undergone 1-5 prior treatments of any type (progression after&#xD;
             transplant/cellular therapy allowed) are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease according to the Lugano classification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years. Because no dosing or adverse event data are currently available on&#xD;
             the use of tazemetostat in combination with belinostat in patients &lt; 18 years of age,&#xD;
             children are excluded from this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 2 (Karnofsky &gt;= 60%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If there is documented lymphomatous involvement of the bone marrow as assessed by&#xD;
                  bone marrow biopsy within 90 days prior to registration, participants should&#xD;
                  have: ANC &gt;= 0.75 × 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 75,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If there is documented lymphomatous involvement of the bone marrow as assessed by&#xD;
                  bone marrow biopsy within 90 days prior to registration, participants should&#xD;
                  have: platelets &gt;= 50 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; .5 institutional upper limit of normal (ULN); unless due to&#xD;
             Gilbert's disease, hemolysis, or lymphomatous involvement of liver in which case total&#xD;
             bilirubin should be =&lt; 5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])&#xD;
             =&lt; 3 x institutional ULN; unless due to Gilbert's disease, hemolysis, or lymphomatous&#xD;
             involvement of liver, in which case AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) should be =&lt; 5 x institutional&#xD;
             ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt;= 30 mL/min/1.73 m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected patients on effective anti-retroviral&#xD;
             therapy with undetectable viral load within 6 months are eligible for this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients with evidence of chronic hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection, the HBV viral&#xD;
             load must be undetectable on suppressive therapy, if indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection must have been treated&#xD;
             and cured. For patients with HCV infection who are currently on treatment, they are&#xD;
             eligible if they have an undetectable HCV viral load&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with treated brain metastases are eligible if follow-up brain imaging after&#xD;
             central nervous system (CNS)-directed therapy shows no evidence of progression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a prior or concurrent malignancy whose natural history or treatment does&#xD;
             not have the potential to interfere with the safety or efficacy assessment of the&#xD;
             investigational regimen are eligible for this trial. Patients whose lymphoma has&#xD;
             transformed from a less aggressive histology remain eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be New York Heart Association Functional Classification of class II or&#xD;
             better&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a QT interval corrected by Fridericia's formula (QTcF) =&lt; 450 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to swallow and retain orally-administered medication and does not have any&#xD;
             clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities that may alter absorption, such&#xD;
             as malabsorption syndrome or major resection of the stomach or bowels&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effects of tazemetostat and belinostat on the developing human fetus are unknown.&#xD;
             For this reason, women of child-bearing potential must agree to use adequate&#xD;
             contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study&#xD;
             entry and for the duration of study participation and for 6 months after the last dose&#xD;
             of the study treatment. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant&#xD;
             while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should inform her&#xD;
             treating physician immediately. Men treated or enrolled on this protocol must also&#xD;
             agree to use adequate contraception prior to the study, for the duration of study&#xD;
             participation, and 3 months after completion of tazemetostat and belinostat&#xD;
             administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
             Participants with impaired decision-making capacity who have a legally-authorized&#xD;
             representative (LAR) and/or family member available will also be eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that have received prior chemotherapy or radiotherapy must have completed&#xD;
             their last treatment at least 2 weeks before entering the study. Rituximab given&#xD;
             between EZH2 analysis and initiation of study drugs will be allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have not recovered from adverse events due to prior anti-cancer therapy&#xD;
             (i.e., have residual toxicities &gt; grade 1) with the exception of alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with central nervous system (CNS) metastases, including lymphomatous&#xD;
             meningitis, as the study drugs are not known to effectively treat CNS disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to belinostat or tazemetostat, or to&#xD;
             compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to these agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving any medications or substances that are strong or moderate&#xD;
             inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4 within 14 days prior to study treatment are&#xD;
             ineligible. Patients receiving strong UGT1A1 inhibitors are ineligible due to expected&#xD;
             increased exposure to belinostat and potential for increased toxicity. Because the&#xD;
             list of these agents is constantly changing, it is important to regularly consult a&#xD;
             frequently-updated medical reference. As part of the enrollment/informed consent&#xD;
             procedures, the patient will be counseled on the risk of interactions with other&#xD;
             agents, and what to do if new medications need to be prescribed or if the patient is&#xD;
             considering a new over-the-counter medicine or herbal product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known UGT1A1 genetic polymorphisms, such as UGT1A1*28, are excluded as&#xD;
             they can have reduced UGTA1A activity and may be at risk for increased belinostat&#xD;
             exposure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study because belinostat, as an HDAC inhibitor,&#xD;
             and tazemetostat, as an EZH2 inhibitor, both have the potential for teratogenic or&#xD;
             abortifacient effects. Because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse&#xD;
             events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the mother with belinostat and&#xD;
             tazemetostat, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated with&#xD;
             belinostat and tazemetostat. Women of childbearing potential must have negative urine&#xD;
             or serum pregnancy test to be eligible for this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic steroids that have not been stabilized to the equivalent of =&lt; 10 mg/day&#xD;
             prednisone prior to the start of the study drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has thrombocytopenia, neutropenia, or anemia of grade &gt;= 3 (per Common Terminology&#xD;
             Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] 5.0 criteria) or any prior history of myeloid&#xD;
             malignancies, including myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has abnormalities known to be associated with MDS (e.g. 5q deletion [del 5q],&#xD;
             chromosome 7 abnormality [chr 7 abn]) and multiple primary neoplasms (MPN) (e.g. JAK2&#xD;
             V617F) observed in cytogenetic testing and deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) sequencing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a prior history of T lymphoblastic lymphoma/T acute lymphoblastic leukemia&#xD;
             (T-LBL/T-ALL)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer E Amengual</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University Cancer Center LAO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Clinical Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairway</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>913-588-3671</phone>
      <email>KUCC_Navigation@kumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aung M. Tun</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66160</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>913-588-3671</phone>
      <email>KUCC_Navigation@kumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aung M. Tun</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Hospital-Westwood Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Westwood</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>913-588-3671</phone>
      <email>KUCC_Navigation@kumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aung M. Tun</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NYP/Columbia University Medical Center/Herbert Irving Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>212-305-6361</phone>
      <email>nr2616@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jennifer E. Amengual</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Public Contact</last_name>
      <phone>405-271-8777</phone>
      <email>ou-clinical-trials@ouhsc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sami Ibrahimi</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 26, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 26, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Belinostat</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>NCI is committed to sharing data in accordance with NIH policy. For more details on how clinical trial data is shared, access the link to the NIH data sharing policy page</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://grants.nih.gov/policy/sharing.htm</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

