<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05616000</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KMU/IBMS/2022/59</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05616000</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Acetyl- L- Carnitine&amp; Folic Acid Versus Coenzyme Q10&amp; Folic Acid on Semen&amp; Hormonal Parameters&amp; Semen Oxidative Status in Patients of Primary Infertility. A Double Blind Randomized Clinical Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of Acetyl- L- Carnitine and Folic Acid Versus Coenzyme Q10 and Folic Acid on Semen and Hormonal Parameters and Semen Oxidative Status in Patients of Primary Infertility. A Double Blind Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Khyber Medical University Peshawar</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Khyber Medical University Peshawar</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators aim is to conduct a double blind randomized clinical trial, to study the&#xD;
      effects of Acetyl-L-Carnitine and folic acid versus Coenzyme Q10 and folic acid on Semen and&#xD;
      hormonal parameters and semen oxidative stress in patients of Primary infertility. Males&#xD;
      diagnosed with Primary Infertility are recruited in the study after fulfilling the inclusion&#xD;
      nd exclusion criteria. The investigators propose that Primary infertile men may have altered&#xD;
      seminal oxidative status &amp; the combinational therapy may achieve favorable seminal ,&#xD;
      hormonal&amp; antioxidant levels in men having Primary infertility.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Historically, male infertility was considered a taboo subject and its role was deliberately&#xD;
      kept in dark until recently when with advances in medical science, the issue was highlighted&#xD;
      and its role came into limelight in couple's infertility. Male infertility is mainly caused&#xD;
      by oxidative stress. O2- (superoxide anion), OH- (hydroxyl ions), H2O2 (hydrogen peroxide),&#xD;
      nitric oxide &amp; ROO- (peroxyl) radicals are all oxygen derived highly reactive oxygen species&#xD;
      with a free unpaired electron in their outer orbit making them short lived, highly reactive &amp;&#xD;
      unstable. They are produced by the sperms &amp; their normal level help in the sperm maturation,&#xD;
      motility, capacitation &amp; facilitation of fertilization. Sperms are at risk of the damage&#xD;
      caused by overproduction of these ions. Several factors have been implicated in the&#xD;
      overproduction of these reactive oxygen species which include men with testicular&#xD;
      hyperthermia (varicocoele, cooks, and drivers) &amp; overproduction by immature sperms &amp;&#xD;
      leucocytes. Their overproduction cause damage to the DNA and peroxidation of the lipid&#xD;
      membrane leading to detrimental effects on sperms causing infertility There has been no&#xD;
      consensus on treatment of male infertility in literature. No standardized treatment is&#xD;
      suggested and different treatment combinations are currently been used to manage male&#xD;
      infertility. The role of CoQ10 &amp; Acetyl- L-Carnitine is explored recently in the different&#xD;
      studies with no consensus on their dosage, duration of treatment &amp; their effect on serum&#xD;
      testosterone. This study is conducted to find out the role of Acetyl- L-Carnitine and Co&#xD;
      enzyme Q 10 in combination with folic acid and their effect on semen parameters, semen&#xD;
      oxidative stress &amp; serum testosterone level in treating primary infertile men.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To find the effects of Acetyl-l-Carnitine and folic acid versus Coenzyme Q10 and&#xD;
      folic acid therapy on sperm parameters, seminal oxidative status &amp; serum testosterone level&#xD;
      in primary infertility male patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 6, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 29, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in semen analysis before&amp; after the administration of antioxidants&amp; folic acid.</measure>
    <time_frame>it will be done at the start of the trial and then after 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis of the patients will be done and sperm count million/ml, motility, grading of motility(grade from 0 to 4), volumein ml will be analyzed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in seminal oxidative status before&amp; after the administration of antioxidants&amp; folic acid.</measure>
    <time_frame>it will be done at the start of the trial and then after 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>seminal plasma of the primary infertile men will be analyzed for total antioxidant capacity(TAC)&amp; superoxide dismustase levels through commercially available Elisa kits.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in serum testosterone in nanograms/dl before&amp; after the administration of antioxidants&amp; folic acid.</measure>
    <time_frame>it will be done at the start of the trial and then after 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>serum testosterone levels of the patients will be analyzed through commercially available Elisa kits</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">86</enrollment>
  <condition>Infertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acetyl-L-Carnitine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acetyl-L-Carnitine (2gm once a day), folic acid 5mg (once a day) 43 Patients with Primary Infertility will receive Acetyl-L-Carnitine (2gm once a day) orally&amp; folic acid 5mg orally was given to all the participants of this group (once a day).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Coenzyme Q10 (400mg once a day) orally was given to all participants&amp; folic acid 5mg (once a day) was also given orally to these participants 43 Patients with Primary Infertility will receive Coenzyme Q10 (400mg once a day), folic acid 5mg (once a day).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acetyl-l-carnitine, folic acid</intervention_name>
    <description>Acetyl-l-carnitine 2gm once a day&amp; folic acid will be given to 43 primary infertile men</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acetyl-L-Carnitine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Treatment naïve primary male infertile patients with Oligospermia, Asthenozoospermia ,&#xD;
             Teratozoospermia &amp; Necrozoospermia&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged between 20 - 45 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Married for more than a year with regular intercourse minimum 3/week.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Normal female partner with normal menstrual cycle&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Azoospermic patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with varicocoele&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Erectile dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Secondary infertility&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients already taking treatment for primary infertility&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mohsin Shah, PhD</name>
      <address>
        <city>Peshawar</city>
        <state>Khyber Pakhtunkha</state>
        <zip>25120</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wischmann T, Thorn P. (Male) infertility: what does it mean to men? New evidence from quantitative and qualitative studies. Reprod Biomed Online. 2013 Sep;27(3):236-43. doi: 10.1016/j.rbmo.2013.06.002. Epub 2013 Jun 19.</citation>
    <PMID>23876974</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zegers-Hochschild F, Adamson GD, de Mouzon J, Ishihara O, Mansour R, Nygren K, Sullivan E, van der Poel S; International Committee for Monitoring Assisted Reproductive Technology; World Health Organization. The International Committee for Monitoring Assisted Reproductive Technology (ICMART) and the World Health Organization (WHO) Revised Glossary on ART Terminology, 2009. Hum Reprod. 2009 Nov;24(11):2683-7. doi: 10.1093/humrep/dep343. Epub 2009 Oct 4.</citation>
    <PMID>19801627</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jarow JP, Sharlip ID, Belker AM, Lipshultz LI, Sigman M, Thomas AJ, Schlegel PN, Howards SS, Nehra A, Damewood MD, Overstreet JW, Sadovsky R; Male Infertility Best Practice Policy Committee of the American Urological Association Inc. Best practice policies for male infertility. J Urol. 2002 May;167(5):2138-44. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>11956464</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agarwal A, Mulgund A, Hamada A, Chyatte MR. A unique view on male infertility around the globe. Reprod Biol Endocrinol. 2015 Apr 26;13:37. doi: 10.1186/s12958-015-0032-1.</citation>
    <PMID>25928197</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agarwal A, Saleh RA, Bedaiwy MA. Role of reactive oxygen species in the pathophysiology of human reproduction. Fertil Steril. 2003 Apr;79(4):829-43. doi: 10.1016/s0015-0282(02)04948-8.</citation>
    <PMID>12749418</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shi JZ, Zhang SS, Zhang Z, Liang Q, Shi Y, Hua JL, Sun T. [Expressions of sperm-specific genes in carnitine-cultured testis sperm of obstructive azoospermia patients]. Zhonghua Nan Ke Xue. 2010 Jun;16(6):504-9. Chinese.</citation>
    <PMID>20608353</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Banihani S, Agarwal A, Sharma R, Bayachou M. Cryoprotective effect of L-carnitine on motility, vitality and DNA oxidation of human spermatozoa. Andrologia. 2014 Aug;46(6):637-41. doi: 10.1111/and.12130. Epub 2013 Jul 3.</citation>
    <PMID>23822772</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahmed SD, Karira KA, Jagdesh, Ahsan S. Role of L-carnitine in male infertility. J Pak Med Assoc. 2011 Aug;61(8):732-6.</citation>
    <PMID>22355991</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 29, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 29, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Khyber Medical University Peshawar</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mohsin Shah</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Infertility, Acetyl-L-Carnitine, Coenzyme Q10</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acetylcarnitine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

