<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796362</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022p000272</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796362</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Single-Dose, Three-Way, Three-Sequence, Crossover BA Study of Azithromycin Oleogel</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Balanced, Single Dose, Three-treatment, Three-period, Crossover Bioavailability Study of Azithromycin Oleogel in Healthy, Adult, Human Subjects Under Fasting Condition.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham and Women's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an exploratory study to describe the pharmacokinetics of the azithromycin oral and&#xD;
      rectal oleogel in humans compared to the reference oral drug to (Zithromax) assess the impact&#xD;
      of the novel formulation on bioavailability. The investigators will perform a randomized,&#xD;
      balanced, single dose, three-treatment, three-period, crossover oral bioavailability study&#xD;
      under fasted conditions to evaluate the safety and tolerability of azithromycin oleogel and&#xD;
      compare the bioavailability of the azithromycin oleogel to the reference drug.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Children have difficulties swallowing tablets including azithromycin (AZT) tablets. In low&#xD;
      socioeconomic countries, tablets are typically crushed, dispersed in water, and administered&#xD;
      as a suspension to the child. This practice introduces several points of failure, including&#xD;
      unpalatability leading to refusal of the drug and lack of clean water for resuspension. Thus,&#xD;
      there remains a critical need to develop dosage forms that do not require crushing and&#xD;
      suspension. The investigators have developed a formulation inspired by techniques recently&#xD;
      described in the field of molecular gastronomy that transform oils into gels, also known as&#xD;
      &quot;oleogels&quot;. Oils have a prolonged history of use in the food industry, and a very&#xD;
      well-established safety profile. Plant-derived oils represent an attractive vehicle for drug&#xD;
      delivery. Many drugs have hydrophobic properties and therefore have a greater wettability and&#xD;
      solubility in oil in comparison to water. Ingestion of fats stimulates secretion of bile&#xD;
      salts and enzymes that enhance drug dissolution in the physiological fluids and drug&#xD;
      absorption. Furthermore, converting oils into gels allows for altering the mouth-feel and&#xD;
      texture of the dosage form, which affects patient acceptance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this exploratory study is to determine azithromycin bioavailability of oral and&#xD;
      rectal oleogels in healthy volunteers as well as to make an initial safety evaluation of the&#xD;
      oleogels. The reference azithromycin tablet has a bioavailability of 38%, with an AUC of 4.3&#xD;
      mcg*hr/ml, Cmax 0.5 mcg/ml, and Tmax of 2.2 hours. The half-life is approximately 68 hours.&#xD;
      The safety profile of azithromycin has been well characterized and single doses of&#xD;
      azithromycin are well tolerated, with common reactions including diarrhea/loose stools,&#xD;
      nausea, abdominal pain, vomiting, dyspepsia, and vaginitis (all less than 10% of subjects in&#xD;
      studies).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intersubject variability of the pharmacokinetics (PK) parameter estimates for the&#xD;
      azithromycin oleogel are derived from our preclinical studies of the azithromycin oleogel in&#xD;
      swine; the coefficient of variation for both the oral tablets, oral oleogels, and rectal&#xD;
      oleogels are between 30-40%. These estimates of intersubject variability informed our number&#xD;
      of subjects, (N=21), for this crossover study. Additional coefficient of variability&#xD;
      estimates for oral tablets were found in the literature and were approximately 30%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Azithromycin is not approved for rectal administration. However, our own studies of the&#xD;
      rectal azithromycin oleogel in female Yorkshire swine at doses of 5 mg/kg (40-70 kg weight&#xD;
      range) found the following pharmacokinetic parameters: Cmax= 0.224 mcg/ml (CV 35%, n=4); AUC&#xD;
      1.680 mcg*h/ml (CV 30%, n=4). The animals were treated with azithromycin oleogel rectally.&#xD;
      After 24 h, tissue mucosal biopsies were collected from the rectum endoscopically under&#xD;
      anesthesia. Samples were fixed and stained with Hematoxylin and Eosin and analyzed by a&#xD;
      clinical pathologist. Overall, there was no evidence of activity, chronicity, or rectal&#xD;
      tissue toxicity in the colorectal mucosa of the rectum in our preclinical swine models,&#xD;
      either by gross observation or histologic examination (Table 2). This is in keeping with two&#xD;
      exploratory clinical trials of an azithromycin suppository, which did not report any&#xD;
      clinically observed or patient-reported safety concerns besides diarrhea at doses of&#xD;
      125-500mg or 1g of azithromycin suppository.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an exploratory study to describe the pharmacokinetics of the azithromycin oral and&#xD;
      rectal oleogel in humans compared to the reference oral drug to assess the impact of the&#xD;
      novel formulation on bioavailability. The investigators will perform a randomized, balanced,&#xD;
      single dose, three-treatment, three-period, crossover oral bioavailability study under fasted&#xD;
      conditions to evaluate the safety and tolerability of azithromycin oleogel and compare the&#xD;
      bioavailability of the azithromycin oleogel to the reference drug. The cross-over design will&#xD;
      minimize intersubject variability. Given azithromycin's coefficient of variability, which is&#xD;
      estimated to be 30% in humans for the reference drug and 30-40% for the oleogel in swine&#xD;
      experiments, the investigators estimate that 21 subjects will be sufficient. This number also&#xD;
      accounts for any potential subject dropouts. Due to the half-life of azithromycin being 68&#xD;
      hours, the investigators will give 17 days between drug administrations to allow for&#xD;
      sufficient wash-out of at least 5 half-lives of azithromycin. Subjects in the study will be&#xD;
      closely monitored for any signs of adverse reactions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be given 250mg of azithromycin in each formulation. The maximum recommended&#xD;
      dose of azithromycin in humans is 2g in the oral formulation (bioavailability = 38%;&#xD;
      effective dose = ~760 mg) or 500mg in the IV formulation. The maximum dose administered to&#xD;
      humans is 4g intravenously with the following pharmacokinetic measurements: Cmax 9.91 mcg/ml,&#xD;
      AUC 82 mcg*h/ml. At this high dose, side effects seen were most commonly nausea, vomiting,&#xD;
      and tinnitus which were mild. In subjects administered 2g intravenous azithromycin, 4 out of&#xD;
      6 developed neutropenia; however, this was not seen at 4g. Based on our non-clinical data in&#xD;
      swine with a dosage of 5 mg/kg and a weight range of 40-70 kg, the equivalent human dose&#xD;
      would be 4.06-4.89 mg/kg (approximately 305-367 mg for a 75 kg person). The maximum&#xD;
      azithromycin a subject would absorb is 250 mg, which is still lower than the 2g dose with 38%&#xD;
      bioavailability (~760mg).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be screened for up to 28 days prior to first dose. Treatment Period 1 begins&#xD;
      with baseline when subjects are admitted to the study center the night before for a 10-hour&#xD;
      overnight fast prior to the first dose. After admission, subjects will undergo pre-study&#xD;
      evaluations. The subjects will be assigned a subject number before the first study-specific&#xD;
      procedure during baseline (e.g., blood sample). A randomization number will be assigned just&#xD;
      prior to dosing, after baseline evaluation results have established their continued study&#xD;
      eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a 10-hour overnight fast, subject will receive a single dose of rectal oleogel test [X]&#xD;
      (250mg drug in about 15 ml of oleogel) with continued fast, oral oleogel test [T] (250mg drug&#xD;
      in about 15 ml of oleogel), or oral reference tablet [R] with 240 mL of water. For four hours&#xD;
      thereafter, subjects should remain in the fasting state and seated in the upright or&#xD;
      semi-recumbent position. Brief periods of ambulation are allowed for study-related activities&#xD;
      and use of the toilet. Blood samples will be obtained predose and over the next 72 hours.&#xD;
      Water will be permitted ad libitum except for one hour before and one hour after dosing.&#xD;
      Subjects will be served standardized meals according to a predefined schedule throughout the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After approximately a 17-day period away from the study, subjects will return to the study&#xD;
      site for Treatment Period 2 and undergo assessments and blood collection similar to Treatment&#xD;
      Period 1. The treatment administered will be defined in the randomization schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After approximately a 17-day period away from the study, subjects will return to the study&#xD;
      site for Treatment Period 3 and undergo assessments and blood collection similar to Treatment&#xD;
      Periods 1 and 2. The treatment administered will be defined in the randomization schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The end-of-study (EOS) evaluation will be performed after completion of the final PK sample&#xD;
      following Treatment Period 3 or up to 7 days thereafter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized, balanced, single dose, three-treatment, three-period, crossover bioavailability study of azithromycin oleogel in healthy, adult, human subjects under fasting condition.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Azithromycin bioavailability via pharmacokinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Up tp 6 weeks (12 days on study total)</time_frame>
    <description>Azithromycin bioavailability of oral and rectal oleogels in healthy volunteers as measured by drug concentrations serum of study participants compared to reference standard bioavailability</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Initial Azithromycin Oleogel Safety Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up tp 6 weeks (12 days on study total)</time_frame>
    <description>Initial safety of azithromycin oral and rectal oleogels in healthy volunteers measured by self reported symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Infectious Disease</condition>
  <condition>Drug Effect</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reference Azithromycin Tablet (Zithromax)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>250 mg azithromycin (Zithromax) tablet to be taken once orally.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral Oleogel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>250 mg azithromycin/ 15 ml oral oleogel (16.67 mg/ml) to be dosed once orally.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rectal Oleogel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>250 mg azithromycin/ 15 ml rectal oleogel (16.67 mg/ml) to be dosed once rectally.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azithromycin Oleogel (Oral and Rectal)</intervention_name>
    <description>Exploratory study of a novel &quot;oleogel&quot; dosage form of Azithromycin (Zithromax)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oral Oleogel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Rectal Oleogel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Reference Azithromycin Tablet (Zithromax)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal, healthy, adult subjects, 18 to 45 years of age, weight of 45 to 70 kg, and&#xD;
             body mass index (BMI) between 18.5 to 26.0 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal hematological, hepatic and renal function as defined by the testing&#xD;
             laboratory's normal ranges, and the inclusion of healthy subjects with out-of-range&#xD;
             values that fall within a certain range that have no clinical significance for healthy&#xD;
             volunteer expansion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to use two forms of contraceptive measures or abstinence for the entire&#xD;
             duration of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in an investigational drug or device study within 30 days prior to study&#xD;
             drug dosing, i.e., there must be at least 30 days in between the last dose on a prior&#xD;
             study and dose administration on this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of tobacco products within the past one year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant disease or condition, including laboratory abnormality, which may&#xD;
             interfere with the conduct of the study, or which would, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, pose an unacceptable risk to the subject in this study, including, but&#xD;
             not limited to coronary heart disease, diabetes, and adrenal-cortical insufficiency,&#xD;
             cancer, alcohol dependency or abuse, drug dependency or abuse, or psychiatric disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or past medical condition that might significantly affect the pharmacokinetics&#xD;
             of azithromycin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to azithromycin, erythromycin, any macrolide or ketolide drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have history of cholestatic jaundice/hepatic dysfunction associated with prior use of&#xD;
             azithromycin.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carlo Giovanni Traverso, MB BChir PhD</last_name>
    <phone>617-732-7429</phone>
    <email>ctraverso@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Peter Chai, MD MMS</last_name>
    <phone>617-732-5640</phone>
    <email>pchai@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>C. Giovanni Traverso MB Bchir PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Azithromycin</keyword>
  <keyword>Oleogel</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Azithromycin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

