<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05620082</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RHM MED1921</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05620082</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The RELISH Study: Compliance and Palatability of Oral Nutritional Supplements in Hospitalised Older Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>The RELISH Study: A Prospective Observational Study to Assess Compliance and Palatability of foRtifiEd Porridge Compared to Standard LIquid-baSed Oral Nutritional Supplementation in Hospitalised Older Adults With Malnutrition</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The RELISH study will investigate a new oral nutritional supplement (fortified porridge) for&#xD;
      older adults in hospital who are undernourished (i.e., have malnutrition). Malnutrition is a&#xD;
      lack of nutritional intake that can lead to poor recovery from illness, increasing hospital&#xD;
      length of stay, and elevating healthcare costs. 22% of hospitalised older adults are&#xD;
      estimated to have malnutrition. Oral nutritional supplementation (ONS) is key in the&#xD;
      management of malnutrition. ONS are energy and nutrient dense products designed to increase&#xD;
      dietary intake when diet alone is insufficient to meet daily nutritional requirements.&#xD;
      However, for the ONS to be effective they need to be palatable (i.e., taste good), so that&#xD;
      patients consume them (i.e., have good compliance) to reap the benefits of extra calories and&#xD;
      protein. Normally, hospital patients are offered liquid based ONS (sip feeds). However,&#xD;
      previous research has pinpointed that 56% of older adults on geriatric wards did not like sip&#xD;
      feeds. Hence, exploration of compliance to different ONS formats is an important research&#xD;
      direction to maximise malnourished older adult's nutritional intake. Therefore, the current&#xD;
      study aimed to investigate the compliance and palatability of novel fortified porridge&#xD;
      compared to traditional sip-feeds in malnourished older adults in hospital.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      22% of hospitalised older adults are estimated to be in a state of malnutrition.&#xD;
      Malnutrition, also known as undernutrition, is a lack of nutritional intake leading to&#xD;
      decreased fat free mass and diminished physiological functioning. Malnutrition impairs&#xD;
      patient recovery, increasing hospital length of stay and escalating healthcare costs.&#xD;
      Therefore, the identification and management of malnutrition is a vital patient-centred&#xD;
      outcome to enhance older adult's health and quality of life and to enable cost-effective&#xD;
      treatment and care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A key method to support individualised nutritional care of hospital in-patients is the use of&#xD;
      oral nutritional supplementation (ONS). ONS are energy and nutrient dense products designed&#xD;
      to increase dietary intake when diet alone is insufficient to meet daily nutritional&#xD;
      requirements. Overall, research suggests favourable impacts of ONS on nutritional status and&#xD;
      healthcare costs, while the impact on functional outcomes and mortality are more&#xD;
      controversial. A burgeoning evidence base attests to the importance of considering&#xD;
      acceptability and compliance of ONS on adequate intake and thus effectiveness of ONS in&#xD;
      practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient compliance to ONS considers the relationship between the amount of ONS prescribed and&#xD;
      the amount of ONS ingested and is important to maximise clinical and cost-effectiveness.&#xD;
      Palatability refers to the hedonic (i.e., pleasantness) evaluation of sensory factors, such&#xD;
      as taste and smell, leading to alterations in food or fluid consumption. Supplemental&#xD;
      preference may be affected by a multitude of factors such as taste, colour, smell, after&#xD;
      taste and texture. Typically, hospital patients are offered liquid based ONS (sip feeds).&#xD;
      However, previous research has pinpointed that 56% of older adults on geriatric wards did not&#xD;
      like sip feeds. Hence, exploration of compliance to different ONS formats is an important&#xD;
      research direction to maximise malnourished older adult's nutritional intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnourished hospitalised older adults should be offered an improved range and provision of&#xD;
      ONS to suit patient preferences and maximise intake. For instance, an attractive alternative&#xD;
      strategy is the use of energy and protein-dense meals (via fortification) or snacks&#xD;
      (supplementation), including fortified bread, protein-enriched main meals and between meal&#xD;
      snacks, such as biscuits, yoghurt and ice cream. Yet this is an understudied area, with&#xD;
      limited data investigating compliance to alternative ONS products compared to ready-made&#xD;
      drinks in hospital, such as powdered ONS and snacks, or their clinical effectiveness.&#xD;
      Therefore, the current study aimed to investigate the compliance and palatability of novel&#xD;
      fortified porridge compared to traditional sip-feeds in malnourished hospitalised older&#xD;
      adults.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research questions include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What are the compliance rates (% intake) of fortified porridge compared to standard&#xD;
           liquid based ONS in malnourished hospitalised older adults?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What are the palatability ratings (e.g., taste) of fortified porridge compared to&#xD;
           standard liquid based ONS in malnourished hospitalised older adults?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. What is the acceptability of fortified porridge compared to standard liquid based ONS in&#xD;
           malnourished hospitalised older adults, including facilitators and barriers to their use&#xD;
           on medical wards?&#xD;
&#xD;
      A mixed methods randomised controlled crossover design will be conducted to determine&#xD;
      compliance and palatability of fortified porridge in malnourished hospitalised older adults&#xD;
      compared to a liquid-based control ONS. The acceptability of products will be assessed&#xD;
      through qualitative interviews to explore patients and healthcare professionals' experiences&#xD;
      and views of using the nutritional supplements. Participants will be prescribed ONS twice per&#xD;
      day for 4 days, in addition to normal meals, in a crossover design. The products will be&#xD;
      offered in-between breakfast and lunch, and after dinner to reduce the detrimental long&#xD;
      period of calorie absence experienced overnight.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of the mean oral nutritional supplement consumed per day (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured daily during the 4 day testing period</time_frame>
    <description>Compliance to oral nutritional supplementation. Leftovers will be weighed (g) using weighing scales (Seca Model 875 digital weighing scale).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Palatability of oral nutritional supplement</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Palatability ratings, including appearance, smell, taste, sweetness, texture, thickness, aftertaste, mouth feel, and overall likability will be assessed with a 7-point hedonic Likert scale (7 = definitely like, 6 = moderately like, 5 = mildly like, 4 = neither like nor dislike, 3 = mildly dislike, 2 = moderately dislike, 1 = definitely dislike).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total caloric intake (kcal)</measure>
    <time_frame>Completed daily during the 4 day testing period.</time_frame>
    <description>total energy intake will be assessed through completion of patient food charts, including estimated proportion of meals consumed. Food charts are a part of patients' standard care and will be completed by the nursing team.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of ONS products will be explored with semi-structured interviews</measure>
    <time_frame>Patients will be interviewed following completion of 4 days of oral nutritional supplementation testing.</time_frame>
    <description>The interviews will seek to explore the views of hospitalised older adults and healthcare professionals working on geriatric medical wards, exploring the acceptability of the ONS products.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Malnutrition</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Malnourished older adults in hospital</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants will be given oral nutritional supplementation twice per day for 4 days, in addition to normal meals, in a crossover design. The products will be offered in-between breakfast and lunch, and after dinner. Products will include traditional sip-feeds (an anonymous ready-made drink supplement, 125g, 306kcal, 18.3g protein) and a new fortified porridge (Adams Vital Nutrition Ltd. High Protein Oats, 157g, 230kcal, 15g protein).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard liquid-based oral nutritional supplement</intervention_name>
    <description>An anonymous ready-made drink supplement: 125g, 306kcal, 18.3g protein.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Malnourished older adults in hospital</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fortified porridge</intervention_name>
    <description>Vital Daily High Protein Oats (Adams Vital Nutrition Ltd.): 157g, 230kcal, 15g protein.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Malnourished older adults in hospital</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Hospitalised older adults with malnutrition.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Older adults ≥65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on University Hospital Southampton (UHS) acute medical wards&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medium-high risk of malnutrition (MUST score 1-4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that have used ONS in previous month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving enteral or parental nutrition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a MUST score &gt;4 (severely malnourished)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a BMI ≤15&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic liver disease, renal failure, dysphagia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had major surgery within the preceding month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a terminal illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving end of life care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to eat by mouth (Nil By Mouth [NBM])&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who require alternative ONS as advised by dietetic support&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samantha J Meredith, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Southampton</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Samantha J Meredith, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+442381206131</phone>
    <email>s.j.meredith@soton.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stephen ER Lim, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+442381206131</phone>
    <email>s.e.lim@soton.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 1, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Malnutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral nutritional supplementation</keyword>
  <keyword>Compliance</keyword>
  <keyword>Palatability</keyword>
  <keyword>Older adult</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

