<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05610228</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>22Laboimmuno01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05610228</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of the Metabolism in the Lymphatic Niche of CLL</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study of the Metabolic Reprogramming of CLL Cells in Ex-vivo Models of the Lymphatic Niche</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic lymphoid leukemia (CLL) is the most common adult leukemia that is characterized by a&#xD;
      malignant monoclonal accumulation of tumoral and quiescent B cells in the peripheral blood.&#xD;
      In advanced stages of the disease (Binet stage C), this population invades the bone marrow&#xD;
      (BM) and proliferate into the lymphoid organs that results in widespread adenopathy.&#xD;
      Richter's transformation is a most aggressive serious complication of CLL (transformation of&#xD;
      the disease into an aggressive lymphoma) detected based on TEP/CT (Positron Emission&#xD;
      Tomography/ computerized tomography) that shows highly derived glucose consumption by cancer&#xD;
      cells. Clinical data from CLL patients with disease acutisation showed hypermetabolic&#xD;
      lymphadenopathy with high standardized uptake value (SUV) whereas there is low grade tracer&#xD;
      uptake into BM. We supposed that the tumor microenvironment of the lymphatic niche promotes&#xD;
      the proliferation and glycolytic activity of CLL cells which become particularly resistant to&#xD;
      treatment. The development of an ex-vivo tumor model that reproduces the microenvironment of&#xD;
      the lymph node niche appears essential to identify and validate new therapeutic targets&#xD;
      because despite the therapeutic arsenal available some patients still relapse or are&#xD;
      refractory to treatment. Our objectives are to i / Characterize this niche of resistance by&#xD;
      the development of an ex-vivo tumor model and ii / Evaluate in-vitro the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      association of current treatments (RFC, Ibrutinib or Venetoclax) with anti-metabolic&#xD;
      therapies (inhibitors of glycolysis) Our lab is developing an ex-vivo models of the lymphatic&#xD;
      niche in CLL based on co-cultures of leukemic cells from patients stimulated with CpG ODN and&#xD;
      IL2 with primary human lymphatic fibroblasts (HLF) (EC 12PP15). This co-culture has never&#xD;
      been described in the literature and allows us to study the lymphatic niche of CLL patients.&#xD;
      Lymph node (LN) exploration in CLL requires invasive access and does not bring any additional&#xD;
      information in initial diagnosis. Then, we validated our co-culture model using complementary&#xD;
      approaches: increased viability, proliferation, and resistance to Ibrutinib, associated with&#xD;
      increased production of anti-apoptotic proteins such as MCL1 and BCL2 after 48 hours of&#xD;
      co-culture. Secondly, we studied the metabolism in this resistance niche. We find an&#xD;
      increased production of lactate and an acute consumption of glucose, associated with a strong&#xD;
      metabolic activation detected by SEAHORSE and by the production of glycolysis enzymes such as&#xD;
      hexokinase 2. Our study constitutes an original project because it characterized the energy&#xD;
      metabolism of the CLL lymphatic niche by developing an original ex-vivo model and enhanced&#xD;
      our understanding of the contribution of the specific microenvironment in the dissociation of&#xD;
      metabolic activity using SUV max in BM and lymphatic niche. Anti-metabolic therapies are&#xD;
      efficient on co-culture CLL cells and could be an alternative for refractory or relapsed&#xD;
      patients under current treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 7, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modelisation of a CLL lymphatic niche by creation of an ex-vivo model</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of viability and proliferation of CLL cells by annexin PI with multiparameter:&#xD;
flow cytometry device, western blot and validation of the model by testing current therapy (Ibrutinib, anti BTK inhibitor)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Study of metabolism in CLL ex-vivo model</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Anlayse of metabolism (ECAR and OCR) by seahorse methods , PCR qnd protein Multiparameter analyse</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate in-vitro the effectiveness of the combination of current treatments (RFC, Ibrutinib or Venetoclax) with anti-inflammatory therapies. -metabolic (glycolysis inhibitors)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Viability using multiparameter flow cytometry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>CLL</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LLC</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NO intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>LLC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      EDTA-anticoagulated whole blood&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        CLL patient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients for whom the diagnosis of CLL has been established cytologically and&#xD;
             phenotypically (Matutes score)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have signed the non-objection form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a solid cancer that is progressive or in remission for less than 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV positive patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic active hepatitis B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allogeneic transplant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Caroline Ruetsch-Chelli</last_name>
    <phone>33492039016</phone>
    <email>ruetsch-chelli.c@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marcel Deckert</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nice University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <zip>06000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Caroline Ruetsch-Chelli</last_name>
      <phone>0492039016</phone>
      <email>ruetsch-chelli.c@chu-nice.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Caroline ruetsch-Chelli</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

