<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05629936</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UMU-MTO-2022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05629936</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving Medication Therapy Through a Digital Interdisciplinary Model</brief_title>
  <acronym>MTO</acronym>
  <official_title>Improving Medication Therapy and Patient Involvement Through a Digital Interdisciplinary Model Among Old People in Primary Care Living in Sparsely Populated Regions in Sweden</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ume책 University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Region V채sterbotten</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ume책 University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study investigates if a digital interdisciplinary medicine therapy optimization (MTO)&#xD;
      model in primary care can improve medication therapy, quality of life and adherence among&#xD;
      patients &gt;65 years living in sparsley populated areas. The intervention includes digital&#xD;
      medication interviews, comprehensive medication reviews, team based patient discussions and&#xD;
      follow-ups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A pilot study to develop the MTO-model including 10-15 patients, will be carried out and&#xD;
      appropriate adjustments to the model will be made before starting the main study. Patients&#xD;
      meeting the inclusion criteria will be invited to participate in the study and sent three&#xD;
      questionnaires, MARS-5, EQ-5D-5L and BMQ-general, to fill in before starting the&#xD;
      intervention. Baseline in this digital intervention is a medication interview with a clinical&#xD;
      pharmacist. Based on the information from this interview, journal- and laboratory data, a&#xD;
      comprehensive medication review will be conducted and a preliminary proposal discussed in a&#xD;
      digital interdisciplinary meeting resulting in a final MTO-plan. The patients will be&#xD;
      informed by their physician if any medication changes have been made and follow-up meetings&#xD;
      with a pharmacist will take place 1-2,4 and 12 weeks after baseline and in addition of&#xD;
      requested by the patients or if the pharmacist consider it necessary. In addition to the&#xD;
      prescheduled meetings with the patient, the intervention includes repeated medical journal&#xD;
      reviews every second week during the 12-weeks intervention. After the last follow-up at 12&#xD;
      weeks, the patient will be asked to fill in the three questionnaires; MARS-5, EQ-5D-5L and&#xD;
      BMQ-general.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-reported health state: EuroQol-5 dimension-5 level questionnaire (EQ-5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in self-reported health state between baseline and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessing health-related quality of life through the EQ-5D-5L-questionnaire. EQ VAS score ranging between 0 and 100, with higher score indicating a higher overall self-rated health status.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-reported adherence: Medication Adherence Report Scale-5 (MARS-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in self-reported adherence between baseline and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessing medication adherence through MARS-5 questionnaire. Total score ranging between 5 and 25, with higher scores indicating a higher level of adherence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-reported beliefs about medicines in general: The Beliefs about Medicines Questionnaire - general (BMQ-general)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in self-reported beliefs about medicines between baseline and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessing beliefs about medicines in general through BMQ-general questionnaire. BMQ-general consists of three different subscales (overuse, harm and benefit) with a total score ranging between 4-20 for each subscale. In two of the subscales (overuse and harm) higher scores indicates a more negative orientation towards medicines in general and in the subscale benefit a higher score indicates a more positive orientation towards medicines.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Drug Use</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>digital intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Digital intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>digital interdisciplinary intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Digital medication interview, comprehensive medication review, interdisciplinary patient team discussion followed by a MTO-plan, follow-ups</description>
    <arm_group_label>digital intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  5 or more medications or recommended by their physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living at home (i.e not in nursing home)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Registered at one of seven specified primary care centers&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not speak Swedish or unable to communicate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Home care services&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed major NCD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scheduled for palliative care&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ume책 University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maria Gustafsson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
  <keyword>Medication reconciliation</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical pharmacist</keyword>
  <keyword>Elderly</keyword>
  <keyword>Adherence</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug-related problems</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

