<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05629169</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05629169</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Video Review of the Frequency and Assessment of Head Impacts During the FIFA World Cup 2022TM</brief_title>
  <official_title>Video Review of the Frequency and Assessment of Head Impacts During the FIFA World Cup 2022TM</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Federation Internationale de Football Association</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Major League Soccer</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Federation Internationale de Football Association</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an exploratory observational study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Broadcasted video footage is used to review all head impacts during all 64 matches in the&#xD;
      football tournament.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All head impacts are registered, and simple descriptive statistics are used to create&#xD;
      overviews of the head impact characteristics, including video signs of potential concussion,&#xD;
      observed contact, location of the head impact, presence and timing of medical assessment,&#xD;
      whether there was foul play and sanction, and if the player was substituted.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be performed at the FIFA World Cup 2022, a football tournament including 32&#xD;
      national men's senior football teams. The tournament includes 64 matches played in Qatar&#xD;
      between November 20th and December 18th, 2022.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recording of head impacts The investigators will use injury spotters and subsequent video&#xD;
      footage review to study head impacts. All matches will be attended by one of eight FIFA&#xD;
      injury spotters, who will register all head impacts on a standardized scoring form. All FIFA&#xD;
      injury spotters are qualified medical doctors with experience in football medicine and are&#xD;
      also FIFA Medical Coordinators in other matches at the same tournament. The injury spotters&#xD;
      are positioned on the tribune above the midline of the pitch with visibility of the entire&#xD;
      pitch. If the injury spotter observes a head impact, they can review video footage on a large&#xD;
      computer screen immediately to identify possible mechanism of injury and the presence of&#xD;
      video signs indicating a possible concussion. The injury spotter can select one or more&#xD;
      angles for review at the same time (up to four close views and four wide views) and rewind&#xD;
      and forward at different speeds, including frame-to-frame views.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A modification of a previous definition of a head impact was clarified to: &quot;a direct head&#xD;
      impact, or impact with indirect forces to the head, where a player is unable to immediately&#xD;
      resume play following impact or subsequently shows potential concussion-related symptoms.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
      Video signs The investigators adjusted the video signs used in previous FIFA tournaments,&#xD;
      which included the six internationally standardized video signs of potential sport-related&#xD;
      concussions (in bold). Further signs were added and grouped into yellow and red flag&#xD;
      categories.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a yellow flag is observed, the injury spotter informs the FIFA Medical coordinator with&#xD;
      details (including player team and number, mechanism of injury, and any video signs of&#xD;
      possible concussion), and they will contact the team doctor with the recommendations for&#xD;
      video review of the head impact and a clinical assessment. Further action will depend on the&#xD;
      clinical assessment findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a red flag is observed, the injury spotter informs the FIFA Medical coordinator with&#xD;
      details, and they will strongly recommend immediate player substitution regardless of&#xD;
      clinical assessment findings. The team doctor will be notified twice if the player is not&#xD;
      substituted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If no signs are observed, the FIFA medical coordinator is also notified. The team doctor is&#xD;
      not notified unless they request further information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The communication is recorded by the FIFA Medical Coordination/Injury spotter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Yellow flags:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lying motionless Lying without purposeful movement on the playing surface for &gt;2 seconds. The&#xD;
      player does not appear to move or react purposefully, respond or reply appropriately to the&#xD;
      game situation (including team-mates, opponents, match officials or medical staff).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blank/vacant look The player exhibits no facial expression or apparent emotion in response to&#xD;
      the environment. This may include a lack of focus/attention of vision.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Disorientation The player appears to be disoriented in their movements and facial&#xD;
      expressions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Slow go get up The player takes longer than normal to rise to both feet after falling to the&#xD;
      ground following a head impact.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dual-head impact mechanism Two-immediate head impacts, such as head to ground impact after&#xD;
      initial head-to-head impact.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Face or skull injury Any visible bleeding from the face or skull.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Red flags:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impact seizure/convulsion Involuntary clonic movements that comprise periods of asymmetric&#xD;
      and irregular rhythmic jerking of axial or limb muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tonic posturing Involuntary, sustained contraction of one or more limbs (typically upper&#xD;
      limbs), so that the limb is held stiff despite the influence of gravity or the position of&#xD;
      the player. Other muscles, such as the cervical, axial and lower-limb muscles, may also be&#xD;
      involved. Tonic posturing may be observed while the player is on the playing surface or in&#xD;
      the motion of falling, where the player may also demonstrate no protective action.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No protective action - Floppy The player falls to the playing surface in an unprotected&#xD;
      manner (i.e. without stretching out their hands or arms to lessen or minimise the fall) after&#xD;
      direct or indirect contact to the head. The player demonstrates loss of motor tone (which may&#xD;
      be observed in the limbs and/or neck*) before landing on the playing surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
      *When the player's arms are being held by a tackling opponent, this may only be observed in&#xD;
      the neck, which was previously known as &quot;cervical hypotonia&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Motor incoordination The player appears unsteady on their feet (including losing balance,&#xD;
      staggering/stumbling, struggling to get up or falling) or in the upper limbs (including&#xD;
      fumbling). May occur when the athlete is rising from the playing surface or in the motion of&#xD;
      walking/running.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Note: Should NOT be recorded if incoordination is considered related to an MSK injury (for&#xD;
      example an ankle injury).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vomiting Any immediate or delayed vomiting following head impact.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visible concussive symptoms following return to play. Any symptoms of a brain injury&#xD;
      following return to play after a head impact, such as confusion, impaired co-ordination,&#xD;
      kneeling while clutching head or calling for team doctor re-assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other signs:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concerning injury mechanism Obvious high head impact force, such as knee-to-head or&#xD;
      fist-to-head. Location of head impact and head impact force (low/medium/high) should be&#xD;
      recorded for all head impacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Uncontrolled emotional response Apparent exaggerated irritability/aggression either verbally&#xD;
      or physically or crying.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clutching of the head The player firmly presses or holds their head tightly immediately&#xD;
      following head impact (rubbing the head with the hands is not considered clutching).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional video review After the tournament, broadcast video footage of all matches will be&#xD;
      reviewed by an independent injury spotter, an athletic trainer with injury spotting training&#xD;
      through Major League Soccer (MLS), and 1-2 years of experience with live injury spotting in&#xD;
      MLS. The spotter will record all observed head impacts, mechanisms of injury, and identified&#xD;
      observable signs, which will then be compared to those recorded during live action matches.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Video footage of each head impact, including the same video angles, which the injury spotter&#xD;
      at the matches have access to, is then scored for video signs of concussion by three&#xD;
      independent injury spotters blinded to each other's scoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to review, these three injury spotters will perform inter-rater reliability testing of&#xD;
      their identification of video signs in 20 head impacts from a set of exemplar signs selected&#xD;
      from different competitions. A kappa value of minimum 0.8 will be required, and continuous&#xD;
      discussion and rescoring will be performed until this is achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For scoring of the included head impacts from the World Cup where there is not 100% agreement&#xD;
      (3 of 3), there will be a review by an expert group to determine a final scoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, a sample of 10% of the incidents with full agreement will be reviewed by the&#xD;
      expert group to ensure alignment on scoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The independent injury spotters will also record the head impact mechanism, location of the&#xD;
      impact, presence and timing of medical assessment, whether there was foul play and sanction,&#xD;
      and if the player was substituted, similar to a previous study.[9] Medical assessment is&#xD;
      defined as any apparent clinical examination, direct talk, or visual inspection while the&#xD;
      medical person is in close range of the player. Stoppage time is registered from when the&#xD;
      ball is out of play, or the game is halted by the referee, following the head impact until&#xD;
      the match is restarted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Official match reports will be checked to determine whether a concussion substitution was&#xD;
      used. The FIFA World Cup tournament follows protocol A of the IFAB additional permanent&#xD;
      concussion substitution trial, where each team is allowed to use one concussion substitute in&#xD;
      a match in addition to their normal substitutions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical diagnosis of a concussion will be recorded as part of the injury and illness&#xD;
      surveillance at the FIFA World Cup, and included in this study if players have provided&#xD;
      specific consent for this.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics Simple descriptive statistics is applied using IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows&#xD;
      (Version 27.0. Armonk, NY: IBM Corp) and results will be presented according to the&#xD;
      distribution of the data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size estimation No a priori sample size calculation is performed. All head impacts&#xD;
      will be included. Based on previous studies during football tournaments, we expect around&#xD;
      120-150 head impacts during the tournament, with up to half of these receiving on-pitch&#xD;
      assessment by team medical staff.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 20, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 18, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of head impacts</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>A head impact is defined as '&quot;a direct head impact, or impact with indirect forces to the head, where a player is unable to immediately resume play following impact or subsequently shows potential concussion-related symptoms.&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and type of video signs that indicate a potential concussion</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Video signs are grouped as yellow or red flags. Yellow flags: Lying motionless Blank/vacant look Disorientation Slow go get up Dual-head impact mechanism Face or skull injury&#xD;
Red flags Impact seizure/ convulsion Tonic posturing No protective action Floppy&#xD;
Motor incoordination Vomiting Visible concussive symptoms following return to play.&#xD;
Other signs:&#xD;
Concerning injury mechanism Uncontrolled emotional response Clutching of the head</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Head impact mechanism</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Direct or indirect contact is categorised according to contact involved.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Location of the impact</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>The area of skull impact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>presence and timing of medical assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Medical assessment is defined as any apparent clinical examination, direct talk, or visual inspection while the medical person is in close range of the player.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Foul play decisions</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Referee decisions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of substitution following head impact</measure>
    <time_frame>November-December 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Official match reports will be check substitutions and to determine whether a concussion substitution was used.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">832</enrollment>
  <condition>Head Injury</condition>
  <condition>Concussion</condition>
  <condition>Brain Injuries</condition>
  <condition>Traumatic Brain Injury</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention applied - observational study only</intervention_name>
    <description>Observational study only. All head impacts will be assessed using video footage.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022 includes 32 national teams, and each team is allowed to&#xD;
        select 26 players, giving at total of 832 potential participants. In total, 64 matches will&#xD;
        be played over 29 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All participating football players at the FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Major League Soccer</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10018</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Craniocerebral Trauma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will not be shared as it contains a high risk of exposing identifiable information.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

