<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05790213</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UCCC-GU-22-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05790213</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Focal Prostate Ablation With Androgen Deprivation and Novel Hormonal Therapy for Intermediate Risk Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Combination of Focal Prostate Ablation With Androgen Deprivation and Novel Hormonal Therapy for the Treatment of Intermediate Risk Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Cincinnati</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Janssen, LP</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cincinnati</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the proportion of men with residual/recurrent&#xD;
      clinically significant prostate cancer (Grade Group ≥2 disease) in the ablated or unablated&#xD;
      prostate tissue following the combination treatment of 6-months of androgen deprivation&#xD;
      therapy, apalutamide, and partial ablation of the prostate in men with newly diagnosed&#xD;
      non-metastatic intermediate risk prostate cancer; specifically, men with a histopathologic&#xD;
      diagnosis of Grade Group 2 &amp; 3, with prostate specific antigen level &lt;20 ng/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      And to assess the safety of the combination treatment of androgen deprivation therapy,&#xD;
      apalutamide, and partial ablation of the prostate for the management of these patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinically significant prostate cancer (GG ≥2) Proportion in ablated tissue measured by mpMRI and MRI-TB.</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months following FT</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of men with clinically significant prostate cancer (GG ≥2) in the ablated prostate tissue by performing a surveillance mpMRI and MRI-TB. GG stands for grade group, which is a way to describe prostate cancer. GG of ≥2 means intermediate (GG = 2 or 3) or high (GG = 4 or 5).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinically significant prostate cancer (GG ≥2) Proportion in unablated tissue measured by mpMRI and MRI-TB. GG stands for grade group, which is a way to describe prostate cancer. GG of ≥2 means intermediate (GG = 2 or 3) or high (GG = 4 or 5).</measure>
    <time_frame>6-months following FT</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of men with clinically significant prostate cancer (GG ≥2) in the unablated prostate tissue by performing a surveillance mpMRI and MRI-TB. GG stands for grade group, which is a way to describe prostate cancer. GG of ≥2 means intermediate (GG = 2 or 3) or high (GG = 4 or 5).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Adverse Events to measure Safety of combination treatment (measured by CTCAE v5)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months following FT</time_frame>
    <description>Demonstrate the safety of combining ADT, apalutamide, and FT for the treatment of men with histopathologic diagnosis of GG 2 &amp; 3 PCa, with PSA level &lt; 20 ng/mL utilizing the NCI's CTCAE v.5 classification to quantify and characterize the incidence of AEs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measuring change in genitourinary and sexual function and health-related quality of life (measured by HRQoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>6-and 12-months after FT</time_frame>
    <description>Define change in genitourinary and sexual function from baseline following ADT, apalutamide, and FT by measuring the subject's HRQoL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PSA response to the combination treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3-months, 6-months, and 1-year from FT</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the PSA response to the combination treatment by measuring the subject's PSA at &quot;baseline&quot; (PSA at time of initial diagnosis) 3-months, 6-months, and 1-year from FT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of men converting therapy or dying of prostate cancer during study</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after FT</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the proportion of men converting to whole gland therapy (radical prostatectomy or radiation therapy) and/or requiring systemic therapy and/or developing metastases and/or dying of PCa during the course of study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post Treatment biopsy with no prostate cancer</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after FT</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the proportion of men without any prostate cancer on any post treatment prostate biopsy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of men with normal baseline serum</measure>
    <time_frame>6-, 9- and 12-months after FT.</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the proportion of men with normal baseline serum testosterone who had testosterone recovery (defined as testosterone levels &gt;300 ng/dL) at 6-, 9- and 12-months after FT.&#xD;
Testosterone recovery: Number of men who have recovered normal serum testosterone levels will be expressed as proportions of total number of eugonadal patients and the 95% confidence interval of the proportion will be presented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">57</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Focal Prostate Ablation + Androgen Deprivation + Novel Hormonal Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A. Apalutamide 240 mg by mouth daily for a total of 6-months B. ADT therapy will consist of any generic luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone agonist which will provide either 6-months of treatment or two injections every 3-months. (e.g., one injection with a treatment period of 6 months or two injections, one at drug start and one 3-months later).&#xD;
C. Focal therapy to be completed within 8- to 12-weeks of the initiation of apalutamide but after the completion of the 8-week mpMRI to allow for it to be used in FT planning</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apalutamide Oral Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Apalutamide 240 mg by mouth daily for a total of 6-months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Focal Prostate Ablation + Androgen Deprivation + Novel Hormonal Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Androgen Deprivation Therapy (ADT)</intervention_name>
    <description>ADT therapy will consist of any generic luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone agonist which will provide either 6-months of treatment or two injections every 3-months. (e.g., one injection with a treatment period of 6 months or two injections, one at drug start and one 3-months later).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Focal Prostate Ablation + Androgen Deprivation + Novel Hormonal Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Focal Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Focal therapy to be completed within 8- to 12-weeks of the initiation of apalutamide but after the completion of the 8-week mpMRI to allow for it to be used in FT planning.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Focal Prostate Ablation + Androgen Deprivation + Novel Hormonal Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must have intermediate-risk PCa as defined by the below criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Favorable intermediate-risk PCa: i. ≤ clinical stage T2c, GG2, and PSA ≤ 10 ng/mL,&#xD;
             and &lt;50% positive biopsy cores with PCa b. Unfavorable intermediate-risk PCa: i. ≤&#xD;
             clinical stageT2c, GG2, and PSA 10-20 ng/mL, or ≥50% positive biopsy cores with PCa,&#xD;
             or ii. ≤ clinical stage T2c, GG3, and PSA &lt; 20 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: The PSA value for this inclusion criteria must be the value obtained just prior&#xD;
             to the subject's MRI-TB that provided the initial histopathologic diagnosis. This is&#xD;
             considered to be the subject's &quot;baseline&quot; PSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
             If the MRI-TB which initially diagnosed the subject's PCa was obtained greater than&#xD;
             3-months from the time of study consent, then a repeat PSA should be completed for&#xD;
             screening purposes to obtain a &quot;baseline&quot; PSA (unless one has been obtained for SOC at&#xD;
             least 3-months after this initial biopsy in which case no repeat value is needed and&#xD;
             this may be used for eligibility). This applies to all participants regardless of GG&#xD;
             used for eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: The histopathologic diagnosis must be obtained via &quot;MRI-TB&quot;, which for the&#xD;
             purposes of the present study, is defined as both a systematic 12-core sextant random&#xD;
             prostate biopsy and a targeted prostate biopsy. The targeted prostate biopsy can be&#xD;
             performed via in-bore mpMRI prostate biopsy, cognitive mpMRI/ultrasound fusion&#xD;
             prostate biopsy or software mpMRI/ultrasound fusion prostate biopsy. This &quot;MRI-TB&quot;&#xD;
             must not be obtained greater than 1 year from the date of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No mpMRI evidence of extra-prostatic extension (EPE) or seminal vesicle invasion, and&#xD;
             if seminal vesical invasion is suspected, it must be excluded by prostate biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects must have confirmed non-metastatic PCa following SOC screening for patients&#xD;
             with unfavorable intermediate-risk PCa, a combination of computed tomography imaging&#xD;
             of the abdomen and pelvis (CTAP) and technetium-99-mDP nuclear medicine bone scan (BS)&#xD;
             and/or prostate-specific membrane antigen positron emission tomography (PSMA/PET) scan&#xD;
             prior to enrollment. The imaging studies should be obtained within 6-months of&#xD;
             enrollment. Additional imaging is not required for men with favorable&#xD;
             intermediate-risk PCa.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject must be male ≥ 18 years-old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects must have a life expectancy of at least 10-years per the opinion of the&#xD;
             treating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects must be designated as Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance&#xD;
             status ≤ 2 or Karnofsky Performance Status Scale Score ≥ 60%, see Appendix A).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects must be fit to undergo general anesthesia and the FT surgical procedure,&#xD;
             which includes adequate visualization of the prostate gland on transrectal ultrasound&#xD;
             imaging, access to the urethra, perineum and rectum, as well as be tolerant of&#xD;
             lithotomy positioning in the opinion of the treating investigator or the operating&#xD;
             surgeon(s) if not the same as the treating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL Leukocytes ≥ 3,000/mcL Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mcL&#xD;
             Platelets ≥ 100,000/mcL Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
             (ULN) AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) ≤ 2.5 × institutional ULN Creatinine &lt; 1.5 institutional ULN&#xD;
             OR Calculated or measured creatinine clearance &gt; 50 mL/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
             eGFR &gt;30 mL/min using the MDRD (modification of diet and renal disease) formula Serum&#xD;
             albumin ≥3.0 g/dL Serum potassium ≥3.5 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with a prior or concurrent malignancy whose natural history or treatment does&#xD;
             not have the potential to interfere with the safety or efficacy assessment of the&#xD;
             investigational regimen are eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects who are sexually active with a woman of childbearing potential must agree to&#xD;
             use a condom with spermicidal foam/gel/film/cream/suppository and his partner must&#xD;
             also be practicing a highly effective method of contraception (i.e., established use&#xD;
             of oral, injected or implanted hormonal methods of contraception; placement of an&#xD;
             intrauterine device or intrauterine system) during treatment and for 3-months&#xD;
             following the last dose of apalutamide.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Subject has had prior or current PCa therapies, such as biologic, chemotherapy,&#xD;
             hormone therapy, radiotherapy or surgery for PCa. Subjects may not have had undergone&#xD;
             pelvic radiation, chemotherapy or immunotherapy treatment for a separate hematologic&#xD;
             or visceral malignancy within 6-months of enrollment in the present study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Subjects with locally advanced, nodal or metastatic prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Subjects who are unfit for pelvic mpMRI scanning (e.g., severe claustrophobia,&#xD;
             permanent cardiac pacemaker, metallic implants that are likely to contribute to&#xD;
             significant image artifacts, allergy or contraindication to gadolinium contrast agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. History of allergy or intolerance to study drug components.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. History of bilateral orchiectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. History of prior use of apalutamide.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. If the subject has an uncontrolled or major debilitating inter-current illness that&#xD;
             would contraindicate or implicate significant morbidity of the proposed combination&#xD;
             treatment, which includes but is not limited to poorly-controlled diabetes mellitus,&#xD;
             medical conditions requiring chronic continuous oxygen therapy, active urinary tract&#xD;
             infection (i.e., the subject must have discontinued all antibiotic(s) for at least one&#xD;
             week prior to first dose of study drug), seizure disorder, or psychiatric&#xD;
             illness/social situation that would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. Subjects who are receiving any other investigational agents, or who have received&#xD;
             other investigational agents in the past and who are no longer receiving these&#xD;
             investigational agents may be eligible at the discretion of the principal investigator&#xD;
             (PI).&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. Subjects with history of seizure or known condition that may pre-dispose to&#xD;
             seizure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina, myocardial infarction, congestive&#xD;
             heart failure, stroke, or transient ischemic attack within 12-months of consent to&#xD;
             participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             10. Subjects who are unable to stop taking the following prohibited medications prior&#xD;
             at least 4-weeks prior to initiating apalutamide treatment and throughout treatment&#xD;
             with apalutamide will be excluded due to the risk of seizure:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Aminophylline/theophylline b. Atypical antipsychotics (e.g., clozapine, olanzapine,&#xD;
             risperidone, ziprasidone) c. Bupropion d. Lithium e. Meperidine and pethidine f.&#xD;
             Phenothiazine antipsychotics (e.g., chlorpromazine, mesoridazine, thioridazine) g.&#xD;
             Tricyclic and tetracyclic antidepressants (e.g., amitriptyline, desipramine, doxepin,&#xD;
             imipramine, maprotiline, mirtazapine)&#xD;
&#xD;
             11. Judgment by the treating investigator or PI that the subject is unsuitable to&#xD;
             participate in the study and the subject is unlikely to comply with study procedures,&#xD;
             restrictions and requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Male</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Abhinav Sidana, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Cincinnati</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>UCCC Clinical Trials Office</last_name>
    <phone>513-584-7698</phone>
    <email>cancer@uchealth.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Cincinnati Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>UCCC CTO</last_name>
      <phone>513-584-7698</phone>
      <email>cancer@uchealth.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Abhinav Sidana, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 7, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 27, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 25, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Cincinnati</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Abhinav Sidana, MD, MPH</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

