<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05625074</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UniversidadePorto</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05625074</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>National Varicose Vein Study - Portugal</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Portuguese National Health Service Reality in Varicose Vein Surgery - a Transversal Study on the Early Postoperative of Superficial Venous Surgery.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidade do Porto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidade do Porto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The National Varicose Vein Study is a cross-sectional, multicenter, observational study. The&#xD;
      primary goal is to evaluate the 30 days outcome of the conventional great saphenous vein&#xD;
      surgery (stripping) in the treatment of the symptomatic chronic venous insufficiency,&#xD;
      comparing the results of difference Portuguese's health centers, comparing the following&#xD;
      variables: thrombo-prophylaxis (pharmacology or mechanic; compliance); antimicrobial&#xD;
      prophylaxis; quality of life; medication compliance; complications and work incapacity&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic venous disease is one of the most prevalent pathologies in the world population. It&#xD;
      presents a spectrum of variable manifestations, culminating in the most severe form, active&#xD;
      venous ulcer. The clinical evaluation, the study of venous anatomy by echo- Doppler and the&#xD;
      indications for surgical treatment are standardized in guidelines. The same applies to the&#xD;
      techniques for surgical treatment that, in the long term, present equally satisfactory&#xD;
      results. Thus, currently, in the Portuguese national health system, the surgical technique&#xD;
      most frequently used is conventional surgery. As for postoperative care, namely&#xD;
      thromboprophylaxis regimens, analgesia regimens, there is greater variability in its&#xD;
      application between clinics and institutions, which may result in significant differences in&#xD;
      postoperative recovery. In this way, we intend to develop an observational, cross-sectional&#xD;
      and multicenter study, comparing postoperative care protocols and patient compliance and&#xD;
      impact on quality of life, as well as absence from work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary goal is to evaluate the 30 days outcome of the conventional great saphenous vein&#xD;
      surgery (stripping) in the treatment of the symptomatic chronic venous insufficiency,&#xD;
      comparing the results of difference Portuguese's health centers, comparing the following&#xD;
      variables: thrombo-prophylaxis (pharmacology or mechanic; compliance); antimicrobial&#xD;
      prophylaxis; quality of life; medication compliance; complications and work incapacity&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacological and/or mechanical thromboprophylaxis</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 and 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>Regimen (low molecular weight Heparin vs direct oral anticoagulant; elastic stockings). duration of the thromboprophilaxis regimen</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibiotic prophylaxis regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 to 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of the regimen. Beta lactamic vs remaining antibiotics</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact on quality of Life;</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 to 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>Eq5D5L; 5-level EQ-5D version (EQ-5D-5L)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact on quality of Life;</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 to 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>CIVIQ14 - ChronIc Venous Insufficiency QOL Questionnaire (CIVIQ)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact on quality of Life;</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 to 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>rVCSS - revised venous clinical seveity score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance with drug therapy;</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 and 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>How many days were recomended to take the drug; How many days the patient took the drug</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications and extraordinary recourse to health care</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 and 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>Observation in the outpatient clinic and urgency department</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Period of work disability</measure>
    <time_frame>In the postoperative period between 25 and 45 days</time_frame>
    <description>measured in days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Venous Insufficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHUP Angiology and Vascular Surgery Service</arm_group_label>
    <description>A transversal study, recruiting consecutive patients undergoing great saphenous vein saphenectomy by stripping technique.&#xD;
Evaluation and Qol Questionnaires performed at the 30th day of the postoperative period (acceptable scope - 25 to 45 days)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHUSJ Angiology and Vascular Surgery Service CHUSJ</arm_group_label>
    <description>A transversal study, recruiting consecutive patients undergoing great saphenous vein saphenectomy by stripping technique.&#xD;
Evaluation and Qol Questionnaires performed at the 30th day of the postoperative period (acceptable scope - 25 to 45 days)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHUC Angiology and Vascular Surgery Service CHUSJ</arm_group_label>
    <description>A transversal study, recruiting consecutive patients undergoing great saphenous vein saphenectomy by stripping technique.&#xD;
Evaluation and Qol Questionnaires performed at the 30th day of the postoperative period (acceptable scope - 25 to 45 days)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conventional surgery for great saphenous vein insufficiency</intervention_name>
    <description>Arch ligation and stripping of great saphenous vein. Prophilatic anticoagulation - Low molecular weight heparin vs DOACs Antibiotics Non-steoridal anti-inflamatory drugs</description>
    <arm_group_label>CHUC Angiology and Vascular Surgery Service CHUSJ</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CHUP Angiology and Vascular Surgery Service</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CHUSJ Angiology and Vascular Surgery Service CHUSJ</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Arch ligation and stripping of great saphenous vein</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients submitted to surgical treatment of symptomatic insufficiency of the great&#xD;
        saphenous vein by conventional surgery (arch ligation +/- trunk stripping), in the&#xD;
        postoperative period between 25 and 45 days, in the hospital centers involved in the study&#xD;
        starting in November 2022 onwards, until the desired sample volume is reached (50 patients&#xD;
        per center).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated at CHUP, CHUSJ and CHUC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age over 18 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All clinical presentations (C) included in the CEAP classification system;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Period from November 2022 onwards;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conventional surgical treatment of at least one great saphenous vein;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated using the following techniques: arch ligation +/- trunk stripping.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusive or concomitant treatment with endovenous surgery (thermal ablation by laser&#xD;
             or radiofrequency…);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment by conservative conventional surgery of the great saphenous vein (CHIVA,&#xD;
             ASVAL);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Varicose surgery not involving the great saphenous vein;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age under 18 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated in hospital units not covered by the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>João Rocha Neves, MD/MSc</last_name>
    <phone>(+351) 910486230</phone>
    <email>joaorochaneves@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculdade de Medicina da Universidade do Porto</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto</city>
        <zip>4200-319</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joao Rocha-Neves</last_name>
      <phone>910486230</phone>
      <email>joaorochaneves@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Portugal</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Maeseneer MG, Kakkos SK, Aherne T, Baekgaard N, Black S, Blomgren L, Giannoukas A, Gohel M, de Graaf R, Hamel-Desnos C, Jawien A, Jaworucka-Kaczorowska A, Lattimer CR, Mosti G, Noppeney T, van Rijn MJ, Stansby G, Esvs Guidelines Committee, Kolh P, Bastos Goncalves F, Chakfe N, Coscas R, de Borst GJ, Dias NV, Hinchliffe RJ, Koncar IB, Lindholt JS, Trimarchi S, Tulamo R, Twine CP, Vermassen F, Wanhainen A, Document Reviewers, Bjorck M, Labropoulos N, Lurie F, Mansilha A, Nyamekye IK, Ramirez Ortega M, Ulloa JH, Urbanek T, van Rij AM, Vuylsteke ME. Editor's Choice - European Society for Vascular Surgery (ESVS) 2022 Clinical Practice Guidelines on the Management of Chronic Venous Disease of the Lower Limbs. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2022 Feb;63(2):184-267. doi: 10.1016/j.ejvs.2021.12.024. Epub 2022 Jan 11. No abstract available. Erratum In: Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2022 Aug-Sep;64(2-3):284-285.</citation>
    <PMID>35027279</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Donnell TF, Balk EM, Dermody M, Tangney E, Iafrati MD. Recurrence of varicose veins after endovenous ablation of the great saphenous vein in randomized trials. J Vasc Surg Venous Lymphat Disord. 2016 Jan;4(1):97-105. doi: 10.1016/j.jvsv.2014.11.004. Epub 2015 Apr 11.</citation>
    <PMID>26946904</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brand FN, Dannenberg AL, Abbott RD, Kannel WB. The epidemiology of varicose veins: the Framingham Study. Am J Prev Med. 1988 Mar-Apr;4(2):96-101.</citation>
    <PMID>3395496</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lurie F, Passman M, Meisner M, Dalsing M, Masuda E, Welch H, Bush RL, Blebea J, Carpentier PH, De Maeseneer M, Gasparis A, Labropoulos N, Marston WA, Rafetto J, Santiago F, Shortell C, Uhl JF, Urbanek T, van Rij A, Eklof B, Gloviczki P, Kistner R, Lawrence P, Moneta G, Padberg F, Perrin M, Wakefield T. The 2020 update of the CEAP classification system and reporting standards. J Vasc Surg Venous Lymphat Disord. 2020 May;8(3):342-352. doi: 10.1016/j.jvsv.2019.12.075. Epub 2020 Feb 27. Erratum In: J Vasc Surg Venous Lymphat Disord. 2021 Jan;9(1):288.</citation>
    <PMID>32113854</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidade do Porto</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>João Rocha Neves</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Venous Insufficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Conventional great vein surgery</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Venous Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Varicose Veins</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

