<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05610605</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FRAGSALUD</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05610605</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Education for Prevention and Treatment of Frailty</brief_title>
  <acronym>FRAGSALUD</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized Clinical Trial to Assess the Efficacy of an Educational Programme for Prevention and Treatment of Frailty in Older Adults Living in the Community: FRAGSALUD Programme</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Cadiz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Malaga</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Instituto de investigación e innovación biomédica de Cádiz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cadiz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Frailty is a condition with a high prevalence in older adults, leading to higher&#xD;
      vulnerability and increasing the risk of adverse health outcomes and disabilities. The aging&#xD;
      of the population in Spain is accelerating quickly, consequently, it is necessary to advise&#xD;
      the population on the appropriate path to healthy aging, free of fragility and their&#xD;
      secondary problems.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the efficacy and efficiency of a Fragsalud program for the prevention and&#xD;
      multifactorial treatment of frailty in people over 65 years of age living in the community&#xD;
      compared to the usual treatment. Material and methods: A Single blind randomized, two-arm&#xD;
      clinical trial; control group and intervention group, multicenter, with 15 months of&#xD;
      follow-up, with evaluations blinded at the beginning, and in the follow-up at 12 and 15&#xD;
      months. A recruitment of 196 people over 65 years of age with criteria of pre-frailty or&#xD;
      frailty according to Fried's criteria. The Fragsalud education program will be taught in the&#xD;
      intervention group; while control group will follow the usual health care. The evolution of&#xD;
      the criteria of frailty, cognitive state, eating pattern, emotional state, quality of sleep,&#xD;
      perceived social support, quality of life, functional capacity in daily life, adverse&#xD;
      results, assessment of self-efficacy and cost-utility analysis variables will be evaluated.&#xD;
      Possible confounding factors such as sociodemographic variables, comorbidity and&#xD;
      polymedication will be controlled. Intention-to-treat analysis will be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 30, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Fried frailty criteria at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Fried frailty criteria adapted to the Spanish population: subjects are considered non-frail when no criteria are present, pre-frail if they meet 1 or 2 of the criteria, and frail if they meet 3 to 5 criteria.&#xD;
Fried frailty criteria are divided into 5: Weight loss, Exhaustion, Physical Activity, Walking time, and Muscle weakness.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Fried frailty criteria at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Fried frailty criteria adapted to the Spanish population: subjects are considered non-frail when no criteria are present, pre-frail if they meet 1 or 2 of the criteria, and frail if they meet 3 to 5 criteria.&#xD;
Fried frailty criteria are divided into 5: Weight loss, Exhaustion, Physical Activity, Walking time, and Muscle weakness.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline weight change at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Unintentional weight loss of 5% or more in the last year: it is calculated using the difference between the current weight and that recorded in the medical record in the last year. If not available, the criterion is considered to be met if the answer is positive to Have you lost weight in the last year? and Have you lost more than 3 kg in the last year?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline weight change at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Unintentional weight loss of 5% or more in the last year: it is calculated using the difference between the current weight and that recorded in the medical record in the last year. If not available, the criterion is considered to be met if the answer is positive to Have you lost weight in the last year? and Have you lost more than 3 kg in the last year?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline exhaustion at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported exhaustion or tiredness: they met the criteria if they answered frequently or always in at least one of the 2 questions of the Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D) questionnaire, do I feel that everything I do is an effort? And I don't feel like doing anything?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline exhaustion at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported exhaustion or tiredness: they met the criteria if they answered frequently or always in at least one of the 2 questions of the Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D) questionnaire, do I feel that everything I do is an effort? And I don't feel like doing anything?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline physical activity at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Based on the reduced version of the Minnesota Leisure Time Activity Questionnaire (VREM) validated in Spanish for this age group, which asks about leisure-time physical activity. The kilocalories (Kcal) per week expended are calculated using a standardized algorithm. This variable is stratified by gender. Men: those with &lt;383 Kcals of physical activity per week meet the frailty criteria. Women: those with &lt;270 Kcals per week meet the criteria for frailty.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline physical activity at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Based on the reduced version of the Minnesota Leisure Time Activity Questionnaire (VREM) validated in Spanish for this age group, which asks about leisure-time physical activity. The kilocalories (Kcal) per week expended are calculated using a standardized algorithm. This variable is stratified by gender. Men: those with &lt;383 Kcals of physical activity per week meet the frailty criteria. Women: those with &lt;270 Kcals per week meet the criteria for frailty.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline walking time at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The results will be stratified by sex and height. Time limit to walk 4.57 meters for frailty, men taller than 1.63 cm: ≥6.4 seconds, all others: ≥7.2 seconds; women with a height over than 1.51 cm: ≥10.5 seconds, the rest: ≥11.2 seconds.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline walking time at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The results will be stratified by sex and height. Time limit to walk 4.57 meters for frailty, men taller than 1.63 cm: ≥6.4 seconds, all others: ≥7.2 seconds; women with a height over than 1.51 cm: ≥10.5 seconds, the rest: ≥11.2 seconds.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline muscle weakness at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The grip strength in the dominant hand will be measured with an arch dynamometer (Jamar® digital hand dynamometer) that expresses the force in kilograms. Those who cannot perform the test or according to the cut-off values meet the criteria: body mass index (BMI) equal to or over than 30 (men ≤15 kg/cm2, women ≤7 kg/cm2); BMI between 25.1 and 29.9 (men ≤13 kg/cm2, women ≤6 kg/cm2), and BMI equal to or less than 25 (men ≤10 kg/cm2, women ≤6 kg/cm2).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline muscle weakness at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The grip strength in the dominant hand will be measured with an arch dynamometer (Jamar® digital hand dynamometer) that expresses the force in kilograms. Those who cannot perform the test or according to the cut-off values meet the criteria: body mass index (BMI) equal to or over than 30 (men ≤15 kg/cm2, women ≤7 kg/cm2); BMI between 25.1 and 29.9 (men ≤13 kg/cm2, women ≤6 kg/cm2), and BMI equal to or less than 25 (men ≤10 kg/cm2, women ≤6 kg/cm2).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Cognitive status at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Cognitive status will be evaluated using The Short Portable Mental Status Questionnaire (SPMSQ) which includes 10 items. Depending on the number of errors, participants will be stratified in: 0-2 errors: normal mental functioning&#xD;
3-4 errors: mild cognitive impairment&#xD;
5-7 errors: moderate cognitive impairment&#xD;
8 or more errors: severe cognitive impairment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Cognitive status at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Cognitive status will be evaluated using The Short Portable Mental Status Questionnaire (SPMSQ) which includes 10 items. Depending on the number of errors, participants will be stratified in: 0-2 errors: normal mental functioning&#xD;
3-4 errors: mild cognitive impairment&#xD;
5-7 errors: moderate cognitive impairment&#xD;
8 or more errors: severe cognitive impairment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Nutritional status at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Nutritional status: the eating pattern will be assessed using the Mini Nutritional Assessment (MNA) test, which is a nutritional assessment and screening method for the elderly population. It consists of two parts: a screening (7 questions), and an evaluation (12 questions). A total score ≥ 24 indicates good nutritional status, between 17-23.5 identifies nutritional risk, and less than 17 the patient presents protein-calorie malnutrition.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Nutritional status at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Nutritional status: the eating pattern will be assessed using the Mini Nutritional Assessment (MNA) test, which is a nutritional assessment and screening method for the elderly population. It consists of two parts: a screening (7 questions), and an evaluation (12 questions). A total score ≥ 24 indicates good nutritional status, between 17-23.5 identifies nutritional risk, and less than 17 the patient presents protein-calorie malnutrition.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Emotional state at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Emotional state: using the Yesavage geriatric depression scale. It is a questionnaire for depression screening in people over 65 years of age. It consists of 15 questions, each wrong answer scores 1. The cut-off points are: 0-4 normal and 5 or + depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Emotional state at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Emotional state: using the Yesavage geriatric depression scale. It is a questionnaire for depression screening in people over 65 years of age. It consists of 15 questions, each wrong answer scores 1. The cut-off points are: 0-4 normal and 5 or + depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Sleep quality at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Self-perceived sleep quality using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), validated in Spanish. 7 components are obtained: subjective quality, sleep latency, sleep duration, &quot;sleep efficiency&quot;, sleep disturbances, use of hypnotic medication, daytime dysfunction. The sum of the partial scores generates a total score, which can range from 0-21. According to Buysse et al, a score of 5 would be the cut-off point that would separate subjects who have good sleep quality from those who have poor sleep quality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Sleep quality at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Self-perceived sleep quality using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), validated in Spanish. 7 components are obtained: subjective quality, sleep latency, sleep duration, &quot;sleep efficiency&quot;, sleep disturbances, use of hypnotic medication, daytime dysfunction. The sum of the partial scores generates a total score, which can range from 0-21. According to Buysse et al, a score of 5 would be the cut-off point that would separate subjects who have good sleep quality from those who have poor sleep quality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Social interaction at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Social interaction through the Duke-UNC questionnaire of perceived social support, consisting of 11 items and a Likert-type response scale (1-5). The scoring range is between 11 and 55 points. The lower the score, the less support. In the Spanish validation, a cut-off point of &lt;32 was chosen. A score equal to or greater than 32 indicates normal support, while less than 32 indicates low perceived social support.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Social interaction at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Social interaction through the Duke-UNC questionnaire of perceived social support, consisting of 11 items and a Likert-type response scale (1-5). The scoring range is between 11 and 55 points. The lower the score, the less support. In the Spanish validation, a cut-off point of &lt;32 was chosen. A score equal to or greater than 32 indicates normal support, while less than 32 indicates low perceived social support.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Health-related Quality of life at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Health-related quality of life: the EuroQol-5D-5L questionnaire validated in Spanish will be used, describing five dimensions (mobility, personal care, daily activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression). It also consists of a visual analogue scale (VAS), graduated from 0 to 100 and labeled &quot;worst imaginable health state&quot; and &quot;best imaginable health state&quot;, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Health-related Quality of life at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Health-related quality of life: the EuroQol-5D-5L questionnaire validated in Spanish will be used, describing five dimensions (mobility, personal care, daily activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression). It also consists of a visual analogue scale (VAS), graduated from 0 to 100 and labeled &quot;worst imaginable health state&quot; and &quot;best imaginable health state&quot;, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Functional capacity in daily life (Lawton &amp; Brody scale and Barthel index) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluation of functional capacities for personal independence, using the Lawton and Brody scale, which evaluates 8 instrumental activities of daily life in 10 Likert-type items. Depending on the degree of dependence, every item is scored between 0 to 10, with a final puntuation between 0 to 100. Depending on the final score, the degree of dependency is evaluated with the lower the score, the more dependency.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Functional capacity in daily life (Lawton &amp; Brody scale and Barthel index) at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluation of functional capacities for personal independence, using the Lawton and Brody scale, which evaluates 8 instrumental activities of daily life in 10 Likert-type items. Depending on the degree of dependence, every item is scored between 0 to 10, with a final puntuation between 0 to 100. Depending on the final score, the degree of dependency is evaluated with the lower the score, the more dependency.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Functional capacity in daily life (Exercise, physical inactivity and sleep) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Assessment of exercise, physical inactivity and sleep that will be carried out using accelerometers for 7 days at the beginning, a year and 15 months. Participants are asked to wear a triaxial accelerometer (GeneActiv, Activinsights Ltd, Kimbolton, Cambs, UK, http://www.geneactiv.org/) on their non-dominant wrist 24 hours a day. The GeneActiv Recorder contains a triaxial MEMS accelerometer with a range of ± 8 g. and a sensitivity ≥ 0.004 g. It records both motion-related acceleration and gravitational acceleration and has linear and equal sensitivity along all three axes (forward/backward, up/down, left/right). This monitor provides the end user with raw accelerometry data. In this study, the accelerometer will be configured at 40 Hz. For data processing, the system developed for the PREDIMEDPLUS study will be used. The data processing is done with an open source package in R, GGIR version 1.5-12.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Functional capacity in daily life (Exercise, physical inactivity and sleep) at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Assessment of exercise, physical inactivity and sleep that will be carried out using accelerometers for 7 days at the beginning, a year and 15 months. Participants are asked to wear a triaxial accelerometer (GeneActiv, Activinsights Ltd, Kimbolton, Cambs, UK, http://www.geneactiv.org/) on their non-dominant wrist 24 hours a day. The GeneActiv Recorder contains a triaxial MEMS accelerometer with a range of ± 8 g. and a sensitivity ≥ 0.004 g. It records both motion-related acceleration and gravitational acceleration and has linear and equal sensitivity along all three axes (forward/backward, up/down, left/right). This monitor provides the end user with raw accelerometry data. In this study, the accelerometer will be configured at 40 Hz. For data processing, the system developed for the PREDIMEDPLUS study will be used. The data processing is done with an open source package in R, GGIR version 1.5-12.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Functional capacity in daily life (Balance assessment) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Assessment of balance by means of single-legged support, it will be requested that they remain as long as possible supported by only one of their lower extremities with their arms at the sides of the trunk. The duration of the test will be considered until one of the following conditions is met: a) The support foot changes position, b) The elevated foot touches the ground, c) The arms come off the trunk, and d) When the leg raised touches the supporting limb. The maximum time considered is 30 seconds. The best time of two attempts will be recorded. Based on the results, the subjects will be divided into two groups. Those who reach a time &gt;5 seconds that will be classified as high performance, and with a score ≤ 5 low performance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Functional capacity in daily life (Balance assessment) at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Assessment of balance by means of single-legged support, it will be requested that they remain as long as possible supported by only one of their lower extremities with their arms at the sides of the trunk. The duration of the test will be considered until one of the following conditions is met: a) The support foot changes position, b) The elevated foot touches the ground, c) The arms come off the trunk, and d) When the leg raised touches the supporting limb. The maximum time considered is 30 seconds. The best time of two attempts will be recorded. Based on the results, the subjects will be divided into two groups. Those who reach a time &gt;5 seconds that will be classified as high performance, and with a score ≤ 5 low performance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Adverse outcomes at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluate the rates of falls, fractures due to falls, hospital admissions, days of hospital admission, interventions, inclusions in home care programs, institutionalizations in residences and deaths. The evaluation will be carried out by consulting the clinical health history and by direct questioning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Adverse outcomes at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluate the rates of falls, fractures due to falls, hospital admissions, days of hospital admission, interventions, inclusions in home care programs, institutionalizations in residences and deaths. The evaluation will be carried out by consulting the clinical health history and by direct questioning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline self perceived confidence at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluation of self-efficacy using the General Self-Efficacy Scale. Consisting of 10 items on a Likert scale ranging from 1 (not at all) to 4 (a lot), the scale assesses the degree to which they perceive self-confidence when managing general activities in daily life. It was developed by Sherer et al., it is validated in Spanish.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline self perceived confidence at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluation of self-efficacy using the General Self-Efficacy Scale. Consisting of 10 items on a Likert scale ranging from 1 (not at all) to 4 (a lot), the scale assesses the degree to which they perceive self-confidence when managing general activities in daily life. It was developed by Sherer et al., it is validated in Spanish.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Cost-utility analysis at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Cost-utility analysis, following the recommendations of the proposed guide for economic evaluation applied to health technologies.&#xD;
Healthcare resources: a) the consumption of healthcare services associated with falls will be analysed: hospital admissions, Primary Care medical and nursing consultations, Primary Care medical and nursing visits at home (during regular hours), emergency medical visits for Primary Care Primary at home, medical consultations in the Hospital (UGC Traumatology and Rehabilitation), emergency medical consultations in the Hospital Center, medication and complementary tests; b) the consumption of services in general will also be analysed: visits to primary nursing and medical care, visits to primary nursing and medical care, visits to the emergency department, visits to medical specialties, hospital admissions and surgical interventions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of baseline Cost-utility analysis at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Cost-utility analysis, following the recommendations of the proposed guide for economic evaluation applied to health technologies.&#xD;
Healthcare resources: a) the consumption of healthcare services associated with falls will be analysed: hospital admissions, Primary Care medical and nursing consultations, Primary Care medical and nursing visits at home (during regular hours), emergency medical visits for Primary Care Primary at home, medical consultations in the Hospital (UGC Traumatology and Rehabilitation), emergency medical consultations in the Hospital Center, medication and complementary tests; b) the consumption of services in general will also be analysed: visits to primary nursing and medical care, visits to primary nursing and medical care, visits to the emergency department, visits to medical specialties, hospital admissions and surgical interventions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of Intervention satisfaction assessed by CSQ-8 at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluation of satisfaction with the intervention: the CSQ-8 (Client Satisfaction Questionnaire) will be used, with 8 questions evaluated according to a 4-point Likert-type scale, with specific cut-off points for each of the items. It has been validated in a Spanish-speaking population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the change of Intervention satisfaction assessed by CSQ-8 at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>- Evaluation of satisfaction with the intervention: the CSQ-8 (Client Satisfaction Questionnaire) will be used, with 8 questions evaluated according to a 4-point Likert-type scale, with specific cut-off points for each of the items. It has been validated in a Spanish-speaking population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Sociodemographic data at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Date of birth, sex, marital status, cohabitation, educational level, amount of pension income.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Sociodemographic data at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Date of birth, sex, marital status, cohabitation, educational level, amount of pension income.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Medical data at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Number and type of chronic pathologies (comorbidities). Number of different medications you take daily and type of medication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Medical data at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Number and type of chronic pathologies (comorbidities). Number of different medications you take daily and type of medication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Blood Sample (Hematocrit) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>1. Hematocrit (%)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Blood Sample (Hematocrit) at 12months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>1. Hematocrit (%)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Hemoglobin, protein and albumin sample at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>2. Hemoglobin (g/dL) 3. Total protein (g/dL) 4. Serum Albumin (g/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Hemoglobin, protein and albumin sample at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>2. Hemoglobin (g/dL) 3. Total protein (g/dL) 4. Serum Albumin (g/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline lipids, and plasma creatinine sample at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>5. Lipid profile (mg/dL) 6. Plasma creatinine (mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline lipids, and plasma creatinine sample at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>5. Lipid profile (mg/dL) 6. Plasma creatinine (mg/dL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Blood Sample (Glycosylated hemoglobin) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>7. Glycosylated hemoglobin (A1C)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Blood Sample (Glycosylated hemoglobin) at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>7. Glycosylated hemoglobin (A1C)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Weight at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>1. Weight (kilograms)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Weight at 12months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>1. Weight (kilograms)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Height at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>2. Height (meters)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Height at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>2. Height (meters)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Body Mass Index at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>3. Body Mass Index (kg/m^2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Body Mass Index at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>3. Body Mass Index (kg/m^2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Waist circunference at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>4. Waist circunference (cm)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Waist circunference at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>4. Waist circunference (cm)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Blood pressure at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>5. Systolic and diastolic Blood pressure (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Biological variables: Blood pressure at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>5. Systolic and diastolic Blood pressure (mmHg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Smoking and alcohol habits</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of cigarettes per day&#xD;
Number of alcoholic drinks per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessed changes from Baseline Smoking and alcohol habits</measure>
    <time_frame>Preintervention/Postintervention (0 and 12 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of cigarettes per day&#xD;
Number of alcoholic drinks per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">196</enrollment>
  <condition>Frailty</condition>
  <condition>Frail Elderly Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who do not receive attention from the Fragsalud program. The control group follows the usual care and preventive measures in Primary Care, according to different protocols implemented and the criteria of nurses and family doctors responsible for their care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The FRAGSALUD Programme is a multidomain intervention programme, which covers the prevention and treatment of frailty from different aspects, fundamentally from a physical and cognitive aspect and to maintain social integration, although other modifiable factors that are related to the presence of fragility such as hearing impairment, visual deficit or depression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health intervention programme: FRAGSALUD</intervention_name>
    <description>The FRAGSALUD Program consists in two parts, a first part of health education that will be taught in a group in four sessions, and a second part of individual treatment and follow-up, individual consultations will have a bimonthly periodicity until reaching one year, at which time that the program ends and a final evaluation will be carried out to assess whether the changes are maintained 15 months after the start.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 65 years of age who present frailty or pre-frailty, assessed using the&#xD;
             Fried criteria adapted to Spanish population;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients belonging to Clinical Management Units participating in the study and who&#xD;
             will remain in it for the 15 months of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who can come to the Health Center alone or accompanied.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients suffering from COPD stage III or IV;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients suffering from unstable angina;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients suffering from uncontrolled congestive heart failure, or unstable arrhythmia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who cannot walk alone or with technical aids, such as bedridden people;&#xD;
             patients in nursing home;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cognitive impairment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who do not understand Spanish;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with allergies to plastic or metal.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>María Ángeles Vázquez Sanchez, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universidad de Málaga</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of Education</name>
      <address>
        <city>Puerto Real</city>
        <state>Cádiz</state>
        <zip>11519</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Elderly Persons</keyword>
  <keyword>Aging</keyword>
  <keyword>Cost-Efficiency Analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Education</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Frailty</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

