<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05795946</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SP0012</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05795946</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Standard Process Heart and Gut Health Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of a Whole Food Based Nutritional Formulation on Trimethylamine N-oxide and Cardiometabolic Endpoints in Healthy Adults.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Standard Process Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Standard Process Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Standard Process Heart and Gut Health Study&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This prospective pilot clinical study will screen 45 healthy participants regularly consuming&#xD;
      omnivorous diet (full fat dairy, red meat, eggs, fish) and have elevated serum Trimethyl&#xD;
      amine N-oxide (TMAO) levels. Trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO) is a gut microbiota derived&#xD;
      dietary metabolite which is emerging as a significant and independent predictor of&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk mainly through inflammation and oxidative stress pathways.&#xD;
      Long term consumption of animal products elevates TMAO levels due to its abundance of TMAO&#xD;
      precursors: choline and L-carnitine. As diet plays a key role in altering the microbial&#xD;
      composition and subsequent TMAO levels, it is important to investigate if whole food based&#xD;
      nutritional formulations can provide the necessary support required to manage TMAO levels and&#xD;
      hence, positively impact cardiometabolic endpoints. Towards this end both B and D vitamins&#xD;
      have been shown to influence the levels of circulating TMAO while maintaining a healthy gut&#xD;
      microenvironment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This pilot study aims to explore the modulation of TMAO response in healthy adults after&#xD;
      supplementation with a whole food matrix-based B vitamins formulation alone, and in&#xD;
      combination with vitamin D. The assessments will be compared to the diet only control group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 15, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>3 groups: 1 for B vitamins only, 1 with B vitamins in addition of D vitamins, and one is diet only.&#xD;
This pilot study aims to explore the modulation of TMAO response in healthy adults after supplementation with a whole food matrix-based B vitamins formulation alone, and in combination with vitamin D. The assessments will be compared to the diet only control group.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>The labels for the vitamins will only have the participant ID on them</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>One outcome is to determine if a combination of whole food-based B-vitamins can modulate gut diversity and TMAO response</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Another outcome is to explore the beneficial interplay between B and D vitamin supplementation in reducing TMAO levels through modulation of gut microbiome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Nutrition, Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diet Only Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Diet only: guided diet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Combination Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combination of whole food-based B and D vitamins</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B Only Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Whole food-based B vitamins</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Whole food-based B and D vitamins</intervention_name>
    <description>Looking at whole food-based B and D vitamins to reduce TMAO levels and if this can modulate gut diversity</description>
    <arm_group_label>B Only Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Combination Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy participants (both male and female) aged 25-80 years with omnivorous diet&#xD;
             (regular consumption of eggs, red meat, dairy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No pre or probiotic consumption during study, no antibiotics during study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to high serum levels of TMAO (more than or equal to 4 uM) determined by a&#xD;
             standard blood test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the participant is on antibiotics, they should finish their medication and wait one&#xD;
             month before testing for TMAO as a screening criterion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal blood pressure, non-smokers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal cholesterol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants can communicate and follow instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants voluntarily signed and dated an informed consent (ICF), reviewed by an&#xD;
             Institutional Review Board (IRB), and provided authorization prior to any&#xD;
             participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are willing to take nutritional supplements and have no known food&#xD;
             allergies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vegan and vegetarian participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants on medically prescribed diet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants not willing to stop consumption of fermented products (plain yogurt,&#xD;
             kefir, kombucha, water kefir, miso, pickled vegetables, and sauerkraut) 2 weeks prior&#xD;
             to the study start date and during the study timeline as this will interfere with gut&#xD;
             microbiome related outcome assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants not willing to stop consuming polyphenols- green tea, cocoa, flaxseed,&#xD;
             berries, and energy drinks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are currently or have participated in other interventional clinical&#xD;
             trials in the last 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants on certain supplements like GI health related (Probiotics, prebiotics,&#xD;
             and/or antimicrobial botanicals), vitamin C, Choline, lecithin or L-carnitine, fish&#xD;
             oil/krill oil containing supplements who don't wish to stop supplementation prior to 2&#xD;
             weeks of study start date&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have any confirmed or suspected infectious disease (such as&#xD;
             tuberculosis, Hepatitis B or C, HIV infection), malignancy, or any other clinically&#xD;
             significant medical condition, which in the investigators' opinion, makes him or her&#xD;
             not suitable for inclusion in the study*&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have pacemakers, an implanted cardioverter defibrillator (ICD), or a&#xD;
             cardiac resynchronization therapy device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have confirmed or suspected pregnancy (self-reported)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant waiting for a heart transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants currently hospitalized for acute myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a planned revascularization within 30 days of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must not have any allergies to supplement ingredients (see list)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have initiated the use of prescription medications (defined as a&#xD;
             medication that can be prescribed only by a properly authorized/licensed clinician),&#xD;
             and not authorized non-prescription medications (over-the-counter medications), and&#xD;
             other nutritional supplements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who do not comply with all study requirements (including clinical visits)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with high cholesterol or on lipid lowering medications like statins&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants on following medication: NSAIDS, Steroids, Prednisone, Acid Reflux/GERD&#xD;
             medicines: Tagamet, Zantac, Pepcid, Prilosec, Prevacid&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chinmayee Panda, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Standard Process Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Brea Nance</last_name>
    <phone>2624956410</phone>
    <email>bnance@standardprocess.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Docs Outside the Box</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33702</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brea Nance</last_name>
      <phone>262-495-6410</phone>
      <email>bnance@standardprocess.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chinmayee Panda, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li XS, Obeid S, Klingenberg R, Gencer B, Mach F, Raber L, Windecker S, Rodondi N, Nanchen D, Muller O, Miranda MX, Matter CM, Wu Y, Li L, Wang Z, Alamri HS, Gogonea V, Chung YM, Tang WH, Hazen SL, Luscher TF. Gut microbiota-dependent trimethylamine N-oxide in acute coronary syndromes: a prognostic marker for incident cardiovascular events beyond traditional risk factors. Eur Heart J. 2017 Mar 14;38(11):814-824. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehw582.</citation>
    <PMID>28077467</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ma J, Li H. The Role of Gut Microbiota in Atherosclerosis and Hypertension. Front Pharmacol. 2018 Sep 25;9:1082. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2018.01082. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>30319417</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brunt VE, Gioscia-Ryan RA, Richey JJ, Zigler MC, Cuevas LM, Gonzalez A, Vazquez-Baeza Y, Battson ML, Smithson AT, Gilley AD, Ackermann G, Neilson AP, Weir T, Davy KP, Knight R, Seals DR. Suppression of the gut microbiome ameliorates age-related arterial dysfunction and oxidative stress in mice. J Physiol. 2019 May;597(9):2361-2378. doi: 10.1113/JP277336. Epub 2019 Feb 27.</citation>
    <PMID>30714619</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sun X, Jiao X, Ma Y, Liu Y, Zhang L, He Y, Chen Y. Trimethylamine N-oxide induces inflammation and endothelial dysfunction in human umbilical vein endothelial cells via activating ROS-TXNIP-NLRP3 inflammasome. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2016 Dec 2;481(1-2):63-70. doi: 10.1016/j.bbrc.2016.11.017. Epub 2016 Nov 8.</citation>
    <PMID>27833015</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhu W, Wang Z, Tang WHW, Hazen SL. Gut Microbe-Generated Trimethylamine N-Oxide From Dietary Choline Is Prothrombotic in Subjects. Circulation. 2017 Apr 25;135(17):1671-1673. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.116.025338. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>28438808</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li D, Lu Y, Yuan S, Cai X, He Y, Chen J, Wu Q, He D, Fang A, Bo Y, Song P, Bogaert D, Tsilidis K, Larsson SC, Yu H, Zhu H, Theodoratou E, Zhu Y, Li X. Gut microbiota-derived metabolite trimethylamine-N-oxide and multiple health outcomes: an umbrella review and updated meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2022 Jul 6;116(1):230-243. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/nqac074.</citation>
    <PMID>35348578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sohouli MH, Ozovanu OD, Fatahi S, Hekmatdoost A. Impact of probiotic supplementation on trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO) in humans: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2022 Aug;50:56-62. doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2022.06.006. Epub 2022 Jun 17.</citation>
    <PMID>35871952</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang Q, Guo M, Liu Y, Xu M, Shi L, Li X, Zhao J, Zhang H, Wang G, Chen W. Bifidobacterium breve and Bifidobacterium longum Attenuate Choline-Induced Plasma Trimethylamine N-Oxide Production by Modulating Gut Microbiota in Mice. Nutrients. 2022 Mar 14;14(6):1222. doi: 10.3390/nu14061222.</citation>
    <PMID>35334879</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dalla Via A, Gargari G, Taverniti V, Rondini G, Velardi I, Gambaro V, Visconti GL, De Vitis V, Gardana C, Ragg E, Pinto A, Riso P, Guglielmetti S. Urinary TMAO Levels Are Associated with the Taxonomic Composition of the Gut Microbiota and with the Choline TMA-Lyase Gene (cutC) Harbored by Enterobacteriaceae. Nutrients. 2019 Dec 25;12(1):62. doi: 10.3390/nu12010062.</citation>
    <PMID>31881690</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keith ME, Walsh NA, Darling PB, Hanninen SA, Thirugnanam S, Leong-Poi H, Barr A, Sole MJ. B-vitamin deficiency in hospitalized patients with heart failure. J Am Diet Assoc. 2009 Aug;109(8):1406-10. doi: 10.1016/j.jada.2009.05.011.</citation>
    <PMID>19631047</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhao LG, Shu XO, Li HL, Gao J, Han LH, Wang J, Fang J, Gao YT, Zheng W, Xiang YB. Prospective cohort studies of dietary vitamin B6 intake and risk of cause-specific mortality. Clin Nutr. 2019 Jun;38(3):1180-1187. doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2018.04.016. Epub 2018 May 4.</citation>
    <PMID>29764693</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reay JL, Smith MA, Riby LM. B vitamins and cognitive performance in older adults: review. ISRN Nutr. 2013 Mar 11;2013:650983. doi: 10.5402/2013/650983. eCollection 2013.</citation>
    <PMID>24959550</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Malik M, Hnatkova K, Batchvarov V, Gang Y, Smetana P, Camm AJ. Sample size, power calculations, and their implications for the cost of thorough studies of drug induced QT interval prolongation. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2004 Dec;27(12):1659-69. doi: 10.1111/j.1540-8159.2004.00701.x.</citation>
    <PMID>15613131</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hsiao PY, Mitchell DC, Coffman DL, Allman RM, Locher JL, Sawyer P, Jensen GL, Hartman TJ. Dietary patterns and diet quality among diverse older adults: the University of Alabama at Birmingham Study of Aging. J Nutr Health Aging. 2013 Jan;17(1):19-25. doi: 10.1007/s12603-012-0082-4.</citation>
    <PMID>23299373</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Borel P, Mekki N, Boirie Y, Partier A, Alexandre-Gouabau MC, Grolier P, Beaufrere B, Portugal H, Lairon D, Azais-Braesco V. Comparison of the postprandial plasma vitamin A response in young and older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1998 Mar;53(2):B133-40. doi: 10.1093/gerona/53a.2.b133.</citation>
    <PMID>9520909</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hubbard GP, Elia M, Holdoway A, Stratton RJ. A systematic review of compliance to oral nutritional supplements. Clin Nutr. 2012 Jun;31(3):293-312. doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2011.11.020. Epub 2012 Jan 17.</citation>
    <PMID>22257636</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhao M, Chen YH, Dong XT, Zhou J, Chen X, Wang H, Wu SX, Xia MZ, Zhang C, Xu DX. Folic acid protects against lipopolysaccharide-induced preterm delivery and intrauterine growth restriction through its anti-inflammatory effect in mice. PLoS One. 2013 Dec 6;8(12):e82713. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0082713. eCollection 2013.</citation>
    <PMID>24324824</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bazzano LA, He J, Ogden LG, Loria C, Vupputuri S, Myers L, Whelton PK. Dietary intake of folate and risk of stroke in US men and women: NHANES I Epidemiologic Follow-up Study. National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Stroke. 2002 May;33(5):1183-8. doi: 10.1161/01.str.0000014607.90464.88.</citation>
    <PMID>11988588</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bazzano LA, He J, Ogden LG, Loria CM, Vupputuri S, Myers L, Whelton PK. Fruit and vegetable intake and risk of cardiovascular disease in US adults: the first National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey Epidemiologic Follow-up Study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2002 Jul;76(1):93-9. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/76.1.93.</citation>
    <PMID>12081821</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Varadharaj S, Kelly OJ, Khayat RN, Kumar PS, Ahmed N, Zweier JL. Role of Dietary Antioxidants in the Preservation of Vascular Function and the Modulation of Health and Disease. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2017 Nov 1;4:64. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2017.00064. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29164133</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ji Y, Tan S, Xu Y, Chandra A, Shi C, Song B, Qin J, Gao Y. Vitamin B supplementation, homocysteine levels, and the risk of cerebrovascular disease: a meta-analysis. Neurology. 2013 Oct 8;81(15):1298-307. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182a823cc. Epub 2013 Sep 18.</citation>
    <PMID>24049135</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barrea L, Muscogiuri G, Annunziata G, Laudisio D, de Alteriis G, Tenore GC, Colao A, Savastano S. A New Light on Vitamin D in Obesity: A Novel Association with Trimethylamine-N-Oxide (TMAO). Nutrients. 2019 Jun 10;11(6):1310. doi: 10.3390/nu11061310.</citation>
    <PMID>31185686</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ozorowski M, Wicinski M, Wrobel L, Fajkiel-Madajczyk A. Cholecalciferol supplementation lowers leptin and TMAO but increases NO and VEGF-A levels in obese vitamin D deficient patients: Is it one of the potential cardioprotective mechanisms of vitamin D? Nutr Metab (Lond). 2022 Apr 29;19(1):31. doi: 10.1186/s12986-022-00666-4.</citation>
    <PMID>35488267</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Obeid R, Awwad HM, Kirsch SH, Waldura C, Herrmann W, Graeber S, Geisel J. Plasma trimethylamine-N-oxide following supplementation with vitamin D or D plus B vitamins. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2017 Feb;61(2). doi: 10.1002/mnfr.201600358. Epub 2016 Oct 10.</citation>
    <PMID>27569255</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang X, Li X, Dong Y. Vitamin D Decreases Plasma Trimethylamine-N-oxide Level in Mice by Regulating Gut Microbiota. Biomed Res Int. 2020 Oct 5;2020:9896743. doi: 10.1155/2020/9896743. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>33083493</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kalagi NA, Abbott KA, Alburikan KA, Alkofide HA, Stojanovski E, Garg ML. Modulation of Circulating Trimethylamine N-Oxide Concentrations by Dietary Supplements and Pharmacological Agents: A Systematic Review. Adv Nutr. 2019 Sep 1;10(5):876-887. doi: 10.1093/advances/nmz012.</citation>
    <PMID>31073588</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gatarek P, Kaluzna-Czaplinska J. Trimethylamine N-oxide (TMAO) in human health. EXCLI J. 2021 Feb 11;20:301-319. doi: 10.17179/excli2020-3239. eCollection 2021.</citation>
    <PMID>33746664</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Masenga SK, Hamooya B, Hangoma J, Hayumbu V, Ertuglu LA, Ishimwe J, Rahman S, Saleem M, Laffer CL, Elijovich F, Kirabo A. Recent advances in modulation of cardiovascular diseases by the gut microbiota. J Hum Hypertens. 2022 Nov;36(11):952-959. doi: 10.1038/s41371-022-00698-6. Epub 2022 Apr 25.</citation>
    <PMID>35469059</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ercolini D, Fogliano V. Food Design To Feed the Human Gut Microbiota. J Agric Food Chem. 2018 Apr 18;66(15):3754-3758. doi: 10.1021/acs.jafc.8b00456. Epub 2018 Apr 5.</citation>
    <PMID>29565591</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guinane CM, Cotter PD. Role of the gut microbiota in health and chronic gastrointestinal disease: understanding a hidden metabolic organ. Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2013 Jul;6(4):295-308. doi: 10.1177/1756283X13482996.</citation>
    <PMID>23814609</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>La Frano MR, de Moura FF, Boy E, Lonnerdal B, Burri BJ. Bioavailability of iron, zinc, and provitamin A carotenoids in biofortified staple crops. Nutr Rev. 2014 May;72(5):289-307. doi: 10.1111/nure.12108. Epub 2014 Apr 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24689451</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Melse-Boonstra A. Bioavailability of Micronutrients From Nutrient-Dense Whole Foods: Zooming in on Dairy, Vegetables, and Fruits. Front Nutr. 2020 Jul 24;7:101. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2020.00101. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>32793622</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cho CE, Taesuwan S, Malysheva OV, Bender E, Tulchinsky NF, Yan J, Sutter JL, Caudill MA. Trimethylamine-N-oxide (TMAO) response to animal source foods varies among healthy young men and is influenced by their gut microbiota composition: A randomized controlled trial. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2017 Jan;61(1). doi: 10.1002/mnfr.201600324. Epub 2016 Aug 3.</citation>
    <PMID>27377678</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koeth RA, Wang Z, Levison BS, Buffa JA, Org E, Sheehy BT, Britt EB, Fu X, Wu Y, Li L, Smith JD, DiDonato JA, Chen J, Li H, Wu GD, Lewis JD, Warrier M, Brown JM, Krauss RM, Tang WH, Bushman FD, Lusis AJ, Hazen SL. Intestinal microbiota metabolism of L-carnitine, a nutrient in red meat, promotes atherosclerosis. Nat Med. 2013 May;19(5):576-85. doi: 10.1038/nm.3145. Epub 2013 Apr 7.</citation>
    <PMID>23563705</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yang S, Li X, Yang F, Zhao R, Pan X, Liang J, Tian L, Li X, Liu L, Xing Y, Wu M. Gut Microbiota-Dependent Marker TMAO in Promoting Cardiovascular Disease: Inflammation Mechanism, Clinical Prognostic, and Potential as a Therapeutic Target. Front Pharmacol. 2019 Nov 19;10:1360. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2019.01360. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31803054</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jimenez-Torres J, Alcala-Diaz JF, Torres-Pena JD, Gutierrez-Mariscal FM, Leon-Acuna A, Gomez-Luna P, Fernandez-Gandara C, Quintana-Navarro GM, Fernandez-Garcia JC, Perez-Martinez P, Ordovas JM, Delgado-Lista J, Yubero-Serrano EM, Lopez-Miranda J. Mediterranean Diet Reduces Atherosclerosis Progression in Coronary Heart Disease: An Analysis of the CORDIOPREV Randomized Controlled Trial. Stroke. 2021 Nov;52(11):3440-3449. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.033214. Epub 2021 Aug 10. Erratum In: Stroke. 2021 Nov;52(11):e754.</citation>
    <PMID>34372670</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lindschinger M, Tatzber F, Schimetta W, Schmid I, Lindschinger B, Cvirn G, Fuchs N, Markolin G, Lamont E, Wonisch W. [Bioavailability of natural versus synthetic B vitamins and their effects on metabolic processes]. MMW Fortschr Med. 2020 Mar;162(Suppl 4):17-27. doi: 10.1007/s15006-020-0230-4. Epub 2020 Mar 19. German.</citation>
    <PMID>32189314</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhou A, Selvanayagam JB, Hypponen E. Non-linear Mendelian randomization analyses support a role for vitamin D deficiency in cardiovascular disease risk. Eur Heart J. 2022 May 7;43(18):1731-1739. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehab809.</citation>
    <PMID>34891159</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barbarawi M, Kheiri B, Zayed Y, Barbarawi O, Dhillon H, Swaid B, Yelangi A, Sundus S, Bachuwa G, Alkotob ML, Manson JE. Vitamin D Supplementation and Cardiovascular Disease Risks in More Than 83 000 Individuals in 21 Randomized Clinical Trials: A Meta-analysis. JAMA Cardiol. 2019 Aug 1;4(8):765-776. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2019.1870. Erratum In: JAMA Cardiol. 2019 Nov 6;:</citation>
    <PMID>31215980</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Parva NR, Tadepalli S, Singh P, Qian A, Joshi R, Kandala H, Nookala VK, Cheriyath P. Prevalence of Vitamin D Deficiency and Associated Risk Factors in the US Population (2011-2012). Cureus. 2018 Jun 5;10(6):e2741. doi: 10.7759/cureus.2741.</citation>
    <PMID>30087817</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Orces C, Lorenzo C, Guarneros JE. The Prevalence and Determinants of Vitamin D Inadequacy among U.S. Older Adults: National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2007-2014. Cureus. 2019 Aug 1;11(8):e5300. doi: 10.7759/cureus.5300.</citation>
    <PMID>31579639</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 8, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Heart health</keyword>
  <keyword>B Vitamins</keyword>
  <keyword>D Vitamins</keyword>
  <keyword>TMAO</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Heart</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We do not plan to share data with other researchers</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

