<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615480</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-KY-009-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615480</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Cerebral Oxygen Saturation Monitoring on POCD of Elderly Patients Undergoing Shoulder Arthroscopy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Controlled Hypotension Guided by Cerebral Oxygen Saturation Monitoring on Postoperative Cognitive Function of Elderly Patients Undergoing Shoulder Arthroscopy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-Sen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-Sen University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To observe whether adjusting the level of intraoperative controlled hypotension through&#xD;
      cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring can improve postoperative cognitive function(POCD) and&#xD;
      reduce postoperative neurological complications, a prospective randomized controlled study&#xD;
      method will be used in this study. 400 elderly patients undergoing shoulder arthroscopic&#xD;
      surgery under general anesthesia combined with brachial plexus block will be selected. They&#xD;
      will be randomly divided into control group and experimental group according to whether&#xD;
      cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring was used during the operation. The control group&#xD;
      maintain the target blood pressure only according to the controlled hypotension guideline,&#xD;
      and the experimental group adjust the controlled hypotension level under the guidance of&#xD;
      cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring. The general condition, operation, anesthesia and&#xD;
      hospitalization related data of the patients will be recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cognitive function will be evaluated within 3 days before operation and 3 days, 14 days and 3&#xD;
      months after operation. Delirium and VAS pain score will be evaluated 24 hours after&#xD;
      operation. Venous blood will be taken before operation and 24 hours after operation to detect&#xD;
      cognitive related markers and inflammatory factors. In addition, 10 blood samples of patients&#xD;
      in each group were selected for RNA omics test. One month, six months and 12 months after&#xD;
      operation, cognitive function was evaluated by cognitive function telephone questionnaire&#xD;
      (TICS-M), and the ability of daily living was evaluated by IDAL. In addition, 20 non-surgical&#xD;
      patients were selected for cognitive function evaluation at the same time point as the&#xD;
      exercise effect of POCD detection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 15, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Recruited patients will be randomly divided into control group and experimental group according to whether cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring was used during the operation. The control group maintain the target blood pressure only according to the controlled hypotension guideline, and the experimental group adjust the controlled hypotension level under the guidance of cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>In this study, different researchers will be responsible for randomization, anesthesia and visit. A researcher is responsible for assigning random numbers to ensure the randomness of the study groups. Due to the intraoperative monitoring of cerebral oxygen saturation in the experimental group, it is impossible to blind the researchers implementing anesthesia. In order to ensure that the whole study is not affected by subjective factors, the visiting researchers are blinded, who do not know the anesthesia grouping, and are responsible for case enrollment screening, signing informed consent, preoperative and postoperative cognitive function evaluation, postoperative pain evaluation, complications and safety evaluation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of postoperative cognitive dysfunction(POCD) 3 days after operation</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days after operation</time_frame>
    <description>The Neuropsychological test, includes: (1) Vocabulary learning; (2) Vocabulary recall; (3) Connection test; (4) Stroop Color word interference; (5) Letter-number coding test.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of postoperative cognitive dysfunction(POCD) 14 days after operation</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days after operation</time_frame>
    <description>The Neuropsychological test, includes: (1) Vocabulary learning; (2) Vocabulary recall; (3) Connection test; (4) Stroop Color word interference; (5) Letter-number coding test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of postoperative cognitive dysfunction(POCD) 3 months after operation</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months after operation</time_frame>
    <description>The Neuropsychological test, includes: (1) Vocabulary learning; (2) Vocabulary recall; (3) Connection test; (4) Stroop Color word interference; (5) Letter-number coding test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Expression changes of cognitive function related markers 24 hours after operation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after operation</time_frame>
    <description>Patients consented on blood sampling receive marker analysis from blood（S100β、NSE and IL-6).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>through hospitalization period, an average of 15 day</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital expenses</measure>
    <time_frame>through hospitalization period, an average of 15 day</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital expenses</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perioperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day (during the surgical period)</time_frame>
    <description>Complications during the surgical period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Complications and adverse reactions of patients during the study period</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Cerebral Oxygen Saturation</condition>
  <condition>Postoperative Cognitive Function</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group maintain the target blood pressure only according to the controlled hypotension guideline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The experimental group adjust the controlled hypotension level under the guidance of cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Controlled hypotension guided by cerebral oxygen saturation monitoring</intervention_name>
    <description>In this group, intraoperative monitoring of cerebral oxygen saturation will be used. When the cerebral oxygen saturation decreased by 20% ~ 25% compared with the baseline for 300 seconds without improvement, or the cerebral oxygen saturation decreased by 25% ~ 30% compared with the baseline for 180 seconds without improvement, intervention would be carried out. When the cerebral oxygen saturation decreased by 30% compared with the baseline, immediate intervention would be carried out. The intervention measures were intravenous administration of deoxyepinephrine 50 ~ 100 μg or ephedrine 5 ~ 10mg, which can be administered multiple times until the cerebral oxygen saturation reaches more than 80% of the baseline.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing elective shoulder arthroscopic surgery under general anesthesia&#xD;
             combined with brachial plexus block;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA grade ≤ grade III;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients Can communicate normally, can cooperate and complete cognitive function test;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients volunteered and signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt; 18 or &gt; 27 kg / m2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of dementia, psychosis or other central nervous system diseases or&#xD;
             mental diseases, such as cerebral infarction, stroke, Parkinson's disease, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients taking sedatives or antidepressants;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcoholics or drug addicts;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Illiteracy, severe hearing or visual impairment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cognitive impairment before operation (MMSE score &lt; 23);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with peripheral vascular diseases and contraindication of arterial puncture&#xD;
             and catheterization;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to carry out long-term follow-up or poor compliance.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <reference>
    <citation>Daiello LA, Racine AM, Yun Gou R, Marcantonio ER, Xie Z, Kunze LJ, Vlassakov KV, Inouye SK, Jones RN, Alsop D, Travison T, Arnold S, Cooper Z, Dickerson B, Fong T, Metzger E, Pascual-Leone A, Schmitt EM, Shafi M, Cavallari M, Dai W, Dillon ST, McElhaney J, Guttmann C, Hshieh T, Kuchel G, Libermann T, Ngo L, Press D, Saczynski J, Vasunilashorn S, O'Connor M, Kimchi E, Strauss J, Wong B, Belkin M, Ayres D, Callery M, Pomposelli F, Wright J, Schermerhorn M, Abrantes T, Albuquerque A, Bertrand S, Brown A, Callahan A, D'Aquila M, Dowal S, Fox M, Gallagher J, Anna Gersten R, Hodara A, Helfand B, Inloes J, Kettell J, Kuczmarska A, Nee J, Nemeth E, Ochsner L, Palihnich K, Parisi K, Puelle M, Rastegar S, Vella M, Xu G, Bryan M, Guess J, Enghorn D, Gross A, Gou Y, Habtemariam D, Isaza I, Kosar C, Rockett C, Tommet D, Gruen T, Ross M, Tasker K, Gee J, Kolanowski A, Pisani M, de Rooij S, Rogers S, Studenski S, Stern Y, Whittemore A, Gottlieb G, Orav J, Sperling R; SAGES Study Group*. Postoperative Delirium and Postoperative Cognitive Dysfunction: Overlap and Divergence. Anesthesiology. 2019 Sep;131(3):477-491. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0000000000002729.</citation>
    <PMID>31166241</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Steinmetz J, Christensen KB, Lund T, Lohse N, Rasmussen LS; ISPOCD Group. Long-term consequences of postoperative cognitive dysfunction. Anesthesiology. 2009 Mar;110(3):548-55. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0b013e318195b569.</citation>
    <PMID>19225398</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Evered LA, Silbert BS, Scott DA, Maruff P, Ames D. Prevalence of Dementia 7.5 Years after Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery. Anesthesiology. 2016 Jul;125(1):62-71. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0000000000001143.</citation>
    <PMID>27127919</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Krenk L, Rasmussen LS, Kehlet H. New insights into the pathophysiology of postoperative cognitive dysfunction. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2010 Sep;54(8):951-6. doi: 10.1111/j.1399-6576.2010.02268.x. Epub 2010 Jul 12.</citation>
    <PMID>20626359</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moller JT, Cluitmans P, Rasmussen LS, Houx P, Rasmussen H, Canet J, Rabbitt P, Jolles J, Larsen K, Hanning CD, Langeron O, Johnson T, Lauven PM, Kristensen PA, Biedler A, van Beem H, Fraidakis O, Silverstein JH, Beneken JE, Gravenstein JS. Long-term postoperative cognitive dysfunction in the elderly ISPOCD1 study. ISPOCD investigators. International Study of Post-Operative Cognitive Dysfunction. Lancet. 1998 Mar 21;351(9106):857-61. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(97)07382-0. Erratum In: Lancet 1998 Jun 6;351(9117):1742.</citation>
    <PMID>9525362</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Newman MF, Grocott HP, Mathew JP, White WD, Landolfo K, Reves JG, Laskowitz DT, Mark DB, Blumenthal JA; Neurologic Outcome Research Group and the Cardiothoracic Anesthesia Research Endeavors (CARE) Investigators of the Duke Heart Center. Report of the substudy assessing the impact of neurocognitive function on quality of life 5 years after cardiac surgery. Stroke. 2001 Dec 1;32(12):2874-81. doi: 10.1161/hs1201.099803.</citation>
    <PMID>11739990</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Needham MJ, Webb CE, Bryden DC. Postoperative cognitive dysfunction and dementia: what we need to know and do. Br J Anaesth. 2017 Dec 1;119(suppl_1):i115-i125. doi: 10.1093/bja/aex354.</citation>
    <PMID>29161395</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tang L, Kazan R, Taddei R, Zaouter C, Cyr S, Hemmerling TM. Reduced cerebral oxygen saturation during thoracic surgery predicts early postoperative cognitive dysfunction. Br J Anaesth. 2012 Apr;108(4):623-9. doi: 10.1093/bja/aer501. Epub 2012 Feb 5.</citation>
    <PMID>22311364</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim J, Shim JK, Song JW, Kim EK, Kwak YL. Postoperative Cognitive Dysfunction and the Change of Regional Cerebral Oxygen Saturation in Elderly Patients Undergoing Spinal Surgery. Anesth Analg. 2016 Aug;123(2):436-44. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000001352.</citation>
    <PMID>27285000</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Tournay-Jette E, Dupuis G, Bherer L, Deschamps A, Cartier R, Denault A. The relationship between cerebral oxygen saturation changes and postoperative cognitive dysfunction in elderly patients after coronary artery bypass graft surgery. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2011 Feb;25(1):95-104. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2010.03.019. Epub 2010 Jul 22.</citation>
    <PMID>20650659</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nilsson PM. The J-shaped curve in secondary prevention: shall clinical practice change? Hypertension. 2012 Jan;59(1):8-9. doi: 10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.111.182774. Epub 2011 Nov 7. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>22068873</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Erdem AF, Kayabasoglu G, Tas Tuna A, Palabiyik O, Tomak Y, Beyaz SG. Effect of controlled hypotension on regional cerebral oxygen saturation during rhinoplasty: a prospective study. J Clin Monit Comput. 2016 Oct;30(5):655-60. doi: 10.1007/s10877-015-9768-6. Epub 2015 Sep 10.</citation>
    <PMID>26358703</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cox RM, Jamgochian GC, Nicholson K, Wong JC, Namdari S, Abboud JA. The effectiveness of cerebral oxygenation monitoring during arthroscopic shoulder surgery in the beach chair position: a randomized blinded study. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2018 Apr;27(4):692-700. doi: 10.1016/j.jse.2017.11.004. Epub 2018 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>29396097</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salazar D, Sears BW, Aghdasi B, Only A, Francois A, Tonino P, Marra G. Cerebral desaturation events during shoulder arthroscopy in the beach chair position: patient risk factors and neurocognitive effects. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2013 Sep;22(9):1228-35. doi: 10.1016/j.jse.2012.12.036. Epub 2013 Feb 15.</citation>
    <PMID>23415820</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 11, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 11, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>controlled hypotension</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

