<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05790538</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00021969</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-05944</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>STUDY00021969</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>R01CA248059</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05790538</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Predicting the Impact of Treatment Toxicities on Health During Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>PATTERN</acronym>
  <official_title>PATTERN: Predicting the Impact of Treatment Toxicities on Health During Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Oregon Health and Science University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study investigates the effects of treatment with chemotherapy for cancer on symptoms,&#xD;
      function, and falls during treatment and through a one-year recovery period. The goal is to&#xD;
      identify simple tests that can help medical providers predict which and when patients show&#xD;
      increased risk for falls and functional decline and inform rehabilitation providers about&#xD;
      which mobility deficits to target.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aggressive treatments for cancer have improved survival, but often cause serious long-term&#xD;
      adverse effects on daily life that last for many years. Chemotherapy-induced peripheral&#xD;
      neuropathy (CIPN) is a persistent cancer treatment-related symptom that may negatively impact&#xD;
      physical functioning, falls, and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The persistence of CIPN symptoms and their relationship with life-threatening falls and&#xD;
      disability point to a gap in oncology and follow-up care. A critical first step toward&#xD;
      filling this gap is to characterize the natural trajectories of symptoms, functioning, and&#xD;
      falls across the in-treatment and recovery phases of cancer care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will prospectively enroll 200 adults with cancer that are scheduled to receive&#xD;
      neurotoxic chemotherapy at the Portland campus of Oregon Health &amp; Science University, 5 OHSU&#xD;
      Knight Cancer Institute community hematology-oncology clinics, and OHSU research affiliate&#xD;
      sites. Data collection occurs at patients' routine clinical appointments and at home via&#xD;
      electronic surveys and passive monitoring devices. In the clinic, data collection occurs at&#xD;
      4-6 week intervals during treatment according to each patient's infusion schedule, and then&#xD;
      approximately every 3 months for an additional year during routine follow-up care.&#xD;
      Clinic-based assessments include tests of perceived sensation (tuning fork, monofilament, and&#xD;
      biothesiometer), upper body strength (handgrip dynamometry), lower body strength (chair stand&#xD;
      test), static balance (postural sway), and dynamic balance (Timed Up and Go test).&#xD;
      Non-clinic-based data collection occurs weekly and assesses symptoms and falls via web-based&#xD;
      surveys. At time points corresponding to clinic testing visits, participants are sent home&#xD;
      with passive monitoring devices (instrumented socks and wrist-worn activity monitors) that&#xD;
      measure physical activity and mobility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To characterize trajectories of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy (CIPN) symptoms&#xD;
      and physical functioning (physical activity, mobility, self-report functioning and&#xD;
      disability) and capture the variability in different patient trajectories across treatment&#xD;
      and one year of recovery among persons receiving neurotoxic chemotherapy for cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine whether or not patient characteristics alone can predict symptom and functioning&#xD;
      trajectories or if adding clinical factors and simple tests of mobility significantly&#xD;
      improves predictive capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients complete surveys and clinic assessments at baseline, every 4-6 weeks during&#xD;
      chemotherapy, and then every 3 months for 1 year after completion of chemotherapy. Clinic&#xD;
      assessments include tests of neuropathy, upper and lower body strength, balance, and&#xD;
      mobility. Patients complete weekly symptom surveys and wear instrumented socks and an&#xD;
      activity monitor at regular intervals at home during chemotherapy treatment and for 1 year&#xD;
      after completion of chemotherapy. Patients' medical records are also reviewed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient-reported neuropathy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the neuropathy subscale of the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - Gynecologic Oncology Group Neurotoxicity (FACT-GOG-NTX-13) questionnaire, which assesses the presence, severity and impact of neuropathy symptoms in patients receiving neurotoxic chemotherapy. The scale ranges from 0-52, with lower scores indicating worse quality of life due to neuropathy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient-reported neuropathy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the Patient-Reported Outcomes version of the Common Toxicity Criteria and Adverse Events version 1.0 (PRO-CTCAE™) reporting tool. Two items from the PRO-CTCAE™ ask if the patient experienced numbness or tingling in the hands or feet in the last 7 days using a 5-pt scale (0=none to 4=very severe) and how much the symptom interfered with their daily life using a 5-pt scale (0=not at all to 4=very much).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in perceived disability</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the disability component of the Late-Life Function and Disability Instrument (LLFDI) which assesses disability in terms of frequency and limitation in performing 16 life tasks. Scores range from 0 to 100, with higher scores indicating less disability.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in daily functional mobility</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using instrumented socks (APDM.com) with inertial sensors embedded into neoprene ankle wraps. Patients wear the instrumented socks during waking hours over 7-day periods that correspond to each in-clinic assessment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in daily physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using ActiGraph GT9X Link devices. The ActiGraph algorithms generate accurate and reliable data on total energy expenditure (kcal/d). Patients wear the devices over 7-day periods that correspond to each in-clinic assessment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Falls</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Falls over the past 12 months will be assessed retrospectively at baseline and prospectively at weekly intervals using in-house surveys. These surveys ask subjects about the number of falls, the number of injurious falls, and medical care resulting from a fall during the observation period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer - Quality of Life Questionnaire for Cancer (QLQ-C30). Global quality of life and subdomains of quality of life are scored from 0-100, with higher scores indicating better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient-reported symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed weekly with the Patient Reported Outcomes - Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (PRO-CTCAE™) reporting tool items. The PRO-CTCAE™ uses 5-pt scales to assess the severity (0=none to 4=very severe), frequency (0=never to 4=almost constantly), and interference (0=not at all to 4=very much) of symptoms in daily life within the previous 7 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in objective loss of perceived sensation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using a tuning fork</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in objective loss of perceived sensation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using a monofilament test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in objective loss of perceived sensation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using biothesiometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in upper extremity strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by handgrip dynamometry.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in static balance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by a postural sway test that assesses how well a person maintains their balance during 30 seconds of quiet standing using Mobility Lab sensors and software (APDM.com). Increased sway indicates poor balance control and is associated with increased risk of falls.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in functional mobility</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Timed Up and Go (TUG) test. The TUG test evaluates the time that it takes a person to rise from a chair, walk 3 meters, then turn around and return to the chair in a seated position. Slower TUG times are associated with an increased risk of falls and disability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in objective functional strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by a timed chair stand test (seconds required to rise from a chair 5 times). Chair stand time &gt;12 seconds has been shown to predict a 2.4 increased risk of falls in older adults.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in skeletal muscle index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year after completion of chemotherapy (average of 16 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinically acquired abdominal and thoracic computed tomography images will be segmented into fat and lean tissue compartments according to their non-overlapping radiodensity ranges. Skeletal muscle index is calculated as skeletal muscle cross-sectional area divided by height in meters squared.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematopoietic and Lymphoid Cell Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (survey, assessment, instrumented socks, activity monitor)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients complete surveys and clinic assessments at baseline, every 4-6 weeks during chemotherapy, and every 3 months for 1 year after completion of chemotherapy. Clinic assessments include tests of neuropathy, upper and lower body strength, balance, and mobility. Patients complete weekly symptom surveys and wear instrumented socks and an activity monitor at regular intervals at home during chemotherapy treatment and for 1 year after completion of chemotherapy. Patients' medical records are also reviewed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Assessment of Therapy Complications</intervention_name>
    <description>Complete clinic assessments</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (survey, assessment, instrumented socks, activity monitor)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Electronic Health Record Review</intervention_name>
    <description>Medical records are reviewed</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (survey, assessment, instrumented socks, activity monitor)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medical Device Usage and Evaluation</intervention_name>
    <description>Wear instrumented socks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (survey, assessment, instrumented socks, activity monitor)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medical Device Usage and Evaluation</intervention_name>
    <description>Wear activity monitor</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (survey, assessment, instrumented socks, activity monitor)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Survey Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Complete surveys</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (survey, assessment, instrumented socks, activity monitor)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with stage I-III cancer, or stage IV cancer considered curable, without neurologic&#xD;
        involvement who are scheduled to receive neurotoxic chemotherapy at Oregon Health &amp; Science&#xD;
        University (OHSU) Knight Cancer Institute&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 40-85 years old on date of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with stage I-III cancer, or stage IV cancer considered curable, other than&#xD;
             cancers or metastases in the brain or spinal cord&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scheduled to receive any neurotoxic chemotherapy including taxane derivatives,&#xD;
             platinum complexes, and/or vinca alkaloids&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously received neurotoxic chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive difficulties that preclude answering the survey questions, participating in&#xD;
             the performance tests, or giving informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A medical condition, movement or neurological disorder, or medication use that&#xD;
             contraindicates participation in mobility testing and/or that confounds the ability to&#xD;
             detect treatment-related changes in balance and mobility. Specific medical conditions&#xD;
             include, but are not limited to, severe dystrophy, severe spasticity, epilepsy,&#xD;
             seizures, Alzheimer's and dementia, while physical conditions include a severe balance&#xD;
             disorder (e.g., later-stage Parkinson's, stroke), inability to ambulate (use of an&#xD;
             assistive device permitted), inability to stand for 3 minutes, or severe hearing or&#xD;
             vision problem.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kerri Winters-Stone</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97239</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kerri Winters-Stone</last_name>
      <phone>503-494-0813</phone>
      <email>wintersk@ohsu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kerri Winters-Stone</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 16, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 16, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>OHSU Knight Cancer Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kerri Winters</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

