<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612620</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0140-21-AAA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612620</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Elucidating the Microbiome in Patients With Recurrent Pregnancy Loss</brief_title>
  <official_title>Elucidating the Microbiome in Patients With Recurrent Pregnancy Loss Vs. Patients Without Gynecological or Obstetrical Conditions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assuta Ashdod Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assuta Ashdod Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recurrent pregnancy loss (RPL) is defined as 2 or more consecutive miscarriages1 This&#xD;
      condition affects about 1-3% of couples during their reproductive years. The role of vaginal&#xD;
      infections in RPL is controversial and microbiological screening is not recommended as per&#xD;
      the international guidelines. Current theories suggest that altered vaginal and uterine&#xD;
      microbiota may trigger an inflammatory response in the endometrium even without the presence&#xD;
      of clinical infection which could affect the success of embryo implantation and future&#xD;
      development of pregnancy2 .Changes in the uterine microbiota can lead to chronic endometritis&#xD;
      (CE). This condition is caused by continuing inflammation of the endometrium, involving a&#xD;
      variety of common bacterial and yeast species and has been associated with RPL3 . Notably, CE&#xD;
      can be found in up to 45% of infertile patients4. Current diagnosis of CE is based on&#xD;
      histopathological examination, immunohistochemistry assay for CD138 cells and morphological&#xD;
      appearance on hysteroscopy. While antibiotic treatment can improve ongoing pregnancy rates in&#xD;
      patients with RPL treatment success is still partial and unpredictable. A mechanistic link is&#xD;
      yet to be established between vaginal and uterine microbiota and RPL and it is unknown&#xD;
      whether restoration of the microbiome in patients with RPL can improve pregnancy outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aims The aim of the current study is to evaluate vaginal and intrauterine microbiota in women&#xD;
      with recurrent pregnancy loss (RPL) as compared to normal controls. Ultimately we would like&#xD;
      to assess whether women with RPL have a characteristic microbiome which may be significantly&#xD;
      different microbiota of healthy patients in our study population. This could later lead to&#xD;
      treatment with a tailored microbiota transplantation approach involving healthy vaginal&#xD;
      microbiota for the treatment of patients with RPL and implement it in a prospective&#xD;
      randomized controlled trial in order to modulate the reproductive tract microbiota and&#xD;
      achieve and improved pregnancy outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      A rapidly growing field in biologic research of human health and disease is that of&#xD;
      microbiome research. The microbiome inhabiting the female reproductive tract has long been&#xD;
      suspected to play an important role in health and disease. Current theories suggest that&#xD;
      altered microbiota even without clinical infection may trigger an inflammatory response in&#xD;
      the endometrium. It affects the success of embryo implantation and future development of&#xD;
      pregnancy.5 Most studies deal with genital tract microbiome in patients with repeated&#xD;
      implantation failure in IVF, however, some studies have also found altered microbiome in&#xD;
      patients with recurrent pregnancy loss (RPL)6 Vaginal and endometrial microbiotas might be&#xD;
      independent. Endometrial microbiota has a richer alpha diversity than vaginal microbiota, and&#xD;
      dysbiosis of vaginal or endometrial microbiota can cause implantation failure. Unlike&#xD;
      previous reports, Ichiyama et al reports that the Lactobacillus rate in the vagina, but not&#xD;
      the endometrium, may be a biomarker for repeated implantation failure7 Small studies showed&#xD;
      association between spontaneous abortion and abnormal vaginal microbiome( 60% intermediate&#xD;
      flora, 20% BV condition), with higher levels of selected metabolites in the vaginal&#xD;
      environment (e.g., inosine, fumarate, xanthine, benzoate, ascorbate)8 Recurrent pregnancy&#xD;
      loss (RPL) is defined American Society for Reproductive medicine as two or more spontaneous&#xD;
      miscarriages before gestational week 22 (not necessarily consecutive) The role of vaginal&#xD;
      infections in RPL is controversial and screening for infections is not routinely recommended&#xD;
      in patients with RPL9&#xD;
&#xD;
      Major immune cells in the human endometrium include uterine Natural Killer (uNK) cells,&#xD;
      macrophages, dendritic cells (DCs) and T cells. Each of these cell populations demonstrated a&#xD;
      specific role. uNK are involved in the success of implantation and maintenance of pregnancy&#xD;
      through their ability both to interact through inhibitor receptors with HLA-G, HLA-E and&#xD;
      HLA-C expressed on trophoblast cells and to produce angiogenic factors Kuon et al in their&#xD;
      small study described that RPL patients with elevated pNK suffer more often from colonization&#xD;
      by Gardnerella vaginalis and gram-negative anaerobes . This might indicate an association&#xD;
      between the vaginal microbiota, local inflammation, changes in immune parameters and&#xD;
      miscarriage.10 Like the vaginal microbiome, the endometrial microbiome is usually dominated&#xD;
      by Lactobacilli. 11 A recent studies illustrated that the presence of a&#xD;
      non-Lactobacillus-dominating microbiome in endometrial fluid of IVF patients was associated&#xD;
      with significantly lower implantation, pregnancy and live birth rates 12 13 According to&#xD;
      researches microbiota composition in endometrial fluid does not fully reflect that in&#xD;
      endometrial tissue.14 However, only few studies have directly probed the microbes within the&#xD;
      uterine environment and how these microbes could influence in implantation , the majority of&#xD;
      them in IVF cycles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      First trimester miscarriage can be associated with reduced prevalence of Lactobacillus spp.&#xD;
      and with changes in the relative abundance of several bacterial genera, including&#xD;
      Fam_Finegoldia, Lac_Coprococcus_3, and Lac_Roseburia 15 16&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chen W et al showed the relative abundances of Actinobacteria and Fusobacteria in the so&#xD;
      called Chronic endometritis group at the phylum level.At the genus level, high relative&#xD;
      abundances of Gardnerella were observed in the Chronic endometriosis and non-pregnancy&#xD;
      groups, which significantly referred to the negative IVF outcome17&#xD;
&#xD;
      Settings and participants All patients referred to Assuta Ashdod university hospital due to&#xD;
      RPL, meeting the inclusion criteria, will be offered recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • women aged 18-40 years old, with two or more consecutive miscarriages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  documented past PID,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  previous history of uterine malformations,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  patients with hyperplasia and endometrial cancer,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  patients with IUD and antimicrobial treatment in the preceding 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study methodology and techniques&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design&#xD;
&#xD;
      After obtaining informed consent we will collect samples from 4 anatomical locations: lower&#xD;
      third of vagina (before speculum placement), posterior fornix and cervical canal ( after&#xD;
      sterile speculum placement), and a sample of gut microbiome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size - 20 women for each pathology in the research group and 20 women control group,&#xD;
      this is similar to other studies on the subject 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following data will be collected from medical records:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  age,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ethnicity,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  BMI,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lifestyle: tobacco use, Number of partners in the past 6 months, diet, hygienic&#xD;
           procedures,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Gynecological and obstetrical history: gravidity, parity, menarche time, regularity of&#xD;
           menstrual cycle,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Type and duration of contraception,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Symptoms: pain, menometrorrhagia,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sonographic findings,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples from the vagina, fornix and cervical canal will be taken by introducing a flocked&#xD;
      nylon swab to the vagina via a speculum and circular swabbing for 5-10 seconds before using&#xD;
      any antiseptics. Thus a total of 160 samples (3 patients groups (n=20*2) * 4 samples) will be&#xD;
      taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples will be snap frozen at -80c and kept until further analysis. Batched swab specimens&#xD;
      will undergo microbial DNA extraction using standard protocols of the Human Microbiome&#xD;
      Project (HMP). Following extraction, a PCR reaction for 16S RNA gene amplification will be&#xD;
      performed using HMP primers sets. 16S amplicons will be sequenced using an Illumina&#xD;
      next-generation sequencing platforms (PE 250bpX2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sequencing data will be analyzed at the Moran-Gilad lab, Ben-Gurion University. The&#xD;
      bioinformatics analysis will be based on the QIIME software package pipeline18 . Briefly,&#xD;
      microbiome data will be analyzed using standard methods for rarefaction, alpha and beta&#xD;
      diversity and abundance of taxa at different taxonomical levels. The ANOVA test will be used&#xD;
      to determine if OTU relative abundance is different between samples, the G test of&#xD;
      independence will be used to determine association of OTU presence/absence with a specific&#xD;
      category, and significant variation between sample groups will be analyzed using DESeq2 R&#xD;
      package 19on the raw non-normalized OTU biom table.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment strategy&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited from outpatients clinic at the Samson Assuta University Hospital&#xD;
      in accordance with a protocol that is under approval process of the local Institutional&#xD;
      Review Board (IRB).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator will inform the patient about the study, its purpose, and method of&#xD;
      randomization of study groups. Patients will not be cajoled into participating in this study.&#xD;
      The Investigator will discuss foreseeable risks involved, as well as potential benefits, for&#xD;
      each study group. Patients who have consented to having their information obtained during the&#xD;
      study for analysis of the results will have their confidentiality maintained at all times&#xD;
      using a study code as an identifier in the research database. The patients will be informed&#xD;
      by the Investigator that their medical treatment will not be affected in any mean by their&#xD;
      decision whether to participate or not in the study. Patients will be informed that they may&#xD;
      choose to withdraw from the study at any stage without jeopardizing any further medical care.&#xD;
      A signed and dated Informed Consent must be obtained by the Investigator from the patient&#xD;
      prior to enrolment into this study. The original signed and dated information sheet and&#xD;
      patient consent will be kept by the Investigator. A signed copy will be provided to the&#xD;
      patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis will be performed using R software environment for statistical computing&#xD;
      and graphics. Categorical variable data will be presented using percentile and statistical&#xD;
      significance will be tested using the X² or Fisher's exact test, as appropriate. Ordinal&#xD;
      variable data will be presented using median and inter quartile range and statistical&#xD;
      significance will be analyzed using Mann Whitney test. Continuous variable data will be&#xD;
      presented using mean and standard deviation, Student t test will be used for statistical&#xD;
      analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study protocol will be submitted to Assuta Ashdod University Hospital Ethics committee&#xD;
      for approval. The study will be conducted in accordance with the ethical principles&#xD;
      originating from the Declaration of Helsinki and GCP (ICH E6) and in compliance with local&#xD;
      regulatory requirements. Participants' identity will be kept confidential, and to the extent&#xD;
      permitted by the applicable laws and/or regulations, will not be made publicly available. If&#xD;
      the study results are published, the participants' identity will remain confidential.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed consent will be obtained in accordance with ICH/GCP Guidelines and the Declaration&#xD;
      of Helsinki and will be implemented before protocol specific procedures are carried out. The&#xD;
      risks and benefits of participating in the study will be verbally explained to each potential&#xD;
      participant prior to signing the consent form in accordance with local regulatory legal&#xD;
      requirements. The signed consent form will be retained by the investigator and a copy&#xD;
      provided to each participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Source Documentation&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator will keep accurate separate records of all participants' study data&#xD;
      collected, including all pertinent study related information. The investigators are committed&#xD;
      to thorough documentation of all side effects and Adverse Events during the study in a&#xD;
      participant study binder including any diagnostic tests conducted during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All study documentation will be kept for 15 years after all participants have completed and&#xD;
      all data has been collected. The IRB/IEC will be notified in writing of the study completion&#xD;
      and archive site.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 14, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Month</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiome differences in patients with repeat pregnancy loss and healthy population</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>microbiome data will be analyzed using standard methods for rarefaction, alpha and beta diversity and abundance of taxa at different taxonomical levels. A statistical analysis will be performed in order to evaluate if there is a significant difference in the presence of different bacteria strains in patients with a history of RPL and healthy controls</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Microbiome</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Pregnancy Loss</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RPL</arm_group_label>
    <description>Samples from the vagina, fornix and cervical canal and rectum will be taken by introducing a flocked nylon swab to the vagina via a speculum and circular swabbing for 5-10 seconds before using any antiseptics.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Samples from the vagina, fornix and cervical canal and rectum will be taken by introducing a flocked nylon swab to the vagina via a speculum and circular swabbing for 5-10 seconds before using any antiseptics.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>coulture</intervention_name>
    <description>Samples from the vagina, fornix and cervical canal will be taken by introducing a flocked nylon swab to the vagina via a speculum and circular swabbing for 5-10 seconds before using any antiseptics.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RPL</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Samples from uterine discharge vaginal discharge and stool samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with two or more consecutive miscarriages ages 18-40 With a normal uterine cavity&#xD;
        as per hysteroscopy, no chromosomal abnormalities and negative APLA test.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • women aged 18-40 years old, with two or more consecutive miscarriages.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • documented past PID,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  previous history of uterine malformations,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  patients with hyperplasia and endometrial cancer,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  patients with IUD and antimicrobial treatment in the preceding 4 weeks.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oshri Barel, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assuta Ashdod Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assuta Ashdod University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ashdod</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Abortion, Spontaneous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fetal Death</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Abortion, Habitual</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

