<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792345</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PEPOST 2022-01964</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792345</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Post-operative Analgesia in Pediatric Superficial TTMPB</brief_title>
  <acronym>PEPOST</acronym>
  <official_title>Comparison of Post-operative Analgesia in Pediatric Superficial TTMPB</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      When a patient is to undergo heart surgery with a sternotomy, a transthoracic block is&#xD;
      performed. The thoracic block is an analgesic technique which consists of injecting&#xD;
      anesthetic product into the nerves, in order to avoid significant pain. The common technique&#xD;
      is to make injections in the sternum by the surgeon. A new, increasingly widespread method is&#xD;
      performed by the anesthetist who performs the block under ultrasound.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This research project aims to determine if performing this transthoracic block under&#xD;
      ultrasound is more effective than injections performed by the surgeon without ultrasound.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiac surgery, and more specifically associated sternotomy, leads to severe pain in the&#xD;
      postoperative period. Adequate analgesia is therefore challenging, but of paramount&#xD;
      importance to reduce associated side effects such as pulmonary hypertensive crisis,&#xD;
      tachyarrhythmia, systemic hypertension, hypoxia, and increased morbidity and length of stay.&#xD;
      Actual opioid crisis and risks associated with intravenous analgesics raises the question of&#xD;
      having an alternative and better approach to relieve severe pain. Currently in the&#xD;
      postoperative suites opiates are also used for sedative purposes. This strategy of sedation&#xD;
      has to change. Recent advances in regional anaesthesia could be the answer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thoracic epidural or paravertebral blocks provide effective analgesia for open cardiac&#xD;
      surgery in paediatric patients. However, the major risk of epidural hematomas caused by&#xD;
      heparinization, hemodynamic instability, technical difficulties and pneumothorax has limited&#xD;
      the application of these two techniques in open cardiac surgery, and promoted the development&#xD;
      of new approaches with safe, reliable, and cost-effective techniques, such as&#xD;
      ultrasound-guided peripheral nerve blocks. This might be the most effective method for pain&#xD;
      management in paediatric patients undergoing cardiac surgery according to recent studies.&#xD;
      Superficial Thoracic Transversus Muscle Plane Block has been recently described and evaluated&#xD;
      for pain management in adult cardiac surgery. It works through the blockade of multiple&#xD;
      anterior branches of the intercostal nerves (Th2-6) in the internal mammary region. It has&#xD;
      also been described in children in a few papers: Zhang and al. in a randomized controlled&#xD;
      trial in 100 children, Abdelbaser and al. conducted a randomized double blind study including&#xD;
      80 children. In these studies, the injection of local anaesthetics was made between the&#xD;
      intercostal and transversus thoracis muscles. But in very small children, the risk of pleura&#xD;
      or internal mammary artery puncture associated with this injection is relatively important.&#xD;
      Superficial TTMPB (located between the intercostal and pectoralis major muscles) seems to&#xD;
      have the same analgesic potency without the aforementioned risks.That is to say that TTMPB is&#xD;
      better than nothing but, to our knowledge, there is no study comparing infiltration by&#xD;
      surgeon and TTMPB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The risks of the procedure are the same with all regional anaesthesia, which are vascular or&#xD;
      nerves punction, hematoma and failure of anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is set up to test the hypothesis that analgesia performed by TTMPB may have a&#xD;
      better antalgic effect than blocks made by surgeons, in patients who undergo cardiac&#xD;
      sternotomy. At first, the standard in CHUV was injections made by surgeon. Nowadays the&#xD;
      decision of technic used is made with a discussion between anesthesist and surgeon during&#xD;
      operative time. The investigators want to bring an evidence based decision with this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioids dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Hour 24 post-operative.</time_frame>
    <description>Opioids dose administered for analgesia in mg and divided by patient weight in kg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioids dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 at Hour 4, 12 and Day 1 post-operative</time_frame>
    <description>Opioids dose administered for analgesia in mg and divided by patient weight in kg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to extubation</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of arrival in the Intensive Care Unit until the time of extubation assessed up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time to extubation in minutes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose of catecholamine (noradrenaline) used</measure>
    <time_frame>At Day 0 Hour 4, 12, 24 and Day 1 post-operative</time_frame>
    <description>Total dose per kg infused</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay in ICU before discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of arrival in the Intensive Care Unit until discharge assessed up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Length of stay in ICU before discharge in days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of adverse events and adverse events of special interest (complications) such as hematomas, arterial puncture, fail of the block, pneumothorax.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>FLACC pain scale (Face, Legs, Activity, Cry, Consolability)</measure>
    <time_frame>at Day 0 at Hours 4, 12 and 24 post-operative;</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative pain evaluated by the Flacc pain scale, From 0 to 10 were 10 is the worst pain experimented by the patient and 0 is the normal state.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Regional Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Infiltration will be performed by surgeon at the site of sternotomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>With TTMPB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Regional anesthesia is performed with direct view of the nerves and vascular position</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transversus Thoracic Muscle Plane Block</intervention_name>
    <description>The transversus thoracic muscle plane block It is most commonly performed following cardiothoracic surgeries (or any surgeries requiring sternotomy) to provide analgesia to the anterior chest wall. he TTMPB, and thoracic fascial plane blocks, are increasingly being employed as part of enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) protocols for cardiothoracic procedures. They have been shown to significantly reduce both the time to extubation and the incidence of acute and chronic perioperative pain</description>
    <arm_group_label>With TTMPB</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Infiltration by surgeon</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients undergoing sternotomy for a cardiac surgery in CHUV, which is an academic&#xD;
             hospital in Switzerland.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants fulfilling all of the following inclusion criteria are eligible for the study&#xD;
        :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed Consent as documented by signature.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age from 0 to 16 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing cardiac surgery with sternotomy in CHUV, Lausanne.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patients older than 16 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sternotomy for operation other than cardiac surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Contraindication to local anesthesic, e.g. known hypersensitivity or allergy to&#xD;
                  Bupivacaine.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Infection at the site of injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not having consented for this procedure/ refusal of participation. Reoperation&#xD;
                  during the same hospitalisation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sylvain Mauron, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sylvain Mauron, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0041 79 556 47 31</phone>
    <email>sylvain.mauron@chuv.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Emeline Christophel-Plathier</last_name>
    <phone>0041 79 556 64 33</phone>
    <email>emeline.christophel@chuv.ch</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bettex DA, Schmidlin D, Chassot PG, Schmid ER. Intrathecal sufentanil-morphine shortens the duration of intubation and improves analgesia in fast-track cardiac surgery. Can J Anaesth. 2002 Aug-Sep;49(7):711-7. doi: 10.1007/BF03017451. English, French.</citation>
    <PMID>12193491</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fletcher D, Martinez V. Opioid-induced hyperalgesia in patients after surgery: a systematic review and a meta-analysis. Br J Anaesth. 2014 Jun;112(6):991-1004. doi: 10.1093/bja/aeu137.</citation>
    <PMID>24829420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aydin ME, Ahiskalioglu A, Ates I, Tor IH, Borulu F, Erguney OD, Celik M, Dogan N. Efficacy of Ultrasound-Guided Transversus Thoracic Muscle Plane Block on Postoperative Opioid Consumption After Cardiac Surgery: A Prospective, Randomized, Double-Blind Study. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2020 Nov;34(11):2996-3003. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2020.06.044. Epub 2020 Jun 18.</citation>
    <PMID>32665179</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ueshima H, Kitamura A. Blocking of Multiple Anterior Branches of Intercostal Nerves (Th2-6) Using a Transversus Thoracic Muscle Plane Block. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2015 Jul-Aug;40(4):388. doi: 10.1097/AAP.0000000000000245. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>26079353</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang Y, Chen S, Gong H, Zhan B. Efficacy of Bilateral Transversus Thoracis Muscle Plane Block in Pediatric Patients Undergoing Open Cardiac Surgery. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2020 Sep;34(9):2430-2434. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2020.02.005. Epub 2020 Feb 11.</citation>
    <PMID>32151511</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abdelbaser II, Mageed NA. Analgesic efficacy of ultrasound guided bilateral transversus thoracis muscle plane block in pediatric cardiac surgery: a randomized, double-blind, controlled study. J Clin Anesth. 2020 Dec;67:110002. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinane.2020.110002. Epub 2020 Jul 24.</citation>
    <PMID>32717448</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ohgoshi Y, Ino K, Matsukawa M. Ultrasound-guided parasternal intercostal nerve block. J Anesth. 2016 Oct;30(5):916. doi: 10.1007/s00540-016-2202-5. Epub 2016 Jun 20. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>27325411</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 18, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 18, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 18, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Eric Albrecht</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, MD, Priva Docent</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>regional anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>cardiac</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

