<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798351</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP220938</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798351</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rectal Carriage of Carbapenemase Producing-Enterobacteriaceae on Admission to a French University Teaching Hospital</brief_title>
  <acronym>Prev-CPE</acronym>
  <official_title>Prevalence of Rectal Carriage of Carbapenemase Producing-Enterobacteriaceae on Admission to a French University Teaching Hospital</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      &quot;The emergence and spread of highly resistant bacteria, including carbapenemase-producing&#xD;
      Enterobacteriaceae (CPE), is a public health challenge given their rapid spread and the lack&#xD;
      of active antibiotics against these bacteria. The spread of extended-spectrum&#xD;
      β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBLE) since the early 2000s raises concerns about&#xD;
      a potential similar spread of CPE in the coming years, especially in the healthcare setting.&#xD;
      Early detection of CPE carriage in hospitalized patients with risk factors for CPE carriage&#xD;
      is essential to prevent their spread in hospitals as well as to guide empiric antibiotic&#xD;
      therapy for CPE carriers with signs of severe infection. However, the prevalence of CPE&#xD;
      carriage on admission to hospital is not precisely known, nor are factors associated with CPE&#xD;
      carriage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hence, the investigators sought to determine the prevalence of CPE carriage and its risk&#xD;
      factors in patients admitted to hospital, in order to identify the appropriate indications&#xD;
      for CPE screening on admission to hospital. Secondly, the investigators aimed to estimate the&#xD;
      annual number of patients with CPE carriage who would not have been identified with the&#xD;
      current targeted screening policy as well as to estimate the annual number of secondary cases&#xD;
      that could be prevented if a universal screening policy was applied on admission (i.e. for&#xD;
      all hospitalized patients, not just those with risk factors).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the investigators plan to carry out a systematic screening for rectal carriage of&#xD;
      CPE on admission in a sample of patients hospitalized at the Bichat - Claude-Bernard&#xD;
      Hospital. Inclusion criteria will include: Age ≥ 18 years, admission to a medical, surgical,&#xD;
      obstetrical or intensive care unit at Bichat - Claude-Bernard Hospital in the previous 72&#xD;
      hours, no objection to participating in the study. Rectal swabs will be taken from all&#xD;
      included patients for detection of CPE and/or ESBLE. Patients' characteristics, including&#xD;
      sociodemographic data, country of birth and residence, clinical ward, current antibiotic&#xD;
      treatment and that in the last 3 months, travel abroad and last geographical areas visited,&#xD;
      hospitalization in France and abroad, and history of CPE and ESBLE carriage or infection in&#xD;
      the previous year, will be collected by questionnaire and from medical records. &quot;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &quot;Introduction The emergence and spread of emerging highly resistant bacteria, including&#xD;
      carbapenemase-producing Enterobacteriaceae (CPE), is a public health challenge given their&#xD;
      rapid spread and the lack of active antibiotics against these bacteria. The spread of&#xD;
      extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBLE) since the early 2000s&#xD;
      raises concerns about a potential similar spread of CPE in the coming years, especially in&#xD;
      the healthcare setting. Early detection of CPE carriage in hospitalized patients with risk&#xD;
      factors for CPE carriage is essential to prevent their spread in hospitals as well as to&#xD;
      guide empiric antibiotic therapy for CPE carriers with signs of severe infection. However,&#xD;
      the prevalence of CPE carriage on admission to hospital is not precisely known, nor are&#xD;
      factors associated with CPE carriage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the investigators plan to carry out a systematic screening for rectal carriage of&#xD;
      CPE on admission in a sample of patients hospitalized at the Bichat - Claude-Bernard&#xD;
      Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To determine the prevalence of CPE carriage in patients admitted to the Bichat -&#xD;
      Claude-Bernard Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the prevalence of ESBLE carriage in patients admitted to the Bichat -&#xD;
           Claude-Bernard Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the risk factors for rectal carriage of CPE and ESBLE on admission&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the annual number of patients with rectal CPE who would not have been&#xD;
           identified with the current targeted screening policy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the annual number of secondary cases that could be prevented that could be&#xD;
           prevented if a universal screening policy was applied on admission (i.e. for all&#xD;
           hospitalized patients, not just those with risk factors).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To characterize the bacterial strains and enzymes identified in CPE carriage on&#xD;
           admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods The study will be performed at a two-site 1000-bed public University&#xD;
      Hospital in Paris (France), which provides primary and tertiary care and is located in an&#xD;
      area serving a large proportion of foreign-born patients, originating mainly from Africa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current criteria for CPE screening on admission to Bichat - Claude-Bernard Hospital include :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  History of hospitalization for more than 24 hours abroad in the last 12 months (since&#xD;
           2010) or&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Travel abroad without hospitalization in the last 12 months, depending on the&#xD;
           hospitalization ward and/or the presence of risk factors such as recent return ,&#xD;
           extended stay or travel in South-East Asia (since 2018)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rectal swabs will be taken from all included patients by nursing staff or by the patients&#xD;
      themselves. Swabs will be discharged on selective media for ESBLE (ChromID ESBLE agar -&#xD;
      bioMérieux) and selective media for CPE (chromID® CARBA agar - bioMérieux and chromID®&#xD;
      OXA-48TM agar - bioMérieux). An identification by MALDI-TOF mass spectrometry and an&#xD;
      antibiogram on Mueller-Hinton agar will be carried out on each suspect colony. A GeneXpert&#xD;
      PCR (Cepheid) on suspect colonies will be carried out jointly in the event of a positive&#xD;
      culture on selective medium for the detection of CPE. In case of a positive GeneXpert PCR on&#xD;
      suspect colonies, a confirmatory GeneXpert PCR will be performed on the native sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following data will be collected from medical records and by questionnaire :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Socio-demographic characteristics of patients: Age, sex, country of birth, main country&#xD;
           of residence, place of residence before hospitalization&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Characteristics of hospital stay: Date of entry into the ward, date of entry into the&#xD;
           hospital, origin before admission&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exposure abroad: Travel/hospitalization abroad in the last 12 months for the patient,&#xD;
           travel/hospitalization abroad in the last 12 months for the person(s) living in the same&#xD;
           household as the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exposure to health care facilities: Hospitalization (&gt; 24h) in a health care facility in&#xD;
           France in the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antibiotic exposure: Antibiotic treatment received on the day of the survey or in the&#xD;
           previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  EBSLE/CPE screening: Known CPE carriage, rectal screening for CPE already taken by the&#xD;
           ward healthcare team&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size was calculated on a hypothesis of a prevalence of CPE carriage. Assuming a&#xD;
      prevalence of 0.5% based on literature data with a 95% confidence interval of [0.1% - 0.9%],&#xD;
      1195 patients should be included. The study will last 6 months with an inclusion period of 6&#xD;
      months; each patient's participation will last 1 day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main outcome will be CPE carriage; CPE carriers will be compared with non carriers.&#xD;
      Categorical variables will be compared using the Chi-2 test or Fisher's exact test and&#xD;
      continuous variables using the Student's t-test or the Mann-Whitney test. Odds ratios (OR)&#xD;
      and 95% confidence intervals (CI) will be calculated. All tests will be two-tailed and the&#xD;
      significance level will be 5%. The open-source software R for Statistical Computing will be&#xD;
      used for the statistical analysis.&quot;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with CPE carriage</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with ESBLE carriage</measure>
    <time_frame>The same rectal swab will be used for detection of CPE carriage and ESBLE carriage</time_frame>
    <description>A rectal swab will be taken within 72 hours of admission from a sample of patients admitted to the Bichat - Claude-Bernard Hospital over a 6-month period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Odds ratios associated with risk factors for CPE and ESBLE carriage on admission to hospital</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after study start</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Annual number of patients with rectal CPE carriage among those with no risk factors for CPE carriage</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after study start</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Annual number of secondary cases of CPE carriage that could be prevented if a universal admission screening policy was implemented</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after study start</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Names and percentages of bacterial species and enzymes identified in CPE screening</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after study start</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1195</enrollment>
  <condition>Rectal Carriage of Carbapenemase Producing-Enterobacteriaceae</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients admitted to an MCO (Medicine-Surgery-Obstetrics) hospitalization department&#xD;
        or intensive care unit at Bichat - Claude-Bernard Hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission to a medical, surgical, obstetrical or intensive care unit at Bichat -&#xD;
             Claude-Bernard Hospital in the previous 72 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No objection to participating in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Non-inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission to Bichat - Claude-Bernard Hospital &gt; 72 hours before inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Readmission to the same ward after discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalization in a rehabilitation unit or a long-stay unit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non affiliation to social security&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under legal protection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Solen Kernéis, MD - PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Solen Kernéis, MD - PhD</last_name>
    <phone>33140256199</phone>
    <email>solen.kerneis@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Claire Durand, MD</last_name>
    <phone>33686016726</phone>
    <email>durand.c@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 3, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 3, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 3, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Universal screening</keyword>
  <keyword>Hospital</keyword>
  <keyword>Rectal carriage</keyword>
  <keyword>Enterobacteriaceae</keyword>
  <keyword>Carbapenemase</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

