<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618847</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC&amp;Mishal Sabir</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618847</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Active Cycle of Breathing Technique With and Without Acapella on Airway Clearance</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Active Cycle of Breathing Technique With and Without Acapella on Airway Clearance, Dyspnea and Pulmonary Function Test in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We are conducting this study to check the effects of active cycle of breathing technique with&#xD;
      or without acapella on airway clearance, dyspnea and pulmonary function test in COPD&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design will be randomized controlled trial. Research will be conducted at Aziz Bhatti&#xD;
      Shaheed Teaching Hospital and National Hospital Gujrat. Written informed consent will be&#xD;
      obtained. Patients will be allocated randomly in two groups. Subjects will meet the&#xD;
      predetermined inclusion and exclusion criteria. Questionnaire used as subjective measurements&#xD;
      of dyspnea and sputum will be given and pulmonary function test values will be obtained prior&#xD;
      to any intervention. One group will receive active cycle of breathing technique and the other&#xD;
      group will receive active cycle of breathing technique with acapella device. Every subject&#xD;
      will perform supervised ACBTs with and without acapella for four weeks. Three sessions per&#xD;
      week will be given with 20 repetitions in two sets. At the end of 4 weeks treatment session,&#xD;
      pulmonary function test values will be monitored and questionnaire will be obtained for&#xD;
      dyspnea and sputum. Data will be analyzed on SPSS 25&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a non-communicable progressive and&#xD;
      non-curable disease, characterized by persistent respiratory symptoms and airflow limitation.&#xD;
      It is potentially fatal and it is the fourth cause of death in the world. Active Cycle of&#xD;
      Breathing Techniques can be used to mobilize and clear excess pulmonary secretions and to&#xD;
      generally improve lung function Loosen and clear secretions from the lungs. Three main phases&#xD;
      of Active Cycle of Breathing Techniques are Breathing Control, Deep Breathing Exercises or&#xD;
      Thoracic Expansion Exercises and Huffing or Forced Expiratory Technique. Acapella is a small&#xD;
      hand held device for airway clearance. It has both resistive and vibratory features, which&#xD;
      help to loosen and clear secretions from chest. This causes the vibration and resistance to&#xD;
      the airflow which is then transmitted to the lungs. The resistance to the airflow will help&#xD;
      to keep the airways open to get air behind the sputum and help it move upwards. The&#xD;
      vibrations will help to loosen secretions from airways and move them up more easily for&#xD;
      effective chest clearance. We are conducting this study to check the effects of active cycle&#xD;
      of breathing technique with or without acapella on airway clearance, dyspnea and pulmonary&#xD;
      function test in COPD patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design will be randomized controlled trial. Research will be conducted at Aziz Bhatti&#xD;
      Shaheed Teaching Hospital and National Hospital Gujrat. Written informed consent will be&#xD;
      obtained. Patients will be allocated randomly in two groups. Subjects will meet the&#xD;
      predetermined inclusion and exclusion criteria. Questionnaire used as subjective measurements&#xD;
      of dyspnea and sputum will be given and pulmonary function test values will be obtained prior&#xD;
      to any intervention. One group will receive active cycle of breathing technique and the other&#xD;
      group will receive active cycle of breathing technique with acapella device. Every subject&#xD;
      will perform supervised ACBTs with and without acapella for four weeks. Three sessions per&#xD;
      week will be given with 20 repetitions in two sets. At the end of 4 weeks treatment session,&#xD;
      pulmonary function test values will be monitored and questionnaire will be obtained for&#xD;
      dyspnea and sputum. Data will be analyzed on SPSS 25&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sputum diary</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The diary card has a graded symptom score for dyspnea, sputum volume and sputum color. In addition, the card includes a score for patient well-being and documented all minor symptoms (cough, chest pain, cold, or flu-like symptoms)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dyspnea-MDP scale</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile (MDP) assesses overall breathing discomfort, sensory qualities, and emotional responses</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulmonary function test</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Pulmonary function tests (PFTS) are an important tool in the investigation and monitoring of patients with respiratory pathology. They provide important information relating to the large and small airways, the pulmonary parenchyma and the size and integrity of the pulmonary capillary bed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">54</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>active cycle of breathing technique with acapella</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sit up with good posture to use the Acapella. Take in a fairly deep breath and hold it for about 3 seconds. Place the Acapella mouthpiece in your mouth. Seal your lips tightly around the mouthpiece.&#xD;
Exhale as much as possible (but not to forcefully) through the mouthpiece. Keep your cheeks as firm as possible when you exhale. Try not to inhale through the device.&#xD;
Repeat this maneuver for 10 breaths. Try to resist coughing during this phase. After these 10 blows, perform 3 huffs, then a big cough to bring the sputum up and out. Try not to swallow the mucus</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>active cycle of breathing technique</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ask patient to breathe in and out gently through nose if he/she can. If patient breathe out through their mouth. Ask patient to let go of any tension in body with each breath out. Gradually try to make the breaths slower. Ask patient to take a long, slow, deep breath in, through nose. Try to keep chest and shoulders relaxed. Repeat 3-5 times. Huff is exhaling through an open mouth and throat instead of coughing. It helps move sputum up in airways so that patient can clear it in a controlled way. To 'huff' ask patient to squeeze air quickly from lungs, out through open mouth and throat, as if trying to mist up a mirror or glasses. Ask to use abdominal muscles to help squeeze the air out, but do not force it so much that cause wheezing or tightness in chest. Huffing should always be followed by breathing control.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acapella,ACBTS</intervention_name>
    <description>Every subject will perform supervised ACBTs with and without acapella for four weeks. Three sessions per week will be given with 20 repetitions in two sets</description>
    <arm_group_label>active cycle of breathing technique with acapella</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ACBTs</intervention_name>
    <description>Every subject will perform supervised ACBTs with and without acapella for four weeks. Three sessions per week will be given with 20 repetitions in two sets</description>
    <arm_group_label>active cycle of breathing technique</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>active cycle of breathing technique with acapella</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Age:45-75&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Both genders&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mentally stable&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diagnosed patients of COPD&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Any neurological condition&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Arrythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous heart or lung surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Madiha younas, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>riphah internationl university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Imran amjad, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>03324390125</phone>
    <email>imran.amjad@riphah.edu.pk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aziz bhatti shaheed teaching hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gujrāt</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>053</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Madiha younas, MS</last_name>
      <phone>0333-8148025</phone>
      <email>madiha.younas@riphah.edu.pk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mishal Sabir, MSCPPT</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ACBT, Acapella, COPD, PEP</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

