<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05621213</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022-A01667-36</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05621213</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Satisfaction of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Regarding Home Assisted Teleconsultation</brief_title>
  <acronym>VNI_SLA</acronym>
  <official_title>Satisfaction of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Under Non-invasive Ventilation Regarding Home Assisted Teleconsultation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AGIR à Dom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AGIR à Dom</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Satisfaction of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis under non-invasive ventilation&#xD;
      regarding home assisted teleconsultation&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive and rapidly progressing&#xD;
      neurodegenerative disease. Depending on the degree of muscle damage, patients may suffer from&#xD;
      reduced mobility, difficulty swallowing, speech difficulties and finally respiratory&#xD;
      weakness. Death occurs within an average of 2-3 years and is usually due to respiratory&#xD;
      failure. Currently there is no cure for ALS, so palliative care and symptomatic treatments&#xD;
      are essential for the management of these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The gold standard treatment for respiratory impairment is non-invasive ventilation (NIV). The&#xD;
      aim of this mask ventilation is to improve gas exchange by compensating for the weakness of&#xD;
      the respiratory muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The progressive nature of ALS requires regular assessment of the patient's clinical condition&#xD;
      and evaluation of NIV parameters. Regular medical appointments are therefore essential to&#xD;
      ensure optimal ventilation and close surveillance of the patient. A day hospitalization or a&#xD;
      consultation is organized every 3 or 4 months. These visits can cause significant fatigue,&#xD;
      not only because of the difficulty patients have to move around but also because of the time&#xD;
      spent waiting in hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ALS is characterised by its severity and it requires our society to think about and implement&#xD;
      new ways of managing the disease. Thus, e-health innovations could be an interesting&#xD;
      potential in the remote follow-up of these patients, to reduce the burden of hospital&#xD;
      consultations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that the patient will be more satisfied with a home assisted&#xD;
      teleconsultation follow-up, while keeping the same quality of non-invasive nocturnal&#xD;
      ventilatory assistance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patient assigned to the interventional group or to the control group if they do not wish to be followed up by teleconsultation</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction of ALS patients followed by teleconsultation at home</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit and the 3-month visit</time_frame>
    <description>Evolution of the overall satisfaction score obtained from the Client Satisfaction Questionnaire CSQ-8, with 8 items, score 8-32. The higher the score, the more satisfied the patient is.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evolution of the patient's physical functions</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in ALS-FRS-R (Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale revised) questionnaire score, score 0-48. The higher the score, the better the patient's physical function.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by S3-NIV (symptoms, sleep quality and side-effects related to the non-invasiv ventilation) questionnaire score 0-10. the higher the score, the fewer ALS-related symptoms the patient has.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by mean nocturnal oxygen saturation (SpO2, %) measured by oximetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by time spent (in minutes) below 90% SpO2, measured by oximetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by mean PtCO2 (in mmHg), measured by capnography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by time spent (in minutes) above 50 mmHg PtCO2 measured by capnography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by the treatment compliance (average daily use) through telemonitoring of the data recorded by the CPAP machine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by the unintentional leakage through telemonitoring of the data recorded by the CPAP machine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-inferiority of ventilatory efficiency compared to conventional management</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Non-inferiority of efficiency will be assessed in a blinded manner by two third party experts in ventilation. This ventilatory efficiency will be assessed by the residual Apnea-Hypopnea Index (AHI) through telemonitoring of the data recorded by the CPAP machine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed from clinical parameters measured by S3-NIV (symptoms, sleep quality and side-effects related to the non-invasiv ventilation) questionnaire, score 0-10. the higher the score, the fewer ALS-related symptoms the patient has.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed from mean PtCO2 (in mmHg), measured by capnography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed from time spent (in minutes) below 90% SpO2, measured by oximetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed from mean nocturnal oxygen saturation (SpO2,%) measured by oximetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed from time spent (in minutes) above 50 mmHg PtCO2 measured by capnography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed by the treatment compliance (average daily use) through telemonitoring of the data recorded by the CPAP machine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed by the unintentional leakage through telemonitoring of the data recorded by the CPAP machine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of the efficiency of ventilation between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the evolution of ventilation efficiency assessed by the residual Apnea-Hypopnea Index (AHI) through telemonitoring of the data recorded by the CPAP machine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction with teleconsultation itself (use and patient/doctor interaction)</measure>
    <time_frame>After each teleconsultation (3-month visit and 6-month visit)</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the score of the Visit Satisfaction Questionnaire (VSQ-VF) score 0-100. The higher the score, the more satisfied the patient is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The evolution of satisfaction between patients who have completed the teleconsultation follow-up visit and those who have completed the face-to-face follow-up visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the variation in the score of the visit satisfaction questionnaire, assessed by the VSQ-VF questionnaire, score 0-100. The higher the score, the more satisfied the patient is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physician satisfaction with teleconsultation</measure>
    <time_frame>After each teleconsultation (3-month visit and 6-month visit)</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation made by Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) from 0 to 10 cm. The higher the score, the more satisfied the physician is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Caregivers' satisfaction with the care of the relative</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in caregiver satisfaction measured with client satisfaction questionnaire score (CSQ-8 modified) with 8 items, score 8-32. The higher the score, the more satisfied the caregivers' is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The feasibility of home teleconsultation for ALS patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Between the initial visit, the 3-month visit, and the 6-months visit</time_frame>
    <description>Number of failed teleconsultations requiring rescheduling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retention of follow-up modality</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who changed follow-up modality, assessed by the number of face-to-face follow-up</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>ALS</condition>
  <condition>Charcot Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who will be followed up by teleconsultation assisted by a physiotherapist or a nurse at home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients not wishing to be followed up by teleconsultation but agreeing to participate in the study and the collection of questionnaires. They will follow up as usual in person (no teleconsultation).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Teleconsultation assisted by a physiotherapist or nurse</intervention_name>
    <description>A home health care provider (with expertise in NIV) will be asked to attend the 2 home teleconsultation sessions.&#xD;
This assistance will make it possible to help, if necessary, the patient to settle in and connect, collect the elements necessary for the doctor's consultation and adjust, if necessary, the NIV settings. He will also be responsible for administering the questionnaires to the patient as well as to his family caregiver.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a diagnosis of ALS coming for a follow-up consultation with their&#xD;
             pneumologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Daily NIV compliance of more than 4 hours in the month prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living at home&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a natural caregiver&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient equipped with computer equipment adapted for teleconsultation (tablet,&#xD;
             computer, telephone... with an internet connection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient able to read and understand the procedure, and able to express consent for the&#xD;
             study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient, or his or her caregiver, able to sign the consent to participate by himself&#xD;
             or herself&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient not available or wishing to change region within 3 months of inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient currently participating or having participated in the month prior to inclusion&#xD;
             in another clinical interventional research study that may have an impact on the&#xD;
             study, this impact is left to the discretion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons referred to in articles L1121-5 to L1121-8 of the French Public Health Code&#xD;
             (corresponding to all protected persons)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women (for women of childbearing age and in the absence of reliable&#xD;
             contraception, the β-HCG (human chorionic gonadotropin) assay will be performed),&#xD;
             parturient women, breastfeeding women,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  persons deprived of their liberty by judicial or administrative decision,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  persons under legal protection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christel Saint-Raymond, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Grenoble Alpes</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Céline Barra</last_name>
    <phone>0750543238</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>c.barra@agiradom.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jean-Christian Borel, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0762707821</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>j.borel@agiradom.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Grenoble Alpes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grenoble</city>
        <zip>38043</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christel Saint-Raymond, PhD</last_name>
      <email>csaint-raymond@chu-grenoble.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christel Saint-Raymond, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Montpellier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34295</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>François Bughin, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0499536218</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>f-bughin@chu-montpellier.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Bronia Ayoub</last_name>
      <email>b-ayoub@chu-montpellier.fr</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>François Bughin, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

