<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05797688</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15586</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05797688</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adipose-derived Stem Cells to Treat Chronic Wounds.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Use of Autologous Adipose-derived Stem Cell to Treat Chronic Wounds</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Winthrop University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cytori Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Winthrop University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to determine whether autologous, adipose-derived regenerative cells&#xD;
      improve the healing of chronic wounds. Ten patients will undergo fat harvest and peri-wound&#xD;
      injection of the isolated cells in addition to the standard of care for the treatment of&#xD;
      their chronic wound. Wound healing will be followed over 24 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be an open-label, preliminary, proof-of-concept trial. Ten patients will&#xD;
      undergo debridement of their wound per the standard of care currently offered by Winthrop&#xD;
      University Hospital along with concurrent fat harvest according to the standard protocols of&#xD;
      the Winthrop University Hospital Plastic surgeons. The harvested fat will be immediately&#xD;
      processed using an automated system to isolate regenerative cells, including stem cells. This&#xD;
      will be followed by same-day subcutaneous injection of the isolated cells into the debrided&#xD;
      wound site. The patients will then undergo weekly wound debridements according to the current&#xD;
      standard of care treatment protocols. They will be followed weekly for 24 weeks in the&#xD;
      outpatient wound clinic and observed for pain, erythema of the injection site, wound&#xD;
      infection, edema, fever, bleeding and wound healing as measured by wound size and area. Fat&#xD;
      harvest and subcutaneous injection will be repeated 3 months after the initial procedure if&#xD;
      the wound has not decreased in size by at least 40%. Patients can undergo a maximum of 2&#xD;
      cycles of fat harvest and cell injection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as assessed by weekly evalutation of the occurrence of wound infection, redness, swelling, pain, fever, chills, bleeding, and wound healing.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete wound healing</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Wounds will be evaluated for 100% epithelialization with no drainage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to healing</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The time when complete healing occurs will be recorded, up to 1 year.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Wound of Skin</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will undergo a fat harvest procedure and the tissue will then be processed by The Celution System to isolate a 5 mL aliquot including stem cells. This will then be injected into the base and within in perimeter of the target wound.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The Celution System</intervention_name>
    <description>The Celution System will isolate regenerative cells, including stem cells, from fat harvested from the treatment patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Celution, Adipose-derived cell processor</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject must agree to adhere to all protocol procedures and return for weekly&#xD;
             scheduled wound assessment visits, including requirements for taking and abstaining&#xD;
             from medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject is willing and able to read, understand and sign a written Informed Consent to&#xD;
             participate in the study or have an appropriate representative available to do so.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject must have a full thickness Stage III or Stage IV pressure ulcer, deep venous&#xD;
             ulcer, deep diabetic ulcer, ischemic ulcer, abdominal wound, nonhealing surgical site&#xD;
             or sickle cell ulcer. For subjects with more than one wound that meet these criteria,&#xD;
             the largest qualifying wound will be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject has adequate (&gt;200 mL) abdominal or other subcutaneous adipose tissue&#xD;
             accessible by syringe-based fat harvest and is able to undergo a fat harvest procedure&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator or per facility guidelines and has activated&#xD;
             platelet thromboplastin time (aPTT) within the normal reference range at the time of&#xD;
             the fat harvest procedure and no contraindication to fat harvest.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject's wound has been refractory to standard of care (no objective/measureable&#xD;
             signs of healing) for at least 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject has local infection with erythema &gt; 2 cm, or involving structures deeper than&#xD;
             skin and subcutaneous tissues (e.g., abscess, osteomyelitis, septic arthritis,&#xD;
             fasciitis), or associated with local wound complications such as prosthetic materials&#xD;
             or protruding surgical hardware.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has ≥ 2 of the following signs of systemic inflammatory response syndrome&#xD;
             (SIRS) or septic shock within 7 days of screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Temperature &gt; 38°C or &lt; 36°C&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Heart rate &gt; 90 beats/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Respiratory rate &gt; 20 breaths/min or PaCO2 &lt; 32 mm Hg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White blood cell count &gt; 12,000 or &lt; 4,000 cells/μL or ≥ 10% immature (band)&#xD;
                  forms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject has received biologic or cell therapy within 12 weeks of initiation of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject not eligible for syringe-based liposuction of at least 200 mL of subcutaneous&#xD;
             adipose tissue, including therapeutic anticoagulation with INR &gt;1.7 or PTT &gt;60, or&#xD;
             receiving GIIb/IIIa inhibitors within 2 weeks prior to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has squamous cell carcinoma, basal cell carcinoma, melanoma or skin carcinoma&#xD;
             of the affected limb or area and underwent treatment within the last year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject is pregnant as determined by a positive pregnancy test prior to procedure, or&#xD;
             breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Clinically significant abnormal findings on laboratory screening panels, including&#xD;
             hemoglobin ≤10 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Hepatic dysfunction, as defined as aspartate aminotransferase (AST), alanine&#xD;
             aminotranferase (ALT), or bilirubin level &gt; 1.5 times the upper limit of normal range&#xD;
             (x ULN) prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Chronic renal insufficiency as defined as a serum creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dL or requires&#xD;
             dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of organ transplantation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Harold Brem, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Winthrop University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Winthrop University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mineola</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11501</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 23, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chronic Wound</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Ulcer</keyword>
  <keyword>stem cell</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

