<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05797324</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21A011</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05797324</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Light Therapy in Modulating the Clinical Phenotype of Patients With Primary and Comorbid Chronic Insomnia.</brief_title>
  <acronym>Luminoterapia</acronym>
  <official_title>Multicenter Study on the Role of Light Therapy in Modulating the Clinical Phenotype of Patients With Primary and Comorbid Chronic Insomnia Through Circadian Phase Modification.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istituto Auxologico Italiano</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>IRCCS National Neurological Institute &quot;C. Mondino&quot; Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ente Ospedaliero Cantonale, Ticino, Switzerland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istituto Auxologico Italiano</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Some evidence indicates that circadian rhythm may play a role in the pathophysiology of&#xD;
      insomnia disorder. This single-blind randomized controlled multicentre prospective study aims&#xD;
      to evaluate the possible therapeutic effect of light therapy in modulating the clinical&#xD;
      phenotype of patients affected by chronic primary and comorbid insomnia, through the&#xD;
      modification of the circadian phase.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Some evidence indicates that circadian rhythm may play a role in the pathophysiology of&#xD;
      insomnia disorder. This single-blind randomized controlled multicentre prospective study aims&#xD;
      to evaluate the possible therapeutic effect of light therapy in modulating the clinical&#xD;
      phenotype of patients affected by chronic primary and comorbid insomnia, through the&#xD;
      modification of the circadian phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY DESIGN AND METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      With regard to the study in question, it should be noted that:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the study is a prospective multicentre randomized single-blind controlled trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the duration of the study is expected to be 3 years with a duration of enrollment of 2&#xD;
           and a half years and a minimum clinical follow-up of 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be divided into two evaluations, an initial evaluation (Time 0, T0) where the&#xD;
      patients will be enrolled and all the measurements required before treatment with light&#xD;
      therapy will be performed, and a final evaluation after 6 weeks of treatment with light&#xD;
      therapy effective or sham (Time 1, T1), where the measurements performed at T0 will be&#xD;
      repeated. Both assessments will be performed at the Sleep Medicine outpatient clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TIME T0&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The diagnosis of primary chronic or comorbid insomnia will be made during the&#xD;
           semi-structured sleep interview by a physician expert in sleep medicine, according to&#xD;
           DSM V criteria, supported by clinical scales (Insomnia Severity Index, Pittsburgh&#xD;
           Quality Index). The presence of mood/behavioral disorders or cognitive deficits will&#xD;
           also be excluded (Beck, Stai, Mini Mental Scale Examination).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A home polysomnography will be performed to rule out the presence of sleep apnea&#xD;
           disorder or periodic limb movement syndrome during sleep&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Circadian parameters (chronotype, Mid sleep, circadian phase, phase angle) will be&#xD;
           evaluated in basal conditions through clinical scales (Morning Eveningness&#xD;
           Questionnaire, Light diet), measurement of salivary melatonin using evening 5-point&#xD;
           wipes at home (DLMO, Elisa) and the actigraphic registration extended for 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The associations between the circadian phase and the various phenotypes of primary or&#xD;
           comorbid insomnia will be then evaluated, according to the duration and the severity of&#xD;
           insomnia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients without ocular contraindications will then undergo a Luminotherapy protocol&#xD;
           (intermittent blue-enriched light therapy with Luminette 10000 lux equivalent) with&#xD;
           morning or evening timing, depending on the circadian phase, or sham treatment (control&#xD;
           subgroup; white light &lt;100 lux equivalent).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients will be randomly assigned to one of two conditions (treatment and sham). The&#xD;
           randomization list will be generated with a simple randomization method through the use&#xD;
           of a &quot;Random number generator&quot; software available at&#xD;
           www.regione.emilia-romagna.t/sin_info/generatore. The algorithm used in this site&#xD;
           coincides with a Lehmer generator (multiplicative congruential generator). Allocation&#xD;
           concealment is guaranteed by a central randomization in a distant and independent&#xD;
           location with respect to the recruitment site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TIME T1&#xD;
&#xD;
      &gt; After 6 consecutive weeks of home light therapy, patients will be re-evaluated with the&#xD;
      same somnometry battery used at study entry. Furthermore, the actigraphic monitoring and the&#xD;
      dosage of salivary melatonin will be repeated, to evaluate the variations of the circadian&#xD;
      phase and of the sleep-wake pattern after light therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Insomnia Severity Index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and after 6 weeks of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Insomnia Severity Index (ISI, Pittsburgh Quality Index) - self-report questionnaire composed of 19 items assessing sleep quality</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in salivary melatonin</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and after 6 weeks of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary melatonin - evening 5-point wipes (DLMO, Elisa)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Insomnia Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Luminette</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients without ocular contraindications undergo a Luminotherapy protocol (intermittent blue-enriched light therapy with Luminette 10000 lux equivalent) with morning or evening timing, depending on the circadian phase.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group (white light &lt;100 lux equivalent).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Luminette</intervention_name>
    <description>Luminotherapy protocol (intermittent blue-enriched light therapy with Luminette 10000 lux equivalent) with morning or evening timing, depending on the circadian rhythm</description>
    <arm_group_label>Luminette</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham</intervention_name>
    <description>Sham protocol (white light &lt;100 lux equivalent).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sham</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary chronic insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbid chronic insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of pharmacological therapy of insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of behavioural and cognitive treatment of insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capacity to understand the study and adhere to the procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Secondary insomnia due to medical conditions or drug treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cerebral diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Invalidating diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eye diseases that contraindicate the use of light therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive decline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Working in night shifts during the last month before enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impossibility to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Riccardo Cremascoli</last_name>
    <phone>+393497292068</phone>
    <email>r.cremascoli@auxologico.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Auxologico Italiano</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oggebbio</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Riccardo Cremascoli, MD</last_name>
      <email>r.cremascoli@auxologico.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 21, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 4, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 4, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 6, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Light therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

