<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05793359</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21A /25.07.2017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05793359</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of the Effectiveness of Two Glucocorticoid Regimens for Treatment of Graves' Orbitopathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Efficacy of Two Different Glucocorticoid Regimens for Treatment of Active Moderate-to-severe Graves' Orbitopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Sofia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Sofia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this interventional study is to compare the effectiveness of two different&#xD;
      glucocorticoid regimens for treatment of active moderate-to-severe Graves' orbitopathy. The&#xD;
      main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Are the two glucocorticoid regimens similarly effective?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Do the two glucocorticoid regimens have similar safety profile? The patients involved&#xD;
           are treated with one of the two glucocorticoid regimens. Their ocular status,&#xD;
           therapeutic response and quality of life reassessed during the treatment, at its end,&#xD;
           and 3 month later.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Systemic glucocorticoids are the mainstay of treatment for active moderate-to-severe Graves'&#xD;
      orbitopathy. However, there are a number of different glucocorticoid regimens with different&#xD;
      total dosage, schemes of administration and duration. The goal of this interventional study&#xD;
      is to compare the effectiveness of two different glucocorticoid regimens for treatment of&#xD;
      active moderate-to-severe Graves' orbitopathy. The main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Are the two glucocorticoid regimens similarly effective?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Do the two glucocorticoid regimens have similar safety profile? The patients involved&#xD;
           are treated with one of the two glucocorticoid regimens. The first group is treated with&#xD;
           modified monthly regimen, including 3 pulses of 3 infusions of 500 mg methylprednisolone&#xD;
           administered in three consecutive months, with application of 125 mg methylprednisolone&#xD;
           intramuscularly once per week between the pulses. Total cumulative dose - 5.5. g.,&#xD;
           duration - 3 months. After completion of the venous infusions, a low dose peroral&#xD;
           glucocorticoid therapy is prescribed for the next 3 months. The second group is treated&#xD;
           with weekly glucocorticoid regimen: 6 infusions of 500 mg methylprednisolone during the&#xD;
           first 6 weeks followed by 6 infusions of 250 mg methylprednisolone during the next 6&#xD;
           weeks. Total cumulative dose - 4.5 g., duration - 3 months. Patients' ocular status and&#xD;
           therapeutic response are assessed at 1st, 3rd and 6th months; quality of life - at 3rd&#xD;
           and 6th month.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 25, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 25, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 25, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>6 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in the overall therapeutic response assessed using Bartalena's criteria during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in the overall therapeutic response assessed using Bartalena's criteria and classified as full, partial and no response during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in clinical activity score, assessed using a 7- or 10-point scale and expressed in points during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in clinical activity score, assessed using a 7-point scale at baseline or 10-point scale during the follow-up and expressed in points as recommended by European Thyroid Association and European Group on Graves' orbitopathy during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in lid aperture expressed in mm during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in lid aperture measured by ruler and expressed in mm during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in proptosis expressed in mm during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in proptosis measured by Hertel's exophthalmometer and expressed in mm during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in visual acuity expressed in decimals during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in visual acuity measured by Snellen chart and expressed in decimals during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in diplopia assessed using Gorman's classification system during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in diplopia assessed using Gorman's classification system and classified as gr. 0 absent, gr. I intermittent, gr. II inconstant, gr. III constant during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in soft tissue involvement evaluated using the colour atlas proposed by European Group on Graves' orbitopathy during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in soft tissue involvement evaluated using the colour atlas proposed by European Group on Graves' orbitopathy and categorized as gr. 0-I absent or mild, gr. II-III moderate or severe during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in subjective symptoms whose severity was reported by patients themselves using subjective scale during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in subjective symptoms whose severity was reported by patients themselves and were graded as 0-I absent or mild, gr. II-III moderate or severe during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the changes in quality of life assessed by disease-specific questionnaire recommended by European Group on Graves' orbitopathy (GO-QoL) аnd expressed as percentages during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the changes in quality of life during the treatment with the two glucocorticoid regimens assessed by disease-specific questionnaire recommended by European Group on Graves' orbitopathy (GO-QoL) аnd expressed as percentages, which includes two subscales - one evaluating the impact of Graves' orbitopathy on patients' visual functioning (QoL-VF) and the other related to the changes of physical appearance as a result of the disease (QoL-AP)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of treatment-emerged adverse events in the two glucocorticoid regimens groups</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number and type of adverse reactions in the study groups reported by patients themselves or found by the laboratory tests or during clinical examination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Graves Ophthalmopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Modified monthly regimen</arm_group_label>
    <description>Treatment with 3 pulses of 3 infusions of 500 mg methylprednisolone on 3 consecutive months with intramuscular administration of 125 mg methylprednisolone per week between the pulses. Additional low dose peroral treatment after completion of the pulses.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Weekly regimen</arm_group_label>
    <description>Treatment with 6 infusions of 500 mg methylprednisolone during the first 6 weeks, followed by 6 infusions of 250 mg methylprednisolone during the next 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Methylprednisolone</intervention_name>
    <description>methylprednisolone applied as intravenous infusions or intramuscularly</description>
    <arm_group_label>Modified monthly regimen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Weekly regimen</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Urbason</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Sixty-two patients with untreated active moderate-to-severe Graves' orbitopathy in&#xD;
        euthyroid state under treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active moderate-to-severe Graves' orbitopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Without previous treatment with glucocorticoids or orbital radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Euthyroid state&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hyper- or hypothyroidism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously treated Graves' orbitopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mild or sight-threatening form of Graves' orbitopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inactive moderate-to-severe Graves' orbitopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications for glucocorticoid treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mariya D Stoynova, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of Sofia: Medicinski universitet-Sofia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Endocrinology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sofia</city>
        <zip>1000</zip>
        <country>Bulgaria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 7, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Sofia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mariya Stoynova</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Graves Ophthalmopathy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

