<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05791747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UNimes3</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05791747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Representations, Beliefs and Attitudes Towards Hypnosis in Patients Followed for Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Representations, Beliefs and Attitudes Towards Hypnosis in Patients Followed for Colorectal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Nimes</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Nimes</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Over the past decade, changes in knowledge and attitudes toward complementary and alternative&#xD;
      medicine have been occurring. One study shows that 21% of patients are turning to them. In&#xD;
      contrast, hypnosis is among the least used. While perceptions of alternative medicine are&#xD;
      improving, there is still widespread skepticism about the beliefs of hypnosis and this may&#xD;
      explain why patients are not turning to it. Although its use in oncology is no longer in&#xD;
      question, and its efficacy in the management of side effects has been demonstrated, no recent&#xD;
      qualitative study has been conducted to examine the representations of hypnosis among cancer&#xD;
      patients. It therefore seems relevant to us today to know the evolution of the&#xD;
      representations and attitudes of cancer patients towards hypnosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cancer patients experience psychological difficulties during the disease, associated with&#xD;
      treatment, and even in the post-treatment period. Among the most common, they mention&#xD;
      emotional distress, significant fatigue, sleep disturbance, or pain. Several authors agree&#xD;
      that there is a cluster of four core symptoms associated with the disease and its treatments,&#xD;
      including fatigue, nausea/vomiting, depression and pain. These symptoms have a significant&#xD;
      impact on daily activities, resulting in a decrease in quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reducing the symptoms of cancer to the sole etiology of the disease or its treatments does&#xD;
      not allow us to consider a management action. Indeed, patients with cancer face the diagnosis&#xD;
      and follow a course of care that includes many medical therapies (surgery, chemotherapy,&#xD;
      radiotherapy, etc.). Integrative medicine takes into account the need for these medical&#xD;
      therapies by adding the importance of supportive care for patients. Specifically, the&#xD;
      expected effects are to reduce the after-effects for people thanks to an offer of support&#xD;
      care adapted to their needs and regularly evaluated, ensuring a better quality of life&#xD;
      immediately and in the longer term, as well as by providing information that allows patients&#xD;
      to make the most informed choices possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical activity, dietary monitoring, and psychosocial interventions remain the most common&#xD;
      complementary therapies offered to patients to reduce treatment side effects. Among this wide&#xD;
      choice, patients can find themselves lost. Over the past decade, changes in knowledge and&#xD;
      attitudes toward complementary and alternative medicine have been occurring. For example, one&#xD;
      study found that 21% of patients are turning to them, indicating a growing interest in this&#xD;
      type of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While perceptions of alternative medicine are improving, there is still widespread skepticism&#xD;
      about hypnosis. As a result, even though scientific research shows positive effects of this&#xD;
      type of therapy, a 2006 study in Canada found that out of 15 breast cancer patients using&#xD;
      psychosocial therapies, only 6% used hypnosis. Another study conducted in 2018 confirms these&#xD;
      results: on a population of 212 patients with different cancers, it appears that hypnosis is&#xD;
      the therapy least used and whose interest is lowest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Few studies have been conducted to determine the reasons for this lack of interest or the&#xD;
      beliefs that are associated with hypnosis. Existing research suggests that patients lack&#xD;
      information about hypnosis and its effectiveness, may have ambivalent perceptions about it or&#xD;
      be skeptical of its effectiveness, and that their beliefs may be influenced by the media.&#xD;
      Specifically, one study point out that positive attitudes toward hypnosis are even associated&#xD;
      with better hypnotic response. While its use in oncology is no longer in question, no recent&#xD;
      qualitative study has been conducted questioning the representations of hypnosis with cancer&#xD;
      patients. It therefore seems relevant to us today to know the evolution of the&#xD;
      representations and attitudes of cancer patients towards hypnosis. To do this, and according&#xD;
      to Leventhal's model of self-regulation, the information obtained by a patient, whether or&#xD;
      not it is medically based, is integrated by the patient in order to provide a &quot;lay&quot;&#xD;
      understanding of the subject in question. Activated representations may then be guided by the&#xD;
      individual's current and prior awareness or by social messages from perceived significant&#xD;
      others or authoritative sources and this impacts attitudes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study was to investigate psychosocial representations related to hypnosis in&#xD;
      colorectal cancer patients and to assess the impact of these representations on the intention&#xD;
      to use hypnosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 21, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>social representations</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The representations will be questioned in terms of identity, beliefs, consequences, temporality and controlability. Semi-structured interviews with qualitative analyses will be conducted to explore represenations in cancer patients. The five major questions as are follows : What is hypnosis/hypnotherapy for you ? What do you think about hypnosis ? If you were to turn to this technique, what would be your expectations ? At what point in your illness/treatment would hypnosis be most appropriate ? Do you think hypnosis can help you manage the symptoms of your illness or the side effects of treatment ?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Barriers and levers to using hypnosis</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Identify what constitutes obstacles and levers to the use of hypnosis in analysing answers made at questions above</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intention to turn to hypnosis</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>What impacts intentions and attitudes towards hypnosis, semi-structured interviews will conclude with the following questions: - Do you intend to turn to this technique or refer a loved one ? What would make it easier for you to access hypnosis ?</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer Colorectal</condition>
  <condition>Hypnosis, Animal</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>semi-structured interviews</intervention_name>
    <description>This is an observational study Patients included in the study will conduct semi-structured interviews to discuss their knowledge and/or experience with supportive care, particularly hypnosis</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Men and women diagnosed with colorectal cancer, still in treatment or not.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Having been diagnosed with colorectal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to understand and read French&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who do not have a telephone or devices that allow remote interviewing&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Medical (neurological, psychiatric, etc.) or psychological conditions that do not&#xD;
             allow participation in the study (completion of the consent form and coherent speech&#xD;
             for the interview)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hearing impaired patient without hearing aids&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient under guardianship or court protection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Louise Baussard, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0678675243</phone>
    <email>louise.baussard@unimes.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Université de Nîmes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nîmes</city>
        <state>Gard</state>
        <zip>30000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Corbett, T., Groarke, A., Walsh, J. C., &amp; McGuire, B. E. (2016). Cancer-related fatigue in post-treatment cancer survivors: Application of the common sense model of illness representations. BMC Cancer, 16(1), 919. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12885-016-2907-8 Curt, G. A., Breitbart, W., Cella, D., Groopman, J. E., Horning, S. J., Itri, L. M., Johnson, D. H., Miaskowski, C., Scherr, S. L., Portenoy, R. K., &amp; Vogelzang, N. J. (2000). Impact of Cancer-Related Fatigue on the Lives of Patients: New Findings From the Fatigue Coalition. The Oncologist, 5(5), 353-360. https://doi.org/10.1634/theoncologist.5-5-353 Forlenza, M. J., Hall, P., Lichtenstein, P., Evengard, B., &amp; Sullivan, P. F. (2005). Epidemiology of cancer-related fatigue in the Swedish twin registry. Cancer, 104(9), 2022-2031. Helyer, L. K., Chin, S., Chui, B. K., Fitzgerald, B., Verma, S., Rakovitch, E., Dranitsaris, G., &amp; Clemons, M. (2006). The use of complementary and alternative medicines among patients with locally advanced breast cancer - a descriptive study. BMC Cancer, 6(1), 39. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2407-6-39 Henry, D. H., Viswanathan, H. N., Elkin, E. P., Traina, S., Wade, S., &amp; Cella, D. (2008). Symptoms and treatment burden associated with cancer treatment: Results from a cross-sectional national survey in the U.S. Supportive Care in Cancer, 16(7), 791-801. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-007-0380-2 Hofman, M., Ryan, J. L., Figueroa-Moseley, C. D., Jean-Pierre, P., &amp; Morrow, G. R. (2007). Cancer-Related Fatigue: The Scale of the Problem. The Oncologist, 12(S1), 4-10. https://doi.org/10.1634/theoncologist.12-S1-4 Lawrence, D. P. (2004). Evidence Report on the Occurrence, Assessment, and Treatment of Fatigue in Cancer Patients. Journal of the National Cancer Institute Monographs, 2004(32), 40-50. https://doi.org/10.1093/jncimonographs/lgh027 Leventhal, H., &amp; Diefenbach, M. (1991). The Active Side of Illness Cognition. In J. A. Skelton &amp; R. T. Croyle (Éds.), Mental Representation in Health and Illness (p. 247-272). Springer US. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4613-9074-9_11 Lind, S. B., Jacobsen, H. B., Solbakken, O. A., &amp; Reme, S. E. (2021). Clinical Hypnosis in Medical Care: A Mixed-Method Feasibility Study. Integrative Cancer Therapies, 20, 153473542110586. https://doi.org/10.1177/15347354211058678 Mendoza, M. E., Capafons, A., &amp; Jensen, M. P. (2017). Hypnosis attitudes: Treatment effects and associations with symptoms in individuals with cancer. American Journal of Clinical Hypnosis, 60(1), 50-67. Miller, S. J., Schnur, J. B., Montgomery, G. H., &amp; Jandorf, L. (2015). African-Americans and Latinos' Perceptions of Using Hypnosis to Alleviate Distress Before a Colonoscopy. NCCN. (2022). NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology-Cancer-Related Fatigue. NCCN.org. Qureshi, M., Zelinski, E., &amp; Carlson, L. E. (2018). Cancer and Complementary Therapies: Current Trends in Survivors' Interest and Use. Integrative Cancer Therapies, 17(3), 844-853. https://doi.org/10.1177/1534735418762496</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 14, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 28, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 28, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 28, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Nimes</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Baussard Louise</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cancer colorectal</keyword>
  <keyword>hypnose</keyword>
  <keyword>representations</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The principal investigator shares with the co-investigator the research protocol, consent, data collected</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>From january 2023 to december 2023 (one year)</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>professionnal computer only</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

