<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615727</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UW 21-386</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615727</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intranasal Dexmedetomidine and Zolpidem for Treatment of Primary Insomnia</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Placebo-controlled Crossover Trial of Intranasal Dexmedetomidine and Zolpidem for Treatment of Primary Insomnia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Insomnia is a significant public health burden, increasing work absenteeism and health care&#xD;
      costs in a large proportion of the population. It causes altered cognition, emotional&#xD;
      disturbances, and reduced quality of life. The purpose of this study is to determine whether&#xD;
      the sleep promoting effect of dexmedetomidine is superior to the conventional sleep promoting&#xD;
      drug, zolpidem.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main outcome of this study is to measure the time taken to fall asleep. Investigators&#xD;
      will also look at incidences of wakening after sleep onset, sleep quality and wake time&#xD;
      during sleep.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Insomnia is a significant public health burden, increasing work absenteeism and health care&#xD;
      costs in a large proportion of the population. It causes altered cognition, emotional&#xD;
      disturbances, and reduced quality of life. Most epidemiologic studies have found that about&#xD;
      one-third of adults report at least one symptom of insomnia e.g. difficulty initiating sleep&#xD;
      or maintaining sleep. There are also similar problems related to circadian rhythm disturbance&#xD;
      as seen in shift workers and &quot;jet lag&quot;. Research indicates that DNA damage is apparent in&#xD;
      doctors subjected to sleep deprivation. Traditional currently available hypnotics which are&#xD;
      used to initiate and maintain sleep (&quot;sleeping tablets&quot;) are either benzodiazepines (BZD) or&#xD;
      the so-called Z-drugs (zolpidem, zopiclone and zaleplon) which are a class of psychoactive&#xD;
      drugs that are very benzodiazepine-like in nature and act by allosterically activating&#xD;
      gamma-aminobutyric acid receptor A (GABAA). They have virtually superseded benzodiazepines&#xD;
      but have almost entirely the same pharmacodynamic effects and, therefore, exhibit similar&#xD;
      action, side-effects, and risks. Despite their name, these drugs do not induce natural sleep&#xD;
      as manifest by EEG. They are central nervous system depressants that disproportionately&#xD;
      promote non-rapid eye movement (NREM) sleep while suppressing REM sleep. Selective REM sleep&#xD;
      deprivation in humans has adverse effects on memory consolidation and pain perception. Other&#xD;
      problems with these drugs include numerous reports of misuse, abuse and dependence,&#xD;
      paradoxical reactions, increased risk of road traffic accidents and exacerbation of asthma. A&#xD;
      retrospective cohort study of more than 100,000 age- and sex-matched patients showed that&#xD;
      those who used these drugs were 3 times more likely to die prematurely during the 7 -year&#xD;
      follow-up period than those who did not, with significant dose-response associations shown&#xD;
      for benzodiazepines and the &quot;Z drugs&quot;. New evidence-based clinical practice guidelines for&#xD;
      the treatment of insomnia disorder were recently developed using the GRADE methodology&#xD;
      (Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluation) and represent the first&#xD;
      comprehensive, systematic analysis of single agents for treatment. Unfortunately, the level&#xD;
      of evidence for all recommendations was &quot;weak&quot; meaning that the strength of the evidence in&#xD;
      the published data were low. Notably, all the recommended treatments for sleep onset&#xD;
      insomnia, besides ramelteon, a melatonin receptor agonist , are Z-drugs or BZD hypnotics. For&#xD;
      sleep maintenance insomnia, three of five of the treatment options are Z-drugs or BZDs. The&#xD;
      US Food and Drug Administration has recently put a Boxed Warning on Z drugs since serious&#xD;
      injuries and death from complex sleep behaviours have occurred in patients with and without a&#xD;
      history of such behaviours. These behaviours can occur after just one dose. Clearly, better&#xD;
      pharmacological treatment is warranted. Dexmedetomidine is a highly selective alpha-2&#xD;
      adrenergic receptor antagonist that acts on the locus ceruleus1 in the brain to produce dose&#xD;
      dependent sedation, anxiolysis and analgesia with no respiratory depression and only modest&#xD;
      haemodynamic effects. It has been extensively studied and used for both adult and paediatric&#xD;
      sedation, premedication, intensive care and in perioperative settings to prevent emergence&#xD;
      delirium after anaesthesia. The sedative effect of this drug is unique in that it produces&#xD;
      prominent slow wave activity in the electroencephalogram (EEG) resembling stage 2 NREM sleep&#xD;
      with facilitated arousal (as with natural sleep). Of the sleeping states, the NREM sleep&#xD;
      period seems fundamental because it happens first (wakefulness to NREM) and lasts the&#xD;
      longest. It has even been suggested as a suitable drug to induce torpor in manned space&#xD;
      flight. The intravenous formulation is also efficacious when administered by the intranasal&#xD;
      route in both children and adults. Since this is not associated with any unpleasant&#xD;
      sensation, there is increasing use for paediatric premedication and procedural sedation. The&#xD;
      bioavailability of intranasal dexmedetomidine administered by atomiser or by drops is&#xD;
      approximately 40% in healthy adult volunteers with an inter-individual variability of around&#xD;
      30%. The pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic profiles of the two modes of administration are&#xD;
      similar and both are equally effective in inducing adequate sedation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Each participant will take part in three sleep investigations. Each sleep investigation will take place after the participant has completed one night of sleep familiarization in the laboratory. The 3 sleep investigations will be conducted after administration of the following in a randomised manner:&#xD;
Placebo&#xD;
Intranasal dexmedetomidine&#xD;
Zolpidem</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>placebo-controlled crossover trial</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep onset latency</measure>
    <time_frame>720 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep onset latency is a measure of how long it takes for the participant to fall asleep once the participant gets into bed. This will be measured in minutes and reported as minutes for each of the treatments</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of wakening after sleep onset; Sleep quality; Wake time during sleep</measure>
    <time_frame>720 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of wakening after sleep onset: This is a measure of how many times the participant will wake up after falling asleep. It will be measured as count data.&#xD;
Sleep quality: This is a subjective measure and will be given as a score from a survey completed by the participant. The data will be reported as count data&#xD;
Wake time during sleep: This will be detected with the polysomnography and will be reported in total minutes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Insomnia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Zolpidem</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine</intervention_name>
    <description>2 mcg/kg of undiluted dexmedetomidine [= 0.02 ml/kg] and oral placebo tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Zolpidem</intervention_name>
    <description>zolpidem 10 mg and intranasal saline 0.02 ml/kg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Zolpidem</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>a placebo oral tablet and intranasal saline at 0.02 ml/kg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants aged between 18 to 25 years, with DSM-5 insomnia disorder. Insomnia will&#xD;
             be diagnosed and confirmed by a clinical interview and will have an Insomnia Severity&#xD;
             Index score of ≥ 15.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Comorbid diagnosis of psychiatric disorders ( major depression, anxiety disorders,&#xD;
             bipolar disorders and psychotic disorders)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Obstructive sleep apnoea as determined by an Apnea Hypoapnea Index of &gt;15 or snoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Restless legs, or periodic limb movements during sleep as measured by the Periodic&#xD;
             Limb Movements Index with arousal of &gt; 15 per hour&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Obesity (body mass index &gt; 30)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known or suspected cardiovascular, pulmonary, metabolic disease or diabetes as&#xD;
             confirmed by the clinician interview during recruitment&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Anyone who has taken trans-meridian travel across more than one time-zone or worked&#xD;
             night shifts in the preceding three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Consuming prescribed or non-prescription sleep medication in the past month&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Micheal Garnet Irwin, M.B. Ch.B</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Micheal Garnet Irwin, M.B. Ch.B</last_name>
    <phone>22553303/ 97018342</phone>
    <email>mgirwin@hku.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HKU Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <zip>999077</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chong</last_name>
      <phone>(852)22553749</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael G. Irwin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>Dexmedetomidine</keyword>
  <keyword>Zolpidem</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Zolpidem</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

