<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05616273</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-22-59</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>319581</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>22/LO/0719</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>Grant # 2012-04188</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05616273</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Stimulated Glucagon as a Biomarker of Hypoglycemic Risk in Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>MUGGLE</acronym>
  <official_title>Stimulated Glucagon as a Biomarker of Hypoglycemic Risk in Type 1 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Exeter</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Royal Devon and Exeter NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Exeter</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Type 1 diabetes (T1D) results from destruction of insulin producing beta cells by the body's&#xD;
      own immune system (autoimmunity) causing an individual to lose the ability to make enough&#xD;
      insulin to control their blood sugar levels and need to have insulin injections to lower&#xD;
      blood glucose levels. Whilst high blood sugar level is a problem for people with Type 1&#xD;
      diabetes, taking insulin medication to lower sugar levels, delayed meals and exercise can all&#xD;
      result in dangerously low blood sugar levels (hypoglycaemia). The biological causes of&#xD;
      hypoglycaemia, and ways to prevent it are poorly understood. In non-diabetic individuals, a&#xD;
      hormone called glucagon is secreted naturally to raise blood glucose levels but it is unclear&#xD;
      why glucagon secretion is impaired during hypoglycaemia in individuals with T1D.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this prospective observational study is to test the relationship between a&#xD;
      glucagon stimulation test and risk of hypoglycaemia in T1D. It is hoped this research will&#xD;
      establish whether this relationship could be used as a blood test and be a clinically useful&#xD;
      biomarker of hypoglycaemia risk and, therefore, directly inform clinical care of people with&#xD;
      T1D, particularly those with highest risk of hypoglycaemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to complete:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  a Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) at Visit 1 or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  an Arginine Stimulation Test (AST) at Visit 1 or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  a Light MMTT or repeat AST at Visit 3 (approx 6-7 months of Visit 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) and self-reported time spent in hypoglycaemia will&#xD;
           be undertaken for 2 weeks following Visits 1 and 3.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Blood glucose levels are normally controlled by insulin, a hormone that lowers high blood&#xD;
      glucose levels, and glucagon which is released into the blood to raise glucose when levels&#xD;
      are low. For people with Type 1 diabetes (T1D), taking insulin medication to lower glucose&#xD;
      levels can sometimes result in dangerously low blood sugar levels (hypoglycaemia). The&#xD;
      ability to release glucagon and correct blood glucose can vary, particularly in people who&#xD;
      have had T1D for years. The study aims to find out how blood glucagon levels after a stimulus&#xD;
      compare to a person's own experience of hypoglycaemia, and hypoglycaemia. This research will&#xD;
      establish whether glucagon measured after a meal could be used as a blood marker of&#xD;
      hypoglycaemia risk and help to identify individuals at high risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Low post-mixed meal (MM) stimulated glucagon secretion predicts hypoglycaemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to consent, all potential participants will be provided with detailed written&#xD;
      information about the study (that complies with the UK General Data Protection Regulation&#xD;
      (GDPR) and Data Protection Act 2018) and an opportunity to discuss it with one of the&#xD;
      research team. All participants will be informed of their right to withdraw from the study at&#xD;
      any time without prejudice or jeopardy to any future clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A unique study ID will be allocated to the participant to link all participant study&#xD;
      information and samples. The participant's clinical characteristics and sample results will&#xD;
      be recorded on the participant's Case Report Form and entered on the study database.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will undergo core data collection, measurements and provide fasted and&#xD;
      stimulated blood samples via a cannula at the baseline MMTT and AST visits 1 and 2 and again&#xD;
      at the 6 months 'Light MMTT' / repeat AST visit. The order of MMTT and AST tests in visits 1&#xD;
      and 2 will be randomised to check for an order effect. Test choice for Visit 3 depends on the&#xD;
      peak glucagon results from Visits 1 and 2. At Visits 1 and 3, participants will be asked to&#xD;
      complete the hypoglycaemia questionnaire data (Clarke and Gold scores) to assess awareness of&#xD;
      hypoglycaemia and quality of life measures which may relate to the MM-glucagon. Participants&#xD;
      will be given an Abbot FreeStyle Libre Pro continuous blood glucose monitor (CGM) and asked&#xD;
      to perform a 2-week continuous measure of blood glucose (CGM). Clinical diabetes care will&#xD;
      not be changed and participants with T1D will use their own insulin regimes and&#xD;
      self-monitoring (even if CGM or Abbot FreeStyle Libre Pro) during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fasted samples will be obtained for baseline measures: routine glucose and HbA1c, plasma and&#xD;
      serum for storage and future batched analysis including measures of glucose, glucagon,&#xD;
      insulin (C-peptide) and other markers of interest, plus sodium heparin and PAXgenesRNA&#xD;
      samples for T1D immune function analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stimulated samples (see test descriptions below): insulin (C-peptide), glucose and glucagon&#xD;
      will be measured at all time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of each test period, the participant's blood glucose will be checked and&#xD;
      appropriate advice will be given relating to insulin dosage adjustments and a light meal will&#xD;
      be provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A) Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) at Visit 1 or 2 (approx 2½ hours) Rationale: The MMTT&#xD;
      will provide confirmatory analysis of post-mixed meal glucagon stored in BD P800 and EDTA&#xD;
      plasma samples at a range of standard MMTT time points (0, 30, 60, 90 and 120 min) in 75&#xD;
      people. Glucose will be measured in Fluoride Oxalate samples at the same time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  be monitored closely throughout their visit for any discomfort or problems and&#xD;
           appropriate advice/support will be given if required.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  be given Ensure HP or Fortisip (6ml/kg to a max of 360mls)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  have blood samples collected, to measure insulin, C-peptide, glucose, and glucagon, at&#xD;
           specific intervals: -10, 0, 30, 60, 90, 120 minutes post meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B) Arginine Stimulation Test (AST) Visit 1 or 2 (approx 1 hour) Rationale. An MMTT (despite&#xD;
      being convenient because it avoids the need for an IV stimulus) has limitations, including&#xD;
      differences in gastric emptying, uptake and effects on enteroendocrine secretion. Therefore,&#xD;
      responses will be compared during the MMTT with those obtained during an intravenous arginine&#xD;
      challenge, Arginine Stimulation Test (AST), (5 g Arginine during 1 min) at a separate visit&#xD;
      from the MMTT visit. Glucose, plasma glucagon and C-peptide will be measured at baseline and&#xD;
      specific intervals following the Arginine bolus injection. This test is designed primarily to&#xD;
      test the maximum insulin secretion capacity of a participant's beta cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The AST test involves:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Set up. Intravenous catheters will be inserted into antecubital veins in both arms. One&#xD;
           arm will be used for infusion of Arginine (amino acid), and the other arm for&#xD;
           intermittent sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Baseline samples will be taken at -10 and 0 minutes. A maximally stimulating dose of&#xD;
           Arginine Hydrochloride (5 g) will be injected intravenously for 45s. Samples will be&#xD;
           collected at 2, 5, 10, 15 and 30 minute intervals following the Arginine bolus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      C) 'Light MMTT' - Visit 3, approx 6 months after Visit 1 (2 hours) This test is as described&#xD;
      above for MMTT but only a single sample will be collected at the most informative time, as&#xD;
      assessed from the first MMTT and AST. Clinical data will be collected, plus hypoglycaemia&#xD;
      questionnaires and 2-week CGM data collection with participant blinded Abbott FreeStyle Libre&#xD;
      Pro.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Visit 3, the choice of test will be either a 'Light MMTT' or a repeat AST, determined by&#xD;
      the peak glucagon results from the tests conducted at Visits 1 and 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection and Recording: Data will be initially recorded using a study-specific case&#xD;
      report form (CRF), with hard copies stored in the Trial Master File (TMF). Anonymised&#xD;
      research data will be recorded on a study-specific database and reviewed for discrepancies&#xD;
      and missing data prior to analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End of Study Definition: The end of the study is the 3 months after the final participant's 7&#xD;
      months follow-up period to allow for final collection of data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for premature withdrawal from the study: Where a participant withdraws, data will be&#xD;
      collected up to the point of withdrawal in line with the protocol and study SOPs. Where a&#xD;
      participant has prematurely withdrawn but not revoked consent, data and samples will remain&#xD;
      within the study and included in any analysis. Where consent is withdrawn, study samples and&#xD;
      data will be kept/destroyed as per local guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples: A detailed SOP/work instruction will detail the clinical procedure for sample&#xD;
      collection, labelling, logging and management. Central laboratory analysis of the study&#xD;
      samples will be undertaken at the Exeter Blood Sciences Laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stored samples: Surplus samples for storage should be processed, logged and frozen at -80°C&#xD;
      within 24 hours of receipt. All saved samples will be stored under the study ID, with the&#xD;
      file linking the study code to personal identifiable information held securely by the&#xD;
      Principal Investigator, accessible only to personnel with training in data protection who&#xD;
      require this information to perform their duties.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety, Definitions and Reporting:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks: The blood samples will be collected by members of the research team trained in&#xD;
      venepuncture. During the MMTT/AST test, there is a possible risk of hyperglycaemia and&#xD;
      appropriate advice/support will be given if required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Benefits: The study may improve understanding of participants' hypoglycaemia risk. In the&#xD;
      longer term, this work may provide evidence that the ability of alpha cells to release&#xD;
      glucagon after a mixed meal is variable within people with T1D, associated with hypoglycaemia&#xD;
      risk, and could be a biomarker for hypoglycaemia risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definitions and reporting of adverse effects (what should be reported?) The timeframe for&#xD;
      recording SAEs will be from the time of consent to one week following the last visit of a&#xD;
      study subject. Any reportable adverse effects noted will be reported within 24 hours to the&#xD;
      CI and the Sponsor as per standard NHS R&amp;D protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Insurance: Sponsor's public liability will be provided by the University of Exeter for the&#xD;
      design and management of the study. NHS indemnity will apply for the conduct of the study at&#xD;
      the site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Handling &amp; Record Keeping: The CI is responsible for ensuring that participant anonymity&#xD;
      is protected and maintained, ensuring that their identities are protected from any&#xD;
      unauthorised parties. The CI is the 'Custodian' of the data. All information related to study&#xD;
      participants will be kept confidential and managed in accordance with the UK GDPR and Data&#xD;
      Protection Act 2018, NHS Caldicott Guardian, UK Policy Framework for Health &amp; Social Care,&#xD;
      and Research Ethics Committee Approval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A unique Study ID will be allocated to each participant. All study data and samples will be&#xD;
      pseudo-anonymised and stored under the Study ID on a secure password-protected study&#xD;
      database. Identifiable information will be stored on a separate, secure password-protected&#xD;
      database held on an NHS server to enable the research team to undertake the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All paper copies of study data will be stored under ID number and kept in locked,&#xD;
      access-controlled offices within the research facilities; research data will be held&#xD;
      separately to identifiable information. Researchers involved in data analysis will not have&#xD;
      access to personal identifiable data, only the anonymised research data. No identifiable data&#xD;
      will be included in research publications or progress reports.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any participant information required to be sent to a third party will adhere to these&#xD;
      pseudo-anonymised parameters. No participant identifiable data will be sent outside the EU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Record Retention and Archiving: When the research study is complete, it is a requirement of&#xD;
      the UK Policy Framework for Health &amp; Social Care and Sponsor Trust Policy that the records&#xD;
      are kept for a further 15 years. At the end of the study, anonymised data will be included in&#xD;
      the study's final dataset and stored indefinitely on vivli.org or similar sponsor/funder&#xD;
      approved data repository. Personal data will be stored where consent is given by the&#xD;
      participant to be contacted for follow-up on their future health status, and/or about&#xD;
      participating in future studies. Where consent is given by the participant, their samples and&#xD;
      data from the project will be gifted to the Peninsula Research Bank (an approved tissue bank,&#xD;
      REC ref 19/SW/1059) to be used for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study, it will be archived by the CI at the University of Exeter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis: For a sample size of 75, it should be possible to detect a correlation&#xD;
      between stimulated glucagon and hypoglycaemia of r=0.3, with 95% confidence intervals 0.08 to&#xD;
      0.49, plus correlation of MM-induced increases in plasma glucagon to plasma co-peptin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compliance: The CI will ensure that the study is conducted in compliance with the principles&#xD;
      of the Declaration of Helsinki (2013), the principles of GCP and in accordance with all&#xD;
      applicable regulatory requirements including but not limited to the UK Policy Framework for&#xD;
      Health &amp; Social Care and the Medicines for Human Use (Clinical Trial) Regulations 2004, as&#xD;
      amended in 2006, 2008 and 2009 and any future relevant or replacement EU Regulations, Trust&#xD;
      and R&amp;D Office policies and procedures and any subsequent amendments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Publication Policy: Results will be written up and submitted for publication in a&#xD;
      peer-reviewed journal(s). Abstracts will be submitted to national and international&#xD;
      conferences. Results will be presented to clinical colleagues at regular in-house meetings. A&#xD;
      letter/newsletter outlining the key findings of the study will be sent to all participants&#xD;
      and will be uploaded to the study website. An in-person/online event may also be arranged.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 23, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>A description of the strength and reproducibility of the relationship of post-Mixed Meal and Arginine stimulated glucagon with hypoglycaemia.</measure>
    <time_frame>22 months</time_frame>
    <description>The longitudinal stability of stimulated glucagon will be described, including its relationship with variation in hypoglycaemia frequency, and the potential to predict future hypoglycaemia. This will be be determined from post-MM &amp; Arginine-induced plasma glucagon levels, continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) time spent in hypoglycaemia, and self-reported hypoglycaemia episodes, hypoglycaemia fear/awareness, and fear of hypoglycaemia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Longitudinal variability of glucagon levels and its relationship to episodes of hypoglycaemia in long-duration T1D.</measure>
    <time_frame>22 months</time_frame>
    <description>Stimulated and plasma glucagon levels, and continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) will be used to describe longitudinal variability of glucagon levels and its relationship to episodes of hypoglycaemia in long-duration T1D.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The relationship between plasma glucagon levels under basal conditions, following a stimulation (by mixed meal or arginine)</measure>
    <time_frame>22 months</time_frame>
    <description>A mechanistic understanding of the relationship between plasma glucagon levels under basal conditions, following a stimulation (by mixed meal or arginine) will be derived. The cause/effect relationship between hypoglycaemia and alpha cell function will be investigated via stimulated and plasma glucagon levels, and continuous glucose monitoring (CGM).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Hypoglycemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MMTT Visit 1, AST Visit 2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) Visit 1 and Arginine Stimulated Test (AST) Visit 2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AST Visit 1, MMTT Visit 2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Arginine Stimulated Test (AST) Visit 1 and Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT) Visit 2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (MMTT)</intervention_name>
    <description>At either Visit 1 or Visit 2, participants will be given Ensure HP or Fortisip (a drink containing the same amounts of carbohydrates, protein and fats as there would be in a meal; 6ml/kg to a max of 360mls), and have blood samples collected, to measure insulin (C-peptide), glucose, and glucagon, at specific intervals: -10, 0, 30, 60, 90, 120 minutes post meal. This test is used to measure how a participant's beta cells are working to produce insulin after a meal and to check for reactive hypoglycaemia.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AST Visit 1, MMTT Visit 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MMTT Visit 1, AST Visit 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Arginine Stimulation Test (AST)</intervention_name>
    <description>At either Visit 1 or Visit 2, participants will be given a dose of Arginine Hydrochloride (5 g Arginine during 1 min) by intravenous injection, and have blood samples collected to measure insulin (C-peptide), glucose, and glucagon, at specific intervals: -10, 0, 2, 5, 10, 15 and 30 minutes following the Arginine bolus injection. This test is designed primarily to test the maximum insulin secretion capacity of a participant's beta cells.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AST Visit 1, MMTT Visit 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MMTT Visit 1, AST Visit 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Light Mixed Meal Tolerance Test (Light MMTT) OR Repeat AST</intervention_name>
    <description>At Visit 3 (approx 6 months after Visit 2), participants will either be given a Light MMTT or a repeat AST. The Light MMTT is as described for the MMTT, but the specific sampling timepoints to measure insulin (C-peptide), glucose, and glucagon, would be reduced to -10, 0, plus the optimal glucagon time point post meal determined by Visits 1 &amp; 2 test results.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AST Visit 1, MMTT Visit 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MMTT Visit 1, AST Visit 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Serum, plasma, RNA, PBMCs at serial timepoints after a meal or intravenous stimulus.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        75 individuals with long duration T1D, identified from participation in the TIGI study (UK&#xD;
        IRAS ID: 141756, REC Number: 13/SW/0312), with consent to be contacted for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The TIGI participants have a clinical diagnosis of T1D, were on insulin from diagnosis and,&#xD;
        if BMI was &gt;30, were autoantibody positive. We will aim to recruit 50 people with&#xD;
        undetectable C-peptide and 25 with detectable C-peptide. The selection of people with&#xD;
        absent C-peptide allows a secondary analysis focussed on stimulated glucagon without any&#xD;
        potential interaction with endogenous insulin secretion. It also focusses on a group of&#xD;
        people known to be at high hypoglycaemia risk due to lack of endogenous insulin.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of Type 1 diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insulin treated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known urine C-peptide status (using Urinary C-Peptide Creatinine Ratio [UCPCR],&#xD;
             positive/negative defined by UCPCR 0.2nmol/mmol cut-off)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 16-65 years inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to provide informed consent/assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 16 year or over 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating (as this may limit blood sampling and affect T cell function)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would affect the&#xD;
             safety of the subject's participation, or validity of results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard A Oram, MRCP (neph)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Exeter</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Richard A Oram, MRCP (neph)</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0) 1392 408538</phone>
    <email>r.oram@exeter.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Michelle Hudson, BSc</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0) 1392 408181</phone>
    <email>m.hudson@exeter.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Devon University Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <zip>EX2 5DW</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Richard A Oram</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0) 1392 408538</phone>
      <email>r.oram@exeter.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Michelle Hudson</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0) 1392 408183</phone>
      <email>m.hudson@exeter.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andrew T Hattersley</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Timothy McDonald</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lund A, Bagger JI, Wewer Albrechtsen NJ, Christensen M, Grondahl M, Hartmann B, Mathiesen ER, Hansen CP, Storkholm JH, van Hall G, Rehfeld JF, Hornburg D, Meissner F, Mann M, Larsen S, Holst JJ, Vilsboll T, Knop FK. Evidence of Extrapancreatic Glucagon Secretion in Man. Diabetes. 2016 Mar;65(3):585-97. doi: 10.2337/db15-1541. Epub 2015 Dec 15. Erratum In: Diabetes. 2016 Jun;65(6):1752.</citation>
    <PMID>26672094</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gerich JE, Langlois M, Noacco C, Karam JH, Forsham PH. Lack of glucagon response to hypoglycemia in diabetes: evidence for an intrinsic pancreatic alpha cell defect. Science. 1973 Oct 12;182(4108):171-3. doi: 10.1126/science.182.4108.171.</citation>
    <PMID>4581053</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Frier BM. Hypoglycaemia in diabetes mellitus: epidemiology and clinical implications. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2014 Dec;10(12):711-22. doi: 10.1038/nrendo.2014.170. Epub 2014 Oct 7.</citation>
    <PMID>25287289</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hypoglycemia in the Diabetes Control and Complications Trial. The Diabetes Control and Complications Trial Research Group. Diabetes. 1997 Feb;46(2):271-86.</citation>
    <PMID>9000705</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Epidemiology of severe hypoglycemia in the diabetes control and complications trial. The DCCT Research Group. Am J Med. 1991 Apr;90(4):450-9.</citation>
    <PMID>2012085</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cryer PE. Minireview: Glucagon in the pathogenesis of hypoglycemia and hyperglycemia in diabetes. Endocrinology. 2012 Mar;153(3):1039-48. doi: 10.1210/en.2011-1499. Epub 2011 Dec 13.</citation>
    <PMID>22166985</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rorsman P, Ramracheya R, Rorsman NJ, Zhang Q. ATP-regulated potassium channels and voltage-gated calcium channels in pancreatic alpha and beta cells: similar functions but reciprocal effects on secretion. Diabetologia. 2014 Sep;57(9):1749-61. doi: 10.1007/s00125-014-3279-8. Epub 2014 Jun 7.</citation>
    <PMID>24906950</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bollyky J, Greenbaum CJ. Editorial: The role of glucagon in postprandial hyperglycemia--the jury's still out. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007 Aug;92(8):2879-81. doi: 10.1210/jc.2007-1312. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>17682088</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zenz S, Mader JK, Regittnig W, Brunner M, Korsatko S, Boulgaropoulos B, Magnes C, Raml R, Narath SH, Eller P, Augustin T, Pieber TR. Impact of C-Peptide Status on the Response of Glucagon and Endogenous Glucose Production to Induced Hypoglycemia in T1DM. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2018 Apr 1;103(4):1408-1417. doi: 10.1210/jc.2017-01836.</citation>
    <PMID>29408994</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Brissova M, Haliyur R, Saunders D, Shrestha S, Dai C, Blodgett DM, Bottino R, Campbell-Thompson M, Aramandla R, Poffenberger G, Lindner J, Pan FC, von Herrath MG, Greiner DL, Shultz LD, Sanyoura M, Philipson LH, Atkinson M, Harlan DM, Levy SE, Prasad N, Stein R, Powers AC. alpha Cell Function and Gene Expression Are Compromised in Type 1 Diabetes. Cell Rep. 2018 Mar 6;22(10):2667-2676. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2018.02.032.</citation>
    <PMID>29514095</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Brown RJ, Sinaii N, Rother KI. Too much glucagon, too little insulin: time course of pancreatic islet dysfunction in new-onset type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2008 Jul;31(7):1403-4. doi: 10.2337/dc08-0575.</citation>
    <PMID>18594062</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sherr J, Tsalikian E, Fox L, Buckingham B, Weinzimer S, Tamborlane WV, White NH, Arbelaez AM, Kollman C, Ruedy KJ, Cheng P, Beck RW; Diabetes Research in Children Network. Evolution of abnormal plasma glucagon responses to mixed-meal feedings in youth with type 1 diabetes during the first 2 years after diagnosis. Diabetes Care. 2014 Jun;37(6):1741-4. doi: 10.2337/dc13-2612. Epub 2014 Apr 2.</citation>
    <PMID>24696460</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Orskov C, Wettergren A, Holst JJ. Secretion of the incretin hormones glucagon-like peptide-1 and gastric inhibitory polypeptide correlates with insulin secretion in normal man throughout the day. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1996 Jul;31(7):665-70. doi: 10.3109/00365529609009147.</citation>
    <PMID>8819215</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rickels MR, Evans-Molina C, Bahnson HT, Ylescupidez A, Nadeau KJ, Hao W, Clements MA, Sherr JL, Pratley RE, Hannon TS, Shah VN, Miller KM, Greenbaum CJ; T1D Exchange beta-Cell Function Study Group. High residual C-peptide likely contributes to glycemic control in type 1 diabetes. J Clin Invest. 2020 Apr 1;130(4):1850-1862. doi: 10.1172/JCI134057.</citation>
    <PMID>31895699</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhang Q, Ramracheya R, Lahmann C, Tarasov A, Bengtsson M, Braha O, Braun M, Brereton M, Collins S, Galvanovskis J, Gonzalez A, Groschner LN, Rorsman NJ, Salehi A, Travers ME, Walker JN, Gloyn AL, Gribble F, Johnson PR, Reimann F, Ashcroft FM, Rorsman P. Role of KATP channels in glucose-regulated glucagon secretion and impaired counterregulation in type 2 diabetes. Cell Metab. 2013 Dec 3;18(6):871-82. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2013.10.014.</citation>
    <PMID>24315372</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Porksen S, Nielsen LB, Kaas A, Kocova M, Chiarelli F, Orskov C, Holst JJ, Ploug KB, Hougaard P, Hansen L, Mortensen HB; Hvidore Study Group on Childhood Diabetes. Meal-stimulated glucagon release is associated with postprandial blood glucose level and does not interfere with glycemic control in children and adolescents with new-onset type 1 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007 Aug;92(8):2910-6. doi: 10.1210/jc.2007-0244. Epub 2007 May 22.</citation>
    <PMID>17519307</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hare KJ, Vilsboll T, Holst JJ, Knop FK. Inappropriate glucagon response after oral compared with isoglycemic intravenous glucose administration in patients with type 1 diabetes. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Apr;298(4):E832-7. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00700.2009. Epub 2010 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>20103744</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Marren SM, Hammersley S, McDonald TJ, Shields BM, Knight BA, Hill A, Bolt R, Tree TI, Roep BO, Hattersley AT, Jones AG, Oram RA; TIGI consortium. Persistent C-peptide is associated with reduced hypoglycaemia but not HbA1c in adults with longstanding Type 1 diabetes: evidence for lack of intensive treatment in UK clinical practice? Diabet Med. 2019 Sep;36(9):1092-1099. doi: 10.1111/dme.13960. Epub 2019 Jun 27.</citation>
    <PMID>30955221</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Geddes J, Wright RJ, Zammitt NN, Deary IJ, Frier BM. An evaluation of methods of assessing impaired awareness of hypoglycemia in type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2007 Jul;30(7):1868-70. doi: 10.2337/dc06-2556. Epub 2007 Apr 6. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>17416785</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wewer Albrechtsen NJ, Bak MJ, Hartmann B, Christensen LW, Kuhre RE, Deacon CF, Holst JJ. Stability of glucagon-like peptide 1 and glucagon in human plasma. Endocr Connect. 2015 Mar;4(1):50-7. doi: 10.1530/EC-14-0126. Epub 2015 Jan 16.</citation>
    <PMID>25596009</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Atkinson MA, Leiter EH. The NOD mouse model of type 1 diabetes: as good as it gets? Nat Med. 1999 Jun;5(6):601-4. doi: 10.1038/9442. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>10371488</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chen YG, Mathews CE, Driver JP. The Role of NOD Mice in Type 1 Diabetes Research: Lessons from the Past and Recommendations for the Future. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2018 Feb 23;9:51. doi: 10.3389/fendo.2018.00051. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>29527189</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ramracheya R, Ward C, Shigeto M, Walker JN, Amisten S, Zhang Q, Johnson PR, Rorsman P, Braun M. Membrane potential-dependent inactivation of voltage-gated ion channels in alpha-cells inhibits glucagon secretion from human islets. Diabetes. 2010 Sep;59(9):2198-208. doi: 10.2337/db09-1505. Epub 2010 Jun 14.</citation>
    <PMID>20547976</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rorsman P, Ashcroft FM. Pancreatic beta-Cell Electrical Activity and Insulin Secretion: Of Mice and Men. Physiol Rev. 2018 Jan 1;98(1):117-214. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00008.2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29212789</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McDonald TJ, Perry MH, Peake RW, Pullan NJ, O'Connor J, Shields BM, Knight BA, Hattersley AT. EDTA improves stability of whole blood C-peptide and insulin to over 24 hours at room temperature. PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e42084. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0042084. Epub 2012 Jul 30.</citation>
    <PMID>22860060</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McDonald TJ, Besser RE, Perry M, Babiker T, Knight BA, Shepherd MH, Ellard S, Flanagan SE, Hattersley AT. Screening for neonatal diabetes at day 5 of life using dried blood spot glucose measurement. Diabetologia. 2017 Nov;60(11):2168-2173. doi: 10.1007/s00125-017-4383-3. Epub 2017 Aug 5.</citation>
    <PMID>28779213</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Battelino T, Danne T, Bergenstal RM, Amiel SA, Beck R, Biester T, Bosi E, Buckingham BA, Cefalu WT, Close KL, Cobelli C, Dassau E, DeVries JH, Donaghue KC, Dovc K, Doyle FJ 3rd, Garg S, Grunberger G, Heller S, Heinemann L, Hirsch IB, Hovorka R, Jia W, Kordonouri O, Kovatchev B, Kowalski A, Laffel L, Levine B, Mayorov A, Mathieu C, Murphy HR, Nimri R, Norgaard K, Parkin CG, Renard E, Rodbard D, Saboo B, Schatz D, Stoner K, Urakami T, Weinzimer SA, Phillip M. Clinical Targets for Continuous Glucose Monitoring Data Interpretation: Recommendations From the International Consensus on Time in Range. Diabetes Care. 2019 Aug;42(8):1593-1603. doi: 10.2337/dci19-0028. Epub 2019 Jun 8.</citation>
    <PMID>31177185</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Milan AM, D'Souza RF, Pundir S, Pileggi CA, Thorstensen EB, Barnett MP, Markworth JF, Cameron-Smith D, Mitchell CJ. Older Adults Have Delayed Amino Acid Absorption after a High Protein Mixed Breakfast Meal. J Nutr Health Aging. 2015 Oct;19(8):839-45. doi: 10.1007/s12603-015-0500-5.</citation>
    <PMID>26412288</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Salehi A, Gunnerud U, Muhammed SJ, Ostman E, Holst JJ, Bjorck I, Rorsman P. The insulinogenic effect of whey protein is partially mediated by a direct effect of amino acids and GIP on beta-cells. Nutr Metab (Lond). 2012 May 30;9(1):48. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-9-48.</citation>
    <PMID>22647249</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>De Marinis YZ, Salehi A, Ward CE, Zhang Q, Abdulkader F, Bengtsson M, Braha O, Braun M, Ramracheya R, Amisten S, Habib AM, Moritoh Y, Zhang E, Reimann F, Rosengren A, Shibasaki T, Gribble F, Renstrom E, Seino S, Eliasson L, Rorsman P. GLP-1 inhibits and adrenaline stimulates glucagon release by differential modulation of N- and L-type Ca2+ channel-dependent exocytosis. Cell Metab. 2010 Jun 9;11(6):543-553. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2010.04.007.</citation>
    <PMID>20519125</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Winzeler B, Cesana-Nigro N, Refardt J, Vogt DR, Imber C, Morin B, Popovic M, Steinmetz M, Sailer CO, Szinnai G, Chifu I, Fassnacht M, Christ-Crain M. Arginine-stimulated copeptin measurements in the differential diagnosis of diabetes insipidus: a prospective diagnostic study. Lancet. 2019 Aug 17;394(10198):587-595. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31255-3. Epub 2019 Jul 11.</citation>
    <PMID>31303316</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Knudsen JG, Hamilton A, Ramracheya R, Tarasov AI, Brereton M, Haythorne E, Chibalina MV, Spegel P, Mulder H, Zhang Q, Ashcroft FM, Adam J, Rorsman P. Dysregulation of Glucagon Secretion by Hyperglycemia-Induced Sodium-Dependent Reduction of ATP Production. Cell Metab. 2019 Feb 5;29(2):430-442.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2018.10.003. Epub 2018 Nov 8.</citation>
    <PMID>30415925</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Walker JN, Ramracheya R, Zhang Q, Johnson PR, Braun M, Rorsman P. Regulation of glucagon secretion by glucose: paracrine, intrinsic or both? Diabetes Obes Metab. 2011 Oct;13 Suppl 1:95-105. doi: 10.1111/j.1463-1326.2011.01450.x.</citation>
    <PMID>21824262</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vergari E, Knudsen JG, Ramracheya R, Salehi A, Zhang Q, Adam J, Asterholm IW, Benrick A, Briant LJB, Chibalina MV, Gribble FM, Hamilton A, Hastoy B, Reimann F, Rorsman NJG, Spiliotis II, Tarasov A, Wu Y, Ashcroft FM, Rorsman P. Insulin inhibits glucagon release by SGLT2-induced stimulation of somatostatin secretion. Nat Commun. 2019 Jan 11;10(1):139. doi: 10.1038/s41467-018-08193-8.</citation>
    <PMID>30635569</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ramracheya RD, McCulloch LJ, Clark A, Wiggins D, Johannessen H, Olsen MK, Cai X, Zhao CM, Chen D, Rorsman P. PYY-Dependent Restoration of Impaired Insulin and Glucagon Secretion in Type 2 Diabetes following Roux-En-Y Gastric Bypass Surgery. Cell Rep. 2016 May 3;15(5):944-950. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2016.03.091. Epub 2016 Apr 21.</citation>
    <PMID>27117413</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hamilton A, Zhang Q, Salehi A, Willems M, Knudsen JG, Ringgaard AK, Chapman CE, Gonzalez-Alvarez A, Surdo NC, Zaccolo M, Basco D, Johnson PRV, Ramracheya R, Rutter GA, Galione A, Rorsman P, Tarasov AI. Adrenaline Stimulates Glucagon Secretion by Tpc2-Dependent Ca2+ Mobilization From Acidic Stores in Pancreatic alpha-Cells. Diabetes. 2018 Jun;67(6):1128-1139. doi: 10.2337/db17-1102. Epub 2018 Mar 21.</citation>
    <PMID>29563152</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>type 1 diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>autoimmune diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>beta cell destruction</keyword>
  <keyword>hypoglycaemia</keyword>
  <keyword>hyperglycaemia</keyword>
  <keyword>glucagon</keyword>
  <keyword>type 1 diabetes genetic risk</keyword>
  <keyword>alpha cell</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>At the end of the study, anonymised data will be included in the study's final dataset and stored indefinitely in a sponsor/funder approved data repository. In addition, where consent is given by the participant, their samples and data from the project will be gifted to the Peninsula Research Bank (an approved tissue bank, REC ref 19/SW/1059) in Exeter to be used for future research.&#xD;
Any participant information required to be sent to a third party will adhere to these pseudo-anonymised parameters, this includes the participant's date of birth, gender, and unique study ID. No participant identifiable data will be sent outside the EU.&#xD;
Anonymised clinical study data will be shared on vivli.org or similar funder and sponsor approved participant-level data repository, which has not yet been finalised at the time of submitting this protocol to ClinicalTrials.gov.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will become available 12 months after the study end.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Applications submitted via the approved data repository would be considered.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

