<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05616754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LKM-2022-NCV-GJ01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05616754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial Evaluate the Immunogenicity and Safety of Recombinant COVID-19 Omicron-Delta Variant Vaccine (CHO Cell)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy co. Ltd.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study was designed as a randomized, blind and controlled trial. A total of 300 patients&#xD;
      aged 18 and above who were immunized with recombinant novel coronavirus protein vaccine (CHO&#xD;
      cell) for more than 4 months (60 patients aged 60 and above) were randomly and blind divided&#xD;
      into the experimental group and the control group, and received the experimental vaccine and&#xD;
      the control vaccine, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, 100 patients over 4 months after the completion of basic immunization with&#xD;
      COVID-19 mRNA vaccine were selected as the open observation group, all of whom received 1&#xD;
      dose of experimental vaccine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The improved vaccine was developed against the Delta and Omicron COVID-19 variants. The&#xD;
      overall design of this clinical trial was as follows: A total of 300 patients aged 18 and&#xD;
      above who completed the basic immunization of recombinant novel coronavirus protein vaccine&#xD;
      (CHO cell) for more than 4 months were randomly divided into the experimental group and the&#xD;
      control group in a blind way, and were inoculated with the experimental vaccine and the&#xD;
      control vaccine respectively. In addition, 100 patients over 4 months after the completion of&#xD;
      basic immunization with COVID-19 mRNA vaccine were selected as the open observation group,&#xD;
      all of whom received 1 dose of experimental vaccine. The main objective was to evaluate the&#xD;
      immunogenicity and safety of Omicron-Delta recombinant novel coronavirus protein vaccine (CHO&#xD;
      cells) against Omicron variants of novel coronavirus in people aged 18 years and above.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 7, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end points</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Geometric mean concentration (GMC) of RBD protein-binding Antibody (IgG) against Omicron variant of novel coronavirus at 14 days after vaccination in experimental group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end points 2</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>RBD protein-bound antibody (IgG) growth ratio (GMI) and positive turnover rate for Omicron variant of novel coronavirus at 14 days after vaccination in experimental group and control group;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end points 3</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>RBD protein-binding antibody (IgG) GMC, GMI and positive turnover were detected against the primary COVID-19 strain and Delta variant 14 days after vaccination in experimental group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end points 4</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>RBD protein-binding antibody (IgG) GMC, GMI and positive turnover against the primary COVID-19 strain, Delta and Omicron variants 6 months after vaccination in the experimental group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end points 5</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>RBD protein-binding antibody (IgG) GMC, GMI and positive turnover against the primary COVID-19 strain, Delta and Omicron variants were detected 14 days after vaccination in the observation group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end points 6</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>RBD protein-binding antibody (IgG) GMC, GMI and positive turnover against the primary COVID-19 strain, Delta and Omicron variants in the observation group for 6 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>People more than 4 months after completing basic immunization with recombinant novel coronavirus protein vaccine (CHO cells)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>People more than 4 months after completing basic immunization with recombinant novel coronavirus protein vaccine (CHO cells)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>People over 4 months after completing basic immunization with COVID-19 mRNA vaccine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Omicron-Delta Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Protein Vaccine (CHO cells)</intervention_name>
    <description>The antigen protein of this product is designed to be expressed in tandem with Delta variant R319-N356 and Omicron variant R319-N356. The antigen is called DO-RBD for short.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Protein Vaccine (CHO cells)</intervention_name>
    <description>This strain was made from the NCP-RBD receptor binding region of the spike glycoprotein of novel coronavirus expressed in recombinant CHO cells, which was purified and added with aluminum hydroxide adjuvant</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age eligible for observation in this clinical trial: adults aged 18 years and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects voluntarily participate in this study, sign informed consent, provide legal&#xD;
             identification, and understand and comply with the requirements of the test protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than 4 months after the completion of the whole course of recombinant novel&#xD;
             coronavirus protein vaccine (CHO cell) basic immunization or more than 4 months after&#xD;
             the completion of the novel coronavirus mRNA vaccine basic immunization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female and male participants of childbearing age took effective contraception during&#xD;
             the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior history of severe allergy to any vaccine or to any component of the test&#xD;
             vaccine, including aluminum preparation, such as anaphylactic shock, allergic&#xD;
             laryngeal edema, purpura, thrombocytopenic purpura, local allergic necrosis reaction&#xD;
             (Arthus reaction), dyspnea, angineurotic edema, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected or confirmed fever (axillary temperature ≥37.3℃/ mouth temperature ≥37.5℃)&#xD;
             within 72 hours before enrollment, or armpit temperature ≥37.3℃/ mouth temperature&#xD;
             ≥37.5℃ on the day of enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed cases of COVID-19 infection, asymptomatic infected persons or positive&#xD;
             nucleic acid test history of COVID-19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled lymphoproliferative disease, unremission stage of aplastic anemia, active&#xD;
             stage of primary immune thrombocytopenia (ITP), uncontrolled stage of coagulation&#xD;
             disease, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a history of congenital or acquired immunodeficiency or autoimmune disease; Absence of&#xD;
             spleen, or history of splenic surgery, trauma, or immunomodulator treatment within 6&#xD;
             months, such as immunosuppressive dose of glucocorticoids (dose reference: equivalent&#xD;
             to prednisone 20mg/ day, over a week); Or monoclonal antibodies; Or thymosin; Or&#xD;
             interferon; But topical use (such as ointments, eye drops, inhalants or nasal sprays)&#xD;
             is permitted;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subunit vaccine and inactivated vaccine should be administered within 14 days before&#xD;
             vaccination, and live attenuated vaccine should be administered within 30 days before&#xD;
             vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with malignant tumors who are undergoing chemotherapy, radiotherapy or&#xD;
             immunotherapy before and after surgery; Patients with organ transplant status;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with uncontrolled epilepsy and other progressive neurological diseases (e.g.&#xD;
             Transverse myelitis, Guillain-Barre syndrome, demyelinating diseases, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with acute disease, or acute episodes of chronic disease, or uncontrolled&#xD;
             severe chronic disease, such as medically uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure ≥150mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure ≥100mmHg);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lactating or pregnant women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The investigator believes that the subject has any disease or condition that could put&#xD;
             the subject at risk; The subject is unable to complete the trial as required by the&#xD;
             protocol, and there are circumstances that interfere with the assessment of vaccine&#xD;
             response.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erkin Musabaev, Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Research institute of virology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Akhmedova Guzal, Bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>998-935281313</phone>
    <email>abidovagoga@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Uzbekistan, Tashkent city, Said baraka street 10</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tashkent</city>
        <zip>100012</zip>
        <country>Uzbekistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Akhmedova Guzal, Bachelor</last_name>
      <phone>998-935281313</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Uzbekistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>IgG</keyword>
  <keyword>GMC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

