<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05613959</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UM 0001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05613959</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating the Novel Veress Plus Needle</brief_title>
  <acronym>Veress+</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the New Veress Needle+ Mechanism; A Study on Thiel-embalmed Bodies.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Prof Jean Calleja-Agius</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Malta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      18 participants (novices, intermediates and experts) performed in total 248 insertions in a&#xD;
      systematic way on Thiel embalmed bodies with wide and small bore versions of the conventional&#xD;
      VNc (conventional Veress Needle) and the VN+(The Veress Needle plus). Insertion depth was&#xD;
      measured by recording the graduations on the needle under direct laparoscopic vision.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In total two Thiel embalmed bodies were used over three days. The first body was a 72 year&#xD;
      old male with no previous laparotomy or abdominal scars, who had died of myocardial&#xD;
      infarction (Length: 170 cm; bodyweight: 70 kg). The 2nd body was a male of 65 years without&#xD;
      abdominal scars. The cause of death had been a hospital acquired pneumonia and pulmonary&#xD;
      embolism secondary to metastatic pancreatic cancer (length186 cm; bodyweight: 80kg).&#xD;
&#xD;
      An Aesculap laparoscopy tower set up (Aesculap, 3773 Corporate Parkway, Center Valley, 18034&#xD;
      PA, USA) was used with a 10 mm 30 degrees scope, which was inserted through a balloon trocar&#xD;
      (Medtronic Netherlands, Larixplein 4, 5616VB Eindhoven, The Netherlands) in the abdomen just&#xD;
      below the umbilicus. Intra-abdominal pressure was stabilized using CO2 (Carbon Dioxide) to 4&#xD;
      mm Hg(Mercury). This pressure-level was as low as possible to allow for unambiguous&#xD;
      visualization of the insertions but almost equalling normal abdominal pressure. Two different&#xD;
      needle types were used, a thin bore needle with a diameter of 2 millimeter (mm) and a length&#xD;
      of 145 mm and a wide bore with 2.8 mm diameter and 145 mm length. The study was registered&#xD;
      under number FRECMDS-2021-134 of the Ethical Committee of Faculty of Medicine and Surgery of&#xD;
      the University of Malta.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaire The investigators used a questionnaire which consisted of questions about&#xD;
      gender, age and previous experience. A 1 to 5 Likert scale was used to score the&#xD;
      &quot;life-likeness&quot; of the Thiel embalmed bodies, realism of the procedure, safety the VN+&#xD;
      procedure, and difficulty of using the new needle design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol After completing the first part of the questionnaire, the participants were&#xD;
      instructed and explained how the mechanism works. During the instruction phase, they were&#xD;
      allowed to try the needle on a dedicated area, away from the intended research area, until&#xD;
      they were able to manage their grip and found their best insertion strategies. To minimize&#xD;
      the risk of hitting organs upon entering the abdominal cavity, certain areas are dedicated&#xD;
      for VN (Veress Needle) placement such as Palmer's point in the left upper quadrant of the&#xD;
      abdomen. In order to use the bodies as efficiently as possible whilst offering a similar&#xD;
      experience in terms of abdominal composition to all participants, the whole upper part of the&#xD;
      abdomen was used for the insertions, which were done in an alternating fashion (with and&#xD;
      without the safety mechanism) for 12 punctures (2x6) from cranial to caudal so a &quot;fresh&quot; part&#xD;
      (with no defect or lesion) of abdominal wall was used for each attempt. The participants were&#xD;
      with their backs to the video monitor so they were blinded to what was happening inside the&#xD;
      abdomen. Insertion of the VN+ was successful when the mechanism fully unlocked. If not, the&#xD;
      attempt was noted as an unsuccessful trial, the cause was determined and the insertion data&#xD;
      was removed. After the hands- on part, the participants were asked to fill out the last part&#xD;
      of the questionnaire with questions about the quality of the bodies and procedures based on&#xD;
      their personal experiences and the difficulty of using the VN+ device. It is important to&#xD;
      note that the VN+ dislodge action is not influenced by the amount of insertion force but only&#xD;
      by the position of the inner stylet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data comparison and Statistical analysis Video footage was used by three observers to&#xD;
      determine the insertion depth, indicated by the number of markings engraved on the part of&#xD;
      the needle surface inside the abdomen. The true insertion depth was calculated in Excel based&#xD;
      on the known distance between each marking. After the participants completed the tests, any&#xD;
      differences in maximum insertion depth between the VNc and VN+ groups were determined with a&#xD;
      Student's t-test (SPSS v16, SPSS, Inc., Chicago, IL). A p-value &lt; 0.05 was considered a&#xD;
      signiﬁcant difference. The same was done comparing the wide bore with the small bore needles&#xD;
      and other variables including the different genders. The potential learning curve was&#xD;
      established based on a regression analysis executed on the averaged outcomes per trial&#xD;
      including all trial data. The potential influence of wear was established based on a&#xD;
      regression analysis conducted on 12 separately executed trials with the wide bore needles.&#xD;
      Wear is defined as diminishing sharpness of the bevel of the Veress needle after each&#xD;
      attempt. For the regression analysis a p-value &lt;0.05 was considered signiﬁcantly different.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 26, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 26, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>depth of insertion</measure>
    <time_frame>20 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>the depth of insertion of the needle into the abdominal cavity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Pneumoperitoneum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Veress +</arm_group_label>
    <description>The Veress+ system was used</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Veress conventional</arm_group_label>
    <description>The Conventional Veress needle was used</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Veress +</intervention_name>
    <description>The Veress+ safety mechanism was used</description>
    <arm_group_label>Veress +</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conventional Veress</intervention_name>
    <description>The Conventional Veress Needle was used</description>
    <arm_group_label>Veress conventional</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Surgical residents, young surgeons, exeprienced surgeons from the University of Malta Mater&#xD;
        Dei Hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  medical background, healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  physically or mentally handicapped&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean Calleja Agius, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Malta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laboratory for Anatomy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valletta</city>
        <zip>MSD 2080</zip>
        <country>Malta</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malta</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 17, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Malta</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof Jean Calleja-Agius</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor; Head of Department of Anatomy</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Veress Needle</keyword>
  <keyword>Thiel Embalmed Cadavers</keyword>
  <keyword>Laparoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety mechanism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumoperitoneum</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 1, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/59/NCT05613959/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 1, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/59/NCT05613959/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

