<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05628519</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CAST2 N°20-119</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05628519</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Captain Sonar Impact on Trauma Patient Management</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAST2</acronym>
  <official_title>Captain Sonar Impact on Trauma Patient Management</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Claude Bernard University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Research on Healthcare Performance Lab U1290</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Laboratoire Interuniversitaire de Biologie de la Motricité</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Claude Bernard University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Trauma patient care requires collaboration and interaction with close relationship between&#xD;
      many stakeholders from different professions (senior doctor, intern, nurse, nurse helpers,&#xD;
      surgeons, etc).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a stressful situation where decision and action need to be quick, decisive and&#xD;
      coordinate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this situation, quality of care and patient safety depends on a good interprofessional&#xD;
      communication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The acquisition of advanced communication skills, team management and leadership, stress&#xD;
      management are essentials elements in the practice of Intensive and trauma care. However,&#xD;
      advanced structured training or assessment of theses skills is lacking in medical education&#xD;
      or Healthcare professionals training. The study therefore, aimed to develop a global and&#xD;
      attractive training to help healthcare professionals to improve their skills.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Captain SonarTM is a naval battle game where two teams each composed of four participants&#xD;
      clash. Each player has a well-defined role and it is imperative to communicate in a closed&#xD;
      loop to advance in the game. This game also includes components similar to support for shock&#xD;
      management: stress, speed of action, central communication and teamwork of four protagonists&#xD;
      (Team Leader-Captain, intern-Second, nurse-Mechanic, Nurse help-Detector). It may improve&#xD;
      team building, team leadership, interprofessional work, communication, stress management. The&#xD;
      study hypothesis is that this board game would have an impact on the performance of&#xD;
      professionals when facing a multiple trauma simulated patient. (differences in terms of&#xD;
      technical and non-technical performance. Different use of closed loop communication,&#xD;
      Different stress management, different efficiency and interprofessional collaboration with&#xD;
      potentially a reduction in the timing of treatment being delivered in trauma room)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All the teams of 4 participants and 1 medical Student previously trained will then benefit&#xD;
      from a training session either exposed to captain sonar or into the control arm with&#xD;
      monopoly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      High-fidelity and multiprofessional simulation session based on the incoming of a severe&#xD;
      traumatized patient will be held. These sessions will take place on high-fidelity mannequins&#xD;
      lent by the CLESS (Lyonnais Center for Health Simulation Education) in pavilion H of Édouard&#xD;
      Herriot Hospital, within the Trauma Center (in situ).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The same scenario will be presented for all groups (exposed and controls) with the same&#xD;
      objectives of realization and the same complexity. An audio-visual recording will take place&#xD;
      during each session in order to allow the evaluation of the study criteria on technical and&#xD;
      non technical skills between the participants a posteriori of the simulation session.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized control Trial, double blind</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical skills</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Total time of care in the trauma room, in seconds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Non technical skills</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation</time_frame>
    <description>use of closed loop communications:&#xD;
- count of the number of closed loops/minute</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stress profile and stress management</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analog Scale of Stress, from 0 to 100 maximum</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographic data</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Demographic data (sex, age, previous experience as health care professional, experience in simulation, experience in gaming, experience in stress management)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Debriefing Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately After Debriefing</time_frame>
    <description>Debriefing Assessment in Simulation in Healthcare (DASH) evaluated by team leader, nurse and facilitator, from 6 to 42 maximum</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of exposure on Performance, communication and stress management</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately After simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analogic Scale, from 0 to 100 maximum</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical skills grid</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation.</time_frame>
    <description>Technical performance score (Grid out of 100 points); from 0 to 100 maximum</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical skills key tasks</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation.</time_frame>
    <description>Completion time for 5 key tasks (Hemocue result, blood pressure result, sample) in seconds Blood, realization of the FAST Ultrasound, Departure for OR/CT).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical skills self efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation.</time_frame>
    <description>Self Efficacy estimation on Several cases, from 0 to 100 maximum Visual analog scale of support performance felt after the simulation session;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non technical skills crew ressource 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation.</time_frame>
    <description>Non technical skills score : from 0 to 54 maximum</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non technical skills crew ressource 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation.</time_frame>
    <description>Non technical skills Score 2: from 1 to 5 maximum</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non technical skills communication anticipation</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during simulation session. Within 20 minutes of the simulation.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of anticipation of each participation (initiation of an act without prior request by the Team leader);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non technical skills quality of team communication</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analog Scale quality of team communication, from 0 to 100 maximum.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non technical skills confidence for team leader</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analog Scale of confidence in the team and the team leader , from 0 to 100 maximum.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analog Scale type of stress</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the simulation session</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analog Scale of stress</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety profile</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the simulation session;</time_frame>
    <description>Stait Trait Anxiety Inventory Trait, from 20 to 80 maximum.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stress profiles and stress management physiological measurement heart rate variability</measure>
    <time_frame>During Simulation within the 20 minutes of simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Physiological stress assessment of 2 of each team members will be performed throughout inclusion (during exposure and during simulation) and measured by non-invasive and continuous recording:&#xD;
- Heart and respiratory rates and heart rate variability (Hexoskin® t-shirt)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stress profiles and stress management electrodermal activity</measure>
    <time_frame>During Simulation within the 20 minutes of simulation</time_frame>
    <description>Electrodermal activity, reflecting the stress and activation of individuals (Empatica E4 watch on the wrist non-dominant)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Trauma Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Captain Sonar</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a training by a game session at Captain SonarTM of 60 min (including 15 min of presentation and prize in hand of the game) against a standardized investigator team</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Monopoly</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group participants will benefit from a 60 min session to play a &quot;Placebo&quot; game: monopoly</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Captain Sonar Exposition</intervention_name>
    <description>Captain SonarTM is a naval battle game where two teams each composed of four participants clash. Each player has a well-defined role and it is imperative to communicate in a closed loop to advance in the game. This game also includes components similar to support for Trauma care: stress, speed of action, central communication and teamwork of four protagonists (Team Leader- Captain, intern-Second, nurse-Mechanic, Caregiver-Detector). This short video describes the rules and the Game progress: https://vimeo.com/173614346.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Captain Sonar</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Monopoly Exposition</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will be invited to play to Monopoly during 60 min</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Monopoly</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Professional working at the Unit&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Anesthesiology and Intensive care medicine, H Building, Hopital Edouard Herriot, Hospices Civils de Lyon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <state>Rhone</state>
        <zip>69008</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gawande AA, Zinner MJ, Studdert DM, Brennan TA. Analysis of errors reported by surgeons at three teaching hospitals. Surgery. 2003 Jun;133(6):614-21. doi: 10.1067/msy.2003.169.</citation>
    <PMID>12796727</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Neily J, Mills PD, Young-Xu Y, Carney BT, West P, Berger DH, Mazzia LM, Paull DE, Bagian JP. Association between implementation of a medical team training program and surgical mortality. JAMA. 2010 Oct 20;304(15):1693-700. doi: 10.1001/jama.2010.1506.</citation>
    <PMID>20959579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>El-Shafy IA, Delgado J, Akerman M, Bullaro F, Christopherson NAM, Prince JM. Closed-Loop Communication Improves Task Completion in Pediatric Trauma Resuscitation. J Surg Educ. 2018 Jan-Feb;75(1):58-64. doi: 10.1016/j.jsurg.2017.06.025. Epub 2017 Aug 2.</citation>
    <PMID>28780315</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 24, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 24, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 24, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Claude Bernard University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lilot Marc</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthcare professionals</keyword>
  <keyword>Technical Skills</keyword>
  <keyword>Non Technical Skills</keyword>
  <keyword>Crew ressource Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress evaluation and management</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

