<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05624151</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R176/2022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05624151</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dexmedetomidine Versus Magnesium Sulphate Added to Bupivacaine in Infraorbital Nerve Block for Perioperative Analgesia in Paediatric Patients for Cleft Lip Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Dexmedetomidine Versus Magnesium Sulphate Added to Bupivacaine in Infraorbital Nerve Block for Perioperative Analgesia in Paediatric Patients for Cleft Lip Surgery: A Prospective, Randomized Double Blinded Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ain Shams University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ain Shams University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Regional analgesia is considered the cornerstone for postoperative analgesia in paediatric&#xD;
      patients. One of the most common birth defects which require surgical intervention early in&#xD;
      life is the cleft lip. Infraorbital nerve block (IONB) has been used for postoperative&#xD;
      analgesia in this delicate and sensitive area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the assessment of pain may be very challenging especially in young children, the local&#xD;
      anaesthetics administration can be a safe alternative to opioids.[2] However, the regional&#xD;
      block after a single dose of local anaesthetic is of limited duration and efficacy. Hence,&#xD;
      the coadministration of adjuvants with local anaesthetics may be helpful for potentiation of&#xD;
      analgesic effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Infraorbital nerve block is a well-recognized regional anaesthetic technique which can&#xD;
      provide intraoperative and postoperative pain relief in nasal endoscopic surgery and in some&#xD;
      types of oral and dental surgery including cleft lip repair . The block may also be used to&#xD;
      help diagnose neuralgia arising from the second division of the trigeminal nerve. The&#xD;
      technique for infraorbital nerve blockade is most performed as it exits the infraorbital&#xD;
      foramen just below the inferior orbital rim.Dexmedetomidine (DE) is a potent α2&#xD;
      adrenoreceptor agonist and it is highly selective for α2 adrenoreceptor seven times more than&#xD;
      clonidine. Many studies documented a prolonged duration and rapid onset of sensory block with&#xD;
      the perineural injection of DE. Dexmedetomidine has been introduced as an adjuvant to local&#xD;
      anaesthetics in both neuroaxial and peripheral nerve blocks. [9, 10] perineural&#xD;
      dexmedetomidine has shown to prolong the duration of postoperative analgesia in addition to&#xD;
      reducing the opioid consumption. The exact mechanism of peripheral nerve block produced by α2&#xD;
      adrenoreceptor agonists includes central analgesia, anti-inﬂammatory effect.Another suggested&#xD;
      mechanism is that DE may exert its action through blocking the hyperpolarization-activated&#xD;
      cation current after the transient sodium influx. The effect of magnesium was first&#xD;
      recognized for the treatment of arrhythmia and preeclampsia, and its effect on anaesthesia&#xD;
      and analgesia has recently been recognized. Magnesium sulphate has also been used as an&#xD;
      adjunct to anaesthesia in recent years. It is also an effective analgesic agent for&#xD;
      perioperative pain. Research have also reported that the intraoperative use of magnesium is&#xD;
      characterized by a reduced use of anaesthetics and muscle relaxants. Furthermore, opioid use,&#xD;
      postoperative nausea and vomiting, hypertension, and shivering have met a decreased trend&#xD;
      with the use of magnesium sulphate. In a study performed by (El-Emam and El motlb) in 2019&#xD;
      they compared the efficacy of dexamethasone versus dexmedetomidine as an adjuvant to&#xD;
      bupivacaine in ultrasound guided infraorbital nerve block in paediatric patients scheduled&#xD;
      for cleft lip repair. they noticed that dexmedetomidine produced a more prolonged duration of&#xD;
      analgesia and a lower pain score and increased sedation than produced by dexamethasone. Also,&#xD;
      they found that Both dexamethasone and dexmedetomidine were tolerable with no significant&#xD;
      difference regarding the incidence of postoperative nausea and vomiting or intraoperative&#xD;
      hemodynamic changes.Aim of the work:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this randomized controlled double-blind study is to compare the efficacy of&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine or Magnesium sulphate as adjuvants for bupivacaine in infraorbital nerve&#xD;
      block in paediatric patients scheduled for cleft lip repair.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 25, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 25, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 15, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>first time to analgesic requirment</measure>
    <time_frame>1st 24 hour</time_frame>
    <description>paracetamol will be given as the first rescue analgesia</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total amount of analgesics</measure>
    <time_frame>1st 24 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pain score (FLACC Score) face, leg , cry, activity ,conslolability</measure>
    <time_frame>1st 24 postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>assess pain in patients (ranging from 0-10, where 0 = no pain, 10 = worst pain)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>postoperative side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>1st 24 hour postoperatively</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Analgesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>general anesthesia+ infraorbital nerve block by dexmedetomidine plus bupivacaine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>general anesthesia+ infraorbital nerve block by magnesium sulphate plus bupivacaine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>general anesthesia+infraorbital nerve block by bupivacaine only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine +Bupivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>infraorbital nerve block by dexmedetomidine plus bupivacaine</description>
    <arm_group_label>general anesthesia+ infraorbital nerve block by dexmedetomidine plus bupivacaine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Magnesium Sulfate + Bupivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>infraorbital nerve block by magnesium sulphate plus bupivacaine</description>
    <arm_group_label>general anesthesia+ infraorbital nerve block by magnesium sulphate plus bupivacaine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>infraorbital nerve block by bupivacaine only</description>
    <arm_group_label>general anesthesia+infraorbital nerve block by bupivacaine only</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who will be scheduled for indicated cleft lip surgery. • physical status&#xD;
             American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) I or II.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  failure to gain the consent from parents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to any of drugs used&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  thrombocytopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of any lower or upper airway disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of sleep apnea syndrome with a suspected need for postoperative ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any wound or infection related to puncture site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  major illness failure to gain the consent of parents.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ain Shams University hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 17, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 17, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 21, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ain Shams University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amin Mohammed Alansary Amin Ahmed Helwa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cleft Lip</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Magnesium Sulfate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

