<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05791019</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Paleolithic diet and T2DM</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05791019</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Paleolithic Diet in Control of Blood Level of Glucose in Type 2 DM Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Paleolithic Diet in Control of Blood Level of Glucose in Type 2 DM Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Efficacy of paleolithic diet in control of blood glucose level in type 2 DM patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Diabetes mellitus has become one of the most common progressive chronic diseases in the&#xD;
      world, with 422 million people affected worldwide. Approximately 95% of people currently&#xD;
      diagnosed with diabetes have type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). The disease is characterized by&#xD;
      chronic hyperglycemia, which can impair pancreatic beta cell function and increase insulin&#xD;
      resistance, deteriorating the metabolic condition and causing microvascular complications in&#xD;
      the retina, kidney or peripheral nerves . Thus, glycemic control is essential for diabetes&#xD;
      management, in order to avoid complications in organs and systems, which are related with&#xD;
      high morbidity and mortality rates. Among T2DM causes are genetic and epigenetic elements&#xD;
      interacting within a societal framework. The genetic predisposition for T2DM takes into&#xD;
      account the increased risk of an individual to develop T2DM when there are other family&#xD;
      members affected. On the other hand, epigenetic elements are those influenced by&#xD;
      environmental factors, i. e., they can be reversible, and therefore manipulated, in order to&#xD;
      treat the disease. Regardless of the causes, the main targets of the treatment are focused on&#xD;
      decreasing insulin resistance and improving beta cell function and decrease the inflammatory&#xD;
      process through diet, exercise and antihyperglycemic agents. Based on this, given the high&#xD;
      prevalence of the disease and the significant benefits of its management, it is of clinical&#xD;
      importance to determine the proper amount and type of carbohydrates in patients' diet, as&#xD;
      they both may influence the glycemic index of a meal. Besides, some foods' intake induce a&#xD;
      marked rise followed by a more or less rapid fall in blood glucose, while others produce a&#xD;
      smaller peak along with a more gradual decline in plasma glucose. Currently, it is&#xD;
      recommended for T2DM patients an intake of 26-44% of total daily energy from carbohydrates,&#xD;
      preferably from high-quality sources, such as vegetables, whole fruits and legumes , which&#xD;
      are rich in fiber. Most fibers, which are unabsorbed carbohydrates, are insoluble and&#xD;
      increase stool weight. In contrast, starches are carbohydrates found in vegetables that are&#xD;
      mostly broken down to sugars by digestive enzymes. Resistant starch, also found in vegetables&#xD;
      and whole fruits, escapes digestion, being fermented in the intestine as well as dietary&#xD;
      fiber. Although the quantity and the quality of carbohydrates in the diet influence blood&#xD;
      glucose levels , influencing insulin secretion and gastric emptying, the most beneficial&#xD;
      type, the ideal amount of dietary carbohydrates and the underlying mechanisms involved remain&#xD;
      a matter of debate. Thus, this study was designed to systematically review the effects of the&#xD;
      type and amount of dietary carbohydrates in studies involving T2DM , in order to clarify&#xD;
      these aspects for improving T2DM management.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of paleolithic diet in control of blood glucose levels in type 2 DM patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Controlling of glucose levels in blood by using specific dietary system and notifying the number of participants who achieve good results</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Patients</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paleolithic diet effect on patients</intervention_name>
    <description>Efficacy of paleolithic diet in control of blood level of glucose in type 2 DM patients</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Newly diagnosed type 2 DM, age less than 45 years old, not less than 5 years of DM, not&#xD;
        diagnosed to have type 1 DM, not having infection, not having history of bariatric surgery&#xD;
        and not following deut regimen for weight reduction&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Newly diagnosed type 2 DM, age less than 45 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  type 1 DM infection bariatric surgery not follow diet regimine before study at least 6&#xD;
             month not on medication for weight reduction&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Muhammed Abbas Said Muhammad El-Masry, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut university hospitals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nagy Nageh Abdo, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>01069854486</phone>
    <email>nagynageh22@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Manal El-Sayed EzzEl-dine, Prof</last_name>
    <phone>01005826070</phone>
    <email>Manal_ezeldeen@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nagy Nageh Abdo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Manal El-Sayed EzzEl-dine, Prof</last_name>
      <phone>01005826070</phone>
      <email>Manal_ezeldeen@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Muhammed Abbas Said Muhammad El-Masry, Prof</last_name>
      <phone>01272196319</phone>
      <email>masaeedr@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kleiner A, Cum B, Pisciotta L, Cincione IR, Cogorno L, Prigione A, Tramacere A, Vignati A, Carmisciano L, Sukkar SG. Safety and Efficacy of Eucaloric Very Low-Carb Diet (EVLCD) in Type 1 Diabetes: A One-Year Real-Life Retrospective Experience. Nutrients. 2022 Aug 5;14(15):3208. doi: 10.3390/nu14153208.</citation>
    <PMID>35956384</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nagy Nageh Abdo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

