<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05799209</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05799209</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Floatation-REST in Methamphetamine Use Disorder: A Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Reduced Environmental Stimulation Therapy (REST) in Methamphetamine Use Disorder: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Laureate Institute for Brain Research, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Laureate Institute for Brain Research, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This early-stage trial aims to examine the feasibility, tolerability, and safety of&#xD;
      Floatation-REST (Reduced Environmental Stimulation Therapy) or an active comparison condition&#xD;
      in 50 individuals receiving treatment for Amphetamine-Type Substance Use Disorder.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Methamphetamine Use Disorder (MUD) is associated with a barrage of mental and physical health&#xD;
      problems including heightened drug craving/relapse/overdose rates, comorbid mood and anxiety&#xD;
      disorders, and cardiovascular dysfunction. Unfortunately, MUD is becoming more prevalent. In&#xD;
      the U.S., methamphetamine-related treatment admissions increased from 15% in 2007 to 26% in&#xD;
      2018 (Jones, Olsen et al., 2020) and 7 out of 1000 individuals reported past-year use from&#xD;
      2015-2018 (Jones, Compton, et al., 2020). Of the individuals reporting past-year use, 53% met&#xD;
      criteria for amphetamine use disorder, 27% reported using &gt;200 days, and 22% injected&#xD;
      methamphetamine (Jones, Compton, et al., 2020). Despite this substantial burden, there are&#xD;
      currently no FDA approved pharmacological treatments for methamphetamine use disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent models of addiction highlight the potential role that negative reinforcement plays in&#xD;
      relapse, such that stress and negative affect increase drug craving, thereby increasing the&#xD;
      likelihood of future drug seeking behaviors despite negative consequences. Consistent with&#xD;
      this model, individuals may persist in methamphetamine use to avoid aversive states such as&#xD;
      anxiety, depression, fatigue, and other withdrawal symptoms, a cycle known as negative&#xD;
      reinforcement. Floatation-REST (Reduced Environmental Stimulation Therapy is a novel&#xD;
      non-pharmacologic intervention that has been shown to reduce anxiety/stress in anxious and&#xD;
      depressed individuals. It seems plausible that it may have the potential to lessen these&#xD;
      aversive states in methamphetamine users, which may also relate to decreased state drug&#xD;
      craving/urges to use. To our knowledge, no studies have tested the feasibility/tolerability&#xD;
      and safety of floatation-REST in individuals with methamphetamine-type substance use&#xD;
      disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current study investigates the safety and feasibility/tolerability of a single session of&#xD;
      floatation-REST in treatment-seeking individuals with methamphetamine use disorder, relative&#xD;
      to an active comparator. In this within-subject crossover design, participants will complete&#xD;
      two counterbalanced sessions: one in a floatation pool (Pool-REST), and the other in a&#xD;
      floatation chair (Chair-REST). Safety and tolerability will be assessed by self-report&#xD;
      questionnaires as well as via pre- and post-session ratings of anxiety, stress, and drug&#xD;
      craving. Feasibility will be assessed by intervention adherence rate. Findings from this&#xD;
      study will inform the design of future feasibility and efficacy studies as well as&#xD;
      mechanistic studies of recovery from methamphetamine addiction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants complete both arms of the study on separate days.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>The investigator and participant are masked to study arm until after the participant completes their baseline assessment visit, at which point they are randomized using a sealed envelope.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Side Effects</measure>
    <time_frame>Over the span of the intervention, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>As a proxy of safety, the negative and positive side effects reported by each participant is equal to the number of instances during the study when a participant reports elevations above mild for any negative or positive effects on the side effect checklist (administered after each float session)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Over the ten days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>As a proxy of feasibility, the rate of adherence for the group is equal to the total randomized minus (dropout plus withdrawn) divided by total randomized&#xD;
All participants are given up to 3 opportunities to reschedule missed appointments, after which they are withdrawn from the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stimulant Craving on the Stimulant Craving Questionnaire (STCQ)-Brief</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>[Average change pre- to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>State Anxiety on the State Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Average change pre to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Negative Affect on Positive and Negative Affective Schedule- X</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Negative Affect subscale [Average change pre- to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive Affect on Positive and Negative Affective Schedule- X</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Positive Affect subscale [Average change pre to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fear on Positive and Negative Affective Schedule- X</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fear subscale [Average change pre- to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue on Positive and Negative Affective Schedule- X</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fatigue subscale [Average change pre- to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serenity on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule-X (PANAS-X)</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Serenity subscale [Average change pre to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Joviality on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule-X (PANAS-X)</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Joviality subscale [Average change pre to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attentiveness on the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule-X (PANAS-X)</measure>
    <time_frame>Through completion of the final float session, up to two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Attentiveness subscale [Average change pre to post-intervention]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Amphetamine-Type Substance Use Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced Environmental Stimulation Pool</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>floating supine in a pool for a prescribed amount of time (1 total session lasting 1 hour)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Zero Gravity Chair</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>floating supine in a zero-gravity chair for a prescribed amount of time (1 total session lasting 1 hour)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Float Pool</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant floats supine in a pool of water saturated with Epsom salt in an environment which minimizes stimulation of the nervous system, including reduced light, sound, and pressure on the spinal cord.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced Environmental Stimulation Pool</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Float Chair</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant floats supine in a zero-gravity chair in an environment which minimizes stimulation of the nervous system, including reduced light, sound, and pressure on the spinal cord.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Zero Gravity Chair</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between 18-55 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meeting criteria for a primary DSM-5 diagnosis of current methamphetamine use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has completed at least two weeks of inpatient treatment (translating into having at&#xD;
             least two weeks of drug/alcohol sobriety) at one of the two recruitment sites (Grand&#xD;
             Addiction and Recovery Center or Women In Recovery) and is still currently enrolled in&#xD;
             this treatment at the time of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of completing all measures during each session of the experiment: able to&#xD;
             provide written informed consent and must have sufficient proficiency in the English&#xD;
             language to understand and complete interviews, questionnaires, and all other study&#xD;
             procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has any of the following DSM-5 disorders: Schizophrenia Spectrum and Other Psychotic&#xD;
             Disorders OR Bipolar I Disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant fails to adhere to our &quot;Pre-float checklist&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any antihistamine that causes drowsiness (e.g., Benadryl).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Caffeine or nicotine consumed within the past 2 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reports a history of unstable liver or renal insufficiency; glaucoma; diabetes;&#xD;
             significant and unstable cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, endocrine,&#xD;
             neurologic, hematologic, rheumatologic, or metabolic disturbance; or any other&#xD;
             condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would make participation not be in&#xD;
             the best interest (e.g., compromise the well-being) of the subject or that could&#xD;
             prevent, limit, or confound the protocol-specified assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A breathalyzer test positive for alcohol or a drug-positive urine test at either&#xD;
             session.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-correctable vision or hearing problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness or inability to complete major aspects of the study protocol (e.g.,&#xD;
             floating). However, failing to complete some individual aspects will be acceptable&#xD;
             (e.g., being unwilling to answer individual items on a questionnaire).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sahib Khalsa, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>918-240-2583</phone>
    <email>skhalsa@laureateinstitute.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laureate Institute for Brain Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tulsa</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>74136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sahib Khalsa, Md, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>918-240-2583</phone>
      <email>skhalsa@laureateinstitute.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 7, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Methamphetamine Use Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Floatation Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

