<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798832</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BursaU</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798832</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Evaluation of Virtual Reality and Traditional Training in Basic Life Support Training</brief_title>
  <acronym>VR-BLS</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Virtual Reality and Traditional Training in Basic Life Support Training: The Case of Paramedic Student Group</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bursa Uludag Universitesi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Uludag University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bursa Uludag Universitesi</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      type of study:A parallel-group trial design was used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main question[s] it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. HI; The &quot;Basic Life Support Knowledge Assessment Form&quot; score average of the students in&#xD;
           the intervention group participating in the VR will be higher than the control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. H1; The Basic Life Support Application Evaluation Form score average of the students in&#xD;
           the intervention group participating in the VR will be higher than the control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. For the classical BLS training group; Traditional BLS VR Training will be held in the&#xD;
      classroom environment for 45 minutes in the form of a lecture, the training session will be&#xD;
      terminated after watching the video and answering questions. Trainings will be conducted by&#xD;
      Derya ASLAN HUYAR in terms of standardization of trainings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B.For VR BLS training group; After the introduction of VR in the VR hall, after the&#xD;
      explanation of the basic concepts of BLS and the completion of the training through VR BLS&#xD;
      scenarios, question-answer will be made and the session will be closed. Trainings will be&#xD;
      conducted by Derya ASLAN HUYAR in terms of standardization of trainings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      An experimental and a pretest-posttest control group design method were applied in this&#xD;
      regard.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population and Sample: The population of the research consists of 89 paramedic students&#xD;
      studying in the first grade of the Bursa Uludag University First and Emergency Aid Program in&#xD;
      the spring semester of the 2021-2022 academic year.The sample size was determined by means of&#xD;
      a power analysis.When the effect size of the difference in knowledge levels between the two&#xD;
      groups at 80% power and 5% significance level is taken as 0.70, 34 participants in each group&#xD;
      are required, with a total of 68 participants.They were randomly assigned to the experimental&#xD;
      and control groups.Participants; Being a first-year paramedic student, not having received&#xD;
      basic life support training, and voluntarily agreeing to participate in the study were&#xD;
      determined as inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The number of people to be sampled from the universe was determined by power analysis. When&#xD;
      the effect size of the difference in knowledge levels between the two groups at 80% power and&#xD;
      5% significance level is taken as 0.70, 34 participants in each group are required, with a&#xD;
      total of 68 participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be assigned to the experimental and control groups by randomization.&#xD;
      Participants; Being a first-year paramedic student, not having received basic life support&#xD;
      training, and voluntarily agreeing to participate in the study were determined as inclusion&#xD;
      criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection Tools Created by researchers; The &quot;Descriptive Information Form&quot; consists of&#xD;
      6 items. (Annex 6-5) &quot;Basic Life Support Information Evaluation Form&quot; was developed by Tank.&#xD;
      This form, which consists of 10 multiple-choice questions, adapted according to the Critical&#xD;
      Skills Descriptors of the Adult Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation and Automatic External&#xD;
      Defibrillator Skills Test published by the American Heart Association; questions their level&#xD;
      of knowledge about basic life support application. Each correct answer given by the student&#xD;
      in the form will be evaluated as 1 point and the average score will be calculated. Students&#xD;
      will be able to get a minimum of 0 and a maximum of 10 points (Appendix 6-5) &quot;Basic Life&#xD;
      Support Application Evaluation Form&quot; was developed by Tank , it consists of 20 items. This&#xD;
      form is used to evaluate the participant's skill status during BLS practice. In the form&#xD;
      containing the application steps, the student's ability to perform the application will be&#xD;
      evaluated as 1 point for each correct step, and the average score will be calculated. The&#xD;
      participant will be able to get a minimum of 0 and a maximum of 20 points at the end of the&#xD;
      evaluation of the 20-item form. (Annex 6-5) Data Analysis: SPSS package program will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Flow Process:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Basic Life Support (BLS) Virtual Reality (VR) and Basic Life Support Traditional Education&#xD;
      Program Flow Process Steps&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Pre-Training Evaluation Students randomly assigned to the VR and Classical education&#xD;
           group; &quot;Descriptive Information Form&quot; and &quot;Basic Life Support Information Evaluation&#xD;
           Form&quot; will be filled.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Education&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. For the classical BLS training group; Traditional BLS VR Training will be held in&#xD;
                the classroom environment in the form of lectures for 45 minutes, and the training&#xD;
                session will end after watching the video and question and answering. In terms of&#xD;
                standardization of the trainings, the trainings will be given by Derya ASLAN HUYAR.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. For the VR BLS training group; After the VR presentation in the VR hall, after the&#xD;
                explanation of the basic concepts of BLS and the completion of the training on VR&#xD;
                BLS scenarios, there will be a question and answer session and the session will be&#xD;
                closed. In terms of standardization of the trainings, the trainings will be given&#xD;
                by Derya ASLAN HUYAR.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Initial Evaluation After Training For practices, students will be divided into groups of&#xD;
           6 to 8 people.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Med-Sim Training simulator will be introduced by the Training Coach and BLS&#xD;
                application steps will be demonstrated.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. A BLS scenario will be given to the participants in the classical and VR BLS&#xD;
                training groups. Then, each participant will perform the application steps on the&#xD;
                Med-Sim simulation model. In the meantime, each participant will be evaluated in&#xD;
                terms of skills by using the &quot;Basic Life Support Application Evaluation Form&quot; by&#xD;
                Derya ASLAN HUYAR and Yeliz ŞAPULU ALAKAN.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Participants in the Classical and VR BLS training groups will fill out the &quot;Basic&#xD;
                Life Support Information Evaluation Form&quot; after the training.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Second Evaluation After Training One month after the training, just like in the phases&#xD;
           applied in the first measurement; BLS scenario will be given to the participants in both&#xD;
           classical and BLS training groups. Each participant will be evaluated in terms of skills&#xD;
           by Derya ASLAN HUYAR and Yeliz ŞAPULU ALAKAN using the &quot;Basic Life Support Application&#xD;
           Evaluation Form&quot; while the participants are doing the application steps on the Med-Sim&#xD;
           simulation model.&#xD;
&#xD;
           One month after the training, the participants in the Classic and VR BLS training groups&#xD;
           will fill out the &quot;Basic Life Support Information Evaluation Form&quot; after the training.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Third Evaluation After Training Planned steps in other measurements will be followed in&#xD;
           the same way. Three months after the training, the participants in the Classical and BLS&#xD;
           training groups will be given a BLS scenario and asked to do the application steps on&#xD;
           the Med-Sim simulation model. Meanwhile, each participant will be evaluated in terms of&#xD;
           skills by using the &quot;Basic Life Support Application Evaluation Form&quot; by Derya ASLAN&#xD;
           HUYAR and Yeliz ŞAPULU ALAKAN while the participants are doing the application steps on&#xD;
           the Med-Sim simulation model.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three months after the training, the participants in the Classic and VR BLS training groups&#xD;
      will fill out the &quot;Basic Life Support Information Evaluation Form&quot; after the training.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 5, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 10, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 10, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>An experimental and a pretest-posttest control group design method were applied in this regard.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The person who will make the statistical analysis; He does not know which group the participants in our study belong to and he does not know the participants.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>before the intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>via google form. Before the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Before the training of the experimental and control group participants, BLS knowledge was measured.&quot;Basic Life Support Information Evaluation Form&quot; is organized according to the Adult Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation and Automatic External Defibrillator Skill steps published by the American Heart Association and consists of 10 multiple choice questions.&#xD;
Each correct answer is 1 point. minimum 0, maximum 10 points can be scored.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>immediately after the intervention,</measure>
    <time_frame>via google form. it took a total of 2 weeks to complete the skill measurements of the control and experimental groups. Control group: May 16-20 experimental group may 23-27</time_frame>
    <description>The BLS knowledge level of the experimental and control groups was measured with the questionnaire.&#xD;
In addition, the researchers gave each student an appointment individually so that the skill levels of both groups could be measured. &quot;Basic Life Support Application Evaluation Form&quot; consists of 20 items. In the form containing the application steps, 1 point is taken for each correct step. The participant will be able to get a minimum of 0 and a maximum of 20 points.&#xD;
The researchers asked the participants to apply the BLS steps on the BLS model. The researchers marked their observations as checklist. Each student was given feedback after the application.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1st months after the intervention.</measure>
    <time_frame>via google form. It took a total of 2 weeks to complete the skill measurements of the control and experimental groups. Control group: 20-24 June experimental group: 27 June 1 July</time_frame>
    <description>The BLS knowledge level of the experimental and control groups was measured with the questionnaire.&#xD;
In addition, the researchers gave each student an appointment individually so that the skill levels of both groups could be measured. &quot;Basic Life Support Application Evaluation Form&quot; consists of 20 items. In the form containing the application steps, 1 point is taken for each correct step. The participant will be able to get a minimum of 0 and a maximum of 20 points.&#xD;
The researchers asked the participants to apply the BLS steps on the BLS model. The researchers marked their observations as checklist. Each student was given feedback after the application.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3rd months after the intervention.</measure>
    <time_frame>via google form. Each student was given an appointment to assess the students' BLS skill level. It took a total of 2 weeks to complete the skill measurements of the control and experimental groups.19 -23 Sep.]</time_frame>
    <description>The BLS knowledge level of the experimental and control groups was measured with the questionnaire.&#xD;
In addition, the researchers gave each student an appointment individually so that the skill levels of both groups could be measured. &quot;Basic Life Support Application Evaluation Form&quot; consists of 20 items. In the form containing the application steps, 1 point is taken for each correct step. The participant will be able to get a minimum of 0 and a maximum of 20 points.&#xD;
The researchers asked the participants to apply the BLS steps on the BLS model. The researchers marked their observations as checklist. Each student was given feedback after the application.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">68</enrollment>
  <condition>Education</condition>
  <condition>Virtual Reality</condition>
  <condition>Basic Cardiac Life Support</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Comparator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The active control group was given traditional Basic Life Support, which already practiced in most schools.For the traditional BLS training group; basic life support was given a lesson in the classroom for 45 to 50 minutes, demonstrated on a model, and the training session was ended after a question and answer session. In terms of standardization of the trainings, the trainings were given by Derya ASLAN HUYAR.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Basic Life Support training with VR was given to the experimental group.For the VR BLS training group; The use of VR was introduced in the VR hall. The lexical meanings of the basic concepts of BLS were explained. The student received training on a scenario he chose in the training module, and then he was asked to perform the steps individually in the assessment mode. After the training was completed, a question-answer was made and the session was closed. In terms of standardization of the trainings, the trainings were made by Derya ASLAN HUYAR.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Virtually reality training group</intervention_name>
    <description>BLS Training with VR</description>
    <arm_group_label>experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Traditional training group</intervention_name>
    <description>BLS Training with Traditional</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active Comparator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being a first-year paramedic student,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not having received basic life support training&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  voluntarily agreeing to participate in the research,&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have previous BLS training&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>derya aslan huyar</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bursa Uludag Universty</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bursa Uludağ Üniversitesi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bursa</city>
        <state>Nilüfer</state>
        <zip>16285</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 19, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 2, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Uludag University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Derya Aslan Huyar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Virtual Reality, Educational</keyword>
  <keyword>Basic Cardiac Life Support</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

