<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618353</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CARA-003-22S</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>I01CX002358-01A2</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618353</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Colchicine on Peri-Operative Major Adverse Cardiovascular Events in Patients With Prior Coronary Revascularization: The Peri-OPerative COlchicine to Reduce Negative Events (POPCORN) Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>POPCORN</acronym>
  <official_title>Impact of Colchicine on Peri-Operative Major Adverse Cardiovascular Events in Patients With Prior Coronary Revascularization</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>NYU School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Heart disease remains the leading cause of death in Veterans. Inflammation in the arteries of&#xD;
      the heart may increase the risk of cardiac death. Patients with heart disease undergoing&#xD;
      major surgery are at increased risk of complications after surgery, including heart attack,&#xD;
      stroke, and death. The proposed research seeks to better understand the role of inflammation&#xD;
      in the damage to the heart and blood vessels after major surgery. This research also seeks to&#xD;
      identify the potential beneficial role of a safe medication, colchicine, which has direct&#xD;
      effects on inflammatory cells and has been used in the treatment of inflammatory diseases for&#xD;
      more than 2000 years, on reducing the rate of complications after surgery. With its quick&#xD;
      onset of action and excellent safety profile, colchicine may have the potential to reduce&#xD;
      risk of heart injury, stroke, or death after major surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with prior coronary revascularization have a high risk of major adverse&#xD;
      cardiovascular events (MACE) after major surgery, up to more than 2-fold when compared to&#xD;
      patients without prior coronary revascularization. The pro-inflammatory and hypercoagulable&#xD;
      states induced by surgery and the hemodynamic changes caused by fluid shifts and anesthesia&#xD;
      are all important triggers of perioperative myocardial ischemia. Indeed, peri-operative&#xD;
      systemic inflammation is associated with a nearly 4-fold increase in the risk of&#xD;
      perioperative MACE. Neutrophils, the most abundant of inflammatory cells, adhere to inflamed&#xD;
      or injured endothelium, migrate into the vessel wall, release proteolytic enzymes that can&#xD;
      lead to erosion or rupture of plaque. Peri-operative cytokine generation may also activate&#xD;
      the inflammasome and, thereby, macrophage-mediated synthesis of interleukin (IL)-1 , a known&#xD;
      target for therapy for secondary prevention of MACE, particularly in the setting of high&#xD;
      C-reactive protein (CRP) concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Colchicine is a safe, well-tolerated anti-inflammatory agent that preferentially accumulates&#xD;
      in neutrophils compared with other inflammatory cells. Colchicine inhibits chemotaxis,&#xD;
      endothelial adhesion, and extravasation of neutrophils at sites of endothelial injury or&#xD;
      inflammation; suppresses the inflammasome-mediated production of IL-1 by macrophages; and&#xD;
      reduces inflammation and MACE in patients with cardiovascular disease. The Colchicine&#xD;
      Cardiovascular Outcomes Trial and Low Dose Colchicine 2 Trial demonstrated a reduction in&#xD;
      MACE with colchicine in about 4000 patients with prior myocardial infarction and about 5000&#xD;
      patients with stable coronary artery disease, respectively. The Colchicine-PCI trial&#xD;
      demonstrated for the first time that administration of colchicine prior to injury dampens the&#xD;
      inflammatory response measured by CRP. The effects of colchicine on peri-operative MACE in&#xD;
      patients with prior coronary revascularization undergoing major surgery, remains unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aims of this trial are to 1) assess the effect of colchicine compared to placebo on&#xD;
      peri-operative MACE in response to intermediate- or high-risk non-cardiac surgery in patients&#xD;
      with prior coronary revascularization; 2) characterize the level of systemic inflammation and&#xD;
      profile of peri-operative neutrophils in this population; and 3) determine the clinical and&#xD;
      genetic predictors of peri-operative MACE and examine factors that determine heterogeneity of&#xD;
      treatment response in this population. This prospective, double-blinded, placebo-controlled,&#xD;
      randomized trial will enroll 700 participants with prior coronary revascularization who&#xD;
      undergo intermediate- or high-risk non-cardiac surgery across five VA medical centers that&#xD;
      serve as cardiovascular referral centers for their VISNs. Following referral for surgery, and&#xD;
      confirmation that the patient meets all study entry criteria, participants will be consented&#xD;
      and randomized 1:1 within center to a loading dose of colchicine or placebo one day before&#xD;
      surgery and twice daily dosing for 14 days post-operation. DNA will be collected at baseline,&#xD;
      while measures of systemic inflammation will be collected at baseline, one day, two days, and&#xD;
      at 14 days post-operation (or hospital discharge, whichever occurs earlier). Follow-up for&#xD;
      all randomized participants who undergo surgery will occur at 30 days + 7 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>One day before surgery: Colchicine 1.2 mg with 0.6 mg PO one hour later. This load will be followed by colchicine 0.6 mg twice daily for a total of 14 days. If a patient is unable to take oral medications (by mouth or nasogastric tube) post-operatively (e.g., post abdominal surgery), colchicine will be held until the clinically treating physician allows resumption of oral medications if still within 14 days post-operation.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Matching placebo at the same time points as the intervention</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Major adverse cardiovascular events</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as a composite rate of myocardial injury, non-fatal MI, non-fatal stroke, and all-cause mortality.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of myocardial injury</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>rate of myocardial injury</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of non-fatal MI</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>rate of non-fatal MI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of non-fatal stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>rate of non-fatal stroke</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of all-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>rate of all-cause mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Unplanned coronary revascularization</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>Unplanned coronary revascularization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prognostic threshold of myocardial injury</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days post-operation</time_frame>
    <description>troponin &gt;30 ng/L (high-sensitivity troponin &gt;65 ng/L or absolute change &gt;14 ng/L or 20-65 ng/L with an absolute change of &gt;5 ng/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hsCRP</measure>
    <time_frame>through 14 days post-operation or at hospital discharge, whichever occurs earlier</time_frame>
    <description>between 1) baseline and one day post-operation, and 2) over time including at two days and 14 days post-operation (or hospital discharge, whichever occurs earlier)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">700</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>One day before surgery: Colchicine 1.2 mg with 0.6 mg PO one hour later. This load will be followed by colchicine 0.6 mg twice daily for a total of 14 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Matching placebo at same time points as active comparator</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Colchicine</intervention_name>
    <description>0.6 mg tablets</description>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Colcrys</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Matching placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women with prior coronary revascularization (via PCI or coronary artery bypass&#xD;
             graft surgery) referred for intermediate- (&gt;3% cardiovascular risk with general&#xD;
             abdominal or intraperitoneal surgery) versus high-risk (&gt;5% cardiovascular risk with&#xD;
             suprainguinal surgery, peripheral vascular surgery, thoracic surgery) surgery [2,89].&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If planned for only a laparoscopic or endovascular approach, at least one component of&#xD;
             the Revised Cardiac Risk Index score (history of myocardial infarction, history of&#xD;
             congestive heart failure, history of transient ischemic attack or stroke,&#xD;
             pre-operative use of insulin, pre-operative creatinine &gt;2 mg/dL) should be present.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Colchicine use within one month or history of colchicine intolerance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inflammatory bowel disease with history of diarrhea as presentation or chronic&#xD;
             diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existent progressive neuromuscular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  hereditary muscular disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  myositis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  necrotizing myopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  myasthenia gravis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  lambert-eaton syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glomerular filtration rate &lt;30mL/minute or on dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cirrhosis, chronic active hepatitis or severe hepatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of myelodysplasia with current evidence of cytopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection defined as fever &gt;100.4oF or antibiotic use with white blood cell&#xD;
             count greater than the upper limit of normal or lower than the lower limit of normal&#xD;
             within 24 hours of randomization (major confounder with increased inflammatory&#xD;
             markers)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing immunosuppressive or immunostimulatory chemo or biologic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant (as confirmed by urine or serum test), nursing, or planning to become&#xD;
             pregnant during study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participating in a competing study or unable to consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any significant condition or situation that may put the participant at higher risk,&#xD;
             confound the study results, or interfere with adherence to study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on strong CYP3A4 and/or P-glycoprotein inhibitors (e.g., ritonavir,&#xD;
             clarithromycin, diltiazem, verapamil) at baseline will also be excluded due to&#xD;
             potential drug interactions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  However, if one of these medications are started during the post-operative study&#xD;
                  period, dose adjustments will be made per drug package insert&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants will also be instructed not to drink grapefruit juice while on study&#xD;
                  drug&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Binita Shah, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Manhattan Campus of the VA NY Harbor Healthcare System, New York, NY</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yelena Linchevskaya</last_name>
    <phone>(212) 686-7500</phone>
    <email>yelena.linchevskaya@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Leandro Maranan</last_name>
    <phone>(212) 686-7500</phone>
    <phone_ext>3926</phone_ext>
    <email>leandro.maranan@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Long Beach Healthcare System, Long Beach, CA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Long Beach</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90822</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Najeeb Shirwany</last_name>
      <phone>909-581-2184</phone>
      <email>najeeb.shirwany@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Arnold Seto</last_name>
      <phone>5628268000</phone>
      <phone_ext>12876</phone_ext>
      <email>arnold.seto@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Manhattan Campus of the VA NY Harbor Healthcare System, New York, NY</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John G Hay, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-686-7500</phone>
      <phone_ext>7470</phone_ext>
      <email>john.hay@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Tricia C Daley-Bowles, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(212) 686-7500</phone>
      <phone_ext>4209</phone_ext>
      <email>tricia.daley-bowles@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Binita Shah, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Durham VA Medical Center, Durham, NC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julienne Reynolds</last_name>
      <phone>919-286-0411</phone>
      <email>julienne.reynolds@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alyssa King</last_name>
      <phone>9192860411</phone>
      <phone_ext>175222</phone_ext>
      <email>alyssa.king@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Louis Stokes VA Medical Center, Cleveland, OH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Margaret Tiktin</last_name>
      <phone>216-791-3800</phone>
      <email>margaret.tiktin@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lauren Huntington</last_name>
      <phone>2167913800</phone>
      <email>lauren.huntington@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA North Texas Health Care System Dallas VA Medical Center, Dallas, TX</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75216</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kathryn Anderson</last_name>
      <phone>214-857-1808</phone>
      <email>kathryn.anderson1@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jennifer McClure</last_name>
      <phone>2148570269</phone>
      <email>jennifer.mcclure@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Coronary artery disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-cardiac surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Colchicine</keyword>
  <keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
  <keyword>Major adverse cardiovascular events</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colchicine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

