<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796076</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NTWC/REC/22003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796076</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Virtual Reality to Reduce Anxiety and Pain During Suture Procedure</brief_title>
  <official_title>Virtual Reality Intervention on Anxiety and Pain Among Adult Patients Ubdergoing an Awake Minor Suture: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tuen Mun Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tung Wah College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tuen Mun Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to examine the effectiveness of virtual reality (VR) in&#xD;
      alleviating anxiety and pain among adult patients undergoing an awake minor suture. The main&#xD;
      questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. How effective is VR intervention in reducing anxiety among adult patients undergoing an&#xD;
           awake minor suture?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. How effective is VR intervention in reducing pain level among adult patients undergoing&#xD;
           an awake minor suture?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. How effective is VR intervention in reducing the medication requirement of adult&#xD;
           patients undergoing an awake minor suture?&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. How effective is VR intervention in reducing the physiological parameters including&#xD;
           blood pressure and pulse rate, in adult patients undergoing an awake minor suture?&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. How effective is VR intervention in enhancing procedure satisfaction in adult patients&#xD;
           undergoing an awake minor suture?&#xD;
&#xD;
      A RCT will be adopted. Participants will be randomly assigned to either an experimental group&#xD;
      or control group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Suture is a frequent medical procedure for treatment and management of wound bleeding in the&#xD;
      emergency department. However, the procedure often provoke anxiety and pain. 1-2 Failure to&#xD;
      manage patients' anxiety and pain during the medical procedures can cause difficulties for&#xD;
      health care providers to complete the procedures and reduce the success rates. 3 Experience&#xD;
      of anxiety and pain may also increase the need for medication, reduce patients' satisfaction&#xD;
      rate and cause negative physiological parameters such as increased blood pressure and heart&#xD;
      rate. 4-5.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Traditionally, nonpharmacological intervention such as listening to music, chatting, and&#xD;
      guided imagery is used to reduce patient's anxiety and pain. However these measures fail to&#xD;
      provide significant distraction for patient with suture because patients would inevitably see&#xD;
      the procedure that causes considerable distress during the procedure. Thus, the development&#xD;
      of further strategies to provide a significant distraction to alleviate patients' anxiety and&#xD;
      pain during suture is warranted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With advanced technologies, virtual reality (VR) provides significant distraction. Clinical&#xD;
      trials indicate that use of VR achieved a statistically significant decrease in anxiety and&#xD;
      pain in different operations such as hand 6, lipoma incision 7, Gynecology 8, and debridement&#xD;
      9. However, only a handful of studies conducted among adult patient with ambulatory&#xD;
      laceration repairing examined the effectiveness of VR in anxiety and pain. To the best of our&#xD;
      knowledge, no study specifically focus on the effects of VR on anxiety and pain in Chinese&#xD;
      adult patients undergoing an awake suture in emergency room in Hong Kong.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eighty participants will be assigned to the experimental group or control group by the&#xD;
      computer generated random numbers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After written informed consent are obtained from patients, the baseline data (T0) will be&#xD;
      obtained from the participants including sociodemographic, anxiety, blood pressure, and pulse&#xD;
      rate. Subsequently, randomization is conducted by computer generated random codes. Throughout&#xD;
      the procedure (T1), the additional medication use and physiological parameters will be&#xD;
      recorded. The pain and satisfaction will also be assessed by visual analogue scales after the&#xD;
      procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be analyzed using IBM SPSS 23.0. Descriptive statistics, including frequency,&#xD;
      percentage, mean and standard deviation will be used to describe the data. Chi-square tests&#xD;
      compare categorical variables, and independent t-tests compare continuous variables. RMANOVA&#xD;
      compare change over time between the two groups. Two-tailed tests will be used with a&#xD;
      significant level of 0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 3, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>After the suture procedure (T2), the anxiety and pain levels, satisfaction, blood pressure and pulse rate of the patients are measured again in the another room by research assistant 2 (RA2), who is blinded to the group assignment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, pre-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The Chinese version of the State Trait Anxiety scale is used to measure anxiety levels of the patients. It contains two separate scales for state and trait anxiety.&#xD;
The first part (state anxiety) evaluates a transitory emotional state that is influenced by intense emotional situations and varies in intensity over time. The second part (trait anxiety) demonstrates a relatively stable anxious tendency and is not significantly influenced by emotionally intense situations. Each item is rated on a 4-point Likert scale, with total scores from 20 to 80. The high the score indicates the high a higher level of anxiety. The STAI-C is validated in Hong Kong and is found to have a high degree of internal consistency (Alpha = 0.9). Participants will be required to complete the state form in this study 10-12</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The Chinese version of the State Trait Anxiety scale is used to measure anxiety levels of the patients. It contains two separate scales for state and trait anxiety.&#xD;
The first part (state anxiety) evaluates a transitory emotional state that is influenced by intense emotional situations and varies in intensity over time. The second part (trait anxiety) demonstrates a relatively stable anxious tendency and is not significantly influenced by emotionally intense situations. Each item is rated on a 4-point Likert scale, with total scores from 20 to 80. The high the score indicates the high a higher level of anxiety. The STAI-C is validated in Hong Kong and is found to have a high degree of internal consistency (Alpha = 0.9). Participants will be required to complete the state form in this study 10-12</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Level</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Pain is measured by visual analogue scales (VAS). VAS is a commonly used method for quantifying pain. The scale comprises a 10cm line with terms representing the extremes of pain at either end. The patient estimates pain by placing a mark on the line. The distance from the zero point is then measured. The VAS has been shown to be a valid tool for the measurement of psychological and health variables such as pain and satisfaction which had been used in clinical studies widely 13-15.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction level</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Satisfaction is measured by visual analogue scales (VAS). VAS is a commonly used method for quantifying pain. The scale comprises a 10cm line with terms representing the extremes of pain at either end. The patient estimates pain by placing a mark on the line. The distance from the zero point is then measured. The VAS has been shown to be a valid tool for the measurement of psychological and health variables such as pain and satisfaction which had been used in clinical studies widely 13-15.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, pre-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>A standard blood pressure monitor is used to measure patients' blood pressure. The blood pressure is recorded as mmHg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>During the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>A standard blood pressure monitor is used to measure patients' blood pressure. The blood pressure is recorded as mmHg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>A standard blood pressure monitor is used to measure patients' blood pressure. The blood pressure is recorded as mmHg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulse rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, pre-procedure</time_frame>
    <description>A standard pulse oximetry is used to measure patients' pulse rate. The pulse rate is recorded as beat per minute (bpm)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulse rate</measure>
    <time_frame>During the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>A standard pulse oximetry is used to measure patients' pulse rate. The pulse rate is recorded as beat per minute (bpm)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulse rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>A standard pulse oximetry is used to measure patients' pulse rate. The pulse rate is recorded as beat per minute (bpm)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Additional local analgesic (1% Lidocaine) requirements</measure>
    <time_frame>During the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of extra local analgesic use (1 % Lidocaine) is recorded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Suture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the control group will be received standard care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Virtual reality</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants in the intervention group will be received VR during the suture procedure. Virtual reality is a three dimensions of width, height and depth that is generated digitally in a computer-generated environment that allows a user to interact with it 16.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Conscious, oriented&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Adult patient (age between 18 and 65 years) with scheduled to receive an awake minor&#xD;
             suture&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Ability to communicate in Chinese, and read and write Chinese language&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Hemodynamic stability as evidenced by blood pressure between 90 to 140 mmHg systolic&#xD;
             and 60 to 90 mmHg diastolic before the procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have visual, hearing or cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of senile dementia, seizure disorder, motion sickness, psychiatric disorders&#xD;
             as indicated in medical record&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have injury or infection above the neck&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known to be on contact precaution&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>KO SHUK YEE, DN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Tuen Mun Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jan Huang, Degree</last_name>
    <phone>852-70723754</phone>
    <email>hjj732@ha.org.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tuen Mun Hospital-Emergency department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chan Chi Chung, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>852-24685187</phone>
      <email>ccc870@ha.org.hk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bryl AW, Bonsu B, Johnson AL, Pommert KBJ, Hollenbach KA, Kanegaye JT. Tablet Computer as a Distraction Tool During Facial Laceration Repair: A Randomized Trial. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2021 Aug 1;37(8):e425-e430. doi: 10.1097/PEC.0000000000001626.</citation>
    <PMID>30422942</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ploghaus A, Narain C, Beckmann CF, Clare S, Bantick S, Wise R, Matthews PM, Rawlins JN, Tracey I. Exacerbation of pain by anxiety is associated with activity in a hippocampal network. J Neurosci. 2001 Dec 15;21(24):9896-903. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.21-24-09896.2001.</citation>
    <PMID>11739597</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Parker SIA, Benzies KM, Hayden KA. A systematic review: effectiveness of pediatric peripheral intravenous catheterization strategies. J Adv Nurs. 2017 Jul;73(7):1570-1582. doi: 10.1111/jan.13211. Epub 2016 Dec 14.</citation>
    <PMID>27864995</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Oliveira GS Jr, Holl JL, McCarthy RJ, Butt ZA, Nouriel J, McCaffery K, Wolf MS. Overestimation of mortality risk and preoperative anxiety in patients undergoing elective general surgery procedures: a propensity matched analysis. Int J Surg. 2014 Dec;12(12):1473-7. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsu.2014.11.016. Epub 2014 Nov 18.</citation>
    <PMID>25463769</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Robleda G, Sillero-Sillero A, Puig T, Gich I, Banos JE. Influence of preoperative emotional state on postoperative pain following orthopedic and trauma surgery. Rev Lat Am Enfermagem. 2014 Oct;22(5):785-91. doi: 10.1590/0104-1169.0118.2481.</citation>
    <PMID>25493674</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoxhallari E, Behr IJ, Bradshaw JS, Morkos MS, Haan PS, Schaefer MC, Clarkson JHW. Virtual Reality Improves the Patient Experience during Wide-Awake Local Anesthesia No Tourniquet Hand Surgery: A Single-Blind, Randomized, Prospective Study. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2019 Aug;144(2):408-414. doi: 10.1097/PRS.0000000000005831.</citation>
    <PMID>31348351</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mosso Vazquez JL, Mosso Lara D, Mosso Lara JL, Miller I, Wiederhold MD, Wiederhold BK. Pain Distraction During Ambulatory Surgery: Virtual Reality and Mobile Devices. Cyberpsychol Behav Soc Netw. 2019 Jan;22(1):15-21. doi: 10.1089/cyber.2017.0714. Epub 2018 Sep 25.</citation>
    <PMID>30256662</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mosso Vázquez JL, Lara Vaca V, Wiederhold BK, Miller IT, Wiederhold MD. Virtual reality pain distraction during gynecological surgery - a report of 44 cases. Surgical Research Updates. 2017;5(1):12-16. doi: 10.12970/2311-9888.2017.05.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoffman HG, Patterson DR, Seibel E, Soltani M, Jewett-Leahy L, Sharar SR. Virtual reality pain control during burn wound debridement in the hydrotank. Clin J Pain. 2008 May;24(4):299-304. doi: 10.1097/AJP.0b013e318164d2cc.</citation>
    <PMID>18427228</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spielberger CD, Gorsuch RC, Lushene RF. Manual of the State Trait Anxiety Inventory. Palo Alto, CA: Consulting psychologists Press; 1970</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shek DTL. The factorial structure of the Chinese version of the state-trait anxiety inventory: a confirmatory factor analysis. Psychol Edu Meas. 1991;51(4):985-997. doi:10.1177/001316449105100418</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shek DT. The Chinese version of the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory: its relationship to different measures of psychological well-being. J Clin Psychol. 1993 May;49(3):349-58. doi: 10.1002/1097-4679(199305)49:33.0.co;2-j.</citation>
    <PMID>8315037</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huskisson EC. Measurement of pain. Lancet. 1974 Nov 9;2(7889):1127-31. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(74)90884-8. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>4139420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kersten P, White PJ, Tennant A. Is the pain visual analogue scale linear and responsive to change? An exploration using Rasch analysis. PLoS One. 2014 Jun 12;9(6):e99485. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0099485. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>24921952</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bodian CA, Freedman G, Hossain S, Eisenkraft JB, Beilin Y. The visual analog scale for pain: clinical significance in postoperative patients. Anesthesiology. 2001 Dec;95(6):1356-61. doi: 10.1097/00000542-200112000-00013.</citation>
    <PMID>11748392</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moskaliuk J, Kimmerle J, Cress U. Virtual reality 2.0 and its application in knowledge building. In handbook of research on web 2.0, 3.0, and X. O: technologies, business and social applications. USA: IGI Global, 2010.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 6, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Tuen Mun Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ko Shuk Yee</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Advanced Practice Nurse</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Virtual reality</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Suture</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>It is only a pilot study and will be modified after the pilot study. We will share it later on in the main study</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

