<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05621525</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LB1002-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05621525</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase I Study of the BBP-398 in Patients With Advance Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I, Open Label, Dose Escalation and Expansion, Two- Part Study of SHP-2 Inhibitor BBP-398 to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Preliminary Anti-cancer Activity in Chinese Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>LianBio LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>LianBio LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open label, dose escalation and expansion, two-part Phase I study for SHP-2&#xD;
      inhibitor BBP-398 to evaluate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, determine MTD&#xD;
      and/or RP2D, and preliminary anti- cancer activity in Chinese subjects with advanced solid&#xD;
      tumors and in Chinese subjects with advanced or metastatic EGFR-mutant NSCLC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Part A of this phase I trial is an abbreviated dose escalation study of BBP-398 following&#xD;
      the USA mono dose escalation study (Study NAV- 1001, clinicaltrials.gov ID NCT04528836). The&#xD;
      purpose of this part is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and&#xD;
      preliminary anti-cancer activity in Chinese subjects with advanced solid tumors. The Part B&#xD;
      of this study is to explore the safety, tolerability and efficacy of BBP-398 in Chinese&#xD;
      subjects with advanced or metastatic EGFR- mutant NSCLC at MTD and/or RP2D. This Phase I&#xD;
      study will provide supportive data to enable Chinese patients to join the combo dose&#xD;
      escalation and expansion studies and/or other clinical trials of BBP-398.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 18, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) of BBP-398</measure>
    <time_frame>Completion of 1 Cycle (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>The MTD will be based on DLT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of anti-tumor activity of BBP-398</measure>
    <time_frame>Completion of 1 Cycle (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Anti-tumor activity will be defined by objective response rate (ORR, complete response + partial response rate) and duration of response (DOR) according to RECIST v1.1</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A:Maximum plasma concentration (Cmax) of BBP-398</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum plasma concentration of BBP-398 after single and multiple dose administration of BBP-398</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A:Time to reach Cmax (Tmax) of BBP-398</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The amount of time to reach Cmax after single and multiple dose administration of BBP-398</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A: Terminal half-life (t1/2) of BBP-398</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6months</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal half-life (t1/2) after single and multiple dose administration of BBP-398</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A: Area under the plasma concentration-time curve (AUC) of BBP-398</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve after single and multiple dose administration of BBP-398</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A: Concentration of BBP-398 in urine</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate BBP-398 excretion via urine after single and multiple dose administration of BBP-398.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part B: Concentration of BBP-398 in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate BBP-398 plasma concentration after multiple dose administration of BBP-398.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Advanced or Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A Dose Escalation and Part B Dose Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Part A: Oral capsules taken in escalating levels to determine MTD/RP2D. Each treatment cycle will be 28 days in duration with BBP-398 administered, once daily (QD).&#xD;
Part B: Oral capsules administered at MTD/RP2D defined dose. Each treatment cycle will be 28 days in duration with BBP-398 administered, once daily (QD)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BBP-398</intervention_name>
    <description>BBP-398 (formerly known as IACS-15509) is a potent, selective, orally active allosteric inhibitor of SHP2, a tyrosine phosphatase that plays a key role in the RTK -MAPK signal transduction pathway. Key components of the MAPK pathway include the small GTPase RAS, the serine/threonine-protein kinase RAF, mitogen-activated protein kinase (MEK) and ERK. In cells, SHP2 binds to phosphorylated tyrosine residues in the intracellular domain of RTKs such as the EGFR, leading to activation of the downstream MAPK signaling pathway.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part A Dose Escalation and Part B Dose Expansion</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>IACS-15509</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients must have the ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written&#xD;
        informed consent document 2 Patients must be willing and able to comply with the scheduled&#xD;
        visits, treatment plan, laboratory tests and other specified study procedures 3. Age ≥18,&#xD;
        male or female 4.Dose escalation: locally advanced or metastatic solid tumors Dose&#xD;
        expansion: Advanced or metastatic EGFR-mutant NSCLC 5. Patients must have measurable&#xD;
        disease by RECIST v1.1. 6. Patients must have an ECOG performance status (PS) ≤2 7.Patients&#xD;
        with a life expectancy of ≥12 weeks. 8. Patients must have adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have previously received a SHP-2 inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who are hypersensitivity to SHP-2 inhibitor or any ingredients&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treatment with any of the related anti-cancer therapies prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             BBP-398 within the stated timeframes&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with known active Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C infection, or HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with any of the cardiac-related issues or findings&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with a history of CVA, myocardial infarction or unstable angina within the&#xD;
             previous 6 months before starting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with known central nervous system (CNS) tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with known active CNS metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with persisting toxicity related to prior therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients who have undergone major surgery within 4 weeks prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Pregnant or breastfeeding female patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients with inability to swallow oral medications or with gastrointestinal illness&#xD;
             that would preclude the absorption of an oral agent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Li Zhang, Master</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>West China Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yongsheng Wang, Doctor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>West China Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lei Mu, Master</last_name>
    <phone>+86-021-23081188</phone>
    <email>Lei.mu@lianbio.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guanzhou</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <zip>510060</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Li Zhang, Master</last_name>
      <phone>+86-020-87343458</phone>
      <email>zhangli@sysucc.org.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West China Hospital Sichuan University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chengdu</city>
        <state>Sichuan</state>
        <zip>610041</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yongsheng Wang, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>18980602258</phone>
      <email>wangy756@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 30, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 30, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 5, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Solid Tumors, NSCLC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

