<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05626088</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Vedolizumab-4045</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05626088</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study in Adults With Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) Receiving Vedolizumab in the Patient Support Program (PSP) in Brazil</brief_title>
  <official_title>Sociodemographic Characteristics, Vedolizumab Persistence and Outcomes in Inflammatory Bowel Disease Patients Participating in the Patient Support Program in Brazil</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary reason of this study is to observe current and past treatment in adult&#xD;
      participants receiving Vedolizumab, intravenous (IV) or subcutaneous (SC), for IBD in Brazil.&#xD;
      There is no treatment involved in this study, this is only an observational review of past&#xD;
      and ongoing treatment data relating to Vedolizumab treatment for IBD (including Ulcerative&#xD;
      Colitis [UC] and Crohn's Disease [CD]).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a non-interventional, observational study in participants with IBD participating in&#xD;
      the PSP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will enroll approximately 1800 participants. Data collection will be done in 2&#xD;
      components, one is retrospective for participants included in the program before the study&#xD;
      starts (from 2016 until study start date) and second is the prospective for participants that&#xD;
      were already part of PSP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be assigned to following two observational cohorts:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  UC participants&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CD participants&#xD;
&#xD;
      This single country trial will be conducted in Brazil. The duration of this observational&#xD;
      study will be approximately 26 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 10, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Vedolizumab Treatment Persistence for Conventional Therapy and Anti-Tumor Necrosis Factor (TNF) Experience</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment persistence will be defined as participants who did not discontinue treatment during follow-up.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Therapies Used Before Vedolizumab Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Vedolizumab Treatment Scheme (Dose Escalation and De-escalation) for Conventional Therapy and Anti-TNF Experience</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Comorbidities Associated or not With CD or UC</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Disease</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Diagnosed With UC or CD</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Vedolizumab Drug Administration Route: Intravenous (IV) or Subcutaneous (SC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Based on Quality-of-life (QOL) as Assessed by Inflammatory Bowel Disease Questionnaire (IBDQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
    <description>The IBDQ Quest contains 32 questions. Each question within each of the domains verified in the Quest is composed of seven alternative answers. Each answer option is worth its own number in points, with 1 = worse quality of life and 7 = better quality of life, with the sum of the total points obtained in each domain. The simple sum of all domains will result in the total score obtained by the participant. The minimum IBDQ score is 32 (if the participant answered all 32 questions as 1) and a maximum of 224 (if the participant answered all 7 questions). Higher score indicates better QOL.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Adverse Events (AEs) or Serious AEs During Vedolizumab use for UC and CD</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Reason for Discontinuing the Vedolizumab Treatment for Conventional Therapy and Experiences Anti-TNF</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Satisfied With the &quot;Entre Nós&quot; Program</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 9 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1800</enrollment>
  <condition>Ulcerative Colitis</condition>
  <condition>Crohn's Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>UC Participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants diagnosed with UC with prescription of vedolizumab, were included in the PSP program before the study starts (from 2016 until study start date of this study) will be observed retrospectively and participants who were already part of PSP or will participate after the study start will be observed prospectively.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CD Participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants diagnosed with CD with prescription of vedolizumab, were included in the PSP program before the study starts (from 2016 until study start date of this study) will be observed retrospectively and participants who were already part of PSP or will participate after the study start will be observed prospectively.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>This is a non-interventional study.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CD Participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>UC Participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants diagnosed with UC or CD with vedolizumab prescription, residing in Brazil and&#xD;
        agree to participate in the program.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Who participated or who will participate in the &quot;Entre Nós&quot; program and participant who&#xD;
        consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        • No exclusion of participants is expected in the present study and the quality of the data&#xD;
        relies in participant reported outcomes for the &quot;Entre Nós&quot; program.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Contact</last_name>
    <phone>+1-877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medinfoUS@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Praxis Pesquisa Medica</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sao Paulo</city>
        <state>SP</state>
        <zip>CEP 09090-790</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Site Contact</last_name>
      <phone>55 11 991163777</phone>
      <email>marjorieargollo@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marjorie Argollo, Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/study-detail/02e9c7fcf086437f?idFilter=%5B%22Vedolizumab-4045%22%5D</url>
    <description>To obtain more information about this study, click this link.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 25, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 25, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Takeda provides access to the de-identified individual participant data (IPD) for eligible studies to aid qualified researchers in addressing legitimate scientific objectives (Takeda's data sharing commitment is available on https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/takedas-commitment?commitment=5). These IPDs will be provided in a secure research environment following approval of a data sharing request, and under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_access_criteria>IPD from eligible studies will be shared with qualified researchers according to the criteria and process described on https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/. For approved requests, the researchers will be provided access to anonymized data (to respect patient privacy in line with applicable laws and regulations) and with information necessary to address the research objectives under the terms of a data sharing agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://vivli.org/ourmember/takeda/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

