<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05626036</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21-14036</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05626036</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Randomized Controlled Trial Comparing Suture Button Versus Fibulink Fixation for Acute Ankle Syndesmosis Injuries</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Trial Comparing Clinical Outcomes of Patients Treated Surgically With Suture Button Versus Fibulink Fixation for Acute Ankle Syndesmosis Injuries</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>United States Naval Medical Center, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>United States Naval Medical Center, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ankle fractures are a common injury with potentially significant morbidity. Syndesmosis&#xD;
      injury occurs in 10% to 13% of ankle fractures and poses a greater risk to long-term outcomes&#xD;
      for patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The gold standard for syndesmosis fixation has traditionally been screw fixation. However,&#xD;
      issues with screw fixation include screw breakage, screw loosening, reoperation, and&#xD;
      malreduction. Due to growing concerns with static screw fixation, implants based on the&#xD;
      flexible suture button design, such as the TightRope system, gained traction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Fibulink Syndesmosis Repair System, a relatively new design that became clinically&#xD;
      available in 2017, has showed promising results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To our knowledge, there is no study that directly compares outcomes with the Fibulink implant&#xD;
      to suture button implants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ankle fractures are a common injury with potentially significant morbidity. Syndesmosis&#xD;
      injury occurs in 10% to 13% of ankle fractures and poses a greater risk to long-term outcomes&#xD;
      for patients1,2. If not recognized and adequately reduced, injuries to the syndesmosis have&#xD;
      shown to result in instability, persistent pain, and post-traumatic arthritis3. 11% of cases&#xD;
      are accompanied by symptomatic advanced osteoarthritis after fixation of the syndesmosis4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The gold standard for syndesmosis fixation has traditionally been screw fixation5. However,&#xD;
      issues with screw fixation include screw breakage, screw loosening, reoperation, and&#xD;
      malreduction6-8. This has been speculated to be a result of the ankle syndesmosis, a dynamic&#xD;
      construct, being inappropriately fixed with static fixation. Due to growing concerns with&#xD;
      static screw fixation, implants based on the flexible suture button design, such as the&#xD;
      TightRope system, gained traction. Advantages with these designs include superior outcome&#xD;
      scores, as well as lower rates of osteoarthritis and reoperation7,9,10. However, despite&#xD;
      achieving improved joint mechanics, these systems have their drawbacks as well, such as&#xD;
      infection or damage to the superficial medial neurovascular bundle9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Fibulink Syndesmosis Repair System, a relatively new design that became clinically&#xD;
      available in 2017, has showed promising results. It has been promoted as an implant that&#xD;
      potentially provides both the fixation of a screw and flexibility of a suture to respect the&#xD;
      dynamic nature of the ankle joint. Benefits of this design include eliminating damage to the&#xD;
      medial neurovascular bundle and soft tissues, promoting physiologic motion of the ankle&#xD;
      joint, and allowing improved tension control. In a case series with 14 patients that received&#xD;
      the Fibulink implant, Desai found no complications with a mean follow-up of 9.5 months9.&#xD;
      However, more long-term data is needed in order to draw any conclusions. The potential&#xD;
      advantage of this system over suture button designs is that it incorporates the rigidity of&#xD;
      screw fixation on top of the dynamic fixation of suture button implants. It also addresses&#xD;
      the limitations of suture button designs, such as avoiding medial soft tissue disruption and&#xD;
      lack of two-way tension control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The comparison between screw fixation and suture button designs has been thoroughly&#xD;
      investigated in the literature. To our knowledge, there is no study that directly compares&#xD;
      outcomes with the Fibulink implant to suture button implants. It is imperative to directly&#xD;
      compare these methods so we can definitively assess their suitability and provide patients&#xD;
      that sustain these injuries the best method of fixation in order to improve patient outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to compare radiographic and clinical outcomes in patients who&#xD;
      sustain an acute ankle fracture with an associated syndesmosis injury by comparing two&#xD;
      surgical treatments currently in the practice of the study investigators. The study will&#xD;
      compare suture button fixation versus Fibulink implant in patients with this injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inadequate syndesmosis fixation has been found to result in significant morbidity to&#xD;
      patients, including persistent pain, instability, and post-traumatic arthritis. This&#xD;
      emphasizes the need to assess the available methods of fixation in order to minimize negative&#xD;
      long-term consequences. Currently, standard single screw fixation remains a common choice&#xD;
      among orthopaedic surgeons. However, there is some evidence of superior outcomes with dynamic&#xD;
      fixation, using designs such as the suture button or the Fibulink system, in terms of&#xD;
      functional results, residual pain, and other measures. With an enhanced understanding of&#xD;
      patient outcomes with these methods of fixation, we will better be able to determine more&#xD;
      effective ways to manage these injures and offer guidance for optimal management and patient&#xD;
      satisfaction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized Controlled Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analog Scale (VAS) pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>VAS pain score is rated from 0-10 with 0 being no pain and 10 being the worst pain possible.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Foot and Ankle Disability Index</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Functional score with a score of 0-104 with higher scores indicating better function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Olerud-Molander Ankle Score</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Functional score with a score of 0-100 with higher scores indicating better function</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with medical or surgical complications</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Medical and surgical complications to include: surgical site infection, re-operation, device failure, loss of motion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Syndesmotic Injuries</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arthrex Tightrope</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Syndesmosis fixation performed with Arthrex Tightrope device. This is a high-tension suture fixation with a button based anchor system.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Synthes Fibulink</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Syndesmosis fixation performed with Synthes Fibulink device. This is a high-tension suture fixation with a screw based anchor system.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Arthrex Tightrope</intervention_name>
    <description>High-tensile strength suture syndesmosis repair</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arthrex Tightrope</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Synthes Fibulink</intervention_name>
    <description>High-tensile strength suture syndesmosis repair</description>
    <arm_group_label>Synthes Fibulink</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ankle fracture with associated syndesmotic injury requiring surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand the content of the patient information/Informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any not medically managed severe systemic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient preference for specific implant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal of randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in any other pharmacologic or medicinal product study within the&#xD;
             previous month that could influence the results of this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Benjamin Wheatley</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NMCSD</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ashley Hughey</last_name>
    <phone>619-532-9535</phone>
    <email>ashley.e.hughey.ctr@health.mil</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Naval Medical Center San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92134</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ashley Hughey</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benjamin Wheatley</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lindsjo U. Operative treatment of ankle fractures. Acta Orthop Scand Suppl. 1981;189:1-131. doi: 10.3109/ort.1981.52.suppl-189.01.</citation>
    <PMID>6787831</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Court-Brown CM, McBirnie J, Wilson G. Adult ankle fractures--an increasing problem? Acta Orthop Scand. 1998 Feb;69(1):43-7. doi: 10.3109/17453679809002355.</citation>
    <PMID>9524517</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sagi HC, Shah AR, Sanders RW. The functional consequence of syndesmotic joint malreduction at a minimum 2-year follow-up. J Orthop Trauma. 2012 Jul;26(7):439-43. doi: 10.1097/BOT.0b013e31822a526a.</citation>
    <PMID>22357084</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ray R, Koohnejad N, Clement ND, Keenan GF. Ankle fractures with syndesmotic stabilisation are associated with a high rate of secondary osteoarthritis. Foot Ankle Surg. 2019 Apr;25(2):180-185. doi: 10.1016/j.fas.2017.10.005. Epub 2017 Oct 28.</citation>
    <PMID>29409288</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bava E, Charlton T, Thordarson D. Ankle fracture syndesmosis fixation and management: the current practice of orthopedic surgeons. Am J Orthop (Belle Mead NJ). 2010 May;39(5):242-6.</citation>
    <PMID>20567742</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gardner MJ, Demetrakopoulos D, Briggs SM, Helfet DL, Lorich DG. Malreduction of the tibiofibular syndesmosis in ankle fractures. Foot Ankle Int. 2006 Oct;27(10):788-92. doi: 10.1177/107110070602701005.</citation>
    <PMID>17054878</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Laflamme M, Belzile EL, Bedard L, van den Bekerom MP, Glazebrook M, Pelet S. A prospective randomized multicenter trial comparing clinical outcomes of patients treated surgically with a static or dynamic implant for acute ankle syndesmosis rupture. J Orthop Trauma. 2015 May;29(5):216-23. doi: 10.1097/BOT.0000000000000245.</citation>
    <PMID>25260059</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Naqvi GA, Cunningham P, Lynch B, Galvin R, Awan N. Fixation of ankle syndesmotic injuries: comparison of tightrope fixation and syndesmotic screw fixation for accuracy of syndesmotic reduction. Am J Sports Med. 2012 Dec;40(12):2828-35. doi: 10.1177/0363546512461480. Epub 2012 Oct 10.</citation>
    <PMID>23051785</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Raeder BW, Figved W, Madsen JE, Frihagen F, Jacobsen SB, Andersen MR. Better outcome for suture button compared with single syndesmotic screw for syndesmosis injury: five-year results of a randomized controlled trial. Bone Joint J. 2020 Feb;102-B(2):212-219. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.102B2.BJJ-2019-0692.R2.</citation>
    <PMID>32009435</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 22, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 22, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 22, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>United States Naval Medical Center, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Benjamin Wheatley</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>syndesmosis</keyword>
  <keyword>clinical outcomes</keyword>
  <keyword>ankle fracture</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ankle Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

