<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05616364</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Sheikh Zayed Medical College &amp;</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05616364</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Compair Efficacy of iv Dexmedetomidine &amp; Tramadol for Post Spinal Shivering in Obs Patients Undergoing Cesarean Section</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Efficacy of Intravenous Dexmedetomidine and Tramadol in Control of Post Spinal Shivering in Obstetric Patients Undergoing Lower Segment Cesarean Section</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sana Bahadur</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sheikh Zayed Medical College</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      When opposed to GA,SA is recommended during c section. Shivering is more prevalent and&#xD;
      inconvenient complication of spinal anaesthesia, with 40 to 70% incidence rate. Tramadol has&#xD;
      been proven to be beneficial in preventing post spinal shivering. Dexmedetomidine is a&#xD;
      sedative, analgesic, anxiolytic, sympatholytic and opioid-sparing alpha adrenergic agonist.&#xD;
      It has been shown to lower the threshold for shivering. The study aims to search for best&#xD;
      drug for blunting shivering response.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      When opposed to general anaesthesia (GA), spinal anaesthesia (SA) is recommended during&#xD;
      caesarean section (CS) because of various advantages, including the prevention of GA-related&#xD;
      neurotoxicity, its early onset and ease of administration, and the reduction of&#xD;
      post-operative pain. Intraoperative shivering is the most prevalent irritating and&#xD;
      inconvenient complication of spinal anaesthesia, and it is a very distressing experience that&#xD;
      causes physiological stress to both patients and perioperative physicians and operating&#xD;
      surgeons. Shivering is a skeletal muscular movement that occurs involuntarily and repeatedly.&#xD;
      It's a common post-anesthesia adverse effect, with a 40-70% incidence rate.Shivering is not&#xD;
      only physically unpleasant for the sufferer, but it can also have several negative&#xD;
      consequences. It can cause pain, and discomfort for patients, obstruct monitoring techniques,&#xD;
      raise intraocular and intracranial pressures, and double or even triple oxygen and carbon&#xD;
      dioxide intake.Various pharmacological and non-pharmacological strategies for managing&#xD;
      intraoperative shivering are discussed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tramadol, a centrally acting analgesic with -opioid agonist properties and little action on&#xD;
      kappa and delta receptors, has been proven to be beneficial in preventing post-spinal&#xD;
      shivering. The method of action is thought to be through a modulatory influence on central&#xD;
      monoaminergic pathways, which inhibits noradrenaline and serotonin neuronal absorption in the&#xD;
      spinal cord while boosting hydroxyltryptamine production, resetting the body temperature&#xD;
      regulatory center.However, it has many side effects, including nausea, vomiting, and&#xD;
      dizziness, which add to the patient's pain. Hence research into novel solutions with adequate&#xD;
      safety and effectiveness is strongly advised. In this sense, despite taking into account the&#xD;
      gold standard for post spinal shivering control is pethidine. it is contraindicated in&#xD;
      breastfeeding which is both legally and ethically challenging for women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine is a sedative, analgesic, anxiolytic, sympatholytic, and opioid-sparing alpha&#xD;
      2 adrenergic agonist with good selectivity and specificity.It has been shown to lower the&#xD;
      threshold for shivering.Dexmedetomidine does not affect the locus ceruleus of the spinal&#xD;
      cord, and it does not cause respiratory depression. In postoperative patients,&#xD;
      dexmedetomidine lowers cortisol and norepinephrine levels, as well as blood glucose,&#xD;
      interleukin (IL)-6, tumour necrosis factor-a, and C-reactive protein, and raises&#xD;
      interleukin-10. Moreover, because Dexmedetomidine does not affect upper airway reflexes, it&#xD;
      is an excellent option.It was believed that the sedative impact of intravenous injection on&#xD;
      newborn infants was very minimal and could be disregarded due to the delayed sedative&#xD;
      effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These drugs have well-defined roles to blunt the &quot;shivering response&quot; and hence have been&#xD;
      used in different comparative studies to develop the single best drug of choice. Yet, there&#xD;
      is no consensus over a single drug. In our research, we intend to compare IV Tramadol and IV&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine for controlling post spinal shivering in obstetric patients. The study aims&#xD;
      to search for the best drug for blunting the shivering response, which may prove fatal in any&#xD;
      patient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of post spinal shivering by observing grades of shivering</measure>
    <time_frame>10 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Control of post spinal shivering Dexmedetomidine and tramadol for post spinal shivering</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Post Spinal Shivering</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dexmedetomidine is a sedative, analgesic, anxiolytic, sympatholytic, and opioid-sparing alpha 2 adrenergic agonist with good selectivity and specificity.It has been shown to lower the threshold for shivering. Dexmedetomidine does not affect the locus ceruleus of the spinal cord, and it does not cause respiratory depression. [8] In postoperative patients, dexmedetomidine lowers cortisol and norepinephrine levels, as well as blood glucose, interleukin (IL)-6, tumour necrosis factor-a, and C-reactive protein, and raises interleukin-10. Moreover, because Dexmedetomidine does not affect upper airway reflexes, it is an excellent option.It was believed that the sedative impact of intravenous injection on newborn infants was very minimal and could be disregarded due to the delayed sedative effects</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tramadol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Tramadol, a centrally acting analgesic with -opioid agonist properties and little action on kappa and delta receptors, has been proven to be beneficial in preventing post-spinal shivering. The method of action is thought to be through a modulatory influence on central monoaminergic pathways, which inhibits noradrenaline and serotonin neuronal absorption in the spinal cord while boosting hydroxyltryptamine production, resetting the body temperature regulatory center. [3] However, it has many side effects, including nausea, vomiting, and dizziness, which add to the patient's pain. [5] Hence research into novel solutions with adequate safety and effectiveness is strongly advised. In this sense, despite taking into account the gold standard for post spinal shivering control is pethidine. it is contraindicated in breastfeeding which is both legally and ethically challenging for women.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexmedetomidine intravenous</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tramadol</intervention_name>
    <description>Tramadol intravenous</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tramadol</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who will give consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA 2 patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female gender of age 18 to 38&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient allergic to any drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled HTN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antepartum&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiomyopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripartum haemorrhage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eclampsia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients refuse to give consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>38 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sheikh Zayed Medical College</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sana Bahadur</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.Sana bahadur</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tramadol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

