<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05614128</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VR64081</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05614128</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Validation of Cutaneous Nerve Demyelination in Diagnosis and Treatment of CIDP</brief_title>
  <official_title>Validation of Cutaneous Nerve Demyelination in Diagnosis and Treatment of CIDP</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>CSL Behring</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this observational study is to learn about chronic inflammatory demyelinating&#xD;
      polyneuropathy. The main question we would like to answer is 1) can skin biopsy identify&#xD;
      demyelination better than nerve conduction studies (electrical tests of the nerves)? and 2)&#xD;
      how do nerves improve after treatment in CIDP? Participants will be asked to undergo skin&#xD;
      biopsy of the finger at baseline and at 3 months and 6 months after treatment with IVIG&#xD;
      (which is the FDA approved treatment for CIDP).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic Inflammatory Demyelinating Polyradiculoneuropathy (CIDP) is an autoimmune disorder&#xD;
      that can cause severe weakness and numbness, difficulty walking if untreated. CIDP is a&#xD;
      disorder where the myelin or outside covering of the nerves which protect nerves and speed&#xD;
      conduction are damaged by the immune system. The typical way CIDP is diagnosed is by&#xD;
      performing electrical stimulation of the nerves (nerve conduction study or NCS) which may not&#xD;
      be very accurate in identifying CIDP. We also are not clear on how CIDP nerve impairment&#xD;
      improves with treatment after IVIg, which is the recommended treatment. This study uses skin&#xD;
      biopsy of the finger to look at the nerves and see if abnormalities of myelin such as&#xD;
      segmental demyelination (loss of myelin along the course of the nerve) can be detected under&#xD;
      microscope. We will repeat the skin biopsy during treatment with IVIg (brand Privigen which&#xD;
      is FDA approved for CIDP) to determine how IVIg improves nerves during treatment. We hope&#xD;
      this study will provide both better ways to diagnose patients with CIDP as well as inform&#xD;
      doctors on how CIDP can improve with treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We are recruiting patients newly diagnosed or within 6 months of diagnosis to study the use&#xD;
      of skin biopsies in diagnosis of CIDP. We are also repeating skin biopsies at 3 months and 6&#xD;
      months to measure improvement in nerve demyelination.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of cutaneous nerves with segmental demyelination</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of nerve fibers with demyelination visualized under microscopy will be calculated per biopsy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>CIDP</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IVIg</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be treated with IVIg as recommended by expert guidelines for treatment of CIDP under care of their primary neurologist. This will not be provided by the study.</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      2 mm punch skin biopsies will be obtained at the index finger on the palm side of the&#xD;
      non-dominant hand.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Newly diagnosed patients with CIDP prior or within 6 months of treatment with IVIg.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults (age ≥ 18 years) with definite or probable CIDP according to the EFNS/PNS&#xD;
             criteria may enter the trial within 6 months of treatment onset or treatment naïve&#xD;
             patients. Written informed consent is obtained by the local investigator before entry&#xD;
             into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. IVIg treatment of 0.8 up to 1.2 g/kg per 30 days will be allowed up to 6 months. It&#xD;
             is expected some patients may be on variable treatment regimens, and as along as they&#xD;
             are not significantly declining, efforts will be made to continue treatment regimens&#xD;
             already instituted.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Prednisone in doses up to 20 mg /day will be allowed as long as dose has been&#xD;
             stable for 90 days and is not being escalated or tapered during study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Previous plasma exchange will be allowed as long as it is not continued during the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Other causes of polyneuropathy, multifocal motor neuropathy, diabetes mellitus,&#xD;
             alcohol, family history of neuropathy, monoclonal gammopathy or malignancy, history of&#xD;
             drug or toxin exposure, which could reasonably cause neuropathy. Coexistent monoclonal&#xD;
             gammopathy will also be used as an exclusion as these patients may not have the same&#xD;
             response to IVIg.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Any other disease that may cause neurological symptoms and signs or that may&#xD;
             interfere with treatment or outcome assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Severe conditions that may interfere with an evaluation of the study product or&#xD;
             satisfactory conduct of the study such as current malignancy or history of allogeneic&#xD;
             bone marrow/stem cell transplant, cardiac insufficiency (New York Heart Association&#xD;
             Classes III/IV), cardiomyopathy, cardiac arrhythmia requiring treatment, unstable or&#xD;
             advanced ischemic heart disease, congestive heart failure or severe hypertension,&#xD;
             chronic kidney disease deemed too severe to safely use IVIg, known hyperprolinemia,&#xD;
             known bleeding disorders, severe skin disease at the planned injection sites or biopsy&#xD;
             site, alcohol, drug or medication abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. History of keloids or other reactions to local anesthetic making skin biopsies&#xD;
             unsafe.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Patients with the following laboratory results:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Positive result at screening on any of the following viral markers: human&#xD;
                  immunodeficiency virus-1 or 2, or hepatitis B or C virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Abnormal laboratory parameters: creatinine greater than 1.5 times the upper limit&#xD;
                  of normal (ULN), blood urea nitrogen greater than three times the ULN if the&#xD;
                  increase is related to potential kidney disease, or hemoglobin less than 10 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
             b. AAbnormal laboratory parameters: creatinine greater than 1.5 times the upper limit&#xD;
             of normal (ULN), blood urea nitrogen greater than three times the ULN if the increase&#xD;
             is related to potential kidney disease, or hemoglobin less than 10 g/dL 6. Fulfilling&#xD;
             the following general criteria: inability to comply with study procedures and&#xD;
             treatment regimen; mental condition rendering the patient unable to understand the&#xD;
             nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study; pregnancy or nursing mother;&#xD;
             intention to become pregnant during the course of the study; female patients of&#xD;
             childbearing potential either not using or not willing to use a medically reliable&#xD;
             method of contraception for the entire duration of the study or not sexually abstinent&#xD;
             for the entire duration of the study or not surgically sterile; participation in&#xD;
             another clinical study or use of another investigational medicinal product within the&#xD;
             same time period of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Additional medications and treatments other than prednisone and IVIg for treatment&#xD;
             of CIDP such as azathioprine, mycophenolate, rituximab and ongoing plasma exchange as&#xD;
             this will either confound or interfere with effects of IVIg.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wende Fedder, Rn</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Diana Davis, RN</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amanda C Peltier</last_name>
    <phone>16159368444</phone>
    <email>amanda.peltier@vumc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amanda Peltier</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Demyelinating Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>October 4, 2022</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/28/NCT05614128/Prot_ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

