<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05795049</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20GA093</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>288003</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05795049</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genetic Carbohydrate Maldigestion as a Model to Study Food Hypersensitivity</brief_title>
  <acronym>GenMalCarb</acronym>
  <official_title>Genetic Carbohydrate Maldigestion as a Model to Study Food Hypersensitivity Mechanism and Guide Personalised Treatment Using a Non-invasive Multiparametric Test (Work Package 1)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>CICbioGUNE</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Christian-Albrechts-University of Kiel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Veterinary Medicine Hannover</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) affects one in seven people with gastrointestinal (GI)&#xD;
      symptoms. IBS strongly impacts quality of life, is a leading cause of work absenteeism, and&#xD;
      consumes 0.5% of the healthcare annual budget. It manifests in women more than men with&#xD;
      symptoms including abdominal pain, bloating, constipation (IBS-C), diarrhoea (IBS-D), and&#xD;
      mixed presentations (IBS-M) (1). The development of therapeutic options is hampered by the&#xD;
      poor understanding of the underlying cause of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many patients find that certain foods (particularly carbohydrates) trigger their symptoms,&#xD;
      and avoiding such foods has been shown effective in IBS, like in the low-FODMAP (fermentable&#xD;
      oligo-, di-, mono-saccharides and polyols) exclusion diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This has suggested that the food-symptom relation may involve malabsorption of carbohydrates&#xD;
      due to inefficient digestion. However only a percentage of patients respond to this diet.&#xD;
      Recently it has been reported that a subset of IBS carries hypomorphic (defective) gene&#xD;
      variant of the sucrase isomaltase (SI), the enzyme that normally digests carbohydrates,&#xD;
      sucrose and starch. This carbohydrate maldigestion (the breakdown of complex carbohydrates by&#xD;
      a person's small bowel enzymes) is characterized by diarrhoea, abdominal pain and bloating,&#xD;
      which are also features of IBS. This possibly occurs via accumulation of undigested&#xD;
      carbohydrates in the large bowel, where they cause symptoms due to gas production following&#xD;
      bacterial fermentation. Similar mechanisms may be acting at the level of other enzymes&#xD;
      involved in the digestion, breakdown and absorption of carbohydrates (carb digestion genes&#xD;
      -CDGs). Aim of the study is to study the prevalence of this genetic alteration in a large&#xD;
      number of IBS patients as compared to asymptomatic controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>number of IBS-D and IBS-M with of SI and CDG hypomorphic variants as compared to asymptomatic controls</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>the prevalence of SI and CDG hypomorphic variants in IBS-D and IBS-M patients across countries and ethnicities, compared to asymptomatic controls</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in age between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- age in years</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in gender between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- gender</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in ethnicity between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- ethnicity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in IBS subtype between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- number of patients with IBS with diarrhoea (IBS-D) and with mixed bowel habit (IBS-M)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in post-infectious onset between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- number of patients with post-infectious onset</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in number of previous abdominal surgery between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- number of patients with IBS with previous abdominal surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in symptoms presentations between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- IBS symptoms severity score for adults. This score range between 0 and 500 and a change of at least 50 is considered a clinically relevant change.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in anxiety and depression between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- Hospital Anxiety and Depression score for adults. A score up to 7 for anxiety and or depression is considered Normal; between 8-10 Borderline abnormal (borderline case) and between 11-21 = Abnormal (case)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in somatisation between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- Somatization score for adults. a score of 5, 10, and 15 represent cutpoints for low, medium, and high somatic symptom severity, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in habitual intake of sugars between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- Total glucose and fructose and excess fructose, lactose, sorbitol, mannitol, oligosaccharides (Fructans and GOS) as measured by CNAQ questionnaire for adults and children</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in quality of life between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- Quality of Life as measured by the Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory™ Gastrointestinal Symptoms (PedsQL™ GI Symptoms) Scale. The high.er the PedsQL score, the better the quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in symptoms between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- GI symptoms using those reported in the Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory™ Gastrointestinal Symptoms Module</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in anxiety and depression between paediatric patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate whether the below parameters differs between patients carriers and non-carriers of defective (hypomorphic) gene:&#xD;
- Anxiety, Depression as measured by the Pediatric Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS®). This use a T-score metric in which 50 is the mean of a relevant reference population and 10 is the standard deviation (SD) of that population.&#xD;
On the T-score metric:&#xD;
A score of 40 is one SD lower than the mean of the reference population. A score of 60 is one SD higher than the mean of the reference population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in in vitro SI enzyme activity in human cells with defective gene as compare with those with normal gene</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in the intensity of the SI protein bands of immunoprecipitations of monoclonal anti-SI antibodies that recognize different conformations of the SI protein</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS)</condition>
  <condition>Sucrase Isomaltase Deficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IBS Patient</arm_group_label>
    <description>IBS patient with diarrhoea or alternating bowel habit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy subject</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants without IBS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stool and saliva sample collection</intervention_name>
    <description>Stool and saliva samples collection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy subject</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>IBS Patient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire completion</intervention_name>
    <description>Questionnaire on;&#xD;
demographic, ethnicity, IBS subtype, post-infection onset, previous surgeries&#xD;
IBS severity score for adults&#xD;
Hospital Anxiety and Depression scores for adults&#xD;
Somatization score for adults&#xD;
Total glucose and fructose and excess fructose, lactose, sorbitol, mannitol, oligosaccharides (Fructans and GOS) as measured by CNAQ questionnaire for adults and children&#xD;
Quality of Life as measured by the PedsQL™ GI Symptoms Module&#xD;
GI symptoms as measured by the PedsQL™ GI Symptoms Module&#xD;
Anxiety, Depression as measured by the Pediatric PROMIS®</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy subject</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>IBS Patient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Saliva and stool sample&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Multicentre study. IBS patients identified through secondary and tertiary care&#xD;
        gastroenterological clinics.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Asymptomatic adult controls recruited at the same site as respective patients or, for&#xD;
        instance, from transfusion clinics, blood donor centres, bowel cancer screening as long as&#xD;
        data on the absence of symptoms is documented.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients age between 5 and 70 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with IBS-D or IBS-M as defined by the Rome III criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous negative endoscopy with biopsies excluding IBD or microscopic colitis in&#xD;
             patients above 50 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative relevant additional screening or consultation whenever appropriate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to conform to the study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with IBS-C or IBS-U according to Rome III criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, makes the&#xD;
             patient unsuitable for participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on opioids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with concurrent organic gastrointestinal disease (inflammatory bowel disease,&#xD;
             celiac disease, cancer), or a major disease such as diabetes, uncontrolled thyroid&#xD;
             disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of bowel surgery (not appendectomy or cholecystectomy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent major confounding condition, e.g. alcohol or substance abuse in the last 2&#xD;
             years (clinician's judgement).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria for healthy controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between 5 and 70 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of Rome III IBS criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for healthy controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood relatives of the participating IBS patient are not allowed to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person with any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, makes them&#xD;
             unsuitable for participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person presenting with a functional or organic GI disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person presenting with underlying disease that may involve the GI tract (e.g.&#xD;
             Parkinson's disease) or be associated with GI symptoms (e.g. anorexia nervosa, major&#xD;
             depression).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maura Corsetti, MD</last_name>
    <phone>07976448821</phone>
    <email>maura.corsetti@nottingham.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Olivia J Henshaw, Bsc</last_name>
    <phone>07812 277103</phone>
    <email>olivia.henshaw@nuh.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.nuh.nhs.uk/genmalcarb-study/</url>
    <description>Sponsor website page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ford AC, Lacy BE, Talley NJ. Irritable Bowel Syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2017 Jun 29;376(26):2566-2578. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1607547. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>28657875</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shepherd SJ, Lomer MC, Gibson PR. Short-chain carbohydrates and functional gastrointestinal disorders. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013 May;108(5):707-17. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2013.96. Epub 2013 Apr 16.</citation>
    <PMID>23588241</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eswaran SL, Chey WD, Han-Markey T, Ball S, Jackson K. A Randomized Controlled Trial Comparing the Low FODMAP Diet vs. Modified NICE Guidelines in US Adults with IBS-D. Am J Gastroenterol. 2016 Dec;111(12):1824-1832. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2016.434. Epub 2016 Oct 11.</citation>
    <PMID>27725652</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ament ME, Perera DR, Esther LJ. Sucrase-isomaltase deficiency-a frequently misdiagnosed disease. J Pediatr. 1973 Nov;83(5):721-7. doi: 10.1016/s0022-3476(73)80362-2. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>4742566</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chumpitazi BP, Lewis J, Cooper D, D'Amato M, Lim J, Gupta S, Miranda A, Terry N, Mehta D, Scheimann A, O'Gorman M, Tipnis N, Davies Y, Friedlander J, Smith H, Punati J, Khlevner J, Setty M, Di Lorenzo C. Hypomorphic SI genetic variants are associated with childhood chronic loose stools. PLoS One. 2020 May 20;15(5):e0231891. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0231891. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>32433684</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Henstrom M, Diekmann L, Bonfiglio F, Hadizadeh F, Kuech EM, von Kockritz-Blickwede M, Thingholm LB, Zheng T, Assadi G, Dierks C, Heine M, Philipp U, Distl O, Money ME, Belheouane M, Heinsen FA, Rafter J, Nardone G, Cuomo R, Usai-Satta P, Galeazzi F, Neri M, Walter S, Simren M, Karling P, Ohlsson B, Schmidt PT, Lindberg G, Dlugosz A, Agreus L, Andreasson A, Mayer E, Baines JF, Engstrand L, Portincasa P, Bellini M, Stanghellini V, Barbara G, Chang L, Camilleri M, Franke A, Naim HY, D'Amato M. Functional variants in the sucrase-isomaltase gene associate with increased risk of irritable bowel syndrome. Gut. 2018 Feb;67(2):263-270. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2016-312456. Epub 2016 Nov 21.</citation>
    <PMID>27872184</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Garcia-Etxebarria K, Zheng T, Bonfiglio F, Bujanda L, Dlugosz A, Lindberg G, Schmidt PT, Karling P, Ohlsson B, Simren M, Walter S, Nardone G, Cuomo R, Usai-Satta P, Galeazzi F, Neri M, Portincasa P, Bellini M, Barbara G, Jonkers D, Eswaran S, Chey WD, Kashyap P, Chang L, Mayer EA, Wouters MM, Boeckxstaens G, Camilleri M, Franke A, D'Amato M. Increased Prevalence of Rare Sucrase-isomaltase Pathogenic Variants in Irritable Bowel Syndrome Patients. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018 Oct;16(10):1673-1676. doi: 10.1016/j.cgh.2018.01.047. Epub 2018 Feb 21.</citation>
    <PMID>29408290</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thingholm L, Ruhlemann M, Wang J, Hubenthal M, Lieb W, Laudes M, Franke A, D'Amato M. Sucrase-isomaltase 15Phe IBS risk variant in relation to dietary carbohydrates and faecal microbiota composition. Gut. 2019 Jan;68(1):177-178. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2017-315841. Epub 2018 Jan 13. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>29331942</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Husein DM, Naim HY. Impaired cell surface expression and digestive function of sucrase-isomaltase gene variants are associated with reduced efficacy of low FODMAPs diet in patients with IBS-D. Gut. 2020 Aug;69(8):1538-1539. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2019-319411. Epub 2019 Jul 22. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>31331993</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zheng T, Eswaran S, Photenhauer AL, Merchant JL, Chey WD, D'Amato M. Reduced efficacy of low FODMAPs diet in patients with IBS-D carrying sucrase-isomaltase (SI) hypomorphic variants. Gut. 2020 Feb;69(2):397-398. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2018-318036. Epub 2019 Jan 18. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>30658996</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spiller RC, Thompson WG. Bowel disorders. Am J Gastroenterol. 2010 Apr;105(4):775-85. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2010.69. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>20372130</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rasquin A, Di Lorenzo C, Forbes D, Guiraldes E, Hyams JS, Staiano A, Walker LS. Childhood functional gastrointestinal disorders: child/adolescent. Gastroenterology. 2006 Apr;130(5):1527-37. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2005.08.063.</citation>
    <PMID>16678566</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Francis CY, Morris J, Whorwell PJ. The irritable bowel severity scoring system: a simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 1997 Apr;11(2):395-402. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2036.1997.142318000.x.</citation>
    <PMID>9146781</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Snaith RP. The Hospital Anxiety And Depression Scale. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2003 Aug 1;1:29. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-1-29.</citation>
    <PMID>12914662</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spiller RC, Humes DJ, Campbell E, Hastings M, Neal KR, Dukes GE, Whorwell PJ. The Patient Health Questionnaire 12 Somatic Symptom scale as a predictor of symptom severity and consulting behaviour in patients with irritable bowel syndrome and symptomatic diverticular disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2010 Sep;32(6):811-20. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2036.2010.04402.x.</citation>
    <PMID>20629976</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Varni JW, Bendo CB, Denham J, Shulman RJ, Self MM, Neigut DA, Nurko S, Patel AS, Franciosi JP, Saps M, Verga B, Smith A, Yeckes A, Heinz N, Langseder A, Saeed S, Zacur GM, Pohl JF. PedsQL gastrointestinal symptoms module: feasibility, reliability, and validity. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2014 Sep;59(3):347-55. doi: 10.1097/MPG.0000000000000414.</citation>
    <PMID>24806837</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Irwin DE, Stucky B, Langer MM, Thissen D, Dewitt EM, Lai JS, Varni JW, Yeatts K, DeWalt DA. An item response analysis of the pediatric PROMIS anxiety and depressive symptoms scales. Qual Life Res. 2010 May;19(4):595-607. doi: 10.1007/s11136-010-9619-3. Epub 2010 Mar 7.</citation>
    <PMID>20213516</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 23, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>nutrigenetics</keyword>
  <keyword>carbohydrates maldigestion</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Food Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

