<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792592</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4253</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792592</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Small Airways Disease (SAD) in Severe Asthma as a Novel Endpoint and Distinct Target for Biological Therapy.</brief_title>
  <acronym>SASAB</acronym>
  <official_title>Small Airways Disease (SAD) in Severe Asthma as a Novel Endpoint and Distinct Target for Biological Therapy. Small Airways Disease (SAD) in Severe Asthma as a Novel Endpoint and Distinct Target for Biological Therapy (SASAB Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Severe asthma is now widely accepted to be a heterogeneous syndrome consisting of multiple&#xD;
      phenotypes identified by specific biomarkers and targeted by tailored biological therapies.&#xD;
      However, much remains unclear regarding the best approaches to manage these patients, or&#xD;
      concerning the pathophysiological mechanisms underlying the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Small airway (SA) are defined as those airways with an internal diameter &lt;2 mm. In patients&#xD;
      affected by asthma, it has been reported that SA are the predominant site of airflow&#xD;
      resistance. Peripheral airways are thickened in asthma due to chronic inflammation in the&#xD;
      epithelium, submucosa and muscle area. It has been suggested that the outer wall is more&#xD;
      inflamed than the inner wall, with a higher number of lymphocytes, eosinophils, and&#xD;
      neutrophils associated to an increased expression of interleukin-4 (IL-4), interleukin-5&#xD;
      (IL-5) and eotaxin. Moreover, it is well documented that SA inflammation and dysfunction&#xD;
      contribute significantly to the clinical impact of asthma and that 50-60% of asthmatics have&#xD;
      a SA involvement across all disease severities. An important question is whether SA disease&#xD;
      in asthma is variable among distinct asthma phenotypes and whether it occurs in all patients.&#xD;
      Cluster analyses have been recently used to identify specific asthma phenotypes, but markers&#xD;
      of SA function have not been investigated. However, evidence is accumulating to support that&#xD;
      SA dysfunction and inflammation may contribute to distinct asthma phenotypes. Recent findings&#xD;
      indicate that SA are significantly affected in severe asthma and that their involvement is&#xD;
      associated with worse disease outcomes. It has been reported that patients with asthma and a&#xD;
      history of frequent exacerbations per year had a significant SA involvement. Furthermore,&#xD;
      peripheral airways significantly contribute not only to the level of asthma control, but also&#xD;
      to patients' quality of life and perception of symptoms. At last more thickened SA and higher&#xD;
      numbers of eosinophils are detectable in subjects with fatal asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The assessment of SA represents a big challenge and requires qualified expertise and&#xD;
      sophisticated techniques including body plethysmography, single and multiple breath nitrogen&#xD;
      washout, impulse oscillometry (IOS), fraction exhaled NO at multiflow, sputum induction and&#xD;
      high-resolution chest CT (HRCT). Such procedures can either provide functional information on&#xD;
      the degree/extent of ventilation heterogeneity and air trapping or facilitate the&#xD;
      understanding of the inflammatory and remodeling processes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, a number of clinical trials have in recent years demonstrated the efficacy of&#xD;
      biologics in severe asthma. Omalizumab, a humanized anti-Imunoglobulin E monoclonal antibody&#xD;
      (mAb) has been well recognized as an important option for treating allergic asthma as an add-&#xD;
      on therapy for uncontrolled disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three anti-IL-5 therapies are currently available for the treatment of severe asthma,&#xD;
      including Mepolizumab, Reslizumab, and Benralizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The newest biologic agent to be approved is Dupilumab that is a human mAb that targets the&#xD;
      subunit of the IL-4 receptor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biologics represent an innovative strategy for the treatment of severe asthma. In most&#xD;
      patients with SAD these drugs control inflammation, improve lung function, ameliorate&#xD;
      clinical symptoms, reduce exacerbations and have a marked steroid-sparing effect. However,&#xD;
      there is still a significant proportion of non-responders and a lack of validated predictive&#xD;
      biomarkers in such subpopulation. In regard to this, very limited findings are available&#xD;
      about the effect of biologics therapy on SA.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study hypothesis We hypothesize that biological therapy has a significant beneficial effect&#xD;
      on small airways disease in severe asthmatics and that the evaluation of small airways before&#xD;
      and during treatment may represent a distinctive marker of response and a novel target for a&#xD;
      preferential use of one over other biological therapies currently available for severe&#xD;
      asthmatic patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate small airway endpoints in severe asthmatics before starting biologic&#xD;
           treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate longitudinal changes of these endpoints at different time points during&#xD;
           biologic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To relate small airway endpoints recorded at baseline and their changes over time to&#xD;
           other functional, laboratory, clinical and patient-reported outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To make comparisons for subgroups identified on the basis of the type of the biological&#xD;
           drug used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study center&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted at the Asthma Center of Fondazione Policlinico Universitario&#xD;
      Agostino Gemelli. Asthma Clinic evaluates approximately 1000 asthmatic patients per year;&#xD;
      furthermore, it is part of the Italian Severe Asthma Network (SANI) and one of the&#xD;
      coordinating centers for the newborn Italian Mild-Moderate Asthma Network (MANI), therefore&#xD;
      representing a center of excellence and reference at a national level, with easy and wide&#xD;
      access to the study population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design This is a 24-month, single-site observational retrospective and prospective&#xD;
      longitudinal cohort study involving asthmatic patients referred to the Asthma Center and&#xD;
      eligible for starting one of the biological therapy currently available. The patient will be&#xD;
      considered eligible only after having optimized adherence, inhalation technique, comorbidity&#xD;
      management and following a multidisciplinary assessment. Subjects will be monitored for 12&#xD;
      months and SA endpoints as well as other functional, clinical, laboratory and&#xD;
      patient-reported outcomes will be recorded at the beginning of the biological therapy (T0)&#xD;
      and after 3,6,12 months (T3, T6, T12). Values and changes in SA endpoints will be also&#xD;
      related to other functional, clinical and patient-reported outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following study procedures will be performed in the framework of the standard care for&#xD;
      severe asthmatic patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical history;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Demographics data (such as age, sex, race et.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Questionnaires (i.e. Asthma Control Test [ACT], Asthma Control Questionnaire [ACQ],&#xD;
           Asthma Quality of Life Questionnaire [AQLQ])&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pulmonary function tests (i.e. spirometry [Forced Expiratory volume in 1 second&#xD;
           (FEV1),Forced Vital Capacity (FVC), FEV1/FVC, body plethysmography [Residual Volume&#xD;
           (RV), Total Lung Capacity (TLC), RV/TLC, impulse oscillometry as resistance at 5 and 20&#xD;
           Hz (R5, R20).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Airway inflammatory markers (i.e. fraction exhaled nitric oxide - FeNO)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Allergy tests (i.e. skin-prick tests and immunoassays for total and specific serum IgE)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biological sampling (i.e. blood and sputum eosinophils).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Imaging (i.e. chest XR and HRCT)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study endpoints The primary endpoint will be represented by the R5-R20 parameter registered&#xD;
      through impulsoscillometry. Baseline values and changes over the one-year follow-up period at&#xD;
      preplanned timepoints (i.e. 3, 6, and 12 months) will be recorded. According to literature&#xD;
      evidence, baseline values ≥0.07 support the evidence of small airways dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints will be represented by indirect parameters of SA involvement (i.e. TLC,&#xD;
      RV, TLC/RV, FEF25-75). Baseline values and changes over the one-year follow-up period at&#xD;
      preplanned timepoints (i.e. 3, 6, and 12 months) will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variations in primary and secondary endpoints will be also related to changes in functional&#xD;
      parameters (i.e FEV1), clinical parameters (exacerbation rate), inflammatory markers (FeNO)&#xD;
      and patients' questionnaire scores (ACT, AQLQ, ACQ). Established minimal clinically important&#xD;
      difference (MCID) thresholds will be taken into consideration for correlation analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis Statistical analysis will be performed using a statistical software.&#xD;
      Data will be tested for normality and will be expressed as mean (SD) or median (IQR).&#xD;
      Comparative analysis will be performed using parametric and non-parametric methods as&#xD;
      appropriate. Single and multiple linear regression analyses will be run to determine&#xD;
      correlation between small airway endpoints and clinical, functional, laboratory, and&#xD;
      patients' reported outcomes. A p-value≥0.05 will be considered statistically significant.&#xD;
      Most appropriate statistical analyses and models will be anyway chosen and run, following the&#xD;
      advice of statisticians at the institutional Department of Public Health. Considering the&#xD;
      &quot;R5-R20 Delta&quot;, measured through impulse oscillometry, as the primary endpoint for the study,&#xD;
      and aiming for a minimal difference of 0.02 (according to literature data), in order to have&#xD;
      an a error of 0.5 and a study power of 80%, at least 54 subjects will have to be enrolled in&#xD;
      the study. Documentation will be stored for a minimum of 10 years after the completion of the&#xD;
      study, including the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study significance and innovation Systems biology approaches are establishing the links&#xD;
      between disease pathways/mechanisms, and clinical/physiologic features. Validation of these&#xD;
      pathways may contribute to better defining severe asthma endotypes and treatable mechanisms.&#xD;
      Precision medicine approaches are necessary to link treatable mechanisms with treatable&#xD;
      traits and biomarkers derived from clinical, physiologic, inflammatory, molecular and genetic&#xD;
      variables. A deep and proper assessment of airway samples along with non-invasive biomarkers&#xD;
      may have a highly relevant translational significance and enable better knowledge and&#xD;
      management of severe asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risk analysis No major difficulties are expected in view of the study's observational design.&#xD;
      No additional costs will be held.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 15, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 16, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 16, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline of R5-R20 over one-year follow-up after the beginning of biological therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, and after 3, 6 and 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>R5-R20</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">54</enrollment>
  <condition>Small Airway Disease</condition>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Uncontrolled Severe asthmatics</arm_group_label>
    <description>Uncontrolled Severe asthmatics</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IOS (Impulse Oscillometry)</intervention_name>
    <description>Small Airways Disease Assessment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Uncontrolled Severe asthmatics</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult (≥ 18 years) male and female subjects, capable to sign the informed consent,&#xD;
        addressed to the Asthma Center, with severe asthma as defined by current guidelines&#xD;
        (≥12months high-dose inhaled corticosteroids + additional controller treatments) and ≥ 2&#xD;
        exacerbations (corticosteroid and/or Emergency Department visit and/or hospitalization in&#xD;
        the previous 12 months). The patient should have a smoking history &lt;2 pack/year and should&#xD;
        be eligible for the administration of one of the approved biological therapy currently&#xD;
        available.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  Adult (≥ 18 years) male and female subjects,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable to sign the informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe asthma (≥12months high-dose inhaled corticosteroids + additional controller&#xD;
             treatments) and ≥ 2 exacerbations (corticosteroid and/or Emergency Department visit&#xD;
             and/or hospitalization in the previous 12 months);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eligible for the administration of one of the approved biological therapy currently&#xD;
             available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A smoking history &lt;2 pack/year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matteo Bonini</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli, IRCCS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matteo Bonini, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>06030156011</phone>
    <email>matteo.bonini@policlinicogemelli.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cristina Boccabella, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>06030156011</phone>
    <email>cristinaboccabella@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario A. Gemelli</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <zip>00168</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matteo Bonini, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>06030156011</phone>
      <email>matteo.bonini@policlinicogemelli.it</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Cristina Boccabella</last_name>
      <phone>06030156011</phone>
      <email>cristinaboccabella@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francesca Cefaloni, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cristina Boccabella, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 7, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 19, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 19, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>BONINI MATTEO</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

