<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05621785</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Kırıkkale University Faculty</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05621785</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Corticosteroid Use in Premature Babies and Lung Ultrasonografi Use in the Progression to Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Postnatal Corticosteroid Use on Lung Ultrasonography Scores in Preventing the Development of Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia in Premature Infants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kırıkkale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kırıkkale University</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) is one of the most common morbidities in premature infants&#xD;
      and is associated with poor neurodevelopmental outcomes . Although mechanical ventilation and&#xD;
      oxygen requirements in premature infants have been identified as triggering mechanisms for&#xD;
      the development of inflammation and BPD over time, data now support that a number of&#xD;
      perinatal events that may stimulate the inflammatory cascade before birth also have important&#xD;
      effects. Corticosteroids such as dexamethasone and hydrocortisone have proven to be&#xD;
      beneficial for the prevention and management of postpartum BPD due to their anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      properties . With this study, the effects of corticosteroid use on lung ultrasound findings&#xD;
      in BPD will be investigated, and acute and chronic lung ultrasonography scores will be&#xD;
      recorded. A prospective observational study was planned in the neonatal intensive care unit&#xD;
      between 2022 and 2024 in premature infants below 32 weeks of gestational age. Demographic&#xD;
      data and Lung Ultrasonography findings of these babies will be recorded. Among the patients&#xD;
      who are predicted to go to BPD, in the group using corticosteroids, Lung Ultrasonographic&#xD;
      imaging will be performed and the effect of corticosteroids on pulmonary findings will be&#xD;
      recorded. It is planned to investigate whether postnatal steroid use has an effect on lung&#xD;
      ultrasound findings in preterm infants with BPD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      It is aimed to show the changes in lung ultrasound findings before, during and after steroid&#xD;
      use in premature newborn babies born under 32/7 weeks. Thus, detailed new information will be&#xD;
      obtained about the role and importance of corticosteroids in preventing the progression to&#xD;
      BPD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postnatal corticosteroids are not routinely used to prevent BPD in our unit in our hospital.&#xD;
      However, if premature babies meet the following criteria, postnatal low-dose corticosteroids&#xD;
      are administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the postnatal third week;&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Premature infants who are still not weaned from invasive mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Those who continue to need non-invasive positive pressure ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Those who need more than 50% oxygen&#xD;
&#xD;
      Applied steroid protocols:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dexomethasone:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Total cumulative dose 0.89 mg/kg&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  0.075 mg/kg/dose PO/IV (every 12 hours) for 3 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  0.05 mg/kg/dose PO/IV (every 12 hours) 3 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  0.025 mg/kg/dose PO/IV (every 12 hours) 2 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  0.01 mg/kg/dose PO/IV (every 12 hours) 2 days&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hydrocortisone:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  1 mg/kg/dose IV/PO (every 12 hours) 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  0.5 mg/kg/dose IV/PO (every 12 hours) 3 days&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dexsometasone treatment is given in accordance with the DART protocol in infants who cannot&#xD;
      wean from invasive mechanical ventilation in accordance with the protocols in use in our&#xD;
      unit, which corticosteroid will be used. . In clinical follow-up, corticosteroid preference&#xD;
      can be changed by the consultant neonatal specialist according to the general clinical&#xD;
      condition of the patient and the accompanying spectrum. Which corticosteroid will be&#xD;
      preferred in this observational study will not be known by the team that will conduct the&#xD;
      study and will be recorded later.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If more than one corticosteroid use is required in the follow-up, pulmonary ultrasonography&#xD;
      findings during the first corticosteroid use will be recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bronkopulmoner Displazi under the corticosteroid</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Although the use of corticosteroids in the course of BPD has a positive effect on lung ultrasound findings in the acute period in premature newborn babies, long-term beneficial effects cannot be observed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</condition>
  <condition>Premature Birth</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lung Ultrasonografi</intervention_name>
    <description>All babies under 32 weeks of gestation will be included in the study. All data of postnatal corticosteroid users will be recorded using lung USG</description>
    <other_name>corticosteroid</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Gestational age below 32/7 weeks, both sex premature infants&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those who were born in Kırıkkale University Faculty of Medicine Hospital or who were&#xD;
             born in other hospitals and were admitted to Kırıkkale University Faculty of Medicine&#xD;
             Neonatal Intensive Care Unit within the first 48 hours of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Gestational age below 32/7 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Those who will be administered postnatal corticosteroids with the decision of the&#xD;
             consultant by meeting the diagnostic criteria for going to BPD&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Informed consent was obtained from the family&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those with cyanotic congenital heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Those with lung and thorax malformations,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Those with major congenital anomalies&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Newborns who do not meet the criteria for postnatal corticosteroid therapy or who are&#xD;
             not given postnatal corticosteroids by the consultant&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The family's refusal to give informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Day</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sevde Nur Vural, Asistant Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>KIRIKKALE UNİVERSİTY FACULTY OF MEDİCİNE</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kırıkkale University Faculty of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kırıkkale</city>
        <zip>71000</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jobe AH, Bancalari E. Bronchopulmonary dysplasia. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2001 Jun;163(7):1723-9. doi: 10.1164/ajrccm.163.7.2011060. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>11401896</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kırıkkale University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sevde Nur Vural</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Asistant Doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

