<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05613153</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2206102</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05613153</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Peppermint Oil as a Treatment for Children With Bladder and Bowel Dysfunction</brief_title>
  <official_title>Peppermint Oil as an Alternative Treatment for Children With Bladder and Bowel Dysfunction: A Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's Hospital of Orange County</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's Hospital of Orange County</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to study the effect of peppermint oil in in children with&#xD;
      bladder and bowel dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main question it aims to answer is: Does peppermint oil improve symptoms of bladder and&#xD;
      bowel dysfunction among children?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Be provided peppermint oil capsules to be taken 3 times daily for 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At baseline and at a follow-up visit (8 weeks later), participants will be asked to&#xD;
           complete the Vancouver Nonneurogenic Lower Urinary Tract Dysfunction/Dysfunctional&#xD;
           Elimination Syndrome Questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers will compare baseline and follow-up questionnaire data for each participant to&#xD;
      determine if there is improvement in symptoms of bladder and bowel dysfunction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom score</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Vancouver Nonneurogenic Lower Urinary Tract Dysfunction/Dysfunctional Elimination Syndrome Questionnaire Score. This includes 13 items scored using a 5-point Likert scale for each item. A score of 0 denotes no complaints and a score of 4 indicates severe symptoms. Range of scores 0-54, with higher scores indicating a worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Bladder and Bowel Dysfunction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Peppermint Oil</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Peppermint oil will be provided free of charge to participants under the trademark Pepogest produced by the maker Nature's Way® (dosage 0.2 mL, 181 mg peppermint oil).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peppermint Oil</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants weighing more than 40 kg will receive 2 peppermint oil capsules 3 times a day. Smaller children who weigh between 30 kg and 40 kg will receive 1 capsule of peppermint oil 3 times a day. All subjects will receive 8 weeks of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Peppermint Oil</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children aged 8-17 years and weighing 30kg or more with non-neurogenic bladder and&#xD;
             bowel dysfunction who have failed behavioral therapy. Behavioral therapy, or also&#xD;
             termed standard urotherapy, is defined as encompassing the following components [15]:&#xD;
             Information and demystification; instruction on avoidance of holding maneuvers,&#xD;
             regular bowel habits, proper voiding posture; lifestyle advice encompassing balanced&#xD;
             fluid intake and diet, diminished caffeine, regular bladder and bowel emptying&#xD;
             patterns; registration of symptoms and voiding habits with bladder diaries or&#xD;
             frequency-volume charts; support and encouragement via regular follow up with&#xD;
             caregiver. Failure of behavioral therapy is defined as no symptomatology improvement&#xD;
             after adherence to behavioral therapy after 6 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be able to swallow pills&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with neurogenic bladder, tethered cord, Society of Fetal Urology grade 3-4&#xD;
             hydronephrosis, vesicoureteral reflux, learning disabilities, or those who have&#xD;
             undergone surgical therapy for bladder and bowel dysfunction will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on medical therapy with oxybutynin within the last 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hiatal hernia, severe gastrointestinal reflux or gallbladder disorders&#xD;
             or on medications for these conditions will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient weighing less than 30 kg.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Heidi A. Stephany, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Hospital, Orange County</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital, Orange County</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vaz GT, Vasconcelos MM, Oliveira EA, Ferreira AL, Magalhaes PG, Silva FM, Lima EM. Prevalence of lower urinary tract symptoms in school-age children. Pediatr Nephrol. 2012 Apr;27(4):597-603. doi: 10.1007/s00467-011-2028-1. Epub 2011 Oct 4.</citation>
    <PMID>21969094</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Neveus T, von Gontard A, Hoebeke P, Hjalmas K, Bauer S, Bower W, Jorgensen TM, Rittig S, Walle JV, Yeung CK, Djurhuus JC. The standardization of terminology of lower urinary tract function in children and adolescents: report from the Standardisation Committee of the International Children's Continence Society. J Urol. 2006 Jul;176(1):314-24. doi: 10.1016/S0022-5347(06)00305-3.</citation>
    <PMID>16753432</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jiang R, Kelly MS, Routh JC. Assessment of pediatric bowel and bladder dysfunction: a critical appraisal of the literature. J Pediatr Urol. 2018 Dec;14(6):494-501. doi: 10.1016/j.jpurol.2018.08.010. Epub 2018 Aug 28.</citation>
    <PMID>30297226</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Landgraf JM, Abidari J, Cilento BG Jr, Cooper CS, Schulman SL, Ortenberg J. Coping, commitment, and attitude: quantifying the everyday burden of enuresis on children and their families. Pediatrics. 2004 Feb;113(2):334-44. doi: 10.1542/peds.113.2.334.</citation>
    <PMID>14754946</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hagglof B, Andren O, Bergstrom E, Marklund L, Wendelius M. Self-esteem before and after treatment in children with nocturnal enuresis and urinary incontinence. Scand J Urol Nephrol Suppl. 1997;183:79-82.</citation>
    <PMID>9165615</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Varlam DE, Dippell J. Non-neurogenic bladder and chronic renal insufficiency in childhood. Pediatr Nephrol. 1995 Feb;9(1):1-5. doi: 10.1007/BF00858952.</citation>
    <PMID>7742205</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bower WF, Yew SY, Sit KY, Yeung CK. Half-day urotherapy improves voiding parameters in children with dysfunctional emptying. Eur Urol. 2006 Mar;49(3):570-4. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2005.12.001. Epub 2006 Jan 4.</citation>
    <PMID>16420968</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arlen AM. Dysfunctional Voiders-Medication Versus Urotherapy? Curr Urol Rep. 2017 Feb;18(2):14. doi: 10.1007/s11934-017-0656-0.</citation>
    <PMID>28213858</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lazarus J. Intravesical oxybutynin in the pediatric neurogenic bladder. Nat Rev Urol. 2009 Dec;6(12):671-4. doi: 10.1038/nrurol.2009.214. Epub 2009 Nov 10.</citation>
    <PMID>19901914</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Donnellan CA, Fook L, McDonald P, Playfer JR. Oxybutynin and cognitive dysfunction. BMJ. 1997 Nov 22;315(7119):1363-4. doi: 10.1136/bmj.315.7119.1363. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>9402781</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ekhart C, Vries T, Hunsel FV. Psychiatric adverse drug reactions in the paediatric population. Arch Dis Child. 2020 Aug;105(8):749-755. doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2019-317933. Epub 2020 Feb 14.</citation>
    <PMID>32060030</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alammar N, Wang L, Saberi B, Nanavati J, Holtmann G, Shinohara RT, Mullin GE. The impact of peppermint oil on the irritable bowel syndrome: a meta-analysis of the pooled clinical data. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2019 Jan 17;19(1):21. doi: 10.1186/s12906-018-2409-0.</citation>
    <PMID>30654773</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kline RM, Kline JJ, Di Palma J, Barbero GJ. Enteric-coated, pH-dependent peppermint oil capsules for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome in children. J Pediatr. 2001 Jan;138(1):125-8. doi: 10.1067/mpd.2001.109606.</citation>
    <PMID>11148527</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Korterink JJ, Rutten JM, Venmans L, Benninga MA, Tabbers MM. Pharmacologic treatment in pediatric functional abdominal pain disorders: a systematic review. J Pediatr. 2015 Feb;166(2):424-31.e6. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2014.09.067. Epub 2014 Nov 8.</citation>
    <PMID>25449223</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Austin PF, Bauer SB, Bower W, Chase J, Franco I, Hoebeke P, Rittig S, Walle JV, von Gontard A, Wright A, Yang SS, Neveus T. The standardization of terminology of lower urinary tract function in children and adolescents: Update report from the standardization committee of the International Children's Continence Society. Neurourol Urodyn. 2016 Apr;35(4):471-81. doi: 10.1002/nau.22751. Epub 2015 Mar 14.</citation>
    <PMID>25772695</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kligler B, Chaudhary S. Peppermint oil. Am Fam Physician. 2007 Apr 1;75(7):1027-30.</citation>
    <PMID>17427617</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chumpitazi BP, Kearns GL, Shulman RJ. Review article: the physiological effects and safety of peppermint oil and its efficacy in irritable bowel syndrome and other functional disorders. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2018 Mar;47(6):738-752. doi: 10.1111/apt.14519. Epub 2018 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>29372567</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Madisch A, Heydenreich CJ, Wieland V, Hufnagel R, Hotz J. Treatment of functional dyspepsia with a fixed peppermint oil and caraway oil combination preparation as compared to cisapride. A multicenter, reference-controlled double-blind equivalence study. Arzneimittelforschung. 1999 Nov;49(11):925-32. doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1300528.</citation>
    <PMID>10604046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Madisch A, Holtmann G, Mayr G, Vinson B, Hotz J. Treatment of functional dyspepsia with a herbal preparation. A double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, multicenter trial. Digestion. 2004;69(1):45-52. doi: 10.1159/000076546. Epub 2004 Jan 30.</citation>
    <PMID>14755152</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>May B, Kohler S, Schneider B. Efficacy and tolerability of a fixed combination of peppermint oil and caraway oil in patients suffering from functional dyspepsia. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2000 Dec;14(12):1671-7. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2036.2000.00873.x.</citation>
    <PMID>11121917</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nash P, Gould SR, Bernardo DE. Peppermint oil does not relieve the pain of irritable bowel syndrome. Br J Clin Pract. 1986 Jul;40(7):292-3. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>3527248</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Afshar K, Mirbagheri A, Scott H, MacNeily AE. Development of a symptom score for dysfunctional elimination syndrome. J Urol. 2009 Oct;182(4 Suppl):1939-43. doi: 10.1016/j.juro.2009.03.009. Epub 2009 Aug 20.</citation>
    <PMID>19695637</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jafarov R, Ceyhan E, Kahraman O, Ceylan T, Dikmen ZG, Tekgul S, Dogan HS. Efficacy of transcutaneous posterior tibial nerve stimulation in children with functional voiding disorders. Neurourol Urodyn. 2021 Jan;40(1):404-411. doi: 10.1002/nau.24575. Epub 2020 Nov 18.</citation>
    <PMID>33205852</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 17, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peppermint oil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

