<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05791578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RTEuniversity</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05791578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Relationship Obsessive Beliefs and Thought Control</brief_title>
  <official_title>Corresponding Author</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Recep Tayyip Erdogan University Training and Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Recep Tayyip Erdogan University Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Obsessive beliefs and thought control have been mostly investigated in obsessive-compulsive&#xD;
      disorder in the literature. However, there is an increasing body of literature indicating&#xD;
      that obsessive beliefs and thought control also play a role in the development of other&#xD;
      anxiety disorders. In the study, investigators hypothesised that obsessive beliefs and&#xD;
      thought control are effective in generalised anxiety disorder and panic disorder and increase&#xD;
      anxiety symptoms and aimed to investigate the accuracy of this hypothesis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Obsessive beliefs are considered as a compulsive thought system in the cognitive model of&#xD;
      obsessive-compulsive disorder. Obsessive beliefs are analysed under six main headings. These&#xD;
      are control of thoughts, intolerance of uncertainty, exaggerated perception of&#xD;
      responsibility, overemphasis of thoughts, exaggerated perception of threat and perfectionism.&#xD;
      Although it is thought to play a role in the development of obsessions, it can sometimes be&#xD;
      seen independent of obsessions . This dysfunctional distorted thought system sometimes turns&#xD;
      into unnecessary threat perception and may pave the way for mental illnesses in the&#xD;
      individual. When these distorted cognitive thoughts come to the mind, the person has an&#xD;
      excessive mental effort to control the thoughts. As much as the thoughts cause distress, the&#xD;
      endeavour to control the thoughts may cause mental distress in the person. Although all of&#xD;
      these dysfunctional thoughts are associated with an obsession, the effect of thought control&#xD;
      and obsessive beliefs on other mental illnesses has recently been investigated. In&#xD;
      particular, perfectionism and increased threat perception have been associated with anxiety&#xD;
      disorders as well as obsessions . Obsessive beliefs have often been associated with&#xD;
      obsessive-compulsive disorder. However, there are similarities in the cognitive schemas of&#xD;
      obsessive-compulsive disorder and anxiety disorders. Anxiety disorders are characterised by a&#xD;
      vague state of anxiety and accompanying physical symptoms. Patients with anxiety disorders&#xD;
      may be hypersensitive to some feelings and thoughts. Anxiety attacks may be triggered by&#xD;
      exaggerated threat perception in obsessive beliefs. In addition, intolerance of uncertainty&#xD;
      is also associated with anxiety disorders. Cognitive distortions have a role in the&#xD;
      development of both obsessive-compulsive disorder and anxiety disorders . Obsessive beliefs&#xD;
      and thought control have been mostly associated with obsessive-compulsive disorder in the&#xD;
      literature. However, it has recently been thought that these dysfunctional compulsive&#xD;
      thoughts and the distress experienced to control these thoughts are the cognitive basis of&#xD;
      all anxiety disorders. Information on this subject is limited in the literature. Our study&#xD;
      aims to contribute to the literature on this subject.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 20, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The study will include healthy controls, patients with panic disorder and patients with anxiety disorder. 3 groups will be formed and obsessive beliefs scale and thought control scale will be applied to the groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Obsessive beliefs and will be applied in patients with panic disorder and anxiety disorder. scale results will be evaluated statistically. the hypothesis of the study is that obsessive beliefs scale scores will be higher in the patient group. The mentioned scales are the scales used for diagnosis in psychiatry. the answers have a score and a numerical value is obtained by adding the scores. the lowest score that can be obtained from the obsessive beliefs scale is 44 and the highest score is 208. higher scores on the scale are negative and mean more obsessive beliefs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The study will include healthy controls, patients with panic disorder and patients with anxiety disorder. 3 groups will be formed and obsessive beliefs scale and thought control scale will be applied to the groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>thought control scale will be applied in patients with panic disorder and anxiety disorder. scale results will be evaluated statistically. the hypothesis of the study is that thought control scale scores will be higher in the patient group. The mentioned scales are the scales used for diagnosis in psychiatry. the answers have a score and a numerical value is obtained by adding the scores.. the lowest score that can be obtained from the thought control scale is 30 and the highest is 120. increasing scores were evaluated negatively. it is associated with more difficult thought control.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Obsessive Thoughts</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        with panic disorder patient and generalized anxiety disorder patient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with panic disorder patient and generalized anxiety disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no other psychiatric illness such as alzheimer, mental retardation, parkinson disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  had academic capacity for filling the scales&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no taking any drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  being age 18-65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  giving consent to be involved in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>RTE University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rize</city>
        <zip>53200</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 30, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 28, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 28, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 28, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Recep Tayyip Erdogan University Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Meltem puşuroğlu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant professor doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>panic disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>generalized anxiety disorder</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

