<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05790395</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NTEC-2023-081</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05790395</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prevention of NCDs Through Screening and Educating Individuals on Health-risk Behaviours in the Community</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prevention of Non-communicable Diseases Through Screening and Educating Individuals on Health-risk Behaviours in the Community</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chinese University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim: to prevent NCDs by screening and educating individuals in the community on health-risk&#xD;
      behaviours. Specifically, we will use a mobile health and a brief self-determination&#xD;
      theory-based intervention in helping individual change their health-risk behaviours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses to be tested: compared with those in the control group, the participants in the&#xD;
      intervention group will experience significantly greater success in modifying their&#xD;
      health-risk behaviours and will have a better health-related quality of life at 12 months&#xD;
      follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To screen individuals for health-risk behaviours and identify risk factors that may&#xD;
           contribute to NCDs&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To educate individuals on the importance of engaging in healthy lifestyles&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To develop a training programme - &quot;Train the Trainers' Toolkit&quot;, with the goal to train&#xD;
           student nurses (Years 2 to 5) as health ambassadors to implement the project on a&#xD;
           long-term basis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Setting:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The project will be carried out in Kwai Chung Estate, one of the largest public housing&#xD;
      estates with many low-income families in Hong Kong.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The project consists of four phases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase I:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To invite 30 university nursing students (Year 2 to 5) to become health ambassadors for the&#xD;
      prevention of NCDs in the community.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase II:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To develop a training curriculum and conduct a one-day workshop for university nursing&#xD;
      students to equip them with knowledge and skills to perform screening for individuals'&#xD;
      health-risk behaviours and educating them to adopt healthy lifestyles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase III:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To recruit 300 individuals (150 each in intervention and control groups) in Kwai Chung Estate&#xD;
      with the aims of screening and educating health-risk behaviours and identifying risk factors&#xD;
      that may contribute to NCDs. Activities will include putting up posters and organizing a&#xD;
      health carnival with health education talks and health checks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Asbury Methodist Social Service will help:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Promotion activities (promotional posters detailing the nature and purpose of the health&#xD;
           promotion project will be posted on notice boards at The Asbury Methodist Social Service&#xD;
           Centres to identify potential participants)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Provide venues for health talks and health checks for subject recruitment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Co-organize a health carnival for subject recruitment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase IV:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To implement a mobile health brief intervention based on self-determination theory in helping&#xD;
      individual change their health-risk behaviours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will first assess for risky behaviours using a behavioural risk factor survey.&#xD;
      In addition, their blood pressure, body weight, height, body mass index (BMI), and&#xD;
      health-related quality of life will be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Intervention group Participants will then receive a brief intervention by trained health&#xD;
           ambassadors using the Ask, Warn, Advise, Refer and Do-it-again (AWARD) model at the time&#xD;
           of recruitment. The brief intervention includes the following steps: (1) ask about and&#xD;
           assess health-risk behaviours; (2) warn about the high morbidity and mortality risks&#xD;
           associated with health-risk behaviours; (3) advise to adopt healthy lifestyle practices&#xD;
           to benefit the health; (4) refer to hotline services on request, such as smoking&#xD;
           cessation, alcohol treatment services and district health centres; and (5) do it again&#xD;
           if they report failure to change a health-risk behaviour at follow-up. The health&#xD;
           ambassadors will ask about the priority the participants place on engagement in&#xD;
           desirable health-related lifestyle practices identified in the completed behavioural&#xD;
           risk factor survey. The participants will also be asked to choose the goal that they&#xD;
           consider easiest to achieve, such as quitting or reducing smoking, consuming more&#xD;
           vegetables or less fatty foods or sugary drinks, performing more exercise or reducing&#xD;
           alcohol consumption. The participants will be encouraged to quit health-risk behaviours&#xD;
           (or adopt a healthy lifestyle) sequentially, but they will also be able to choose to&#xD;
           quit them simultaneously if they are confident in doing so. Each participant will then&#xD;
           receive a brief (approximately 10 minutes), individual intervention with health advice&#xD;
           about the selected health-related lifestyle practice. The participants will also be&#xD;
           given a Practical Resource Hub for Healthy Life leaflet containing information on&#xD;
           various applications, including (i) 'Move Your Body', (ii) 'Eat Healthy', (iii) 'Live&#xD;
           Alcohol Free', and (iv) 'Stay Away from Tobacco', which were developed by the Hong Kong&#xD;
           Department of Health.&#xD;
&#xD;
           For the first 6 months of the project period, the health ambassadors will deliver&#xD;
           WhatsApp/WeChat messages about once per week as a reminder for the participants to&#xD;
           adhere to their desirable health-related lifestyle practice. If a participant does not&#xD;
           own a smartphone or is unable to receive WhatsApp/WeChat messages (uncommon in Hong&#xD;
           Kong), the health ambassadors will make a telephone call, instead of sending a message.&#xD;
           Participants will be assessed to determine their success in changing their targeted&#xD;
           health-related lifestyle practice at 3, 6, and 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Control group The control group participants will also be given a Practical Resource Hub&#xD;
           for Healthy Life leaflet containing information on various applications. However, the&#xD;
           health ambassadors will simply advise the participants to modify their health-risk&#xD;
           behaviours and/or adopt a healthy lifestyle practice. The participants will also receive&#xD;
           follow-up for outcome assessments with the same schedule as those in the intervention&#xD;
           group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject recruitment The investigators will obtain ethical approval from the Joint CUHK-NTEC&#xD;
      CREC. Potential participants will be assessed for eligibility, and the purpose, design,&#xD;
      procedures, and potential benefits and risks of the study will be explained to them. Informed&#xD;
      written consent will then be sought. All subjects will be assured that their participation&#xD;
      will be voluntary, with no prejudice attached to refusal, and that the information they&#xD;
      provide will be kept confidential. The researcher is responsible for its safekeeping and the&#xD;
      only one who would have access to the raw data or study record during or after the study.&#xD;
      After the period of storage, all raw data and records will be destroyed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed study will adhere to the Declaration of Helsinki - Ethical Principles for&#xD;
      Medical Research Involving Human Subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization and allocation concealment Stratified block randomisation with 1:1 allocation&#xD;
      will be conducted using varying block sizes of 2-4 to achieve an appropriate balance of&#xD;
      participant numbers between the two groups and to optimise allocation concealment.&#xD;
      Randomization will be performed by the research assistant, who will unseal a serially&#xD;
      labelled, opaque envelope containing a card to indicate the group allocation. To ensure&#xD;
      allocation concealment, the random numbers used for allocation will be computer-generated by&#xD;
      a co-investigator before subject recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data processing and analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Instruments:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A behavioural risk-factor survey will be used to collect the eligible participants'&#xD;
      demographic and clinical data and information about their health-risk behaviours at baseline&#xD;
      and at 3, 6, and 12 months. This questionnaire is adapted from a questionnaire used by the&#xD;
      Hong Kong Department of Health and was used to investigate multiple health-risk behaviours&#xD;
      among Chinese adults in Hong Kong in 2021.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The EuroQoL 5-Dimension 5-level (EQ-5D-5L) will be used to measure subjects' health-related&#xD;
      quality of life at baseline, 6 months, and 12 months. The psychometric properties of the&#xD;
      Chinese version of the EQ-5D-5L have been tested, and the findings indicate that this tool is&#xD;
      a valid, reliable, and sensitive measure of health-related quality of life. A&#xD;
      Chinese-specific EQ-5D-5L value set will enable the estimation of health utility scores&#xD;
      applicable to the Chinese population and quality-adjusted life-years (QALY) for&#xD;
      cost-effectiveness analysis (CEA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SPSS for Windows (SPSS version 26.0; IBM Corp., Armonk, NY, USA) will be used for the&#xD;
      quantitative data analysis. Descriptive statistics will be used to calculate the mean,&#xD;
      standard deviation, and frequency of the demographic and health-risk behaviour data. The&#xD;
      analysis including the main effect, i.e., behavioural changes at 12 months in the&#xD;
      intervention group versus those in the control group, will be performed using a chi-square&#xD;
      test or Fisher's exact test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Abstain from health-risk behaviour</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>About 10% of participants will successfully abstain from at least one health-risk behaviour at 12-month follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in health-risk behaviours</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in health-risk behaviours (≥ 50% reduction from baseline) at 12-month follow-up</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in health-related quality of life at 12-month follow-up compare to baseline using questionnaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ambassadors' knowledge and skill on providing professional health advice and support to participants about changing their health-risk behaviours</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement of ambassadors' knowledge and skill on providing professional health advice and support to participants about changing their health-risk behaviours by comparing pre-, post-training and 6-month evaluation questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in blood pressure at 12-month follow-up compare to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvements in body mass index at 12-month follow-up compare to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">330</enrollment>
  <condition>Health-risk Behaviours</condition>
  <condition>Non Communicable Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants will also be given a Practical Resource Hub for Healthy Life leaflet containing information on various applications. The participants will receive a brief telephone intervention using the Ask, Warn, Advise, Refer and Do-it-again (AWARD) model. For the advice step, the research assistant will ask about the priority the participants place on engagement in desirable health-related lifestyle practices identified in the completed behavioural risk factor survey. The participants will also be asked to choose the goal that they consider easiest to achieve, such as quitting or reducing smoking, consuming more vegetables or less fatty foods or sugary drinks, performing more exercise or reducing alcohol consumption. The participants will be encouraged to quit health-risk behaviours (or adopt a healthy lifestyle) sequentially, but they will also be able to choose to quit them simultaneously if they are confident in doing so.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group participants will also be given a Practical Resource Hub for Healthy Life leaflet containing information on various applications. However, the health ambassadors will simply advise the participants to modify their health-risk behaviours and/or adopt a healthy lifestyle practice. The participants will also receive follow-up for outcome assessments with the same schedule as those in the intervention group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Theory of planned behaviour, foot-in-the-door technique, and self-determination theory intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The participants will also be asked to choose the goal that they consider easiest to achieve and encouraged to quit health-risk behaviours. The research assistant will assist in achieving the participant's health-related goals by sending WhatsApp/WeChat messages or via telephone calls once per week for the first 6 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>health-risk behaviors</intervention_name>
    <description>The participants will be simply advised to modify their health-risk behaviours and/or adopt a healthy lifestyle practice. The participants will also receive follow-up for outcome assessments with the same schedule as those in the intervention group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Chinese adults in Kwai Chung Estate:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. the presence of at least one health risk behaviour (tobacco use, harmful use of&#xD;
             alcohol, unhealthy diet and physical inactivity)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. able to communicate in Cantonese&#xD;
&#xD;
        Nursing students:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Year 2 to 5&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. poor cognitive state or mental illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. participation in another related study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Li Ho Cheung William</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Health-risk Behaviours</keyword>
  <keyword>Non Communicable Diseases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Noncommunicable Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The relevant anonymized patient level data, full dataset, technical appendix, and statistical code are available on reasonable request. The approval from the Principal Investigator for the purpose of data use is required.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After the project has been completed and the results of the project has been published</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Request could be sent to Principal Investigator (williamli@cuhk.edu.hk)</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

