<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612009</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S1s7s9s3</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612009</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of Different Imaging Systems for Dental Plaque Scoring</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of Different Imaging Systems for Dental Plaque Scoring: an In-vivo Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Marmara University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Marmara University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study was to analyze the correlation between the dental plaque indices&#xD;
      measured different imaging systems and conventional clinical indices that assess dental&#xD;
      plaque. From among the patients who visited Marmara University, Faculty of Dentistry 30&#xD;
      adults between the age of 18-30, who had under 3 DMFT scores, were selected for full-mouth&#xD;
      imaging. Digital dental photography, digital scanning system and fluorecam methods were used&#xD;
      for taking intraoral images. The Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index (TMQHPI) was&#xD;
      scored both by the clinical examination method and on the images taken. The correlations&#xD;
      between the clinical examinaton, digital photography, digital scanning system and fluorecam&#xD;
      scores were analyzed. Maxillary and mandibulary anterior teeth's buccal surfaces were scored&#xD;
      to TMQHPI after using disclosing agent.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study was performed with 30 adult patients aged between 18-35, recruited from among the&#xD;
      outpatients who visited the Marmara University, Faculty of Dentistry, Restorative Dentistry&#xD;
      Department, agreed to the terms of the experiment, had a DMFT score 3 or lower, and had&#xD;
      relatively even teeth arrangement. Among patients, those with orthodontic bracket placed,&#xD;
      severe crowding of teeth not visually verified in the photograph, fixed or implant&#xD;
      restoration installed, more than 3 DMFT score, and serious systemic diseases were excluded&#xD;
      from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to standardize the study, the volunteers were informed that they shouldn't eat any&#xD;
      nutrients and do oral hygiene practices after dinner. Visualization of plaque samples formed&#xD;
      in the mouth at least 8-12 hours between 08:30 and 10:00 a.m. in the morning and collecting&#xD;
      dental plaque samples for microbiological examination were performed after the volunteers&#xD;
      signed the informed consent form. The Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index (TMQHPI) was&#xD;
      scored both by the clinical examination method and on the images taken. The correlations&#xD;
      between the manuel examinaton, digital photography, digital scanning system and fluorecam&#xD;
      scores were analyzed. Maxillary and mandibulary anterior teeth's buccal surfaces were scored&#xD;
      to TMQHPI after using disclosing agent. Using the standard toothbrush provided to the&#xD;
      volunteers, they were asked to brush their teeth twice a day for 21 days with the recommended&#xD;
      brushing method. After 21 days, dental plaque scoring and imaging procedure was repeated and&#xD;
      dental plaque samples were collected again and placed in Eppendorf tubes. Eppendorf tubes&#xD;
      were kept at -80 °C during the study. Bacterial changes in the samples taken on Day 0 and Day&#xD;
      21 were examined by Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) method in Marmara University Faculty of&#xD;
      Medicine, Department of Clinical Microbiology. The levels in plaque samples of Streptococcus&#xD;
      mutans, Lactobacillus acidophilus, Actinomyces viscosus, , Candida albicans, Staphylococcus&#xD;
      aerus, were measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 17, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 27, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1. Dental plaque scoring clinically before staining agent</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Dental plaque of the volunteer's anterior teeth were scored to Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>2. Dental plaque scoring clinically after applying staining agent</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Dental plaque of the volunteer's anterior teeth were scored to Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>3.Dental plaque scoring after applying staining agent on the taken images with FluoreCam</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Dental plaque of the volunteer's anterior teeth were scored on the images taken with FluoreCam to Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>4. Dental plaque scoring after applying staining agent on the taken images with Digital Camera</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Dental plaque of the volunteer's anterior teeth were scored on the images taken with FluoreCam to Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>5. Dental plaque scoring after applying staining agent on the taken images with Intraoral Scanner</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>Dental plaque of the volunteer's anterior teeth were scored on the images taken with Intraoral Scanner to Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Plaque Imaging Methods</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1. Signal Expert Protection</arm_group_label>
    <description>After scoring clinically and with dental plaque imaging methods, Signal Expert Protection toothpaste was given to 10 volunteers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2. Colgate Hemp Seed Oil</arm_group_label>
    <description>After scoring clinically and with dental plaque imaging methods, Colgate Hemp Seed Oil toothpaste was given to 10 volunteers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3. Gumgumix</arm_group_label>
    <description>After scoring clinically and with dental plaque imaging methods, Gumgumix toothpaste was given to 10 volunteers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toothpastes</intervention_name>
    <description>Signal Expert Protection: Conventional toothpaste including Sodium Lauryl Sulphate and fluoride.&#xD;
Colgate Hemp Seed Oil: Herbal toothpaste including hemp seed oil and also fluoride.&#xD;
Gumgumix: Herbal toothpaste including ginger extract (no fluoride).</description>
    <arm_group_label>1. Signal Expert Protection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>2. Colgate Hemp Seed Oil</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>3. Gumgumix</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Signal Expert Protection, Colgate Hemp Seed Oil, Gumgumix</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      dental plaque samples of volunteers&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study was performed with 30 adult male and female patients aged between 18-35,&#xD;
        recruited from among the outpatients who visited the Marmara University, Faculty of&#xD;
        Dentistry, Restorative Dentistry Department, agreed to the terms of the experiment, had a&#xD;
        DMFT score 3 or lower, and had relatively even teeth arrangement. Among patients, those&#xD;
        with orthodontic bracket placed, severe crowding of teeth not visually verified in the&#xD;
        photograph, fixed or implant restoration installed, more than 3 DMFT score, and serious&#xD;
        systemic diseases were excluded from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The volunteers between the ages of 18-35, No systemic disease, Teeth that do not contain&#xD;
        hereditary, morphological, drug-induced structural changes, Not using orthodontic wires and&#xD;
        appliances, Having a DMFT score of 3 and less than 3, Have not received antibiotic&#xD;
        treatment in the last 6 weeks, Not using mouthwash in the last 6 weeks, Without dental&#xD;
        calculus, Oral hygiene habits are similar to each other, University student or graduate,&#xD;
        Thirty volunteers who were conscious of being able to understand and apply the guidelines&#xD;
        set forth in the study were included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Among volunteers, those with orthodontic bracket placed, severe crowding of teeth not&#xD;
        visually verified in the photograph, fixed or implant restoration installed, more than 3&#xD;
        DMFT score, and serious systemic diseases were excluded from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Marmara University Department of Restorative Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>dental plaque</keyword>
  <keyword>dental photography</keyword>
  <keyword>digital scanning system</keyword>
  <keyword>fluorecam</keyword>
  <keyword>Turesky Modified Quigley Hein Plaque Index</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Plaque</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be shared after the publication of the article.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>data will be available in 2 years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>all researchers may access the data of this study</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

