<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05626881</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Soh-Med-22-04-08</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05626881</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Intralesional PRP +/- Topical Silymarin in the Treatment of Melasma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Efficacy and Tolerability of Autologous Intralesional Platelet-rich Plasma, Topical Silymarin, and Combined Autologous Intralesional Platelet-rich Plasma With Topical Silymarin in the Treatment of Melasma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sohag University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sohag University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Melasma is an acquired disorder of melanogenesis leading to hyperpigmentation and manifested&#xD;
      by symmetrical brown to gray-black macules and patches with serrated irregular edges . It&#xD;
      occurs especially in sun-exposed areas and affects young to middle-aged women. It is most&#xD;
      commonly seen on the face and less commonly on the neck, arms, and chest . Platelet rich&#xD;
      plasma (PRP) is defined as a small volume of autologous plasma that contains a high&#xD;
      concentration of platelets obtained by centrifugation of autologous blood and subsequent&#xD;
      suspension of platelets&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in mMASI SCORE</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>The mMASI score is calculated by subjective assessment of 3 factors: area (A) of involvement, darkness (D), and homogeneity (H), with the forehead (f), right malar region (rm), left malar region (lm), and chin (c), corresponding to 30%, 30%, 30%, and 10% of the total face, respectively. The area of involvement in each of these 4 areas is given a numeric value of 0 to 6 (0 = no involvement; 1 = \10%; 2 = 10%-29%; 3 = 30%-49%; 4 = 50%-69%; 5 = 70%-89%; and 6 = 90%- 100%). Darkness and homogeneity are rated on a scale from 0 to 4 (0 = absent; 1 = slight; 2 = mild; 3 = marked; and 4 = maximum). The MASI score is calculated by adding the sum of the severity ratings for darkness and homogeneity, multiplied by the value of the area of involvement, for each of the 4 facial areas.&#xD;
The total score range is 0 to 48.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Melasma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PRP group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>It will include patients with melasma treated with PRP sessions every two weeks for three monthsPRP is injected intralesionally at the site of melasma using a 30 G hypodermic needle through an insulin syringe. A maximum of 2.0 ml of PRP will be injected into the dermis (about 1.5-2.0 mm deep) about 1 cm apart to raise dermal papules</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Silymarin group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>It will include patients with melasma applying with topical Silymarin cream. Silymarin cream will be prepared in the Faculty of Pharmcy according to the following formulation: stearic acid 15 g, glycerin 5 g, KOH 0.72 g, H2O 79 g, sodium benzoate (0.1%), and Tween-80 (1%). Silymarin was manufactured with concentration of 1.4%. Silymarin will be applied twice daily. The duration of treatment will be 3 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PRP + silymarin group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>It will be treated by using both PRP sessions and applying topical Silymarin cream. Silymarin will be applied twice daily, while PRP sessions every 2 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PRP</intervention_name>
    <description>It will include patients with melasma treated with PRP sessions every two weeks for three months. 10 ml of venous blood will withdraw by means of a wide bore needle and a vacutainer containing an anticoagulant (Acid citrate dextrose).&#xD;
Double centrifugation will be done. First centrifugation, will be done for 10 minutes. After the first centrifugation, three layers will be seen , Second centrifugation will be done for 10 min, after which the platelets separate and form a grayish pellet at the bottom of the tube and the rest will be platelet-poor plasma. About 1 ml of this platelet-poor plasma will be decanted off and the platelet pellet will be resuspended in the remaining plasma to get PRP. With 10 ml blood, about 1-1.5 ml of PRP will be obtained.&#xD;
PRP is injected intralesionally at the site of melasma using a 30 G hypodermic needle through an insulin syringe.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PRP + silymarin group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PRP group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sylimarin cream</intervention_name>
    <description>Silymarin was manufactured with concentration of 1.4%</description>
    <arm_group_label>PRP + silymarin group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Silymarin group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females in the reproductive age (18 years old and above) presented with melasma&#xD;
             confirmed by wood's light.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic diseases that may cause facial hyperpigmentation (e.g: thyroid diseases,&#xD;
             renal, hepatic or endocrinal disorders).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving depigmenting drugs oral or topical in previous 3 months, drugs that&#xD;
             prolong bleeding as aspirin, hormone replacement therapy or contraceptive pills.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with anemia, thrombocytopenia, coagulopathies or patient on anticoagulant&#xD;
             therapy and patients with iron deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with infections in the face e.g. herpes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of scarring or keloid formation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Walaa k shaker, resident doctor</last_name>
    <phone>01064123800</phone>
    <email>dr_lolo1234@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>. Mohammed A ali, assistant professor</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sohag University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sohag</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Magdy M Amin, professor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sarkar R, Arora P, Garg VK, Sonthalia S, Gokhale N. Melasma update. Indian Dermatol Online J. 2014 Oct;5(4):426-35. doi: 10.4103/2229-5178.142484.</citation>
    <PMID>25396123</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cestari TF, Dantas LP, Boza JC. Acquired hyperpigmentations. An Bras Dermatol. 2014 Jan-Feb;89(1):11-25. doi: 10.1590/abd1806-4841.20142353.</citation>
    <PMID>24626644</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Achar A, Rathi SK. Melasma: a clinico-epidemiological study of 312 cases. Indian J Dermatol. 2011 Jul;56(4):380-2. doi: 10.4103/0019-5154.84722.</citation>
    <PMID>21965843</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sirithanabadeekul P, Dannarongchai A, Suwanchinda A. Platelet-rich plasma treatment for melasma: A pilot study. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2020 Jun;19(6):1321-1327. doi: 10.1111/jocd.13157. Epub 2019 Sep 30.</citation>
    <PMID>31568636</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 17, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sohag University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Walaa Kamal Shaker</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident physician at Dermatology department, Sohag University</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

