<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05625243</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14422018454217</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05625243</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Proximal Contact Quality in Posterior Complex Carious Cavities Restored With Bulk Fill Ormocer and Resin Composite Using a Precontoured Circumferential Matrix System Versus Pre Contoured Sectional Matrix System</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Proximal Contact Quality in Posterior Complex Carious Cavities Restored With Bulk Fill Ormocer and Resin Composite Using a Precontoured Circumferential Matrix System Versus Precontoured Sectional Matrix System</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The use of ormocers with precontoured circumferential matrix system allow predictable&#xD;
      restoration of complex proximal posterior cavities with less time and fewer tools required to&#xD;
      produce optimum proximal contact size, location and magnitude and restoration durability with&#xD;
      higher wear resistance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After profound local anesthesia, conservative cavity preparations will be performed with&#xD;
      high-speed burs (no.:330, Meisinger, Germany) under constant refrigeration. Intermittent&#xD;
      rotary instrument contact with tooth limited to the removal of compromised enamel. The cavity&#xD;
      outline is restricted to the removal of carious tissue with spherical carbide burs at low&#xD;
      speed. In the removal of defective restorations, the friable enamel and remnant carious&#xD;
      tissue will be removed in the same way. All teeth will be restored using a rubber dam. The&#xD;
      universal bonding agent (Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) will be applied with previous selective&#xD;
      enamel etching with 37% phosphoric acid for 30 seconds. These materials will be inserted&#xD;
      following the manufacturer's instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After cavity preparation, each participant will choose a random number from an opaque sealed&#xD;
      envelope, then patient will select from random numbers prepared by Y.H. to randomly assign&#xD;
      interventions to the participant oral cavity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All restorations will be prepared, restored, finished and polished by one operator.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 26, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 6, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proximal Contact quality</measure>
    <time_frame>one year follow up</time_frame>
    <description>50 micro sectional matrix band (Saddle matrix, TORVM, Moscow, Russia)&#xD;
FDI criteria (Hickel et al., 2010)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Posterior Complex Carious Proximal Cavities</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured circumferential matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A suitable size precontoured circumferential matrix band will be selected and placed. Teeth separation will be acquired with a suitable size wedge and a separation ring . Then the bulk-fill ormocer will be applied and light cured according to the manufacturer instructions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured Saddle matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Teeth separation will be acquired with a suitable size wedge (fixing wooden wedges and a separation ring Then the bulk-fill ormocer will be applied and light cured according to the manufacturer instructions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>X-tra fill, Voco) with Precontoured circumferential matrix (Palodent 360, Dentsply )</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>.Bulk-fill resin composite (X-tra fill, Voco) with Precontoured circumferential matrix system (Palodent 360) will be applied</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill resin composite with Precontoured sectional matrix systym</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Teeth separation will be acquired with a wooden wedge and a separation ring (Delta ring, TORVM, Moscow, Russia). Then the bulk fill resin composite will be applied and light cured according to the manufacturer instructions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bulk-fill ormocer (Admira fusion x-tra, Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) with Precontoured circumferential matrix system (Palodent 360, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA)</intervention_name>
    <description>A suitable size precontoured circumferential matrix band (Palodent 360, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA) will be selected and placed. Teeth separation will be acquired with a suitable size wedge (Palodent V3, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA) and a separation ring (Palodent V3 universal ring, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA). Then the bulk-fill ormocer (Admira fusion x-tra, Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) will be applied and light cured according to the manufacturer instructions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured Saddle matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured circumferential matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill resin composite with Precontoured sectional matrix systym</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>X-tra fill, Voco) with Precontoured circumferential matrix (Palodent 360, Dentsply )</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bulk-fill ormocer (Admira fusion x-tra, Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) with Precontoured sectional matrix systym (Saddle matrix, TORVM, Moscow, Russia)</intervention_name>
    <description>A suitable size precontoured sectional matrix band (Saddle matrix, TORVM, Moscow, Russia) will be selected and placed. Teeth separation will be acquired with a suitable size wedge (fixing wooden wedges, TORVM, Moscow, Russia) and a separation ring (Delta ring, TORVM, Moscow, Russia). Then the bulk-fill ormocer (Admira fusion x-tra, Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) will be applied and light cured according to the manufacturer instructions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured Saddle matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured circumferential matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill resin composite with Precontoured sectional matrix systym</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>X-tra fill, Voco) with Precontoured circumferential matrix (Palodent 360, Dentsply )</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bulk-fill resin composite (X-tra fill, Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) with Precontoured circumferential matrix system (Palodent 360, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA)</intervention_name>
    <description>A suitable size precontoured circumferential matrix band (Palodent 360, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA) will be selected and placed. Teeth separation will be acquired with a suitable size wedge (Palodent V3, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA) and a separation ring (Palodent V3 universal ring, Dentsply Caulk, Millford DE, USA). Then the bulk fill resin composite (X-tra fill, Voco, Cuxhaven, Germany) will be applied and light cured according to the manufacturer instructions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured Saddle matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill ormocer with Precontoured circumferential matrix system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Bulk-fill resin composite with Precontoured sectional matrix systym</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>X-tra fill, Voco) with Precontoured circumferential matrix (Palodent 360, Dentsply )</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Posterior complex proximal carious lesions Vital upper or lower posterior teeth with no&#xD;
        signs of irreversible pulpitis. Presence of adjacent and opposing teeth with normal&#xD;
        occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proximal carious cavities in the mesial surface of first premolars. Periapical&#xD;
             pathology or signs of pulpal pathology. Possible prosthodontic restoration of teeth.&#xD;
             Heavy occlusion and occlusal contacts or history of bruxism. Pulpitis, non-vital or&#xD;
             endodontically treated teeth. Sever periodontal affection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmed Alghaffar khafagi, master</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cairo University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ahmed Alghaffar khafagi, master</last_name>
    <phone>01016997764</phone>
    <email>ahmed.khafagi@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>fatheya el shinawy, master</last_name>
    <phone>01007830829</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of Dentistry, Cairo University,</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Faculty of Dentistry, Cairo University,</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 21, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 21, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 21, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed Abd Alghaffar Khafagi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Evaluation of the proximal contact quality in posterior complex carious cavities restored with bulk fill ormocer and resin composite using a precontoured circumferential matrix system versus precontoured sectional matrix system</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Polymethyl Methacrylate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

