<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798377</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SH SugarStudy23</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>5P20GM121341-04</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798377</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maternal Stress and Blood Sugar Metabolization</brief_title>
  <official_title>Maternal Stress and Blood Sugar Metabolization During Pregnancy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanford Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIGMS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanford Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      During pregnancy, gestational diabetes increases the risk of complications and adverse&#xD;
      outcomes for mother and child, however about 50% of gestational diabetes cases are diagnosed&#xD;
      without a known risk factor present. This project uses both a large sample retrospective&#xD;
      study, and a prospective study to help us understand the mechanisms by which mental health&#xD;
      and stress impact glucose metabolization during pregnancy and delineate their contribution to&#xD;
      gestational diabetes and racial disparities. The investigators expect, to improve the ability&#xD;
      to identify women at risk, and advance options for preventative care and treatment,&#xD;
      decreasing the impact of gestational diabetes and related complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) impacts an estimated 3% to 9% of pregnancies, increasing&#xD;
      the risk of serious health complications for mother and child. The identified risk factors&#xD;
      for developing GDM include both individual characteristics (e.g., higher body mass index,&#xD;
      advanced maternal age) and heritable factors (e.g., family history of Type 2 diabetes,&#xD;
      historically marginalized racial/ethnic identity). However, approximately 50% of GDM&#xD;
      diagnoses occur in the absence of any known risk factor(s). Additional research on&#xD;
      biopsychosocial factors related to glucose metabolism, such as mental health and stress&#xD;
      processes, may help to identify individuals at risk. In this project, the investigators seek&#xD;
      to understand the mechanisms by which mental health and stress impact glucose metabolization&#xD;
      during pregnancy and delineate their contribution to GDM racial disparities. The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that there will be associations between maternal mental health,&#xD;
      glucose metabolization, and GDM related adverse pregnancy outcomes that are moderated by&#xD;
      stress, and that the magnitude of the of these associations underlay GDM health disparities&#xD;
      experienced by African American (AA) and Native American (NA) women in comparison to&#xD;
      non-Hispanic white (NHW) women. This project will: 1) identify stress-related variables that&#xD;
      moderate associations between maternal mental health and GDM-related health outcomes; 2)&#xD;
      delineate associations among maternal mental health, stress, glucose metabolization, and&#xD;
      related adverse outcomes, differ among AA, NA, and NHW women; and 3) increase the&#xD;
      understanding of how psychophysiological stress reactivity interacts with maternal stress and&#xD;
      mental health, to predict glucose metabolization during pregnancy, and associations with&#xD;
      adverse perinatal outcomes. A retrospective study of 4,845 de-identified pregnancy-related&#xD;
      medical records of Sanford Health patients, and a prospective study which follows 150&#xD;
      pregnant women recruited from Sanford Health prenatal care providers will be conducted. Data&#xD;
      from medical records and prospective assessments will be used to identify associations&#xD;
      between maternal health, mental health, blood glucose metabolization and pregnancy outcomes.&#xD;
      Indicators of stress will be tested as moderators in these associations. These analyses will&#xD;
      aid in identifying which combinations of maternal depression, anxiety, and stress, are&#xD;
      associated with increased risk of GDM and GDM related outcomes. The retrospective study will&#xD;
      compare the impact of modeled associations, among women of NA, AA, and NHW heritage, with&#xD;
      results that will provide insights as to the role of psychosocial factors in GDM related&#xD;
      health disparities among AA and NA women. The prospective study, participants will complete a&#xD;
      laboratory stress task while the investigators assess physiological markers of stress&#xD;
      reactivity, including cortisol, immunoglobulin A, c-reactive protein, and cardiovascular&#xD;
      responses. Results from the prospective study will provide novel information about the role&#xD;
      of physiological pathways by which combinations of maternal mental health and stress impact&#xD;
      blood sugar metabolization, GDM and GDM related outcomes. By modeling pathways between&#xD;
      maternal stress and glucose metabolism, the investigators aim to improve our ability to&#xD;
      identify women at risk of GDM improving access to prevention and treatment, and of GDM and&#xD;
      related complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral Glucose Tolerance Test</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Amount of glucose remaining in blood after one hour challenge</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators will recruit 150 pregnant women prior to their 17th week of gestation&#xD;
        from Sanford Health prenatal care providers in the Sioux Falls area.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 17 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy single baby pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of endocrine disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Assistive reproductive technology (in-vitro fertilization)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anna M Strahm, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sanford Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Valentina Ayala Catala</last_name>
    <phone>605 3126406</phone>
    <email>strahmlab@sanfordhealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 6, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 23, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 23, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

