<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05621083</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REK sør-øst B 482316</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05621083</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Omega-3 Fatty Acids on Personal Post-Prandial Triglycerides (TG) Response</brief_title>
  <acronym>Omega 3-PT</acronym>
  <official_title>Effects of Omega-3 Fatty Acids on Personal Post-Prandial Triglycerides Response in Healthy Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oslo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Throne-Holst Foundation for Nutrition Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Horizon 2020 - European Commission</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GC Rieber VivoMega AS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oslo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this project is to elucidate how omega-3 fatty acids for 6 weeks affect mean and&#xD;
      individual postprandial TG responses after a high fat meal with butter (50 g fat) in healthy&#xD;
      subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators aim to perform a randomized controlled crossover trial where each&#xD;
      participant will act as his or her own control. Participants will be randomized to either&#xD;
      start to receive fish oil (the omega-3 fatty acid supplement, dose of 2.3 g Eicosapentaenoic&#xD;
      acid fatty acids (EPA) + Docosahexaenoic acid fatty acids (DHA) /day) for 6 weeks or a&#xD;
      high-oleic sunflower oil (HOSO) containing no omega-3 fatty acids, as control followed by a&#xD;
      wash-out period of minimum 12 weeks, before the treatment is changed for 6 weeks. Before and&#xD;
      after each intervention period the investigators will take fasting blood samples and collect&#xD;
      spot morning urine and perform a postprandial meal test with 61 g butter (containing 50 g&#xD;
      fat), and take blood samples 2, 4, 6, and 8 hours after intake of the meal. The investigators&#xD;
      will use first part of the trial to define postprandial TG responders and non-responders. The&#xD;
      investigators will also monitor the postprandial TG response to HOSO to see the participants'&#xD;
      postprandial response to a control oil without omega-3 fatty acids. After a 12 week wash-out&#xD;
      period, the investigators will then repeat the fish oil intervention period once more for all&#xD;
      in order to see if those the investigators defined as responders continue to be defined in&#xD;
      the same category in the repeated fish oil intervention (adaptive design). The investigators&#xD;
      will collect exposure data, including dietary intake, physical activity, and clinical data&#xD;
      such as BMI, body composition (such as fat mass, visceral fat, fat free mass), blood&#xD;
      pressure, lipids and glucose and specific single nucleotide polymorphism (SNPs) to understand&#xD;
      the impact of these factors on the individual postprandial TG response. In addition, the&#xD;
      investigators will collect feces samples before taken before each meal test day for gut&#xD;
      microbiota analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Start with control oil (HOSO) or start with fish oil, and then change after 12 weeks of wash out.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The principal investigator will have access to the randomization code containing the order of the oils (starting with HOSO or starting with fish oil), which is generated by an external statistician. The PI will make sure that the identical boxes with capsules (both HOSO and fish oil) will be marked only with Identification (ID) number and period number (cross over 1 and 2). The participant, the care provider and the outcomes assessor will not know the randomization code before after the data of the primary outcome has been analyzed.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial TG</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>measure iAUC of TG values postprandially (0,2,4,6,8,hours)-compare Incremental Area Under the Curve (iAUC) before and after intake of omega-3 or HOSO</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting TG</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline levels of circulating triglycerides</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting and postprandial total cholesterol, free fatty acids (FFA), LDL cholesterol, high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol, Apo A1, Apo B, Apo B-48 and Apo C-III, and lipoprotein subclasses, glucose and insulin</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>measure fasting levels and iAUC of all lipids and postprandially (0,2,4,6,8,hours)-compare fasting levels and iAUC before and after intake of omega-3 or HOSO</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting and postprandial plasma cytokines, acute phase proteins and soluble adhesion molecules</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>measure fasting levels and iAUC of all inflammatory markers and postprandially (0,2,4,6,8,hours)-compare fasting levels and iAUC before and after intake of omega-3 or HOSO</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting and postprandial whole genome Peripheral Blood Mononuclear Cells (PBMC) transcriptome (mRNA and miRNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>compare fasting levels before and after intervention and fasting levels with 4 hours after intake of meal</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting and postprandial epigenome in PBMCs</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>compare fasting levels before and after intervention and fasting levels with 4 hours after intake of meal</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting and postprandial targeted and non-targeted metabolic profiling in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>measure fasting levels and iAUC of metabolites and postprandially (0,2,4,6,8,hours)-compare fasting levels and iAUC before and after intake of omega-3 or HOSO</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Targeted and untargeted metabolomics of spot urine to measure dietary intake biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measure food intake metabolites in spot urine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SNPs in whole blood</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once at baseline</time_frame>
    <description>measure specific SNPs related to omega-3 intake and TG response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Composition of the gut microbiome (both metabolites and bacteria composition)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>measure metabolites in blood and feces and bacteria composition in feces</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">52</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fish oil (the omega-3 fatty acid supplement)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to either start to receive fish oil (the omega-3 fatty acid supplement) for 6 weeks. Followed by a wash-out period of a minimum of 12 weeks before the treatment is changed.&#xD;
Once the classical Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) has finished, all the participants will repeat the fish oil intervention period (adaptive design) to determine if those the investigators defined as responders continue to be defined in the same category.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High-oleic sunflower oil (HOSO) containing no omega-3 fatty acids</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to either start to receive high-oleic sunflower oil (HOSO) for 6 weeks. Followed by a wash-out period of minimum 12 weeks, before the treatment is changed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Omega- 3</intervention_name>
    <description>In each visit, the investigators will perform a postprandial meal test (set breakfast: Butter (61 g) with jam and three slices of white bread) In the fish oil supplement period, the participants will receive concentrated fish oil which is equal to in total 2.3 g EPA+DHA per day during 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fish oil (the omega-3 fatty acid supplement)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HOSO</intervention_name>
    <description>In each visit, the investigators will perform a postprandial meal test (set breakfast: Butter (61 g) with jam and three slices of white bread) In the HOSO period, the participants will receive similar amount of HOSO per day during 6 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>High-oleic sunflower oil (HOSO) containing no omega-3 fatty acids</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) between 18.5-30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting TG level at ≥1.0 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Max eating one portion of fatty fish per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must be willing to take two capsules with either fish oil or HOSO.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must be able to eat three slices of bread with butter and jam as&#xD;
             breakfast (x6; each visit)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They all need to accept to avoid taking omega-3 supplementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they use omega-3 supplements, they should wait 12 weeks before starting the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt;18.5 and &gt;30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight change of ± 5 % of body weight in the last three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TG &lt;1.0 mmol/L and &gt; 1.7 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  C reactive protein (CRP) &gt;10 mg/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total cholesterol &gt;6.1 mmol/L for subjects 18-29 years, &gt;6.9 mmol/L for subjects 30-49&#xD;
             years and &gt;7.8 mmol/L for subjects ≥50 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood pressure &gt;160/100 mm Hg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbidities including diabetes type I and II (blood glucose ≥7 mmol/L fasting),&#xD;
             Cardiovascular diseases(CVD)/Coronary heart disease (CHD), haemophilia, anaemia&#xD;
             (hemoglobin &lt;120 gram/L), gastro intestinal disease, hyperthyroidism (TSH &gt;4&#xD;
             Milliunits per litre (mU/L)) or inflammatory diseases such as rheumatoid arthritis&#xD;
             (RA), systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), polymyalgia and other connective tissue&#xD;
             diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having CVD/CHD or cancer past 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergic or intolerant to gluten, milk protein and/or lactose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications affecting lipids and lipid metabolism, blood clotting or&#xD;
             inflammation. Stable dose of blood pressure medications during the trial is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to separate any use of omega-3 fatty acid supplements and other supplements&#xD;
             during the study, and fish intake more than one portion per week, 12 weeks prior to&#xD;
             and during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hormone treatment (stabile dose of contraception or thyroxin for the last three months&#xD;
             excepted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood donation two months prior to or during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tobacco smoking and snuff&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stine M Ulven, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+47 22840208</phone>
    <email>smulven@medisin.uio.no</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Oslo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Oslo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Stine Marie Ulven</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Department of Nutrition, Principal Investigator, Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
  <keyword>Postprandial TG response</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

