<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05621174</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>82695</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2022-003237-19</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>82695</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05621174</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Difference in the Mechanism of Action Between Two Brands of Dexamfetamine in Adults With ADHD</brief_title>
  <acronym>DAVE</acronym>
  <official_title>The Difference in Pharmacodynamic and Pharmacokinetic Profiles Between Tentin and Magisterial Dexamfetamine in Adults With Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder, a Double Blinded Randomised Crossover-controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Academisch Medisch Centrum - Universiteit van Amsterdam (AMC-UvA)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Academisch Medisch Centrum - Universiteit van Amsterdam (AMC-UvA)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to compare in the pk/pd profiles of magisterial&#xD;
      dexamfetamine and Tentin in adults with Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). The&#xD;
      main question[s] it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Q1: is there a difference between pk/pd profiles of the two forms of dexamfetamine?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Q2: how does the pharmacokinetic variability influences the objective and subjective (side)&#xD;
      effects experienced by adult patients with ADHD?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  take the Quantified behavior Test for analysis of objective effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  undergo blood sampling for analysis of the plasma concentration of dexamphetamine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  undergo blood pressure and heart rate measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  fill out 4 types of questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers will compare the outcomes between magisterial dexamphetamine and Tentin use in a&#xD;
      crossover setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives The primary objective is to compare the pharmacological profile of the magisterial&#xD;
      form of dexamfetamine sulfate to the pharmacological profile of the brand-name form of&#xD;
      dexamfetamine (Tentin©) in adult patients diagnosed with attention deficit hyperactivity&#xD;
      disorder (ADHD) and assess whether there is a difference between pk/pd profiles of the two&#xD;
      forms of dexamfetamine. The secondary objective is to assess how pharmacokinetic variability&#xD;
      influences the objective and subjective (side) effects experienced by adult patients with&#xD;
      ADHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements At three moments (0, 60 and 120 minutes after drug administration) on each&#xD;
      intervention-day, participants will complete the QbTest to assess objective performance and&#xD;
      the QbPerformance to assess subjective performance. At eight moments (0, 45, 60, 75, 90, 120,&#xD;
      150 and 180 minutes after drug administration) on each intervention-day, participants will&#xD;
      undergo blood sampling to determine dexamfetamine plasma concentrations and vital sign&#xD;
      measurements for safety monitoring and possible outcome-effects. At eight moments (0, 45, 60,&#xD;
      75, 90, 120, 150 and 180 minutes after drug administration) on each intervention-day,&#xD;
      participants will fill out questionnaires to assess subjective experiences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 14, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 20, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 20, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantified behavior Test (QbTest) - Time Active</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Time Active for analysis of objective effects. The Quantified behaviour Test (QbTest) provides data to assess the three core symptoms of ADHD, that is: hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. Time Active (in %) is one of the scores used to measure hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. For the current study cardinal outcomes will be derived from a Principal Component Analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantified behavior Test (QbTest) - Distance</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Distance for analysis of objective effects. The Quantified behaviour Test (QbTest) provides data to assess the three core symptoms of ADHD, that is: hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. Distance (in meters) is one of the scores used to measure hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. For the current study cardinal outcomes will be derived from a Principal Component Analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantified behavior Test (QbTest) - Area</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Area for analysis of objective effects. The Quantified behaviour Test (QbTest) provides data to assess the three core symptoms of ADHD, that is: hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. Area (in cm2) is one of the scores used to measure hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. For the current study cardinal outcomes will be derived from a Principal Component Analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantified behavior Test (QbTest) - Micro Events</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Micro Events for analysis of objective effects. The Quantified behaviour Test (QbTest) provides data to assess the three core symptoms of ADHD, that is: hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. Micro Events (in millimeters) is one of the scores used to measure hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. For the current study cardinal outcomes will be derived from a Principal Component Analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantified behavior Test (QbTest) - Motion Simplicity</measure>
    <time_frame>0-120 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Motion Simplicity for analysis of objective effects. The Quantified behaviour Test (QbTest) provides data to assess the three core symptoms of ADHD, that is: hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. Motion Simplicity (in %) is one of the scores used to measure hyperactivity, inattention and impulsivity. For the current study cardinal outcomes will be derived from a Principal Component Analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood samples</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>For analysis of the plasma concentration of dexamfetamine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>For autonomic and adverse effects measurements. Measured in mmHg Normal value: 120/80 mmHg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>For autonomic and adverse effects measurements. Measured in BPM Normal value: 60-100 BPM</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Addiction Research Centre Inventory (ARCI) - Acute Subjective Response to Substances (ASRS): Amphetamine Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>45-180 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective effects measurement In this trial, only amphetamines will be administered, therefore only the first 11 questions of the amphetamine-scale will be used. The investigators have adjusted the 'true-false' questions in the amphetamine-scale to Visual Analog Scale (VAS)-questions, since VASs are more sensitive to subtle changes than Likert-scales and VAS enables rapid completion leading to a lower participant burden. The ARCI questions 1 t/m 11 are in line with the therapeutic effects of dexamfetamine.&#xD;
For each question, the VAS can be marked between 0 and 10 cm, 0 meaning 'not at all' and 10 meaning 'very much' when answering the questions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bond-Lader Visual Analog Scale (BL-VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective effects measurement The Bond &amp; Lader VAS Mood Rating Scale (BL-VAS) is used to measure the effects of drugs on the participants' mood. It consists of 16 dimensions (VAS) of mood. Ultimately, these dimensions are combined to create the following dimensions: alertness, contentedness, and calmness.&#xD;
For each question, the VAS can be marked between 0 and 10 cm, 0 meaning 'not at all' and 10 meaning 'very much' when answering the questions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>QbTest performance questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>0-180 minutes after drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective effects measurement QbPerformance to assess subjective performance on the QbTest.&#xD;
For 1 question, a 'yes' or 'no' answer will be given. For 3 questions, the VAS can be marked between 0 and 10 cm, 0 meaning 'not at all' and 10 meaning 'very much' when answering the questions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Leeds Sleep Evaluation Questionnaire (LSEQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Before drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep deprivation can negatively impact attention functioning in adults with and without ADHD. Sleep deprived participants performed worse on the QbTest. Therefore, the sleep quality of participants must be taken into account. The Leeds Sleep Evaluation Questionnaire (LSEQ) consists of ten bipolar 100mm visual analogue scales (VAS) questions that are associated with sleep. The LSEQ covers the following four aspects of sleep, namely: getting to sleep, quality of sleep, awakening from sleep and behavior following wakefulness (F1-CRF). The LSEQ has provided evidence for validity in clinical research. Furthermore, the LSEQ has been cross-culturally validated in multiple countries and languages. The LSEQ is a consistent, reliable and validated tool to evaluate sleep and should therefore be included in the current study. Participants will be asked to fill in the questionnaire once at baseline (T=0), since it only evaluates the sleep quality of participants of the night before.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Attention Deficit Disorder With Hyperactivity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Magisterial Dexamphetamine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Magisterial Dexamphetamine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tentin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Tentin</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamfetamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Magisterial Dexamfetamine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Magisterial Dexamphetamine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Magisterial Dexamfetamine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamfetamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Tentin</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tentin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Tentin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is aged ≥ 18 years at time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is diagnosed with ADHD according to the DSM 5 criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has switched from Tentin© to magisterial dexamfetamine due to the adverse&#xD;
             effects of Tentin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is being treated adequately with dexamphetamine, as determined by their&#xD;
             practitioner, at time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant or their legal representative is able and willing to provide written&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is able and willing to comply with the study protocol (e.g. swallow&#xD;
             capsules, have blood samples taken, can visit the outpatient clinic twice).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has not participated in another study in the past three months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a disorder that might affect drug absorption (e.g. gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             metabolic, endocrine or liver disorder).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is allergic to the ingredients of the capsules.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Glenn JH Dumont, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Academisch Medisch Centrum - Universiteit van Amsterdam (AMC-UvA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Esra Pirgon, BSc</last_name>
    <phone>+31 (0) 20 566 7048</phone>
    <email>e.pirgon@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Glenn JH Dumont, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31 (0) 20 566 7048</phone>
    <email>g.j.dumont@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Glenn Dumont</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <state>Noord-Holland</state>
        <zip>1105AZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Esra Pirgon, BSc</last_name>
      <phone>+31 (0) 20 566 7048</phone>
      <email>e.pirgon@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Glenn JH Dumont, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+31 (0) 20 566 7048</phone>
      <email>g.j.dumont@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Glenn JH Dumont, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.geneesmiddeleninformatiebank.nl/smpc/h115446_smpc.pdf</url>
    <description>Summary of Product Characteristics - DMB 5 mg</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.geneesmiddeleninformatiebank.nl/smpc/h124800_smpc.pdf</url>
    <description>Summary of Product Characteristics - Tentin 5 mg</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lott DC, Kim SJ, Cook EH, de Wit H. Serotonin transporter genotype and acute subjective response to amphetamine. Am J Addict. 2006 Sep-Oct;15(5):327-35. doi: 10.1080/10550490600859868.</citation>
    <PMID>16966188</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martin WR, Sloan JW, Sapira JD, Jasinski DR. Physiologic, subjective, and behavioral effects of amphetamine, methamphetamine, ephedrine, phenmetrazine, and methylphenidate in man. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1971 Mar-Apr;12(2):245-58. doi: 10.1002/cpt1971122part1245. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>5554941</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong YN, Wang L, Hartman L, Simcoe D, Chen Y, Laughton W, Eldon R, Markland C, Grebow P. Comparison of the single-dose pharmacokinetics and tolerability of modafinil and dextroamphetamine administered alone or in combination in healthy male volunteers. J Clin Pharmacol. 1998 Oct;38(10):971-8. doi: 10.1002/j.1552-4604.1998.tb04395.x.</citation>
    <PMID>9807980</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dolder PC, Strajhar P, Vizeli P, Hammann F, Odermatt A, Liechti ME. Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Lisdexamfetamine Compared with D-Amphetamine in Healthy Subjects. Front Pharmacol. 2017 Sep 7;8:617. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2017.00617. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>28936175</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dan O, Cohen A, Asraf K, Saveliev I, Haimov I. The Impact of Sleep Deprivation on Continuous Performance Task Among Young Men With ADHD. J Atten Disord. 2021 Jul;25(9):1284-1294. doi: 10.1177/1087054719897811. Epub 2020 Jan 9.</citation>
    <PMID>31916494</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Parrott AC, Hindmarch I. The Leeds Sleep Evaluation Questionnaire in psychopharmacological investigations - a review. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1980;71(2):173-9. doi: 10.1007/BF00434408.</citation>
    <PMID>6777817</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tarrasch R, Laudon M, Zisapel N. Cross-cultural validation of the Leeds sleep evaluation questionnaire (LSEQ) in insomnia patients. Hum Psychopharmacol. 2003 Dec;18(8):603-10. doi: 10.1002/hup.534.</citation>
    <PMID>14696019</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Manzar MD, Salahuddin M, Maru TT, Alghadir A, Anwer S, Bahammam AS, Pandi-Perumal SR. Validation of the adapted Leeds sleep evaluation questionnaire in Ethiopian university students. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2018 Mar 13;16(1):49. doi: 10.1186/s12955-018-0876-0.</citation>
    <PMID>29534726</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Haertzen CA. Development of scales based on patterns of drug effects, using the addiction Research Center Inventory (ARCI). Psychol Rep. 1966 Feb;18(1):163-94. doi: 10.2466/pr0.1966.18.1.163. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>5908477</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>HILL HE, HAERTZEN CA, WOLBACH AB Jr, MINER EJ. THE ADDICTION RESEARCH CENTER INVENTORY: STANDARDIZATION OF SCALES WHICH EVALUATE SUBJECTIVE EFFECTS OF MORPHINE, AMPHETAMINE, PENTOBARBITAL, ALCOHOL, LSD-25, PYRAHEXYL AND CHLORPROMAZINE. Psychopharmacologia. 1963 May 15;4:167-83. doi: 10.1007/BF02584089. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>14048539</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lader MH, Bond AJ. Interaction of pharmacological and psychological treatments of anxiety. Br J Psychiatry Suppl. 1998;(34):42-8.</citation>
    <PMID>9829016</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Setnik B, Roland CL, Pixton G, Webster L. Measurement of Drug Liking in Abuse Potential Studies: A Comparison of Unipolar and Bipolar Visual Analog Scales. J Clin Pharmacol. 2017 Feb;57(2):266-274. doi: 10.1002/jcph.801. Epub 2016 Aug 23.</citation>
    <PMID>27444046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahearn EP. The use of visual analog scales in mood disorders: a critical review. J Psychiatr Res. 1997 Sep-Oct;31(5):569-79. doi: 10.1016/s0022-3956(97)00029-0.</citation>
    <PMID>9368198</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ashinoff BK, Abu-Akel A. Hyperfocus: the forgotten frontier of attention. Psychol Res. 2021 Feb;85(1):1-19. doi: 10.1007/s00426-019-01245-8. Epub 2019 Sep 20.</citation>
    <PMID>31541305</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schmid Y, Hysek CM, Simmler LD, Crockett MJ, Quednow BB, Liechti ME. Differential effects of MDMA and methylphenidate on social cognition. J Psychopharmacol. 2014 Sep;28(9):847-56. doi: 10.1177/0269881114542454. Epub 2014 Jul 22.</citation>
    <PMID>25052243</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pourhoseingholi MA, Baghestani AR, Vahedi M. How to control confounding effects by statistical analysis. Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench. 2012 Spring;5(2):79-83.</citation>
    <PMID>24834204</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kang H. The prevention and handling of the missing data. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2013 May;64(5):402-6. doi: 10.4097/kjae.2013.64.5.402. Epub 2013 May 24.</citation>
    <PMID>23741561</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 4, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 4, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Academisch Medisch Centrum - Universiteit van Amsterdam (AMC-UvA)</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Glenn Dumont</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</keyword>
  <keyword>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>ADHD</keyword>
  <keyword>ADD</keyword>
  <keyword>AD(H)D</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dextroamphetamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Privacy protocol</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

