<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05616429</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>6834-20-TA-CTIL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05616429</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Alcat Based Elimination Diet for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome; a Randomized Double Blind Sham Control Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>Alcat Based Elimination Diet for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome; a Randomized Double Blind Sham Control Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sheba Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cell science systems</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sheba Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is the most common GI condition with global prevalence ranging&#xD;
      between 10-20%. Although the exact cause is not known there are increasing insights&#xD;
      concerning the possible multifactorial etiology including low grade inflammation,&#xD;
      neuromodulation, dysbiosis, impaired integrity of the intestinal barrier and more.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, it is believed that changes in the microbiota may activate mucosal innate immune&#xD;
      responses, resulting in increased epithelial permeability, activated nociceptive sensory&#xD;
      pathways, and dysregulation of the enteric nervous system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nearly two thirds of patients with IBS perceive their GI symptoms to be food related, hence,&#xD;
      food intolerance may be important factor in the pathogenesis. Diet is a part of IBS treatment&#xD;
      but adherence, on the one hand, and restriction, on the other, remain a major problem. [Chey&#xD;
      WD, Am J Gastroenterol,2016].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Confocal laser endomicroscopy (CLE) is a technique that permits real-time detection and&#xD;
      quantification of changes in intestinal tissues and cells, including increases in&#xD;
      intraepithelial lymphocytes and fluid extravasation through epithelial leaks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on CLE analysis of IBS patients with a suspected food intolerance, exposure to&#xD;
      candidate food antigens caused immediate breaks, increased intervillous spaces, and increased&#xD;
      IELs in the intestinal mucosa. These changes are associated with patient responses to&#xD;
      exclusion diets. [Fritscher-Ravens A et al, Gastroenterology. 2019, Gastroenterology. 2014]&#xD;
      This technic, also efficient according to former studies, is costly and invasive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Alcat Test is a lab based immune stimulation test in which a patient's WBC's (white blood&#xD;
      cell) are challenged with various substances including foods, additives, colorings,&#xD;
      chemicals, medicinal herbs, functional foods, molds and pharmaceutical compounds. The Alcat&#xD;
      Test objectively classifies a patient's response to each test substance as reactive,&#xD;
      borderline or non-reactive. Based on these classifications, a customized elimination/rotation&#xD;
      diet may be designed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Diet therapies for IBS are becoming an important part of the treatment for patients with IBS&#xD;
      [Lenhart A et al, J Neurogastroenterology Motil 2018] There are many types of elimination&#xD;
      diets utilized by patients with IBS including personalized diets based upon mediator release&#xD;
      testing and IgG (immunoglobulin G) antibody. These diets have the potential for tailor made&#xD;
      personal diet but currently have little or no clinical evidence for efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diet therapies, like medical therapies for IBS, should be properly evaluated in appropriate&#xD;
      designed clinical trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is also important to protect our patients with IBS from potentially ineffective, costly&#xD;
      and unsafe intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double blind randomized clinical trial (RCT) comparing Alcat based personal diet for the treatment of IBS versus &quot;sham&quot; standard balanced diet</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) Symptom Severity Scale questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>decrease of 50 points. Values range: 0-500</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Irritable Bowel Syndrome Global Symptom Assessment (IBS-GSA) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>4 and 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Compared to how you felt then, how would you rate your overall IBS symptoms during the past week? Possible answers are one of the following: Significantly relieved (+3); Moderately relieved (+2); A little bit relieved (+1); Unchanged (0); A little bit worse (-1); Moderately worse (-2); Significantly worse (-3).&#xD;
[ Rome Foundation]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Abnormal laboratory value - bio marker</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>decrease level - CRP (C reactive protein) milligrams per liter (mg/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Monitoring serum level of Syndecan-1 (Sdc1) ng/mL</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Syndecan-1 (Sdc-1) is a type 1 transmembrane heparan sulfate proteoglycans that are implicated in maintenance of intestinal epithelial barrier. Sdc-1 is predominantly expressed by plasma cells and mucosal epithelial cells, such as intestinal epithelial cells.&#xD;
Changes of Sdc1 level in sera will be assessed primarily to the diet intervention and at the end of the diet after 8 weeks</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) Adequate Relief questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>IBS-Adequate Relief (IBS-AR) is a dichotomous single item that asks participants &quot;Over the past week have you had adequate relief of your IBS symptoms?</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Irritable Bowel Syndrome Quality of life questionnaire - specific for IBS (IBS-QoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline to Week 8 in IBS-QOL total and subscale scores . Values: 34-170</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Irritable Bowel Syndrome Global Improvement Scale (IBS-GIS)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Compared to the way you felt before you entered the study, have your IBS symptoms over the past 7 days been: 1) Substantially Worse, 2) Moderately Worse, 3)Slightly Worse, 4) No Change, 5) Slightly Improved, 6) Moderately Improved or 7) Substantially Improved. A responder is defined as a patient who answered &quot;moderately improved&quot; or &quot;substantially improved&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>IBS - Irritable Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Alcat based personal diet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard balanced diet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alcat based personal diet</intervention_name>
    <description>Alcat based personalized diet with dietician supervision and follow-up + usual care</description>
    <arm_group_label>Alcat based personal diet</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard balanced diet</intervention_name>
    <description>&quot;Sham&quot; standard balanced diet with dietician supervision and follow up + usual care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard balanced diet</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>usual care</intervention_name>
    <description>usual care</description>
    <arm_group_label>Alcat based personal diet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard balanced diet</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Only adults (&gt;18 years of age) meeting the Rome 4 Criteria for IBS D/M/U and who are&#xD;
             willing to adhere to diet restrictions, will be eligible for entry into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with 'warning symptoms' (e.g., unexplained weight loss, history of GI cancer&#xD;
             or inflammatory bowel disease, rectal bleeding etc) will be required to have had a&#xD;
             detailed workup to exclude organic pathology prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants will be allowed to continue their IBS medications (e.g., fiber,&#xD;
             anti-spasmodics, antidepressants, loperamide, etc.) as long as they had been on stable&#xD;
             doses for at least 30 days prior to entering the study and agreed not to change&#xD;
             medications or dosages during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. In addition, patients will be required to have active symptoms at the entry of the&#xD;
             study as defined by having an IBSSSS score of &gt;150 (0-500 scale).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients will be excluded if they fulfill ROME 4 IBS C criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have an inflammatory bowel disease, celiac or other inflammatory or gut disorder other&#xD;
             than IBS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have active malignancy of any kind&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If they are not able to eat PO&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. If they are Using NSAIDS more than once per month and within the 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. If C reactive protein is above 2 times the normal value or if stool Calprotectin is&#xD;
             above 200mcg/gr&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. If they had recent antibiotic use (within 1 month). -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tal Engel</last_name>
    <phone>+97235307072</phone>
    <email>tal.engel@sheba.health.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Revital Dvir</last_name>
    <email>revital.dvir@sheba.health.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sheba Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <zip>5262000</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tal Engel, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+97235307072</phone>
      <email>tal.engel@sheba.health.gov.il</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 9, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 9, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 13, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sheba Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Tal Engel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

