<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05795751</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZWQ21886</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05795751</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Timings for Awake Prone Positioning in Covid-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Timings for Awake Prone Positioning in Covid-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ruijin Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ruijin Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 is an infectious disease caused by a virus called SARS-CoV-2. The spread rate and&#xD;
      mortality rate of the virus have had a significant impact on global health and economic&#xD;
      systems. Comprehensive treatment and supportive care are required to help COVID-19 patients&#xD;
      recover. During the treatment of COVID-19, the respiratory system of patients may be&#xD;
      affected, and measures need to be taken to support respiratory function. Currently, awake&#xD;
      prone positioning(APP) is an effective method for treating respiratory failure when&#xD;
      mechanical ventilation is not feasible or unavailable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the prone position, the patient's face is facing the ground, the chest is sinking, and the&#xD;
      abdomen is rising. This posture can improve alveolar ventilation and blood flow distribution,&#xD;
      reduce pulmonary edema and pulmonary vascular resistance. In addition, the prone position can&#xD;
      also improve the coordination of respiratory muscles, promote pulmonary expectoration, and&#xD;
      increase functional residual capacity. Although the prone position has been widely used,&#xD;
      there is still some controversy over when to use it. Some studies have shown that using the&#xD;
      APP for early-stage COVID-19 patients can reduce mortality rates and respiratory dependence&#xD;
      time, while others believe that using the APP in the later stages may increase the risk of&#xD;
      lung injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, it is necessary to further study when to use the APP and its impact on treatment&#xD;
      effectiveness and safety. Such research may need to consider multiple factors, such as the&#xD;
      patient's clinical symptoms, the severity of lung lesions, lung function indicators, and the&#xD;
      duration of using the prone position. Determining the optimal time to use the APP will help&#xD;
      guide clinical physicians to better apply this treatment strategy in the treatment of&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients. In addition, the prone position can also be used in the treatment of other&#xD;
      respiratory system diseases, so relevant research can also provide references and inspiration&#xD;
      for the treatment of other diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this observational study is to learn about the details which might optimize the&#xD;
      effect of APP in COVID-19 patients. The main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The optimal time to start in the prone position&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the optimal duration of APP treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the strategies to improve the tolerance of the awake prone position&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Setting and design&#xD;
&#xD;
           Retrospectively collect relevant data from the electronic medical records of COVID-19&#xD;
           patients who were admitted to the research center from December 2022 to February 2023.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Study Participants&#xD;
&#xD;
           Convenient sampling of COVID-19 patients admitted to the research center from December&#xD;
           2022 to February 2023.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  age 18 years or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  radiographic evidence of pulmonary inflammation;&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  clear consciousness and ability to communicate verbally;&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  patients who have undergone prone position ventilation at least once during&#xD;
                hospitalization;&#xD;
&#xD;
           Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
           • patients who received mechanical ventilation and oral intubation immediately after&#xD;
           admission or within 2 hours of admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Sample Size Determination Sample size of the multivariable Cox regression model for&#xD;
           patients' overall survival is calculated by using the previously reported method. Based&#xD;
           on the generally accepted rule of thumb of 10 events per variable and the final Cox&#xD;
           model containing 4 variables, the field size was expected to be 40 events. A sample size&#xD;
           of at least 440 patients are warranted based on an estimated 10% event rate and a 10%&#xD;
           loss to-review rate among the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.1 Baseline data: Gender, age, comorbidities, body mass index (BMI), smoking status,&#xD;
           use of anti-Covid-19 drugs (Paxlovid and Azvudine), use of corticosteroids, and&#xD;
           radiological results, etc., as baseline and demographic data.&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.2 Data related to awake prone positioning: Time from admission to first use of awake&#xD;
           prone positioning, oxygen delivery method and oxygen concentration at first use of awake&#xD;
           prone positioning, peripheral oxygen saturation during use of awake prone positioning,&#xD;
           systolic blood pressure and respiratory rate at first use of awake prone positioning,&#xD;
           duration of daily use of awake prone positioning, total number of days using awake prone&#xD;
           positioning, achievement of awake prone positioning goals, acceptance of maintenance&#xD;
           measures for awake prone positioning, changes in oxygen delivery method and oxygen&#xD;
           concentration after first use of awake prone positioning, and adverse events caused by&#xD;
           awake prone positioning (dislodged catheter, skin injury, and gastrointestinal&#xD;
           reactions).&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.3 primary outcome: Mortality rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.4 Secondary outcomes: Intubation, upgrading of oxygen supply equipment, deterioration&#xD;
           of respiratory failure, and length of hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Data collection and management Data is collected through the hospital's electronic&#xD;
           medical record management system and recorded in the original registration log. All data&#xD;
           is recorded clearly to ensure accurate interpretation and traceability. All data and&#xD;
           original documents are kept for a minimum of 3 years, and publication and data sharing&#xD;
           agreements are made.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Statistical Analysis Quantitative variables will be described using means (standard&#xD;
           deviations) or medians [interquartile ranges], while categorical variables will be&#xD;
           described using counts (proportions). We will use t-tests to compare normally&#xD;
           distributed variables and chi-square tests to compare proportions. For non-normally&#xD;
           distributed variables, we will use the Mann-Whitney U test. We will examine the&#xD;
           predictive ability of SPO2:FIO2 for various respiratory outcomes and mortality rates by&#xD;
           calculating the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve and the Youden&#xD;
           index and explore the optimal discriminating threshold. We will then divide study&#xD;
           subjects into low and high SPO2:FIO2 groups based on the threshold and compare their&#xD;
           characteristics in univariate analysis. In addition, we will compare characteristics of&#xD;
           patients with and without adverse respiratory outcomes in univariate analysis. We will&#xD;
           further investigate the relationship between adverse respiratory outcomes occurring&#xD;
           within 28 days and variables with P values &lt;0.10 in univariate analysis using Cox&#xD;
           proportional hazards regression models to analyze the relationship between the time to&#xD;
           occurrence of adverse respiratory outcomes (up to 28 days) and these variables. The same&#xD;
           methods will be used to explore the relationship between these variables and 28-day&#xD;
           hospital mortality rate. We will also use Kaplan-Meier curves to plot the percentage of&#xD;
           Covid-19 patients who experience adverse respiratory outcomes or die within 28 hospital&#xD;
           days based on the SpO2/FiO2 ratio at first application of awake prone positioning,&#xD;
           controlling for these covariates through Cox regression. A significance level of 0.05&#xD;
           will be used for all two-tailed tests. Data will be analyzed using SPSS 26.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Quality Control&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.1 Establish a unified case information collection register. Before collecting data, all&#xD;
      data collectors will receive unified training to clarify the concept of data collection and&#xD;
      screening standards, ensuring the consistency of data collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.2 Data collection will be carried out simultaneously by two individuals and entered into&#xD;
      the electronic medical record information collection register to ensure accuracy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.3 If any unresolved or uncertain issues arise during the data collection process, timely&#xD;
      communication with the principal investigator will be conducted to ensure consistency of the&#xD;
      information.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>From December 2022 to February 2023</time_frame>
    <description>hospital mortality</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of adverse respiratory outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>From December 2022 to February 2023</time_frame>
    <description>intubation after APP, escalation of respiratory support,Deterioration of respiratory failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">450</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus Pneumonia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        COVID-19 patients admitted to two tertiary hospitals in Shanghai, China from December 2022&#xD;
        to February 2023&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age 18 years or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  radiographic evidence of pulmonary inflammation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clear consciousness and ability to communicate verbally;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who have undergone prone position ventilation at least once during&#xD;
             hospitalization;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Patients who were mechanically ventilated with oral intubation immediately after&#xD;
        admission or 2 h after admission.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>weiqing zhang, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ruijin Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>weiqing zhang, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>86 18521525300</phone>
    <email>weiq.zh@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 3, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 3, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

