<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05611411</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022ZSLYEC-493</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05611411</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maximum Alveolar Concentration of Sevoflurane for Maintaining Effective Spontaneous Respiration</brief_title>
  <acronym>MaACesr</acronym>
  <official_title>The Exploration of Maximum Alveolar Concentration of Sevoflurane for Maintaining Effective Spontaneous Respiration</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sixth Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sixth Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mechanical ventilation will bring many adverse effects. Positive pressure can affect&#xD;
      hemodynamics. Inhalation of higher concentrations of oxygen during mechanical ventilation can&#xD;
      result in reabsorbed atelectasis for the lungs with a low ventilation-perfusion ratio.&#xD;
      Patients who are intubated and mechanically ventilated are at risk for ventilator-associated&#xD;
      pneumonia. Mechanical ventilation can induce or aggravate lung injury, called&#xD;
      ventilator-induced lung injury (VILI) , Minimizing the duration of mechanical ventilation is&#xD;
      the best way to reduce complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sevoflurane is a halogen group of inhaled anesthetics commonly used in clinical, with&#xD;
      sedation, analgesia, muscle relaxation. Sevoflurane also inhibited respiratory function,&#xD;
      tidal volume decreased with the depth of anesthesia, respiratory rate increased, higher than&#xD;
      the conscious respiratory rate, but not enough to fully compensate for the decreased tidal&#xD;
      volume. The results showed that with the increase of the depth of anesthesia, the minute&#xD;
      ventilation decreased, and the ability to remove carbon dioxide also decreased.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the background of the study and the pharmacological properties of sevoflurane, we&#xD;
      sought to explore the maximum alveolar concentration of sevoflurane for maintaining effective&#xD;
      spontaneous respiration in patients, i.e.FiO2 = 30% , PaO2 &gt; 92% , VT &gt; 5 ml/kg, RR &gt; 8/min,&#xD;
      PETCO2 &lt; 50 mmHg, sustained &gt; 20s, the time from the beginning of inhalation induction to 1&#xD;
      point OAAS, the changes of hemodynamics during induction, and the recall of induction and&#xD;
      operation were also explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Mechanical ventilation is the most widely used short-term life support technique in the&#xD;
      world, which can not only provide good condition for anesthesiologists to manage airway, it&#xD;
      can also prevent respiratory muscle fatigue and carbon dioxide accumulation caused by&#xD;
      insufficient ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the same time, mechanical ventilation will also bring a lot of adverse effects. Positive&#xD;
      pressure ventilation can affect hemodynamics, and studies have shown that high intrathoracic&#xD;
      pressure, especially high plateau pressure, can adversely affect right ventricular afterload&#xD;
      and function. Inhalation of higher concentrations of oxygen during mechanical ventilation can&#xD;
      result in reabsorbed atelectasis for the lungs with a low ventilation-perfusion ratio.&#xD;
      Patients who are intubated and mechanically ventilated are at risk for ventilator-associated&#xD;
      pneumonia due to low oral and pharyngeal secretions, reduced cough efficiency, and impaired&#xD;
      mucociliary clearance. Mechanical ventilation can induce or aggravate lung injury, called&#xD;
      ventilator-induced lung injury (VILI) .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Minimizing the duration of mechanical ventilation is the best way to reduce complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sevoflurane is a halogen group of inhaled anesthetics commonly used in clinical, with&#xD;
      sedation, analgesia, muscle relaxation. The blood/gas distribution coefficient is low and the&#xD;
      effect is quick. The elimination mainly depends on the lung exhalation, about 5% passes&#xD;
      through the liver metabolism, is affected by the anaesthesia time long little. Long-term&#xD;
      low-flow sevoflurane inhalation anesthesia has little effect on liver and kidney function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sevoflurane also inhibited respiratory function, tidal volume decreased with the depth of&#xD;
      anesthesia, respiratory rate increased, higher than the conscious respiratory rate, but not&#xD;
      enough to fully compensate for the decreased tidal volume. The results showed that with the&#xD;
      increase of the depth of anesthesia, the minute ventilation decreased, and the ability to&#xD;
      remove carbon dioxide also decreased.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the background of the study and the pharmacological properties of sevoflurane, we&#xD;
      sought to explore the best alveolar concentration of sevoflurane for maintaining effective&#xD;
      spontaneous respiration in patients, i.e. FiO2 = 30% , PaO2 &gt; 92% , VT &gt; 5 ml/kg, RR &gt; 8/min,&#xD;
      PETCO2&lt; 50 mmHg, sustained &gt; 20s, the time from the beginning of inhalation induction to 1&#xD;
      point OAAS, the changes of hemodynamics during induction, and the recall of induction and&#xD;
      operation were also explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 6, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 3, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MaACesr</measure>
    <time_frame>2022.12.01-2023.06.01</time_frame>
    <description>maximum alveolar concentration of sevoflurane for maintaining effective spontaneous respiration</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Sevoflurane</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients scheduled for elective surgery under general anesthesia with tracheal&#xD;
        intubation，with better general situation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 20-60 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ASA gradeⅠ~Ⅱ&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Scheduled for elective surgery under general anesthesia with tracheal intubation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Elective head and neck and chest surgery patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Chronic respiratory disease or acute respiratory infection;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Indication of difficult airway during preoperative visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Risk of reflux aspiration;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Did not receive regular antihypertensive therapy or blood pressure was not well&#xD;
             controlled；&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Severe organic heart disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Abnormal function of liver and kidney;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Allergic to inhaled anesthetics and known or suspected genetic history of malignant&#xD;
             hyperthermia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Mental disorders or long-term history of taking psychotropic drugs and cognitive&#xD;
             impairment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of drug abuse and alcohol abuse;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or nursing;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participated in any clinical trial as a subject within the last 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Refuse to participate or do not sign or refuse to sign an informed consent form;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>洁琳 郑</last_name>
    <phone>18359188309</phone>
    <email>962536345@qq.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>the Sixth Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guangzhou</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <zip>510655</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>SanQing Jin, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0086-13719366863</phone>
      <email>sanqingjin@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 6, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sixth Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>SanQing Jin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief anesthesiologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

