<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05617781</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>22-PP-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05617781</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Empathy in Post-traumatic Stress Disorder in Comparaison to a Control Population</brief_title>
  <official_title>Analysis of Empathy in Patients With Post-traumatic Stress Disorder Followed at the Hospital of Nice: Case-control Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It has been shown in the literature that the symptoms of post-traumatic stress disorder&#xD;
      influence the quality of life of patients, in particular through the cognitive alterations&#xD;
      they can cause. Social cognition is also itself impacted. It refers to the perception,&#xD;
      interpretation and processing of information relating to the social environment and&#xD;
      relationships. It is affected by the symptomatology of PTSD both in terms of the response to&#xD;
      emotional stimuli, the perception of self and others, and the quality of intimate&#xD;
      relationships. These elements lead to reflection on the origin of these alterations, in&#xD;
      particular the impact of PTSD on the patient's empathy capacity, defined as the recognition&#xD;
      and understanding of the feelings and emotions of another individual. This parameter is also&#xD;
      little studied in the literature, only a study dating from 2010 finds a correlation between&#xD;
      PTSD and empathy. It is in this context that the realization of a new study studying the&#xD;
      capacity for empathy of patients with PTSD in comparison with a control group with a larger&#xD;
      and more representative population was envisaged. The primary outcome of this study is to&#xD;
      analyze the post-traumatic stress disorder's repercussions on empathy by passing the&#xD;
      Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI) on patients in comparison with a control group. The&#xD;
      first hypothesis is a lower total score but a higher personal distress sub-score in the PTSD&#xD;
      population. The secondary outcomes are to describe the cofactors that can influence empathy&#xD;
      in association or not with post-traumatic stress disorder: sociodemographic data (age, sex,&#xD;
      education level…), traumatic event type determined through the &quot;Inventory of Traumatogenic&#xD;
      Events&quot;, human intervention, duration and severity of the disorder (evaluated by the Impact&#xD;
      of Events Scale) … The number of subjects required was calculated at 19 patients and 19&#xD;
      controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 9, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 visit for inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>The Interpersonal Reactivity Index is a validated self-questionnaire allowing the measurement of empathy from 28 items. For each item, five rating levels are proposed in the form of a Likert scale ranging from 0 (&quot;does not describe me at all&quot;) to 4 (&quot;describes me completely&quot;). The IRI is divided into four subscales of seven items corresponding to conceptual adaptation (tendency to spontaneously adopt the point of view of others in daily life), fantasy (tendency to imagine oneself in fictitious situations) , empathic concern (tendency to experience feelings of sympathy and compassion in response to the distress of others) and personal distress (tendency to experience distress and discomfort in response to the distress of others.) The score of each subscale therefore varies from 0 to 28 and the total score of the IRI is between 0 and 112.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Post-traumatic Stress Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Empathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnary</intervention_name>
    <description>The primary outcome of this study is to analyze the post-traumatic stress disorder's repercussions on empathy by passing the Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The patients included will be followed at the Hospital of Nice for post-traumatic stress&#xD;
        disorder diagnosed according to the DSM-V criteria. They are volunteers, adults, French&#xD;
        speakers. The control population will be randomly selected (advertising, social networks…),&#xD;
        adults and French speakers too, having no follow-up or current psychiatric treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Any patient or controls who score positively off the diagnostic criteria for comorbidities&#xD;
        such as major depressive episode, generalized anxiety disorder, psychotic disorder and&#xD;
        autism spectrum disorder are not included. These criteria will be assessed through the MINI&#xD;
        diagnostic interview and the Autism Spectrum Quotient.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chaïma KEBAIR-RACHDI, Dr</last_name>
    <email>kebairrachdi.c@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Corentin ANELLI</last_name>
    <email>anelli.c2@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de Nice</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <zip>06001</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Corentin ANELLI</last_name>
      <email>anelli.c2@chu-nice.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

