<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615428</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-22007105 Validation Study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615428</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fast Assessment of Surfactant Deficiency in Preterm Infants to Speed up Treatment - Validation Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>FAST2</acronym>
  <official_title>FAST TRIAL 2 -Fourier-transform Infrared Spectroscopy(FTIR)Guided Surfactant Therapy - Validation Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Odense University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aalborg University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aarhus University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Holbaek Sygehus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim is to re-validate a FTIR spectroscopy test for measuring lung maturity/Respiratory&#xD;
      Distress Syndrome (RDS) before conducting a RCT using this test to guide surfactant treatment&#xD;
      of preterm infants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The test has been validated previously (NCT03235882) but needs re-validation due to continued&#xD;
      improvement in accuracy and since the test is now developed into a Point of Care test&#xD;
      (POC-test).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose is to accurately predict RDS using Lecithin/Sphingomyelin ratio (L/S ratio&#xD;
      determined by a rapid FTIR in a newly developed point of care test (POC-test) on fresh&#xD;
      gastric aspirates using retrospective analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The FAST 2 Validation Study is a part of the FAST 2 Trial consisting of a validation study&#xD;
      and a subsequent randomized clinical trial, that will be registered separately on&#xD;
      clinicaltrials.gov (NTC XXXXXXXXX)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Treatment of respiratory distress syndrome (RDS) has evolved greatly over the past three&#xD;
      decades. Major advances in treatment include antenatal steroids, early nasal continuous&#xD;
      positive airway pressure (nCPAP) combined with early rescue surfactant replacement strategies&#xD;
      such as Intubation Surfactant Extubation (INSURE) and Less Invasive Surfactant Administration&#xD;
      (LISA), together with use of lung protective ventilation and overall reduced use of&#xD;
      mechanical ventilation. However, RDS and bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) are still major&#xD;
      causes of mortality and morbidity in premature infants. To improve the outcome, very early&#xD;
      treatment with surfactant is necessary. However, only about half of infants with a&#xD;
      gestational age (GA) below 30 weeks need surfactant treatment and prophylactic surfactant&#xD;
      treatment increases the combined mortality and incidence of BPD contrary to selective rescue&#xD;
      surfactant treatment. Therefore, there is a need for a rapid test to guide early targeted&#xD;
      surfactant treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have recently developed a new test of lung maturity based on measuring the lecithin&#xD;
      sphingomyelin ratio (L/S) in fresh gastric aspirates (GAS) from newborn preterm infants using&#xD;
      mid-red Fourier Transform Infrared spectroscopy (FTIR). The sphingomyelin concentration in&#xD;
      amniotic fluid and accordingly in GAS is relatively constant during the pregnancy, whereas&#xD;
      the lecithin (or dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC), the lung surfactant phospholipid with&#xD;
      the highest surface activity) concentration increases with the lung maturation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have demonstrated in clinical observational trials that our laboratory based L/S-test&#xD;
      predicts development of RDS when measured immediately at delivery (FAST 1 Trial).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The L/S-test has now been developed into an easy-to-use Point of Care (POC) test for bedside&#xD;
      use that expresses the L/S ratio in approximately 10 minutes. We believe this new POC test&#xD;
      can be used to guide surfactant therapy, enabling very early rescue treatment, potentially&#xD;
      even before symptoms occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To obtain evidence-based knowledge on harms and benefit of surfactant therapy guided by the&#xD;
      L/S test, a randomized clinical trial with relevant clinical short-and long-term outcomes&#xD;
      needs to be performed, which is why the FAST 2 Trial has been designed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During design and development of the FAST 2 Trial protocol extensive engineering work has&#xD;
      been conducted towards building a fully automated L/S POC Device (AIMI 1.0/2.0) from the&#xD;
      prototypes in the first L/S studies (including FAST 1 Trial).&#xD;
&#xD;
      During this process the accuracy of the L/S algorithm has been improved through machine&#xD;
      learning and use of artificial intelligence. Consequently, the previously defined cut-off&#xD;
      ratio from the FAST 1 Trial needs to be re-validated using the L/S POC Device in a new&#xD;
      population of preterm infants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The FAST 2 Trial therefore consists of two individual studies starting with the FAST 2&#xD;
      Validation Study which will followed by the FAST 2 Randomized Clinical Trial (FAST 2 RCT)&#xD;
      once completed. The FAST 2 RCT will be registered at clinicaltrials.gov separately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of FAST 2 Validation study is:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In preterm infants with gestational age at birth of ≤ 29+6 weeks less than 45 minutes of age&#xD;
      who have not received surfactant prior to the measurenent, we aim to:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • measure L/S-ratio in fresh GAS using the AIMI 1.0/2.0 L/S POC Device&#xD;
&#xD;
      and compare the L/S-ratio by: • the need for surfactant treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      with the aim to:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • validate the previously defined optimal cut-off L/S-ratio for surfactant treatment and to&#xD;
      determine if the cut-off L/S ratio needs to be adjusted before starting FAST 2 RCT&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 16, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>LS-ratio cut-off</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective is to measure the L/S-ratio in fresh GAS using the AIMI 1.0/2.0 L/S POC Device and compare the L/S-ratio with the need for surfactant treatment aiming to validate the previously defined cut-off L/S-ratio for surfactant treatment and to determine if the cut-off L/S ratio needs adjustment before starting FAST 2 RCT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Surfactant Deficiency Syndrome Neonatal</condition>
  <condition>Respiratory Distress Syndrome in Premature Infant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>observational group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
GA ≤29+6, inborn at a participating centre&#xD;
Age less than 45 minutes as gastric aspirate must be sampled within 45 minutes from delivery.&#xD;
Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
Treated with surfactant beforerandomisation and obtaining gastric aspirates&#xD;
Diagnosis of major malformations (major congenital heart defects, congenital diaphragmatic hernia, gastroschisis/omphalocele, pulmonary abnormalities including pulmonary hypoplasia and trachea-oesophageal fistula&#xD;
Antenatal suspicion of significant oligohydramnios and lung hypoplasia&#xD;
Any intrauterine intervention except if done for genetic testing</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LS-ratio</intervention_name>
    <description>Included infants will have a gastric aspirate sampled via an NG tube at birth. This sample will be analyzed to determine the LS-ratio The LS-ratio will retrospectively be compared to RDS development and need for surfactant treatment to establish the cut-off ratio for LS-ratio with respect to surfactant treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>observational group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Gastric aspirate from newborn infants&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Preterm newborn babies that have gastric secretions sampled before 45 minutes of age.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        GA ≤29+6, inborn at a participating centre Age less than 45 minutes as gastric aspirate&#xD;
        must be sampled within 45 minutes from delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Treated with surfactant beforerandomisation and obtaining gastric aspirates&#xD;
&#xD;
        Diagnosis of major malformations (major congenital heart defects, congenital diaphragmatic&#xD;
        hernia, gastroschisis/omphalocele, pulmonary abnormalities including pulmonary hypoplasia&#xD;
        and trachea-oesophageal fistula&#xD;
&#xD;
        Antenatal suspicion of significant oligohydramnios and lung hypoplasia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any intrauterine intervention except if done for genetic testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Minutes</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christian Heiring</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christian Heiring</last_name>
    <phone>+4535453545</phone>
    <email>christian.heiring@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Christian Heiring</last_name>
    <email>christian.heiring@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aalborg University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalborg</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anne-Cathrine Viuff, phD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aarhus University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aarhus</city>
        <zip>8200</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tine B. Henriksen, Professor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Odense University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Odense</city>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gitte Zachariasen, Professor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christian Heiring</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>surfactant replacement therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>surfactant assay</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

