<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05610098</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HREC 243/2022</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>AOS-DIA-22-029-TRA</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05610098</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Gene Expression Profiles in Spinal Tuberculosis.</brief_title>
  <acronym>SpinalTBX</acronym>
  <official_title>Comparing Gene Expression Profiles of Adults With Isolated Spinal TB to Disseminated Spinal TB Identified by 18FDG-PET/CT at Time of Diagnosis, 6-and 12-months Follow-up</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Cape Town</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Zurich</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cape Town</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis (TB) is one of the top ten causes of death worldwide with approximately 10&#xD;
      million cases globally and 1.2 million deaths. Sub-Saharan Africa carries the highest burden&#xD;
      of TB. South Africa has one of the highest HIV and TB rates worldwide with an HIV prevalence&#xD;
      rate in adults of 19% and a TB case notification rate of 615/100,000 in 2019. Over many&#xD;
      years, focus has been paid to pulmonary TB and extrapulmonary TB (EPTB) has received only&#xD;
      little attention even though it accounts for almost a quatre of all TB cases. The diagnosis&#xD;
      of EPTB remains challenging simply because sample collection requires invasive procedures in&#xD;
      the absence of a blood-based diagnostic test. Spinal TB (spondylitis or spondylodiscitis&#xD;
      caused by Mycobacterium tuberculosis) - often known as Pott's disease - accounts for up to&#xD;
      10% of EPTB and affects young children, people with HIV-coinfection and elderly, and often&#xD;
      leads to lifelong debilitating disease due to devastating deformation of the spine and&#xD;
      compression of neural structures. Little is known with regards to the extent of disease and&#xD;
      isolated TB spine as well as a disseminated form of TB spine have been described. The latter&#xD;
      presents with a spinal manifestation plus disseminations to other organs such as the lungs,&#xD;
      pleura, lymph nodes, the GIT or urinary tract or even the brain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the Spinal TB X cohort, the investigators aim to describe the clinical phenotype of spinal&#xD;
      TB using whole body PET/CT and identify a specific gene expression profile for the different&#xD;
      stages of dissemination and compare findings to previously described signatures for latent&#xD;
      and active pulmonary TB. A blood-based test for spinal TB would lead to earlier diagnosis and&#xD;
      treatment in all settings globally and improve treatment outcome of this devastating disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the Spinal TB X cohort, the investigators aim to describe the clinical phenotype of spinal&#xD;
      TB using whole body PET/CT and identify a specific gene expression profile for the different&#xD;
      stages of dissemination and compare findings to previously described signatures for latent&#xD;
      and active pulmonary TB. A blood-based test for spinal TB would lead to earlier diagnosis and&#xD;
      treatment in all settings globally and improve treatment outcome of this devastating disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The investigators hypothesize that spinal TB may present as two clinical phenotypes:&#xD;
           isolated spinal TB with no additional lesion on whole body PET/CT and disseminated&#xD;
           spinal TB with a spinal lesion plus an additional extraspinal lesion on whole body&#xD;
           PET/CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The investigators hypothesize that a specific gene expression profile may distinguish&#xD;
           between the two clinical entities above and allows for treatment monitoring during&#xD;
           antimicrobial therapy (&quot;personalized medicine&quot;)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The investigators hypothesize that whole body PET/CT is superior to MRI in diagnosing&#xD;
           spinal and extraspinal TB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      To describe the clinical phenotype of spinal TB using whole body PET/CT and to identify mRNA&#xD;
      gene expression profiles of isolated spinal TB versus disseminated spinal TB stratified by&#xD;
      HIV status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To identify the distributive patterns of suspected spinal TB using two imaging&#xD;
           modalities: MRI and PET/CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To analyse the genomes of Mtb. extracted from different sites of the body (if available)&#xD;
           and to identify differences in their genome regarding SNPs and drug sensibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To analyse imaging findings using PET/CT at treatment initiation, 6 months, and 12&#xD;
           months to better understand treatment outcome using PET/CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To compare imaging findings on PET/CT and MRI at baseline to evaluate the role of PET/CT&#xD;
           in spinal TB diagnostics (virtual biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective cohort study to develop new diagnostics for isolated spinal TB versus&#xD;
      disseminated spinal TB and treatment monitoring. Furthermore, this study investigates genetic&#xD;
      variability in spinal TB and its distributional pattern. After MRI-confirmation of spinal TB&#xD;
      according to local algorithms, patients will be included in the study. At baseline, clinical&#xD;
      examination as well as blood collection will be performed. Every patient with no confirmed&#xD;
      HIV will undergo HIV-testing. Sputum will be collected and screening for diabetes and&#xD;
      pregnancy will be completed. Whole-body PET/CTs will be performed at 0 months, 6 months, and&#xD;
      12 months. Spinal biopsies will be gathered if surgery is being performed. Samples of the&#xD;
      sites of disease will be acquired if applicable and TB culture as well as GeneXpert will be&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with newly diagnosed spinal TB at the Department of Orthopaedics, Groote Schuur&#xD;
      Hospital, Cape Town, South Africa.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 25, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical phenotype of spinal TB</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To describe the clinical phenotype of spinal TB using whole body PET/CT a semiquantitative approach will be used. Regions of interest (ROIs) will be identified with increased FDG uptake against background and total lesion glycolysis (TLG) of each ROI will be measured using MIM software</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>mRNA gene expression profiles of spinal TB</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>mRNA gene expression profiles of isolated spinal TB versus disseminated spinal TB described in outcome 1 will be measured and stratified by HIV status.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MRI vs. PET/CT at the site of disease (spine level)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To identify the distributive patterns of suspected spinal TB using two imaging modalities: MRI and PET/CT. MRI is measure T1, T2 and diffusion weighted images. Regions of interest (ROIs) in the spine will be identified with increased FDG uptake against background and total lesion glycolysis (TLG) of each ROI will be measured using MIM software</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Whole Genome Sequencing of Mtb. isolates</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>To analyse the genomes of Mtb. extracted from different sites of the body (if available) and to identify differences in their genome regarding SNPs and drug sensibility.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PET/CT changes over 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Regions of interest (ROIs) in the spine will be identified with increased FDG uptake against background and total lesion glycolysis (TLG) of each ROI will be measured using MIM software at different timepoints: treatment initiation, 6 months, and 12 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis, Spinal</condition>
  <condition>Tuberculosis, Osteoarticular</condition>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <condition>Mycobacterium Infections</condition>
  <condition>Infections</condition>
  <condition>Bone Diseases, Infectious</condition>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Spinal Disease</condition>
  <condition>Spondylitis</condition>
  <condition>Spondylitis; Tuberculosis (Manifestation)</condition>
  <condition>Spondylodiscitis</condition>
  <condition>Positron-Emission Tomography</condition>
  <condition>Diagnostic Imaging</condition>
  <condition>Diagnostic Techniques and Procedures</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Site of disease specimen collection (sputum, spinal abscess/disc/bone tissue collection);&#xD;
      whole-blood samples, serum, PBMC, Paxgene.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants with clinically and MR-suspected spinal TB will be recruited from the&#xD;
        Department of Orthopaedics, Groote Schuur Hospital, Cape Town, South Africa. According to&#xD;
        the current caseload, the investigators will be able to include 50-100 participants per&#xD;
        year, aiming for 100 participants in total. In result, the investigators are aiming for 300&#xD;
        PET/CTs (100 initial, 100 at 6 months, 100 at 12 months) and 300 peripheral blood samples&#xD;
        for gene expression analysis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant has completed the written informed consent process prior to undergoing any&#xD;
             clinical evaluations and willing to undergo HIV testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. TB spine based on clinical and radiological criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age 18 or older with a body weight of at least 40 kg body weight&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able and willing to return to follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to have samples, including DNA including RNA extraction, stored&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing to consistently practice a highly reliable method of pregnancy prevention&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnancy or active desire to become pregnant within the next 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Uncontrolled diabetes (HbA1c ≥ 6.5% / random glucose concentration ≥11.1 mmol/l,&#xD;
             fasting plasma glucose ≥ 7.0 mmol/l)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Alcohol and substance abuse which might interfere with medication adherence during the&#xD;
             trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Positive SARS-CoV-2 PCR in the past 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Suspicion of malignancy on MRI or known malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Suspicion of inflammatory disease and other rheumatological conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any person for whom the physician feels this study is not appropriate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>friedrich Thienemann, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Cape Town</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Friedrich F Thienemann, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+27 (0)21 406 6358</phone>
    <email>friedrich.thienemann@uct.ac.za</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Michael Held, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+27 (0)21 406 6358</phone>
    <email>michael.held@uct.ac.za</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Groote Schuur Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cape Town</city>
        <state>Western Cape</state>
        <zip>7935</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julian F Scherer, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+27762030775</phone>
      <email>schjul017@myuct.ac.za</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Friedrich Thienemann, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Held, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Julian Scherer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sandra Mukasa, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tessa Kotze, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.gmgh.africa</url>
    <description>General Medicine &amp; Global Health research group at the University of Cape Town</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 24, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Cape Town</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof Friedrich Thienemann</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, Principal Investigator and Research Group Leader</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Spinal TB</keyword>
  <keyword>tuberculous spondylodiscitis</keyword>
  <keyword>FDG-PET/CT</keyword>
  <keyword>POC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Spondylitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mycobacterium Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Discitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Diseases, Infectious</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Spinal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Osteoarticular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Spondylarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Spinal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

