<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619835</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1566-2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619835</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Usability Study of a Tele-health Service for Patients With Peripheral Arterial Disease.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Usability Study of a Tele-health Service for Patients With Peripheral Arterial Disease.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Graz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AIT Austrian Institute of Technology GmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Graz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to analyze the applicability (usability) of a tele-health service as&#xD;
      part of a potential disease management program for patients with peripheral arterial disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following investigations will be conducted as part of the usability study. In the context&#xD;
      of a tele-health service, knowledge, physical condition (including walking distance) will be&#xD;
      documented during face-to-face and televisits, dislocated supervised gait training and&#xD;
      education will be provided, and satisfaction with the tele-health service will be evaluated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Disease management programs (DMPs) are one of the methods used to optimize the care of&#xD;
      patients with chronic diseases. DMPs are coordinated health care measures for patient&#xD;
      populations with diseases in which active patient participation in treatment can lead to&#xD;
      substantial effects. Specific treatment regimens, based on evidence-based treatment&#xD;
      guidelines and structured patient information, are predominantly aimed at preventing disease&#xD;
      exacerbations and complications. The World Health Organization (WHO) also recommends, among&#xD;
      other things, forcing patient adherence through structured information and patient&#xD;
      empowerment strategies to establish participatory treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peripheral arterial disease (PAD) causes oxygen and nutrient deprivation of tissues through&#xD;
      narrowing of arterial vessels in the extremities. The cause of PAD is arteriosclerosis. The&#xD;
      course of the disease begins asymptomatically and manifests itself over time with pain and&#xD;
      cramps predominantly in the muscles of the lower extremity. The pain symptoms usually occur&#xD;
      initially during physical exertion, and later at rest. As PAD progresses, chronic ulceration&#xD;
      and necrosis occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Professional societies such as the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European&#xD;
      Society of Vascular Medicine (ESVM) regularly publish guidelines for the diagnosis and&#xD;
      treatment of PAD. Therapy of PAD consists of drug therapy for the purpose of cardiovascular&#xD;
      risk reduction (lipid and blood pressure lowering drugs and anticoagulant drugs as well as&#xD;
      therapy of diabetes mellitus). Another aspect in the event of disease progression is&#xD;
      interventional angioplasty, in which the affected constriction in the leg arteries is dilated&#xD;
      and, if necessary, treated with stents. Another important pillar is also structured and&#xD;
      supervised gait training and, in general, an improvement in lifestyle with cessation of&#xD;
      nicotine abuse and a healthy diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In particular, structured gait training, which should be performed at least three times a&#xD;
      week for 30 to 60 minutes, is strongly recommended in the current ESVM and ESV guidelines.&#xD;
      Studies showed that structured gait training can increase walking distance by 200% in 12&#xD;
      weeks in patients with claudication. Daily individual interval training of 60 minutes with 5-&#xD;
      to 15-minute intervals also proved effective in increasing walking distance. This is to&#xD;
      overcome the pain threshold of claudication while walking. Furthermore, evidence showed that&#xD;
      gait training may be equivalent to endovascular interventions in terms of long-term outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to analyze the applicability (usability) of a telehealth service as&#xD;
      part of a potential disease management program for patients with peripheral arterial disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A prospective monocentric pilot study will be conducted at the clinical department of&#xD;
      angiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study duration per participant is 90 (±14) days and is divided into 2 observation phases.&#xD;
      In phase 1, there will be supervision by a certified nurse and the telehealth service app,&#xD;
      and in phase 2, there will be only singular use of the app without contact by the certified&#xD;
      nurse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Declaration of Helsinki (as amended from time to time) and the guidelines of &quot;Good&#xD;
      Clinical Practice&quot; were taken into account in the conduct and also the planning of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, the framework guideline for the &quot;IT infrastructure in the application of&#xD;
      telemonitoring&quot; was used for the planning of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the manufacturer's manuals, the pedometers AS80/AS97/AS99 from the company&#xD;
      Beurer are not medical devices. The app serves as a diary for patients and is not a Clinical&#xD;
      Decision Support System. The &quot;User's Manual PAD Stepping&quot; is included with the study&#xD;
      material.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reference Projects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The DMS app system is also already being used in routine care in the &quot;Herzmobil&quot; project in&#xD;
      Styria and Tyrol. Here, patients with chronic heart failure are cared for.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of the DMS app is currently also being used in two other studies. These are&#xD;
      observational studies that are not subject to the Medical Devices Act. Both projects have a&#xD;
      positive ethics vote and are listed under the following titles:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Telemedical follow-up of hospitalized patients with coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19)&#xD;
           DRKS ID of the study: DRKS00022244.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Building a training database of voice data recordings and body weight trajectories in&#xD;
           hemodialysis patients for algorithm development.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 11, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction with the telehealth service.</measure>
    <time_frame>At time point visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Study participants will undergo guided interviews measuring patient satisfaction with telehealth service.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients, who would be satisfied with the telehealth service if telephone calls would not be provided by a nurse during the programme</measure>
    <time_frame>At time point visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Yes/No</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of walking distances in the 6 minute walk test determined by the certified nursing staff in response to the telehealth service.</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Walking distances in the 6 minute walk test will be determined by the certified nursing staff.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of subjective limitations in the activities of daily living.</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Study participants will undergo a questionaire (SF36) measuring subjective limitations in the activities of daily living.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of knowledge about peripheral arterial disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Study participants will undergo a questionaire measuring knowledge about peripheral arterial disease before and 12 weeks after a structured education.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of performed 6 minute walk tests during the telehealth service.</measure>
    <time_frame>At time point visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Study participants will perform 6 minute walk tests independently using the App during the telehealth service.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences of the walking distance in the same 6 minute walk test determined by the nursing staff compared the App.</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and at visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Walking distances in the 6 minute walk test will be determined by the certified nursing staff as well as by the App.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average steps per day during the telehealth service.</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Descriptive</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of summed seconds in the &quot;Time up and Go Test&quot;.</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to visit 3, which is 12 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The &quot;Time up and Go Test&quot; will be performed by an installed automatic measure system and will be observed by the certified nursing staff. The patient has to stand up from a chair and walk three meter straight. The time needed for this procedure will be measured exactly by a sensor supported measure system.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Arterial Disease</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients diagnosed with IIa and IIb PAD at the Department of Angiology at the&#xD;
        LKH-University Hospital Graz.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented diagnosis of &quot;peripheral arterial occlusive disease&quot; in, IIa and IIb&#xD;
             (according to Fontaine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smartphone with Android operating system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understanding of how to use the tele-health service&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with PAD stages I, III and IV (according to Fontaine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smartphone with non-Android operating system or incompatible software&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andreas Prenner, Mag.</last_name>
    <phone>0043316385</phone>
    <phone_ext>81326</phone_ext>
    <email>andreas.prenner@stud.medunigraz.at</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Günther Silbernagel, Assoc.-Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>0043316385</phone>
    <phone_ext>17622</phone_ext>
    <email>guenther.silbernagel@medunigraz.at</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of Graz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <state>Steiermark</state>
        <zip>8036</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Romana Schuh, Dipl. Päd.</last_name>
      <phone>+43 316 385 12911</phone>
      <email>Romana.Schuh@klinikum-graz.at</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Günther Silbernagel, Assoz.-Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Graz</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Günther Silbernagel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc.-Prof. Priv.-Doz. Dr.med.univ. et scient.med.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Peripheral Arterial Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Walking exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Tele-health Service</keyword>
  <keyword>Disease Management Program</keyword>
  <keyword>Preventive Medicine</keyword>
  <keyword>Integrated care</keyword>
  <keyword>Vascular Medicine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

