<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05614388</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RES-376</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05614388</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study on Voluntary Routine COVID-19 Self-testing in Mizoram, India.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study on Utilization, Adherence, and Acceptability of Voluntary Routine COVID-19 Self-testing Among Students, Staff and Health Workers at Two Institutions in Mizoram, India.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>PATH</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UNITAID</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Zoram Medical College (ZMC)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pacchunga University College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Association for Leprosy Education Rehabilitation &amp; Treatment India (ALERT India)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Government of Mizoram</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>PATH</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This interventional study aims to evaluate the utilization, adherence, and acceptability of&#xD;
      voluntary, free, routine self-testing for COVID-19 (Corona Virus (19) Disease) and related&#xD;
      information, education and communication (IEC) messages in two institutional settings in&#xD;
      Mizoram, India. In addition, it will assess and measure preferences for assisted vs&#xD;
      unassisted and observed vs unobserved self-testing, assess adherence and measure dropout rate&#xD;
      and describe dropout characteristics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research questions it aims to address are -&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What is the uptake and adherence of voluntary, free, routine self-testing for COVID-19&#xD;
           and related IEC messages vy students, employees, and healthcare workers in two&#xD;
           institutional settings in India? Are there any dropouts from routine self-testing and&#xD;
           what are the factors related to dropouts?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What is the preferred mode of self-testing- observed or unobserved, assisted or&#xD;
           unassisted? Do these preferences change over time? The researchers will be measuring -&#xD;
           Utilization rate, Adherence rate, Proportion of preference to assisted vs unassisted&#xD;
           self-testing, Proportion of preference to observed vs unobserved self-testing, Time to&#xD;
           dropout and Acceptability of COVID-19 self-testing kits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Testing is a critical component of the pandemic response. It serves two purposes; for&#xD;
      clinical purposes, it focuses on identifying disease in symptomatic patients, while testing&#xD;
      for epidemiological purposes, spread in the population is also assessed. India uses a mix of&#xD;
      both Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction (RT PCR) and Antigen Rapid Diagnostic&#xD;
      Tests (Ag RDTs) for COVID-19 testing. RT PCR is the reference standard test for detection of&#xD;
      the virus. However, not all facilities have RT PCR, and many communities have poor access.&#xD;
      This leads to a long turn-around time (TAT) for the results to be obtained and a high load on&#xD;
      RT PCR facilities. Hence, to prevent the spread of the virus, cases must get detected early.&#xD;
      At the peak of the first wave of the pandemic in the country, Ag RDTs constituted close to&#xD;
      50% of all the tests conducted in the country. Self-testing for COVID-19 has emerged as a&#xD;
      viable complementary testing modality. The use of self-testing kits while ensuring the&#xD;
      availability of other COVID-19 tests at the nearest point of care addresses many of the usual&#xD;
      barriers to uptake of services, leading to timely testing of individuals, diagnosis, and&#xD;
      access to care. It can also reduce the burden on existing testing infrastructure especially&#xD;
      during a surge in the cases. It also reduces overcrowding at testing facilities thereby&#xD;
      reducing the risk of disease transmission. To improve access to testing and prevent&#xD;
      overreliance on RT PCR laboratories, the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) approved&#xD;
      and validated the use of COVID-19 self-testing kits. As of March 2022, sixteen self-testing&#xD;
      kits have been validated in India of which 10 are found to be satisfactory. While there are&#xD;
      many benefits to self-testing, it is also essential to understand the utilization of the&#xD;
      self-testing strategy, including whether or not the community can follow the steps for&#xD;
      self-testing and what support, if any, the community may require to use self-test kits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present study proposes the demonstration of ICMR and US-FDA (United States Food &amp; Drug&#xD;
      Administration) approved SURE STATUS self-testing kit in the healthcare workers and&#xD;
      educational institution setting in Mizoram for a period of 5 months. With the ease of&#xD;
      lockdown and movement restrictions, workplaces and educational institutes are gradually&#xD;
      opening up. However, with the threat of the pandemic still looming large, it is prudent to&#xD;
      put in place systems for regular screening within these settings to promote early diagnosis&#xD;
      and care and prevent outbreaks. COVID-19 self-test has been identified as one way any&#xD;
      institution can scale up COVID-19 testing to improve COVID-19 status awareness by reaching&#xD;
      out to as many people as possible at a given point of time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While COVID-19 self-tests are available and widely used in India, these kits are largely used&#xD;
      within the confines of individual homes. It is learnt that the reporting of the results of&#xD;
      the self-test is poor as compared to the utilization of the self-test kits. To the&#xD;
      investigator's knowledge, no study has been conducted in India to assess the utilization of&#xD;
      self-testing as a routine procedure in places of mass indoor gathering, like workplaces and&#xD;
      educational institutions. To address this gap, the investigators will conduct a study to&#xD;
      evaluate the utilization, adherence, and acceptability of routine COVID-19 self-testing among&#xD;
      students, employees and healthcare workers in two congregate settings: one University College&#xD;
      and one Medical College and Hospital in Mizoram, India. The proposed study will document&#xD;
      challenges, if any, in reporting of self-test results and document the key processes in&#xD;
      operationalizing routine COVID-19 self-testing among students, employees and healthcare&#xD;
      workers and provide learning and recommendations for systematic use of self-tests for future&#xD;
      models of institution based COVID-19 self-testing in congregate settings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The participants include health care workers, non-medical hospital staff and medical students at ZMC; and faculty, students and supporting staff at the Pacchunga University College. All these groups will be participating in the study simultaneously. The study results will be compared for all these 6 groups.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Utilization rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Individual level: the proportion of tests each individual uses till the end of the follow-up period from the minimum number of tests allocated to them.&#xD;
Sample-level: mean and standard deviations calculated based on the individual utilisation rates</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adherence Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Individual level: the proportion of tests an individual performs according to the testing schedule over the total number of tests they perform.&#xD;
Sample-level: mean and standard deviations calculated based on the individual adherence rates</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Preferences of participants on self testing</measure>
    <time_frame>5 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of preference to assisted vs unassisted self-testing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Observation proportions of participants on self testing</measure>
    <time_frame>5 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of preference to observed vs unobserved self-testing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to dropout</measure>
    <time_frame>5 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The time to drop out will be the time from enrolment of the participant till drop-out</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of COVID-19 self-testing kits</measure>
    <time_frame>5 Months</time_frame>
    <description>A composite indicator based on ease of use of COVID-19 self-testing kits, ease of interpretation of test results, and recommendation to others</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">646</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The study procedure is universal to all the participants from both the institutes. There are no control arms defined separately. The groups within the participants include - include health care workers, non-medical hospital staff and medical students at ZMC; and faculty, students and supporting staff at the Pacchunga University College.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 Self testing and related messaging</intervention_name>
    <description>Provisioning of voluntary, free self-testing for COVID-19 (approved and validated in the country) and related Information, Education and Communication (IEC) messages</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Above the age of 18 years, irrespective of gender and past COVID-19 status&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Registered with participating institutions&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able and willing to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Owns a smartphone capable of downloading the SURE STATUS app for uploading results&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Able to read the instructions in the Mizo or English or Hindi&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Does not consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Has any contraindication to nasal sample collection, including recent nasal injury,&#xD;
             nasal surgeries.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Personnel who are directly involved in the conduct of the study, e.g., investigator,&#xD;
             sub-investigator, research assistant, pharmacist, study coordinator or anyone&#xD;
             mentioned in the delegation log.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jane Ralte, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Zoram Medical College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Muneer Kutty, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>+919999798283</phone>
    <email>mkutty@path.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID 19</keyword>
  <keyword>Self-Test</keyword>
  <keyword>Pandemic Preparedness</keyword>
  <keyword>Infectious diseases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We do not plan to share any individual participant data. We will share collective learnings on various parameters at both the sites.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

