<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615571</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHUBX 2017/38</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615571</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing of NBIA Genes: Analysis of Genetic Heterogeneity and Validation of Mitochondrial Markers for Assessing Causality of Sequence Variants.</brief_title>
  <acronym>NBIA MITO</acronym>
  <official_title>Testing of NBIA Genes: Analysis of Genetic Heterogeneity and Validation of Mitochondrial Markers for Assessing Causality of Sequence Variants.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Bordeaux</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Bordeaux</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Neurodegeneration with brain iron accumulation (NBIA) represent a group of rare&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental diseases, genetically as well as phenotypically heterogeneous.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The diagnosis is based on brain MRI. It is also based on genetic testing. However overlaps&#xD;
      exist between the different clinical presentations and the molecular diagnosis may be&#xD;
      misinterpreted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two main purposes must be addressed to get a better molecular diagnosis: on one hand reaching&#xD;
      enough exhaustivity which may be performed with a larger gene panel and next generation&#xD;
      sequencing; on the other hand, it is now necessary to validate or infirm the deleterious&#xD;
      consequences of variants with the help of functional studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Neurodegeneration with brain iron accumulation (NBIA) represent a group of rare&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental diseases, genetically as well as phenotypically heterogeneous.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The diagnosis is based on brain MRI. It shows abnormal deposit of iron in the basal ganglia,&#xD;
      especially in the globus pallidus and the substance nigra. It is also based on genetic&#xD;
      testing. Ten individualized forms are now described. However overlaps exist between the&#xD;
      different clinical presentations and the molecular diagnosis may be misinterpreted because of&#xD;
      variants, named as variants of unknown signification, whom the pathogenic role is not proven.&#xD;
      Approximately half of the clinically relevant cases with iron deposits on brain MRI remain&#xD;
      without any molecular deleterious alteration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two main purposes must be addressed to get a better molecular diagnosis: on one hand reaching&#xD;
      enough exhaustivity which may be performed with a larger gene panel and next generation&#xD;
      sequencing; this panel will include new genes and could be enlarged as more genes are&#xD;
      identified. On the other hand, it is now necessary to validate or infirm the deleterious&#xD;
      consequences of variants with the help of functional studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Four major pathways are involved in the pathophysiology of NBIA: iron and lipids metabolisms,&#xD;
      mitochondrial metabolism and autophagy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering that biochemical mechanisms inside the mitochodrion are involved in these four&#xD;
      pathways, the investigators performed a first test starting from patient's fibroblasts and&#xD;
      analyzed the literature in order to define the parameters that could be pertinent as&#xD;
      biological markers of NBIA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two different groups will be studied :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A group of NBIA patients without found mutation after sequencing of the gene panel&#xD;
           currently used at the university hospital of Bordeaux. Genetic testing will be performed&#xD;
           with the help of an alternative method of target enrichment applied to 16 NBIA genes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A group of patients with 2 frequent forms of NBIA with identified variants will be&#xD;
           analysed to assess the best mitochondrial markers from fibroblasts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to transfer these new genetic and biochemical strategies to the&#xD;
      diagnostic procedures with the support of the french rare disease network in charge of&#xD;
      neurodegenerations and the &quot;CARAMMEL&quot; network involved in the diagnosis of mitochondrial&#xD;
      diseases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 4, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sequencing tests of a panel of 22 genes using a dedicated custom capture and a medium throughput sequencing protocol.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Records of coverage (% of designed regions)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sequencing tests of a panel of 22 genes using a dedicated custom capture and a medium throughput sequencing protocol.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Records of depth of sequencing (reads number)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of the dominant form using biochemical analysis in patient's fibroblasts</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Counting of mitochondria with Voltage-dependent anion channel (VDAC) labeling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of the dominant form using biochemical analysis in patient's fibroblasts</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Measurements of iron and ferritin cellular levels after iron deprivation and iron loading</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Neurodegeneration With Brain Iron Accumulation (NBIA)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with NBIA who remain without molecular diagnosis</arm_group_label>
    <description>A group of 40 patients with NBIA, who remain without molecular diagnosis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with NBIA with identified mutations in genes</arm_group_label>
    <description>A group of patients with 2 frequent forms of NBIA, carrying mutations in genes (already studied in the CHU molecular diagnostic laboratory)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Establishment of mitochondrial markers</intervention_name>
    <description>Establishment of mitochondrial markers from fibroblasts in culture, obtained from a skin biopsy. Establishment of yeast models to show biochemical mitochondrial alterations: introduction of missense variants in the pantothenate kinase yeast gene Cab1 whose deletion is lethal, followed by growth of mutant strains on fermentation and respiratory media.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with NBIA with identified mutations in genes</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sequencing tests</intervention_name>
    <description>sequencing tests of a panel of 22 genes (9 already known and 13 new genes) using a dedicated custom capture and a medium throughput sequencing protocol.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with NBIA who remain without molecular diagnosis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      cutaneous biopsy and blood samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with NBIA&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NBIA Patients diagnosed with a pathogenic variation or any variation that could impact&#xD;
             gene function (class 4 or 5 according to ACMG criteria) in the following genes:&#xD;
             C19ORF12, PANK2, PLA2G6, DCAF17, FA2H, WDR45, FTL, CP and ATP13A2 and whose&#xD;
             fibroblasts have been collected at Bordeaux University Hospital for functional&#xD;
             analysis during the diagnosis procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NBIA patients without conclusive testing in none of these nine genes and whose DNA has&#xD;
             been collected during the diagnosis procedure at Bordeaux University Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without imaging (MRI or scan) signs of NBIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without french healthcare insurance&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Patricia FERGELOT MAURIN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Bordeaux</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Bordeaux</name>
      <address>
        <city>Talence</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pantothenate Kinase-Associated Neurodegeneration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nerve Degeneration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

