<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792735</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Shenzhen CRC-004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792735</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neoadjuvant Cadonilimab Plus Chemotherapy Following Short-Course Radiotherapy in Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>NeoCaCRT</acronym>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Open-Label, Single-Arm and Multicentre Phase II Study to Explore the Efficacy and Safety of Neoadjuvant Cadonilimab Plus Chemotherapy Following Short-Course Radiotherapy in Middle and Lower Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shenzhen People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sixth Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong-Shenzhen Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shenzhen People's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to test the efficacy and safety in patients with locally&#xD;
      advanced middle and lower rectal cancer. The main questions it aims to answer are:• Whether&#xD;
      Cadonilimab combined with chemotherapy following short-course radiation can improve&#xD;
      pathological complete response(pCR) rate? •Are the toxicities of the combination therapy&#xD;
      manageable? Participants will be given radiation of 5 Gy for 5 days and then neoadjuvant&#xD;
      Cadonilimab combined with modified fluorouracil, leucovorin, and oxaliplatin (mFOLFOX6) for 6&#xD;
      cycles. Without progressed disease, total mesorectal excision (TME) or transanal local&#xD;
      excision will be performed. If clinical complete response was received, watch and wait&#xD;
      strategy is one of choices. Adjuvant Cadonilimab plus mFOLFOX6 for another 6 cycles could be&#xD;
      suggested for non-pCR participants,while surveillance is also suitable for pCR ones.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Long-term synchronous chemoradiation (CRT) with sequential TME is the treatment recommended&#xD;
      by current guidelines for locally advanced rectal cancer (LARC). The latest STELLAR study&#xD;
      showed that preoperative short-course radiotherapy (SCRT) combined with preoperative&#xD;
      chemotherapy is safe and effective and can be used as an alternative to conventional CRT in&#xD;
      LARC [1]. In recent years, new therapies blocking immune checkpoints (cytotoxic T&#xD;
      lymphocyte-associated molecular protein 4 (CTLA-4), programmed cell death 1 (PD1) and&#xD;
      programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1)) have achieved landmark achievements in the field of&#xD;
      cancer therapy. Several clinical trials are evaluating the efficacy of a combination of RT&#xD;
      and immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) in rectal cancer (NCT02948348, NCT04124601,&#xD;
      NCT04558684). The results of the study suggest that radioimmunotherapy is safe and effective&#xD;
      in rectal cancer. A number of studies have shown that combined PD-1 and CTLA-4 blockade is&#xD;
      associated with a higher response rate whereas more toxicities in multiple tumor types.&#xD;
      Cadonilimab is a tetrameric PD-1/CTLA-4 bispecific antibody, based on the Akeso Tetrabody&#xD;
      platform. It introduces novel T cell targeting mechanisms of action that may provide an&#xD;
      improved therapeutic index and a favorable toxicity profile compared to PD-1 and CTLA-4&#xD;
      combination therapy. The study of SCRT combined with Cadonilimab and chemotherapy in middle&#xD;
      and lower LARC has not been reported at home or abroad.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, this study plans to recruit 27 patients with middle and lower LARC to explore the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of radiation of 5 Gy for 5 days followed by Cadonilimab 6mg/kg plus&#xD;
      mFOLFOX6 (oxaliplatin 85 mg/m2, leucovorin 400 mg/m2, 5-fluorouracil bolus 400 mg/m2 on day&#xD;
      1, and 5-fluorouracil infusion 2400 mg/m2 for 48 h) every 2 weeks for total 6 cycles&#xD;
      preoperatively. The primary endpoint is the pathological complete response (pCR) after&#xD;
      surgery. The secondary endpoints consist of a clinical complete response (cCR), major&#xD;
      pathological response (MPR), objective response rate (ORR), recurrence-free survival (RFS),&#xD;
      overall survival (OS) and safety. Clinical response was evaluated by endoscopy, digital&#xD;
      rectal examination and pelvic MRI. Safety was analyzed in all patients who receive at least&#xD;
      one dose of treatment. The exploratory endpoint covers the quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After surgery, non-pCR patients receive adjuvant Cadonilimab combined with mFOLFOX6 for 6&#xD;
      cycles while pCR ones have two options: adjuvant treatment which is the same as the&#xD;
      neoadjuvant regimen or observation. As for cCR patients, TME or transanal local excision is&#xD;
      one of options while the watch and wait (W&amp;W) strategy can also be considered especially for&#xD;
      ultra-low rectal cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pathological Complete Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of patients with no tumor cells in the postoperative specimens</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Free Survival Time from the date of treatment administration until the date of the first documented event of: disease recurrence Disease Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time from the date of treatment administration until the date of the first documented event of: disease recurrence following surgery (preferably biopsy proven), or death - whichever occurs first</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival is defined as time from the date of treatment administration until the date of death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of participants that achieve either a complete response (CR) or a partial response (PR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Complete Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Digital examination of rectum and multi-point puncture of colonoscopy indicate no tumor, and ultrasound colonoscopy and tumor markers&#xD;
and MRI are normal, which is considered as clinical complete response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major Pathological Response Rate (MPR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of cancer cells in the resected tumors and lymph nodes is less than 10%.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events (TRAE) as assessed by CTCAE v5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with AE, TRAE, immune-related AE (irAE), serious adverse event (SAE) assessed by CTCAE v5.0, change from baseline in liver function, kidney function, peripheral blood counts, etc. at 3 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life (QoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of death from any cause, assessed up to 10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life will be evaluated using the European O-rganization for Reasearch and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire-C30（EORTC QLQ-C30） (range 0-100). It evaluates the quality of life from 30 aspects, including appetite, mental status, sleep quality, fatigue, etc. The higher scores mean a better quality of life.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Locally Advanced Rectal Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cadonilimab group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cadonilimab is administrated with 6mg/kg and repeated every 2 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cadonilimab Injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Cadonilimab, an anti-CTLA-4/PD-1 bispecific antibody, at a dose of 6mg/kg is given in combination with chemotherapy every 2 weeks preoperatively and postoperatively.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cadonilimab group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AK104</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Short-course radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Preoperative short-course radiotherapy (5x5 Gy)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cadonilimab group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SCRT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Consolidation chemotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Oxaliplatin 85 mg/m2, leucovorin 400 mg/m2, 5-fluorouracil bolus 400 mg/m2 on day 1, and 5-fluorouracil infusion 2400 mg/m2 for 48 h) every 2 weeks for total 6 cycles preoperatively and postoperatively.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cadonilimab group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>mFOLFOX6</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥18 yeas and ≤79 years. The gender is not limited.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histopathology confirmed the diagnosis of rectal adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with rectal cancer based on endoscopic ultrasound and / or pelvic MRI&#xD;
             contrast + contrast, chest CT, head MRI or CT + contrast, or positron emission&#xD;
             tomography / computed tomography （PET / CT）, staging criteria per American Joint&#xD;
             Committee on Cancer (AJCC) 8th edition cancer stage, cT 3-T4 / N + M0.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least 20 unstained sections of formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded tumor tissue&#xD;
             sections, or fresh tumor tissue, can be provided for genomic and proteomic testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance status (ECOG PS) 0- 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate bone marrow and organ function meets the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Neutrophil count (ANC)≥1.5×l09/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelet (PLT) ≥80×109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hemoglobin (Hb) level ≥90 g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Total bilirubin level≤1.5×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) level≤3×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) level ≤3×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. International normalized value (INR) or prothrombin time (PT) or activated&#xD;
                  partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) ≤1.5×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Serum creatinine (Cr) level ≤1.5×ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Creatinine clearance #50 ml/min (Calculated according to the Cockcroft-Gault&#xD;
                  formula)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous history of severe hypersensitivity to other monoclonal antibodies or any&#xD;
             component of Cadonilimab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Preoperative pathology was diagnosed as squamous cell carcinoma or neuroendocrine&#xD;
             tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Within 5 years before enrollment for malignancies other than colorectal cancer with&#xD;
             negligible risk of metastasis or death (e. g., expected 5-year OS&gt; 90%) and expected&#xD;
             radical results after treatment (e. g., adequately treated cervical carcinoma in situ,&#xD;
             basal or squamous cell skin carcinoma, localized prostate carcinoma for curative&#xD;
             intent, ductal carcinoma in situ surgically treated with curative intent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous treatment against the PD-1 receptor or its ligand PD-L1 or the cytotoxic T&#xD;
             lymphocyte-associated protein-4 (CTLA-4) receptor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of autoimmune diseases, including but not limited to myasthenia gravis,&#xD;
             myositis, autoimmune hepatitis, series, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, inflammatory bowel disease, vascular thrombosis related to antiphospholipid&#xD;
             syndrome, Wegener's granulomatosis, Sjogren's syndrome, Guillain-Barre syndrome,&#xD;
             multiple sclerosis, vasculitis, vasculitis, or glomerulonephritis; patients with&#xD;
             autoimmune-related hypothyroidism were eligible for stable-dose thyroid hormone&#xD;
             replacement therapy; patients with type 1 diabetes under control after a stable&#xD;
             insulin regimen were eligible to participate in this study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Usage of systemic immune activation drugs (including but not limited to interferon or&#xD;
             Interleukin-2) within 4 weeks prior to enrollment or within 5 half-lives of the drug&#xD;
             (whichever is shorter);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Usage of systemic corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg/d of prednisone equivalent) or other&#xD;
             systemic immunosuppressive agents (including but not limited to prednisone,&#xD;
             prednisone, dexamethasone, cyclophosphamide, azathioprine, methotrexate, thalidomide,&#xD;
             and anti-tumor necrosis factor agents [anti-TNF]) within 2 weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
             Local, ocular, intra-articular, nasal, and inhaled corticosteroids are permitted;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients requiring baseline and subsequent MRI tumor evaluation with previous allergic&#xD;
             reactions to intravenous contrast agents may use preventive steroids;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Allowing the use of inhaled corticosteroids for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease,&#xD;
             corticosteroid hydrochloride (e. g., fluorohydrocortisone) in patients with&#xD;
             orthostatic hypotension, and low-dose corticosteroid maintenance for adrenal cortical&#xD;
             insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with previous allogeneic bone marrow transplantation or previous solid organ&#xD;
             transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, drug-induced pneumonia, mechanical pneumonia (i. e.&#xD;
             bronchiolitis obliterans), history of idiopathic pneumonia or chest CT scan at&#xD;
             screening showed evidence of active pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Any live vaccine (e. g., vaccine against infectious diseases, such as influenza&#xD;
             vaccine, varicella vaccine, etc.) within 4 weeks (28 days) before enrollment.13 Active&#xD;
             infections, including tuberculosis (TB) (clinical diagnosis including clinical&#xD;
             history, physical examination and imaging findings, and TB tests performed per local&#xD;
             medical practice), hepatitis B {known HBV surface antigen (HBsAg) positive and HBVDNA&#xD;
             1000 cps / ml}, hepatitis C or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV antibody positive).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients with prior or cured HBV infection (defined as hepatitis B core antibody&#xD;
             positive and HBsAg negative) were to be eligible to participate in the study only if&#xD;
             HBVDNA was negative (HBVDNA˂ 1000 cps / ml);&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients with positive hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are not eligible for the study only&#xD;
             if polymerase chain reaction shows negative HCVRNA;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Clinically meaningful basic medicine, disease (e. g., dyspnea, pneumonia,&#xD;
             pancreatitis, poorly controlled, poorly controlled diabetes, infection active or&#xD;
             poorly controlled, or drug or alcohol abuse).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Presence of severe neurological or psychiatric disorders, including dementia and&#xD;
             epileptic seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. The NCI-CTCAE grade 2 peripheral neuropathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Female patients during pregnancy or lactation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Chronic bowel disease or short bowel syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase (DPD) enzyme deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Major cardiovascular diseases, such as New York Heart Association heart disease (grade&#xD;
             II or higher), myocardial infarction within 3 months before randomization, unstable&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or unstable angina pectoris.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Patients with known coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure not meeting the&#xD;
             above criteria, or left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;50% must have an optimized&#xD;
             stable medical regimen as determined by the treating physician, consulting a&#xD;
             cardiologist if required.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wan He, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+8618823719462</phone>
    <email>hewanshenzhen@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Guixiong Liao, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+8615914153267</phone>
    <email>liaoguixiang@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jin J, Tang Y, Hu C, Jiang LM, Jiang J, Li N, Liu WY, Chen SL, Li S, Lu NN, Cai Y, Li YH, Zhu Y, Cheng GH, Zhang HY, Wang X, Zhu SY, Wang J, Li GF, Yang JL, Zhang K, Chi Y, Yang L, Zhou HT, Zhou AP, Zou SM, Fang H, Wang SL, Zhang HZ, Wang XS, Wei LC, Wang WL, Liu SX, Gao YH, Li YX. Multicenter, Randomized, Phase III Trial of Short-Term Radiotherapy Plus Chemotherapy Versus Long-Term Chemoradiotherapy in Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer (STELLAR). J Clin Oncol. 2022 May 20;40(15):1681-1692. doi: 10.1200/JCO.21.01667. Epub 2022 Mar 9.</citation>
    <PMID>35263150</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hodi FS, Chiarion-Sileni V, Gonzalez R, Grob JJ, Rutkowski P, Cowey CL, Lao CD, Schadendorf D, Wagstaff J, Dummer R, Ferrucci PF, Smylie M, Hill A, Hogg D, Marquez-Rodas I, Jiang J, Rizzo J, Larkin J, Wolchok JD. Nivolumab plus ipilimumab or nivolumab alone versus ipilimumab alone in advanced melanoma (CheckMate 067): 4-year outcomes of a multicentre, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2018 Nov;19(11):1480-1492. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30700-9. Epub 2018 Oct 22. Erratum In: Lancet Oncol. 2018 Dec;19(12):e668. Lancet Oncol. 2018 Nov;19(11):e581.</citation>
    <PMID>30361170</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sharma P, Siefker-Radtke A, de Braud F, Basso U, Calvo E, Bono P, Morse MA, Ascierto PA, Lopez-Martin J, Brossart P, Rohrberg K, Mellado B, Fischer BS, Meadows-Shropshire S, Abdel Saci, Callahan MK, Rosenberg J. Nivolumab Alone and With Ipilimumab in Previously Treated Metastatic Urothelial Carcinoma: CheckMate 032 Nivolumab 1 mg/kg Plus Ipilimumab 3 mg/kg Expansion Cohort Results. J Clin Oncol. 2019 Jul 1;37(19):1608-1616. doi: 10.1200/JCO.19.00538. Epub 2019 May 17. Erratum In: J Clin Oncol. 2019 Aug 10;37(23):2094.</citation>
    <PMID>31100038</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shamseddine A, Zeidan YH, El Husseini Z, Kreidieh M, Al Darazi M, Turfa R, Kattan J, Khalifeh I, Mukherji D, Temraz S, Alqasem K, Amarin R, Al Awabdeh T, Deeba S, Jamali F, Mohamad I, Elkhaldi M, Daoud F, Al Masri M, Dabous A, Hushki A, Jaber O, Charafeddine M, Geara F. Efficacy and safety-in analysis of short-course radiation followed by mFOLFOX-6 plus avelumab for locally advanced rectal adenocarcinoma. Radiat Oncol. 2020 Oct 7;15(1):233. doi: 10.1186/s13014-020-01673-6.</citation>
    <PMID>33028346</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 19, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 19, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Shenzhen People's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Wan He</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor Wan He</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anti-CTLA-4/PD-1 bispecific antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Neoadjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Rectal cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Short-course radiotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

