<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792423</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022P003180</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792423</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Conditionally Increased Output (CIO) Enhanced Ultrasound System</brief_title>
  <official_title>Improving the Performance of Ultrasound Shear Wave Elastography (SWE) in Obese Fatty Liver Disease Patients by Developing a Conditionally Increased Output (CIO) Enhanced Ultrasound System</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GE Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to assess possible bioeffects that may be caused by the use of shear wave&#xD;
      elastography (SWE) with conditionally increased acoustic output pressure (CIO). Bioeffects&#xD;
      will be monitored by of a series of liver function tests (LFTs) with results graded according&#xD;
      to the NCI scale for drug hepatoxicity. LFTs will be collected prior to SWE imaging using&#xD;
      CIO, as well up to 7 days post-imaging. Secondarily, this study aims to understand the degree&#xD;
      to which SWE imaging results have improved with the use of COI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is the most common cause of chronic liver disease in&#xD;
      the United States, with an estimated prevalence of approximately 30%. NAFLD is a disease with&#xD;
      a spectrum that can be categorized as 1) simple steatosis/non-alcoholic fatty liver, defined&#xD;
      as excess liver fat without inflammation, and 2) non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) in&#xD;
      which excess liver fat is associated with inflammation, fibrosis, and healing, ultimately&#xD;
      culminating in cirrhosis. Nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) can progress to conditions&#xD;
      associated with high morbidity and mortality such as portal hypertension, cirrhosis, liver&#xD;
      failure and hepatocellular carcinoma. NASH is currently the second most common indication for&#xD;
      liver transplantation in the United States, and is expected to become the leading cause in&#xD;
      the near future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Liver biopsy is currently accepted as the gold-standard method to detect liver fibrosis,&#xD;
      though it is an invasive procedure with high morbidity and mortality rates. Alternatively,&#xD;
      imaging is useful for NAFLD diagnosis, disease management, and monitoring treatment response.&#xD;
      Several imaging methods are used for these purposes, including ultrasound, MRI, and CT based&#xD;
      techniques. Ultrasound (US) is preferred by many physicians because it is a low-cost&#xD;
      technique that is widely available. Shear wave elastography (SWE) is an ultrasound-based&#xD;
      technique that is commonly used for liver fibrosis staging. When performing ultrasound&#xD;
      imaging, it is known that several patient-related factors may influence the quality of the&#xD;
      image.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In NAFLD patients, several factors including high skin-to-liver capsule distance (SCD) may&#xD;
      change the attenuation and aberration of the acoustic waves, change the quality of the image,&#xD;
      and make diagnosis harder for radiologists. SCD is the distance between skin and Glisson's&#xD;
      capsule, when assessed with standard B-mode ultrasound imaging. In patients with high SCD,&#xD;
      and particularly in patients with abdominal obesity, the shear wave elasticity elastogram box&#xD;
      may not fill properly, which may cause unreliable SWE measurements. Technical failure and&#xD;
      unreliable SWE measurements have been previously reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current FDA guidelines recommend the use of a maximum derated spatial peak temporal&#xD;
      average intensity (ISPTA) of ≤ 720 mW/cm2, and either the maximum MI should be ≤ 1.9 or the&#xD;
      maximum derated spatial peak pulse average intensity (ISPPA) should be ≤ 190 W/cm2. In&#xD;
      addition, clinical justification is required if the TI exceeds 6. Several diagnostic modes&#xD;
      that are clinically used and FDA approved use acoustic output values that approach these&#xD;
      maximum guidelines. These diagnostic modes include acoustic radiation force impulse (ARFI)&#xD;
      based techniques, harmonic imaging techniques, and Doppler based techniques. In the past&#xD;
      decade, the AIUM has published reports on the benefits and limitations of both the TI and MI,&#xD;
      including recommendations that transient increases may be warranted if there were associated&#xD;
      clinical benefit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using the acoustic and thermal limits in current FDA guidelines, it is not always possible to&#xD;
      get reliable SWE measurements. Therefore, conditionally increasing the acoustic pressure of a&#xD;
      SWE system may help clinicians to obtain reliable and accurate SWE results from patients with&#xD;
      abdominal obesity, potentially minimizing the need for liver biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to assess possible bioeffects that may be caused by the use of SWE with&#xD;
      conditionally increased acoustic output pressure (CIO). Bioeffects will be monitored by of a&#xD;
      series of liver function tests (LFTs) with results graded according to the NCI scale for drug&#xD;
      hepatoxicity. LFTs will be collected prior to SWE imaging using CIO, as well up to 7 days&#xD;
      post-imaging. Secondarily, this study aims to understand the degree to which SWE imaging&#xD;
      results have improved with the use of COI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in aspartate transaminase (AST) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day7 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 7 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>AST value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in alanine transaminase (ALT) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day7 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 7 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>ALT value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in alkaline phosphatase (ALP) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day7 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 7 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>ALP value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in IQR/Median ratio between standard and CIO SWE</measure>
    <time_frame>Single visit (1day)</time_frame>
    <description>IQR/median is a commonly accepted variability analysis tool for SWE. We are hoping to understand the variability difference between these two ultrasound modes in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in aspartate transaminase (AST) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day1 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 1 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>AST value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in aspartate transaminase (AST) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day2 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 2 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>AST value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in alanine transaminase (ALT) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day1 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 1 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>ALT value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in alanine transaminase (ALT) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day2 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 2 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>ALT value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in alkaline phosphatase (ALP) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day1 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 1 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>ALP value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference in alkaline phosphatase (ALP) value in U/L unit between pre-imaging and day2 post-imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-ultrasound imaging and 2 day after the ultrasound imaging (within 2 weeks timeframe)</time_frame>
    <description>ALP value difference between pre and post imaging will be collected to monitor potential liver injury effect of the CIO enhanced liver stiffness measurement method in this safety study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver</condition>
  <condition>Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis</condition>
  <condition>Fatty Liver</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>24 healthy adult volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GE ultrasound system with increased acoustic output settings</intervention_name>
    <description>We will perform liver stiffness measurements with standard settings and an increased acoustic output enhanced ultrasound system. Pre and post ultrasound LFTs will be collected to monitor unexpected liver tissue damage.</description>
    <arm_group_label>24 healthy adult volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI 18.5-39.9&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to undergo abdominal ultrasound&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to undergo repeated blood sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable medication and supplement list and dosing for 30 days preceding enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excess alcohol consumption: &gt; 7 units/week (F) or &gt; 14 units/week (M)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of drug induced liver injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior liver transplantation recipient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving drug/placebo in treatment trial now or within 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received systemic chemotherapy within past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed or suspected pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pacemaker, nerve stimulator, or other implanted electronic device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plans to alter medication or supplement list or dosage during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or recent (within 30 days) acute illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent ultrasound contrast administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent alanine transaminase (ALT), aspartate transaminase (AST), or alkaline&#xD;
             phosphatase (ALP) greater than the laboratory upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other factors that the PI considers likely to compromise study endpoints or subject&#xD;
             safety&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anthony Samir, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>617-643-2009</phone>
    <email>asamir@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anthony Samir, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>617-643-2009</phone>
      <email>asamir@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 19, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 19, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Anthony Samir</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Service Chief, Ultrasound, Department of Radiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

