<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619640</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21/360</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619640</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Potential Role of sRAGE, KL-6, and SP-D as Prognostic Factors in Children With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Potential Role of Receptor for Advanced Glycation End-Products, Serum, Krebs Von Den Lungen-6, and Surfactant Protein D as Prognostic Factors in Children With Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS-CoV-2)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Haseki Training and Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Saglik Bilimleri Universitesi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Haseki Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 causes a wide spectrum of clinical illness, from upper respiratory symptoms to&#xD;
      severe respiratory failure and death. Several plasma biomarkers -such as IL-6, C-reactive&#xD;
      protein (CRP), D-dimer, the neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio, and ferritin, among others- have&#xD;
      been studied as markers of disease severity and prognosis. Besides, as alveolar damage&#xD;
      biomarkers such as Surfactant protein D (SP-D), Krebs von den Lungen-6 (KL-6), and soluble&#xD;
      Receptor for Advanced Glycation end products (sRAGE) can be used in lung diseases as well as&#xD;
      COVID-19 pneumonia. The investigators hypothesized that serum SP-D, KL-6 and sRAGE levels&#xD;
      increases in the setting of COVID-19 pneumonia. In this prospective study the investigators&#xD;
      aimed to determine the clinical value of serum KL-6, SP-D and sRAGE levels as a prognostic&#xD;
      marker in children with COVID-19 patients. In the literature review, it has been determined&#xD;
      that there is no study conducted or published in pediatric patients for this purpose, and it&#xD;
      is aimed that our study will be a pioneer study on this subject.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      It aimed to determine the clinical value of serum KL-6, SP-D and sRAGE levels as a prognostic&#xD;
      marker in children with COVID-19 patients.. This study was planned as a case-control study&#xD;
      with patients hospitalized in the Haseki Training and Research Hospital Pediatric Infection&#xD;
      Ward. A total of 150 children, including at least 30 patients in each group were included in&#xD;
      the study. The study group was divided into three groups according to COVID-19 WHO clinical&#xD;
      progression Scale: uninfected (Group 1), mild (Group 2) and moderate (group 3). In order to&#xD;
      investigate the relationship between disease severity and alveolar damage, serum KL-6, SP-D&#xD;
      and sRAGE levels and high sensitive C-reactive protein were measured. These biomarkers levels&#xD;
      were compared between three groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 21, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between SARS-CoV-2 severity and alveolar damage biomarker levels</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples were obtained from all patients on admission. The data set divided into three groups according to COVID-19 WHO Clinical progression scale. The Surfactant protein D, Krebs von den Lungen-6, high sensitive C-reactive protein and soluble receptor for Advanced Glycation end products levels were determined by using ELISA kits. These biomarker levels were compared between three groups by using Kruskal-Wallis test and Tukey post test for multiple comparisons.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">150</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS CoV 2 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Alveolar; Injury</condition>
  <condition>Children</condition>
  <condition>Pneumonia, Viral</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>The study group divided into 3 groups according to COVID-19 WHO Clinical progression scale: Uninfected; No viral RNA detected</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <description>The study group divided into 3 groups according to COVID-19 WHO Clinical progression scale: Ambulatory mild disease Viral RNA detected but asymptomatic course, Symptomatic but not given any medication and Symptomatic given medication</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <description>The study group divided into 3 groups according to COVID-19 WHO Clinical progression scale: Hospitalized moderate disease Hospitalized but no oxygen therapy and Hospitalized and given oxygen by mask or nasal cannula</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      3-5 cc serum was obtained from participants. serum samples were stored at -80° C&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children and adolescents diagnosed as diagnosed SARS-CoV-2 infection and whose parents sign&#xD;
        the informed consent from to participate the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Between 1 month-18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. SARS-CoV-2 PCR positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Not having a chronic disease (cystic fibrosis, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Volunteering to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Healty Control&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Having a chronic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who could not be diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 infection by laboratory and/or&#xD;
             radiological examinations&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Not volunteering to participate in the stud&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gulsen Akkoc, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Haseki Training and Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Haseki Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO Working Group on the Clinical Characterisation and Management of COVID-19 infection. A minimal common outcome measure set for COVID-19 clinical research. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020 Aug;20(8):e192-e197. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30483-7. Epub 2020 Jun 12. Erratum In: Lancet Infect Dis. 2020 Oct;20(10):e250.</citation>
    <PMID>32539990</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Determann RM, Royakkers AA, Haitsma JJ, Zhang H, Slutsky AS, Ranieri VM, Schultz MJ. Plasma levels of surfactant protein D and KL-6 for evaluation of lung injury in critically ill mechanically ventilated patients. BMC Pulm Med. 2010 Feb 16;10:6. doi: 10.1186/1471-2466-10-6.</citation>
    <PMID>20158912</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kommoss FKF, Schwab C, Tavernar L, Schreck J, Wagner WL, Merle U, Jonigk D, Schirmacher P, Longerich T. The Pathology of Severe COVID-19-Related Lung Damage. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2020 Jul 20;117(29-30):500-506. doi: 10.3238/arztebl.2020.0500.</citation>
    <PMID>32865490</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sivapalan P, Bonnesen B, Jensen JU. Novel Perspectives Regarding the Pathology, Inflammation, and Biomarkers of Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Int J Mol Sci. 2020 Dec 28;22(1):205. doi: 10.3390/ijms22010205.</citation>
    <PMID>33379178</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Haseki Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Gulsen Akkoc</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>soluble receptor for Advanced Glycation end products</keyword>
  <keyword>Krebs von den Lungen-6</keyword>
  <keyword>Surfactant protein D</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS CoV 2 Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Pneumonia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia, Viral</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The IPD are available from the principal investigator upon reasonable request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

