<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05628376</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UCL - 151927</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05628376</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>TRAcking Non-small Cell Lung Cancer Evolution Through Therapy (Rx) EVO</brief_title>
  <official_title>TRAcking Non-small Cell Lung Cancer Evolution Through Therapy (Rx) EVO</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University College, London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cancer Research UK</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College, London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      TRACERx EVO is a programme of work using a prospective observational cohort study of&#xD;
      participants with early- and late-stage non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and small cell&#xD;
      lung cancer (SCLC).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      TRACERx EVO is a programme of work linked to an observational cohort study that consists of&#xD;
      early and late-stage lung cancer. Participants will receive anti-cancer therapies (systemic&#xD;
      therapies, radiotherapy and surgery, as per local and national guidelines). This study&#xD;
      involves collecting a large amount of data, covering demographic and clinical&#xD;
      characteristics, data throughout their follow up from the time of baseline/surgery, genomics&#xD;
      and all other laboratory results using their blood, tissue, urine, saliva and stool samples.&#xD;
      Data would also be retrieved from participant medical records. As such, there will be a wide&#xD;
      range of analyses&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2034</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2029</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer, Non-small Cell</condition>
  <condition>Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
    <description>300 participants with early stage resectable I-IIIB NSCLC</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
    <description>200 participants with unresectable late stage IIIB-IIIC or de novo metastatic disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort C</arm_group_label>
    <description>50-100 participants with stage I-IV SCLC.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Tissue, blood, saliva, sputum, urine, stool, nasal curette&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        I-IIIC Non-small cell lung cancer, stage I-IV Small cell lung cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort A, B and C :&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Written Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Agreement to be followed up (including on-study assessments and sample&#xD;
                  collection) every 3 months in the first 2 years and then 6 monthly.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Agreement to be followed up at a TRACERx EVO site&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort A:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants ≥18 years of age, with early stage I-IIIB NSCLC disease who are eligible&#xD;
             for primary surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathologically confirmed NSCLC, or a strong suspicion of cancer on lung imaging&#xD;
             necessitating surgery (e.g., diagnosis determined from frozen section in theatre)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary surgery in keeping with NICE guidelines in (lobectomy, either open or&#xD;
             thoracoscopic), lung parenchymal-sparing operations (segmentectomy or wedge resection)&#xD;
             if a complete resection can be achieved, extensive surgery (bronchoangioplastic&#xD;
             surgery, bilobectomy, pneumonectomy) if necessary to obtain clear margins, hilar and&#xD;
             mediastinal lymph node sampling or en bloc resection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum tumour diameter at least 10mm to allow for sampling of at least two tumour&#xD;
             regions (if 10mm, a high likelihood of nodal involvement on pre-operative imaging&#xD;
             required to meet eligibility according to stage, i.e., T1 N1-3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deemed to be fit for surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considered sufficiently fit for standard of care adjuvant therapy if indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status 0 to 1&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort B:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants ≥18 years of age, with late-stage unresectable stage IIIB and above NSCLC&#xD;
             disease (TNM 8th edition) or presenting with stage IV de novo metastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient tissue (at least 1 region/biopsy), either FFPE or fresh frozen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deemed to be fit for anti-cancer treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status 0 to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort C:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants ≥18 years of age, with any stage SCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient tissue (at least 1 region/biopsy), either FFPE or fresh frozen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deemed to be fit for anti-cancer treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status 0 to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort A, B and C:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other active malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any other* malignancy diagnosed or relapsed at any time, which is currently being&#xD;
                  treated (including by hormonal therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any other* current malignancy or malignancy diagnosed or relapsed within the past&#xD;
                  3 years**.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  *Exceptions are: non-melanomatous skin cancer, stage 0 melanoma in situ, and&#xD;
                       in situ cervical cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  **An exception will be made for malignancies diagnosed or relapsed more than&#xD;
                       2, but less than 3, years ago only if a pre-operative biopsy of the lung&#xD;
                       lesion has confirmed a diagnosis of NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Psychological condition that would preclude informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diagnosis other than NSCLC or SCLC confirmed following surgery or biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of intravenous drug abuse within the last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Confirmed diagnosis of known high-risk infections (e.g., Human Immunodeficiency&#xD;
                  Virus) (HIV), Hepatitis B Virus (HBV), Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) or syphilis&#xD;
                  infection, tuberculosis and Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease) unless participant case is&#xD;
                  of a particular scientific interest and agreed in advance with research staff,&#xD;
                  local mortuary staff and pathologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Contra-indicated co-morbid conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women who are pregnant or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort A:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive margins, incomplete resection or insufficient nodal sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in a neo-adjuvant or adjuvant therapeutic trial with non-standard of&#xD;
             care therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient tissue, i.e., a minimum of two tumour regions unlikely to be obtained for&#xD;
             the study based on pre-operative imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant found to have pre-invasive lesions rather than invasive cancer following&#xD;
             surgery, such as adenocarcinoma in situ or minimally invasive lesions will be&#xD;
             withdrawn. However, the surgical tissue and baseline blood already collected will be&#xD;
             sent to the central laboratory. These participants will not be followed-up in the&#xD;
             study or required to provide any further blood samples. If these participants&#xD;
             subsequently develop invasive cancer, the date of diagnosis and the tumour histology&#xD;
             will be reported on the electronic data capture system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort B/C:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Insufficient tissue, i.e., at least one tissue biopsy to be obtained (Fresh Frozen or&#xD;
        FFPE)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anne Marie Hacker</last_name>
    <phone>02076799010</phone>
    <email>ctc.tracerxevo@ucl.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

