<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05614076</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14422019474770</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05614076</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Performance Of Conserved Chalky White Demineralized Enamel Cavity Margins Versus Totally Removed Carious Margins In Class V Cavities Restored With Composite Resin</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Performance Of Conserved Chalky White Demineralized Enamel Cavity Margins Versus Totally Removed Carious Margins In Class V Cavities Restored With Composite Resin</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to compare the clinical performance of conserved chalky white demineralized&#xD;
      enamel margins with total removal of demineralized enamel margins in class v cavities&#xD;
      restored with composite in patients with acute carious cervical lesions&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      With limited evidence-based information about the clinical performance of conserved white&#xD;
      chalky enamel margins in class v .it is beneficial to compare the newly concept of preserved&#xD;
      the white chalky deminerlized enamel margins using a randomized clinical trial to test the&#xD;
      null hypothesis that this new concept has the same clinical performance as total removal of&#xD;
      demineralized enamel margins in class v cavities restored with composite in patients with&#xD;
      acute carious cervical lesions .The comparator will be the concept of total removal of&#xD;
      demineralized enamel margins in class v cavities restored with composite Patients are&#xD;
      selected according to the eligibility criteria, Local anesthesia will be administered and the&#xD;
      operative field will be isolated before starting the restorative procedure. For the&#xD;
      comparator group, standard class V cavities will be prepared at labial surface with totally&#xD;
      removed carious enamel margins. For interventional group, class V cavity prepared at labial&#xD;
      surface with preserved the chalky demineralized enamel margins then applications of&#xD;
      remineralizing agent(MI paste plus) before the application of resin composite restoration.&#xD;
      Local anesthesia will be administered and the operative field will be isolated before&#xD;
      starting the restorative procedure. For control group, standard class V cavities will be&#xD;
      prepared at labial surface with totally removed carious enamel margins. For experimental&#xD;
      group, class V cavity prepared at labial surface with preserved the chalky demineralized&#xD;
      enamel margins then applications of remineralizing agent(MI paste plus) before the&#xD;
      application of resin composite restoration. both cavities groups restored with resin&#xD;
      composite restorations. The restorations are assessed using the modified USPHS criteria at&#xD;
      the time intervals stated in the outcome measures&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>1:1</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participant and Outcomes Assessor</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>marginal discoloration</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>ordinal criteria scoring system (ordinal)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>marginal discoloration</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>ordinal criteria scoring system (ordinal)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>marginal discoloration</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>ordinal criteria scoring system (ordinal)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>color change</measure>
    <time_frame>3 month</time_frame>
    <description>ordinal criteria scoring system (ordinal)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>color change</measure>
    <time_frame>6 month</time_frame>
    <description>ordinal criteria scoring system (ordinal)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>color change</measure>
    <time_frame>12 month</time_frame>
    <description>ordinal criteria scoring system (ordinal)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">34</enrollment>
  <condition>Class V Dental Caries</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conservation of the demineralized chalky white enamel margin of class V cavities</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>for cavity design in this arm we Conserved the demineralized chalky white enamel margin of class V cavities then application of resin composite restoration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Total removal of demineralized enamel margin of class V cavities</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>for cavity design in this arm is Total removal of demineralized enamel margin of class V cavities and restoration with resin composite</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>conserved chalky white enamel margins of class V cavities</intervention_name>
    <description>during cavity preparation, we conserved chalky white enamel margins of class V cavities and then restored them with resin composite restorations,we assessed the restorations with visual inspection using a mirror and explorer according to USPHS Criteria</description>
    <arm_group_label>Conservation of the demineralized chalky white enamel margin of class V cavities</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Total removal of demineralized enamel margins of class V cavities</intervention_name>
    <description>during cavity preparation, we removed the total chalky white enamel margins of class V cavities and then restored them with resin composite restorations, we assessed the restorations with visual inspection using a mirror and explorer according to USPHS Criteria</description>
    <arm_group_label>Total removal of demineralized enamel margin of class V cavities</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  class V carious lesions in premolars and molars.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vital upper or lower teeth with no signs of irreversible pulpitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of favorable occlusion and teeth are in normal contact with the adjacent&#xD;
             teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deep carious defects (close to pulp, less than 1 mm distance).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periapical pathology or signs of pulpal pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Endodontically treated teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tooth hypersensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Possible prosthodontic restoration of teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heavy occlusion or occlusal contacts or history of bruxism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe periodontal affection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maryam Salim Dawood, master</last_name>
    <phone>00201011270500</phone>
    <email>maryam.salim@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mohamed Refaat El-Bialy, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>00201202552666</phone>
    <email>mohamed.refaat@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of dentistry, Cairo University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11511</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abdalla AI, Garcia-Godoy F. Clinical performance of a self-etch adhesive in Class V restorations made with and without acid etching. J Dent. 2007 Jul;35(7):558-63. doi: 10.1016/j.jdent.2007.02.006. Epub 2007 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>17467137</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alexandria AK, Nassur C, Nobrega CBC, Valenca AMG, Rosalen PL, Maia LC. In situ effect of titanium tetrafluoride varnish on enamel demineralization. Braz Oral Res. 2017 Nov 6;31:e86. doi: 10.1590/1807-3107BOR-2017.vol31.0086.</citation>
    <PMID>29116298</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bayne SC, Schmalz G. Reprinting the classic article on USPHS evaluation methods for measuring the clinical research performance of restorative materials. Clin Oral Investig. 2005 Dec;9(4):209-14. doi: 10.1007/s00784-005-0017-0. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>16421996</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baratieri LN, Ritter AV. Critical appraisal. To bevel or not in anterior composites. J Esthet Restor Dent. 2005;17(4):264-9. doi: 10.1111/j.1708-8240.2005.tb00126.x.</citation>
    <PMID>16231497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen H, Liu X, Dai J, Jiang Z, Guo T, Ding Y. Effect of remineralizing agents on white spot lesions after orthodontic treatment: a systematic review. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2013 Mar;143(3):376-382.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.ajodo.2012.10.013.</citation>
    <PMID>23452972</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kielbassa AM, Ulrich I, Schmidl R, Schuller C, Frank W, Werth VD. Resin infiltration of deproteinised natural occlusal subsurface lesions improves initial quality of fissure sealing. Int J Oral Sci. 2017 Jun;9(2):117-124. doi: 10.1038/ijos.2017.15. Epub 2017 Jun 16.</citation>
    <PMID>28621326</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Korner P, El Gedaily M, Attin R, Wiedemeier DB, Attin T, Taubock TT. Margin Integrity of Conservative Composite Restorations after Resin Infiltration of Demineralized Enamel. J Adhes Dent. 2017;19(6):483-489. doi: 10.3290/j.jad.a39280.</citation>
    <PMID>29152623</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lata S, Varghese NO, Varughese JM. Remineralization potential of fluoride and amorphous calcium phosphate-casein phospho peptide on enamel lesions: An in vitro comparative evaluation. J Conserv Dent. 2010 Jan;13(1):42-6. doi: 10.4103/0972-0707.62634.</citation>
    <PMID>20582219</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koc Vural U, Kerimova L, Kiremitci A. Clinical comparison of a micro-hybride resin-based composite and resin modified glass ionomer in the treatment of cervical caries lesions: 36-month, split-mouth, randomized clinical trial. Odontology. 2021 Apr;109(2):376-384. doi: 10.1007/s10266-020-00550-8. Epub 2020 Sep 9.</citation>
    <PMID>32902766</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brkanovic S, Ivanisevic A, Miletic I, Mezdic D, Jukic Krmek S. Effect of Nano-Filled Protective Coating and Different pH Enviroment on Wear Resistance of New Glass Hybrid Restorative Material. Materials (Basel). 2021 Feb 5;14(4):755. doi: 10.3390/ma14040755.</citation>
    <PMID>33562810</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 7, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 7, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maryam Salim Dawood</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>main investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

