<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619380</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KB-0012/102/13</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619380</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Physiotherapy Treatments in Temporomandibular Joint Dysfunction</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Manual Therapy and Therapeutic Exercises on Mandibular Analgesia, Muscles Relaxation, and Range of Motion in Patients With Masticatory Muscles Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pomeranian Medical University Szczecin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pomeranian Medical University Szczecin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will determinate the influence of four selected physiotherapeutic procedures on the&#xD;
      pain intensity, the bioelectrical activity of the masseter muscle, and the range of&#xD;
      mandibular mobility in patients with TMDs (temporomandibular joint dysfunction).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Temporomandibular joint disorders (TMDs) are a major public health problem as they are one of&#xD;
      the primary sources of chronic pain and impairment of chewing, swallowing, speech, and&#xD;
      breathing function [1]. TMDs are not limited to the temporomandibular joints (TMJ) or&#xD;
      masticatory muscles alone. Still, they are often associated with other symptoms affecting the&#xD;
      head and neck region, such as headache, ear symptoms, and cervical spine dysfunction [1].&#xD;
&#xD;
      In recent years, there has been a significant development in the knowledge of the aetiology,&#xD;
      diagnosis and treatment of TMDs. With the continuous search for better diagnostic and&#xD;
      therapeutic methods, attention has begun to turn to the possibility of using non-invasive&#xD;
      therapeutic strategies in patients with TMDs symptoms. In particular, the collaboration&#xD;
      between dentist and physiotherapist helps in early diagnosis and improves the effectiveness&#xD;
      of therapeutic interventions [2].&#xD;
&#xD;
      The limited number of randomised controlled trials (RCTs) comparing the efficacy of soft&#xD;
      tissue manual therapy and self-therapy interventions prompted the researchers to focus on the&#xD;
      analgesic and myorelaxant use of massage, post-isometric muscle relaxation (PIR) and&#xD;
      therapeutic exercise in female patients with TMDs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main goals of using physiotherapy to treat TMDs are to reduce pain, reduce hypertonic&#xD;
      muscle hyperactivity and improve tension in hypotonic muscles, restore TMJ joint mobility,&#xD;
      and enhance mandibular proprioception and biomechanics. Physiotherapy treatment is usually&#xD;
      reversible and non-invasive. Physiotherapy methods generally include physical techniques&#xD;
      (laser, ultrasound, currents, heat and cold therapy), manual therapy (soft tissue therapy,&#xD;
      joint mobilisations, massage) and therapeutic exercises. Manual therapy and therapeutic&#xD;
      exercise in physiotherapy interventions are increasingly being used by clinicians and&#xD;
      researched due to positive results in TMJ and some musculoskeletal problems [3].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Scientific papers show the effectiveness of masticatory muscle massage in the treatment of&#xD;
      soft tissue disorders, achieving both muscle relaxation, improved tissue blood supply and&#xD;
      joint range of motion and reduced pain [4]. Post-isometric relaxation (PIR) is one of the&#xD;
      most well-known mobilisation techniques using muscle excitation and inhibition phenomena. It&#xD;
      reduces the tension of a muscle or even an entire muscle group, as it inhibits the motoneuron&#xD;
      field of a given muscle and thus leads to reflex relaxation. The reason for this is the&#xD;
      activation of the Golgi tendon organs during contraction. There are 2 PIR targets -&#xD;
      short-term and long-term. The immediate goal is primarily to combat pain and other effects of&#xD;
      static muscle overload and to reduce muscle and connective tissue irritation. On the other&#xD;
      hand, the long-term goal is to restore the expected length and flexibility of contracted&#xD;
      muscles, regain normal joint range of motion and combat joint overload. As a result,&#xD;
      post-isometric muscle relaxation is effective in, among other things, treating increased&#xD;
      tension and reducing TrPs. It is now widely used in everyday clinical practice for both&#xD;
      musculoskeletal therapy and TMDs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the daily practice of physiotherapy, it is imperative to make the patient aware of the&#xD;
      causes and consequences of the resulting complaints and disorders. In addition to patient&#xD;
      education, a key role is played by implementing home self-therapy into the improvement&#xD;
      programme, mainly consisting of the systematic performance of therapeutic exercises (TE)&#xD;
      individually selected to the patient's condition. Thanks to such management, the patient&#xD;
      actively and consciously participates in the healing process and is taught responsibility for&#xD;
      their own health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 20, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double (Participant,Investigator)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain relief</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement on Visual Analogue Scale (VAS). It consists of a line, approximately 100 mm in length, at the left end of the scale &quot;Score 0&quot; witch means &quot;no pain&quot;, at the right end of scale &quot;Score 100mm&quot; witch means &quot;worst imaginable pain&quot;. The average value of all measurements will be analyzed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Electromyography surface of masseter muscle [uV- microvolts] - Rest test</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Examination of the electrical activity of the masseter muscle at rest (Rest Test): the test will be performed on relaxed and relaxed patients. The dental arches remained slightly open during the examination. In order to eliminate the registration of signals related to the electrical activity of the eye circular muscle, these persons had their eyelids closed during the measurements. The patients were instructed not to swallow saliva during the examination and to place their tongue in a resting position. The SEMG values obtained were normalized as the ratio of RLX to MVC.&#xD;
Activity normalized to MVC [%] = Relax - RLX [µV]/ MVC [µV] x 100%&#xD;
SEMG recordings from the masseter muscles will be performed with a two-channel NeuroTrac MyoPlus 2 device with NeuroTrac software (Verity Medical Ltd., Tagoat, Ireland).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Electromyography surface of masseter muscle [uV] - maximal muscle contraction (MVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Study of the bioelectrical activity of the masseter muscle during maximal muscle contraction (MVC): SEMG signal will be recorded in a sitting position, while clenching the teeth, using the greatest possible force, within 5 seconds. The computer program with which the device cooperated registers the minimum and maximum values and calculates the average values of electric potentials. The SEMG values obtained were normalized as the ratio of RLX to MVC.&#xD;
Activity normalized to MVC [%] = RLX [µV]/ MVC [µV] x 100%&#xD;
SEMG recordings from the masseter muscles will be performed with a two-channel NeuroTrac MyoPlus 2 device with NeuroTrac software (Verity Medical Ltd., Tagoat, Ireland).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of the range of motion (ROM) [mm]</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of the range of mobility of the maximum abduction of the mandible (linear measurement from in mm. the upper to the lower incisor). The average value of all measurements will be analyzed.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of the range of the lateral movement of the mandible [mm]</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of the range of mobility of the lateral movements of the mandible. The average value of all measurements will be analyzed.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <condition>Temporomandibular Joint Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Muscle Hypertonia</condition>
  <condition>Myofacial Pain</condition>
  <condition>Analgesia</condition>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Pain</condition>
  <condition>Craniomandibular Osteopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapeutic procedures: auto-therapy (therapeutic exercises)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Specialized therapeutic exercises:&#xD;
Gerry's exercise - Starting position: tongue placed on the palate. Movement: slowly opening and closing the mouth. The number of repetitions: 6 times a day for 10 movements.&#xD;
Active lateral movements of the mandible:&#xD;
Starting position: separable teeth. Movement: slow movements of the lower jaw to the right and left. The number of repetitions: 6 times a day for 10 movements.&#xD;
Protrusion and mouth opening:&#xD;
Starting position: teeth separated. Movement: a) lowering the jaw forward, b) opening the mouth c) closing the mouth d) retracting the lower jaw.&#xD;
Number of repetitions: 6 times a day for 10 movements.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapeutic procedures: manual therapy (massage) and auto-therapy (therapeutic exercises)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Manual therapy of soft tissues in the masseter muscle:&#xD;
Extraoral massage of the masseter muscle (duration 5 minutes)&#xD;
Intraoral massage of the masseter muscle (duration 5 minutes)&#xD;
Functional massage of the masseter muscle (duration 5 minutes)&#xD;
Auto-therapy: The patient will receive instructions on how to perform therapeutic exercises at home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapeutic procedures: manual therapy (PIR) and auto-therapy (therapeutic exercises)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Manual therapy of soft tissues in the masseter muscle:&#xD;
1. Post-isometric relaxation of the masseter muscle (duration 15 minutes).&#xD;
Auto-therapy: The patient will receive instructions on how to perform therapeutic exercises at home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>physiotherapy treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Three different physiotherapy treatments will be used for, to reduce pain and tension in the masseter muscles. The assessment of pain intensity on the VAS scale will be assessed each time after the therapy. After the 5th and 10th day of therapy, it will be measured ROM and sEMG.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapeutic procedures: auto-therapy (therapeutic exercises)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapeutic procedures: manual therapy (PIR) and auto-therapy (therapeutic exercises)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapeutic procedures: manual therapy (massage) and auto-therapy (therapeutic exercises)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>therapeutic exercises</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  myofacial pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  limited mobility of TMJ&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  increased muscle tension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female sex&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  earlier splint therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pharmacotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  rheumatic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  metabolic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  fibromyalgia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mental diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  orthodontic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inflammation in the oral cavity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  masticatory organ injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of stability in the masticatory organ motor system&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Magdalena Gębska, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>914417253</phone>
    <email>mgebska@pum.edu.pl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Musculoskeletal System Rehabilitation, Pomeranian Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Szczecin</city>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kapos FP, Exposto FG, Oyarzo JF, Durham J. Temporomandibular disorders: a review of current concepts in aetiology, diagnosis and management. Oral Surg. 2020 Nov;13(4):321-334. doi: 10.1111/ors.12473. Epub 2020 Jan 25.</citation>
    <PMID>34853604</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>von Piekartz H, Schwiddessen J, Reineke L, Armijo-Olivio S, Bevilaqua-Grossi D, Biasotto Gonzalez DA, Carvalho G, Chaput E, Cox E, Fernandez-de-Las-Penas C, Gadotti IC, Gil Martinez A, Gross A, Hall T, Hoffmann M, Julsvoll EH, Karegeannes M, La Touche R, Mannheimer J, Pitance L, Rocabado M, Strickland M, Stelzenmuller W, Speksnijder C, van der Meer HA, Luedke K, Ballenberger N. International consensus on the most useful assessments used by physical therapists to evaluate patients with temporomandibular disorders: A Delphi study. J Oral Rehabil. 2020 Jun;47(6):685-702. doi: 10.1111/joor.12959. Epub 2020 May 4.</citation>
    <PMID>32150764</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Daniela Biasotto-Gonzalez, Fausto Bérzin., Electromyographic study of patients with masticatory muscles disorders, physiotherapeutic treTMJent (massage), Brazilian Journal of Oral Sciences 3(10), 2004.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ravishankar Krishna, Anoop Sharma, Shobhit Agarwal, Sweekriti Mishra, Sanober Khan, Alternative Therapies in the Treatment of Temporomandibular Disorders, Journal of Dental &amp; Oro-facial Research Vol. 15 , 1,2018.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>manual therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>physiotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>therapeutic exercises</keyword>
  <keyword>masseter muscle</keyword>
  <keyword>pain</keyword>
  <keyword>electromyography</keyword>
  <keyword>range of motion</keyword>
  <keyword>temporomandibular joint</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Temporomandibular Joint Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Temporomandibular Joint Dysfunction Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Muscle Hypertonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Facial Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

