<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615935</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202209065RINA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615935</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Experiential HIV Testing Increasing Testing Related Knowledge and Practice, and Reduce Stigma Toward HIV of Nurses.</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of Experiential HIV Testing to Improve Knowledge and Practice, and Reduce Stigma Toward HIV of Emergency Department Nurses</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized controlled trial design. The investigators plan to recruit about 60 to&#xD;
      70 emergency department nurses from a medical center in Taipei, Taiwan. After completing the&#xD;
      paper consent form, these nurses will be randomly assigned to 2 groups, which are a control&#xD;
      group and an experimental group. The pre-test includes the demographic data sheet, HIV&#xD;
      testing related knowledge and practice scale, and The Health Care Provider HIV/ AIDS Stigma&#xD;
      Scale (HPASS). All nurses will receive a learning material when they finish the pre-test. In&#xD;
      addition, the experimental group will be provided a real HIV testing and counselling by a&#xD;
      researcher. The post-test will be finished one month later of pre-test in the control group,&#xD;
      and one month later while the intervention completed in the experimental group. The&#xD;
      semi-structural interview will be performed to the experimental group to collect and analyze&#xD;
      their opinion toward the experiential HIV testing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This project aims to develop an intervention of &quot;experiential HIV testing&quot; and to verify the&#xD;
      following effects on emergency nurses: (1) Improve HIV testing related knowledge and&#xD;
      practice; (2) Reduce HIV-related stigma; (3) Find out the possible demographic factors that&#xD;
      might affect the effectiveness of experiential HIV Testing. During the intervention, nurses&#xD;
      can directly participate in the whole process of anonymous HIV testing in the role of who&#xD;
      need to be screened, and pre- and post-testing counselling accompanied the education and&#xD;
      discussion will also be provided to them by a researcher. Through the above-mentioned&#xD;
      measures, the knowledge and practices related to the HIV testing could be improved, and the&#xD;
      stigma attitude toward HIV could be reduced through the self-reflection on the testing&#xD;
      process.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 9, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV testing related knowledge and practice</measure>
    <time_frame>one month later</time_frame>
    <description>A self-development scale, &quot;HIV testing related knowledge and practice scale&quot;, is applied to measure the HIV testing related knowledge and practice. There are twenty-eight questions, including True-False questions and multiple-choice questions. One correct answer could get one point, and the total score is 28 points. Higher scores mean a better outcome (having more HIV testing related knowledge and practice) of the participants.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV related stigma</measure>
    <time_frame>one month later</time_frame>
    <description>The questionnaire of &quot;The Healthcare Provider HIV/AIDS Stigma Scale (HPASS)&quot; will be used to measure this outcome. There are thirty questions, each question is scaled from one to six points. The minimum value of the total score is 30 points; the maximum value of the total score is 180 points. Higher scores mean a worse outcome, more stigma toward people living with HIV of the participant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The demographic factors which affect the effectiveness of experiential HIV testing</measure>
    <time_frame>one month later</time_frame>
    <description>Two-way ANOVA(mixed design) will be used to analyze this outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative analysis of post-test interview in experimental group.</measure>
    <time_frame>one month later</time_frame>
    <description>In order to qualitatively analyses and understands the participants' opinions of the experiential learning, four open-ended questions are applied to the interview in the post-test period. The four questions are: &quot;After experiencing HIV testing, what changes in your mind while waiting for the test results?&quot;; &quot;After experiencing HIV testing, does it make you curious about HIV or want to know more about HIV-related knowledge?&quot;; &quot;After experiencing HIV testing, what changes have you felt towards HIV-related stigma?&quot;; &quot;How and what is this experiential learning method different from traditional lecture class?&quot;</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Hiv</condition>
  <condition>HIV Testing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Get a learning material and a experiential HIV Testing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>These participants in the experimental group will be provided a learning material about HIV testing, then an experiential HIV Testing, which includes HIV testing and counselling, education and discussion, and a post-test interviews will be provided.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Get a learning material only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>These participants in the control group will be provided a learning material about HIV testing only. After the post-test, the experiential HIV Testing will be provided to them.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experiential HIV Testing</intervention_name>
    <description>The content of experiential HIV Testing includes HIV testing, counselling, and education and discussion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Get a learning material and a experiential HIV Testing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - have registered nurse license and do clinical care in emergency department&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have registered nurse license but doesn't do clinical care, likes head nurse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  do clinical care in emergency department but doesn't have registered nurse license,&#xD;
             like volunteers or assistant nurse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have experienced non-occupational HIV testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  had been a nurse in HIV/AIDS-focus ward or HIV/AIDS case manager.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>CHENG-RU HE, Bachelor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Taiwan University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>CHENG-RU HE, Bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>+886910174949</phone>
    <email>r08426002@ntu.edu.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>PIAO-YI CHIOU, Doctoral</last_name>
    <phone>+886-2-2312-3456</phone>
    <phone_ext>288427</phone_ext>
    <email>piaoyi@ntu.edu.tw</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>School of Nursing of National Taiwan University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>100</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>PIAO-YI CHIOU, doctoral</last_name>
      <phone>+886-2-23123456</phone>
      <phone_ext>88427</phone_ext>
      <email>piaoyi@ntu.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Taiwan University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Piao-Yi Chiou</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>stigma</keyword>
  <keyword>knowledge</keyword>
  <keyword>Education, nursing</keyword>
  <keyword>situated learning</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

