<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05625685</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1P50MD017347-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05625685</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Equitable Smoking Relapse Prevention</brief_title>
  <official_title>Accelerating Health Equity Via Just-In-Time Adaptive Interventions (JITAIs): Scalable and High Impact mHealth Precision Smoking Relapse Prevention.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bryan W. Heckman</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City of Hope Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Virginia Tech Carilion School of Medicine and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Meharry Medical College</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to test a GPS (Global Positioning System)-enabled&#xD;
      smartphone app (QuitBuddy) in current smokers. The main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Is Quitbuddy a good treatment for quitting smoking and &quot;staying quit&quot;?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Will a second treatment that connects people to help for their social and financial&#xD;
           needs improve Quitbuddy?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  get nicotine lozenges in the mail&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  check in with the study team to report on their quitting progress after 1 day, 1 week, 1&#xD;
           month, 2 months, 3 months, and 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers will compare Quitbuddy to an app made by the National Cancer Institute to see if&#xD;
      Quitbuddy is better for helping people stay quit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tobacco smoking is a primary preventable trans-diagnostic risk factor that if targeted more&#xD;
      effectively, could reduce a wide range of health disparities in prevalence, severity,&#xD;
      treatment efficacy, and mortality across many chronic health conditions (e.g., diabetes,&#xD;
      obstructive sleep apnea), reduce treatment complexity/multi-morbidity, and reduce healthcare&#xD;
      costs up to 80%. The Southeast, in particular, has an urgent need to disrupt the status quo&#xD;
      of tobacco control (&lt;2% The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) recommended&#xD;
      tobacco control appropriations; highest smoking and mortality) driven in large part through&#xD;
      neglected patterns of social determinants of health (SDoH; poverty, access to care) that&#xD;
      disproportionately impact racial and ethnic minorities in the form of greater smoking and&#xD;
      chronic disease rates, and ultimately nearly a decade of life lost. Unfortunately, only 5% of&#xD;
      smoking cessation attempts last at least one year, with lower success among Black smokers&#xD;
      even though they smoke at similar rates and intensity, and make more quit attempts.&#xD;
      Accordingly, mobile health (mHealth) may have particular utility in addressing racial&#xD;
      disparities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Black smokers show high engagement rates with smartphones to access healthcare and greater&#xD;
      adherence to digital interventions, which may facilitate tailoring to meet distinct needs.&#xD;
      There is an urgent need to overcome equity gaps, which will require diversity and inclusion&#xD;
      of individuals from underrepresented races/ethnicities to identify effective treatments.&#xD;
      There is a need for just-in-time adaptive interventions (JITAIs) that 1) can be deployed&#xD;
      rapidly (ideally before craving occurs), 2) effectively prevent or attenuate cravings&#xD;
      quickly, and 3) are amenable to personalized treatment. Quitbuddy, the automated, yet&#xD;
      personalized, JITAI app developed by the investigators, allows patients to prepare for&#xD;
      high-risk situations before they arise, effectively promoting abstinence and preventing&#xD;
      relapse. The overall goals are to optimize smart algorithms, identify personalized relapse&#xD;
      risk, and automatically prompt NRT delivery in a real-time, preemptive manner, upon&#xD;
      approaching personalized high-risk locations. Results from a National Institute on Drug abuse&#xD;
      (NIDA)-funded (K23) pilot randomized controlled trial demonstrated outstanding usability (top&#xD;
      10% of over 500 apps), acceptability (&gt;80% compliance), and technical feasibility (&lt;10% GPS&#xD;
      data loss). The investigators will build upon these promising data by testing effectiveness&#xD;
      in a fully powered and rigorous SMART design with diverse representation of underserved&#xD;
      populations and meeting community needs for SDoH interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims 1 &amp; 2: Evaluate QuitBuddy and SDoH augmentation intervention effectiveness for smoking&#xD;
      cessation and relapse prevention via pragmatic remote SMART design (N=2,090).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected Outcome: Superior 6-month biochemically verified abstinence rates for the QuitBuddy&#xD;
      and SDoH augmentation interventions, relative to controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Aims: Test potential moderators/mediators of the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This approach integrates for the first time established theories of relapse risk,&#xD;
      evidence-based treatment, smartphone/GPS technology, and SDoH. This project offers&#xD;
      high-impact solutions to address health disparities across a wide range of chronic diseases&#xD;
      that disproportionately affect under-served populations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Will employ two interventions as part of a sequential multiple-assignment randomized trial (SMART).&#xD;
First-stage intervention - Participants are randomized to one of two arms, QuitBuddy (a novel smoking cessation app) or Control.&#xD;
Participants will be randomized again after reaching a predefined tailoring variable, operationalized as biochemically verified 24h smoking abstinence within 1-week from target quit date (TQD).&#xD;
Second-stage intervention - Social determinants of health (SDoH) intervention.&#xD;
Participants are randomized to receive either a digital SDoH intervention (powered by findhelp.org and integrated into QuitBuddy) or will receive an emailed list of social service providers in their Zip Code (standard care control).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Abstinence Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report. Participant enters number of cigarettes smoked.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>NRT Compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Self report. Participant enters number of nicotine lozenges used.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cravings</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Self reported number of cravings experienced.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Withdrawal 1-day</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured one day after a participant's target quit-date.</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Nicotine Withdrawal Scale - A nine-item self-report scale for examining the severity of nicotine withdrawal symptoms in a subject. Participants select 0 (none) - 4 (severe) for each of the items. Higher scores correspond to higher perceived severity of withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Withdrawal 1-week</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured one week after a participant's target quit-date.</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Nicotine Withdrawal Scale - A nine-item self-report scale for examining the severity of nicotine withdrawal symptoms in a subject. Participants select 0 (none) - 4 (severe) for each of the items. Higher scores correspond to higher perceived severity of withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Withdrawal 1-month</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured one month after a participant's target quit-date.</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Nicotine Withdrawal Scale - A nine-item self-report scale for examining the severity of nicotine withdrawal symptoms in a subject. Participants select 0 (none) - 4 (severe) for each of the items. Higher scores correspond to higher perceived severity of withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Withdrawal 2-month</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured two months after a participant's target quit-date.</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Nicotine Withdrawal Scale - A nine-item self-report scale for examining the severity of nicotine withdrawal symptoms in a subject. Participants select 0 (none) - 4 (severe) for each of the items. Higher scores correspond to higher perceived severity of withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Withdrawal 3-month</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured three months after a participant's target quit-date.</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Nicotine Withdrawal Scale - A nine-item self-report scale for examining the severity of nicotine withdrawal symptoms in a subject. Participants select 0 (none) - 4 (severe) for each of the items. Higher scores correspond to higher perceived severity of withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Withdrawal 6-month</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured six months after a participant's target quit-date.</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Nicotine Withdrawal Scale - A nine-item self-report scale for examining the severity of nicotine withdrawal symptoms in a subject. Participants select 0 (none) - 4 (severe) for each of the items. Higher scores correspond to higher perceived severity of withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2090</enrollment>
  <condition>Tobacco Use Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Tobacco Dependence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Quitbuddy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be assigned to use a smartphone app (QuitBuddy) that will automatically guide NRT treatment delivery through the integration of ecological momentary assessments (EMA) and GPS into personalized relapse prevention algorithms.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control is intended to approximate the real-world experience where Participants will use The National Cancer Institute's smartphone app (QuitGuide) and will self-manage NRT treatment delivery based on written instructions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quitbuddy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be mailed a one week supply of nicotine lozenges as nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) for their upcoming quit attempt, with the ability to order more as needed. Participants will have a set &quot;Target Quit Date&quot; (TQD) set on Day 8 after enrollment, following one week of ad-lib smoking that comprises the pre-TQD EMA/GPS smoking data collection. GPS guided NRT usage prompts, via hotspot algorithms, will be provided to participants in the Quitbuddy Arm. Participants will contribute four weeks of post-TQD EMA/GPS data to capture lapses and NRT use in real-time. Carbon Monoxide (CO) levels will be tested at each of the six post-TQD remote assessments to provide objective verification of smoking status (i.e., 1 day, 1 week, 1 month, 2 month, 3 month, and 6 month abstinence rates). Computerized data collection methods (RedCap) will be used throughout the study to optimize quality assurance.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Quitbuddy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be mailed a one week supply of nicotine lozenges as nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) for their upcoming quit attempt, with the ability to order more as needed. Participants will have a set &quot;Target Quit Date&quot; (TQD) set on Day 8 after enrollment, following one week of ad-lib smoking that comprises the pre-TQD smoking data collection. Participants will contribute four weeks of post-TQD data to capture lapses and NRT use. CO levels will be tested at each of the six post-TQD remote assessments to provide objective verification of smoking status (i.e., 1 day, 1 week, 1 month, 2 month, 3 month, and 6 month abstinence rates). Computerized data collection methods (RedCap) will be used throughout the study to optimize quality assurance.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SDoH Augmentation</intervention_name>
    <description>The SDoH intervention is based on the findhelp.org online platform, with customization to meet the specific needs of the study and communities being served: includes validated SDoH assessments, personalized social needs searching based on priorities, access to the most comprehensive social service database, and a streamlined closed loop referral system that integrates with workflows.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Quitbuddy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SDoH Control</intervention_name>
    <description>No SDoH intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Quitbuddy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 21 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking at least 10 cigarettes per day for the past year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Literate in English/Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to make a NRT-aided quit attempt within the next week&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy (according to urine pregnancy test)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breastfeeding or planning to become pregnant (self-report)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (past 3 months) cardiovascular trauma: myocardial infarction, stroke&#xD;
             (self-report)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use (past 30 days) of alternative tobacco products (e.g., electronic&#xD;
             cigarettes, smokeless tobacco) or smoking cessation medications (self-report)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bryan W Heckman, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Meharry Medical College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bryan W Heckman, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>7179511275</phone>
    <email>bheckman@mmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Duncan Y Amegbletor, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <email>damegbletor@mmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Meharry Medical College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37208</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bryan W Heckman, Ph.D</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://health-equity-action.org/project/jitais-smoking-relapse-prevention</url>
    <description>Project on the Southeast Collaborative for Innovative and Equitable Solutions to Chronic Disease Disparities website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 1, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 21, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 14, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Meharry Medical College</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bryan W. Heckman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Smoking Cessation</keyword>
  <keyword>Nicotine Replacement Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Ecological Momentary Assessment</keyword>
  <keyword>GPS</keyword>
  <keyword>mHealth</keyword>
  <keyword>Digital Intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Determinants of Health</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

