<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618015</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>60116787-020/49018/13</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618015</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of the Supervised and Home-Based Progressive Resistant Training in Female Total Knee Arthroplasty Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Effectiveness of Supervised and Home-Based Progressive Resistant Training in the Mid-Term Postoperative Period in Female Total Knee Arthroplasty Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pamukkale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pamukkale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Early postoperative rehabilitation programs after TKA aims to provide optimal functional&#xD;
      recovery. The current rehabilitation process in TKA typically includes 2 to 3 months&#xD;
      post-surgery, as the greatest declines in strength and functional performance occur&#xD;
      immediately after surgery. Yet, the content, duration, and intensity of the rehabilitation&#xD;
      programs for the reorganization of physical function after surgery have not yet been fully&#xD;
      clarified. Whether home-based rehabilitation is comparable to supervised rehabilitation in&#xD;
      the midterm period requires further research, as practices after TKA vary. The purpose of&#xD;
      this study is to compare the effectiveness of supervised and home-based progressive&#xD;
      resistance training (PRT) in the midterm postoperative period in female patients undergoing&#xD;
      TKA.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to compare the pain, quadriceps strength, knee function, joint&#xD;
      awareness, and quality of life between supervised or home-based PRT at 3 months after the&#xD;
      total knee arthroplasty.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study design is a single-blinded randomized trial. Both groups received standard&#xD;
      physiotherapy for three months. In the third month postoperatively, supervised and home-based&#xD;
      PRE, which consisted of sixteen sessions of exercise lasting eight weeks initiated. The&#xD;
      clinical outcomes were compared at baseline (third month postoperatively) and the fifth month&#xD;
      postoperative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical outcomes consisted of pain, range of motion (ROM), quadriceps and hip abductor&#xD;
      muscle strength, and WOMAC (Western Ontario and McMaster University Arthritis Index ) score.&#xD;
      The performance-based activity limitation test consisted of the 30-second sit-to-stand test,&#xD;
      the 40-meter fast-paced walk test and the 9-step stair climb test. Joint awareness was&#xD;
      assessed with Forgotten Joint Score-12 (FJS12). The quality of life was evaluated with the&#xD;
      World Health Organization Quality of Life Instrument, Short Form (WHOQOL-BREF).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 16, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 25, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 3, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Due to the nature of the intervention, it is not possible to blind participants or the treating physiotherapist. To reduce the bias risk, the outcome assessor was blinded to treatment allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quadriceps and hip abductor muscles strength</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The muscle strength was assessed with a hand-held dynamometer. For the quadriceps muscle test, the patient was seated on the edge of a hard bed. The dynamometer was placed on the midline of the tibia 5 cm proximal to the lateral malleolus. The patient was asked to force his leg into extension by overcoming the resistance of the dynamometer. For measurement of hip abductors muscle strength, the patient was placed supine and the dynamometer was placed on the lateral side of the leg, 5 cm proximal to the lateral malleolus. The patient was asked to force his leg into extension by overcoming the resistance of the dynamometer. The quadriceps and hip abductor muscles' strength were assessed at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>30s sit-to-stand test</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The total number of sit-to-stand repetitions completed in 30 seconds was recorded. 30s sit-to-stand test is a measurement of lower limb strength and endurance. 30s sit-to-stand test was assessed at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>40m fast-paced walk test</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The 40m fast-paced walking test measures short-distance walking activities. 40m fast-paced walk test was assessed at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stair climbing test</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Functional limitations specific to ascending stairs were assessed with timed stair climbing and descending using a standard 9 steps (16-20 cm). Participants were instructed to climb stairs safely as soon as possible. Stair climbing test was assessed at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knee range of motion (ROM)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The universal goniometer was used to measure active knee flexion and extension while the participants were sitting with their knees hanging down on the edge of a firm bed. Knee ROM was assessed at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knee pain: Visual Analogy Scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Knee pain intensity during rest and activity (walking, sitting-to-standing, climbing stairs) were measured using separate 10 cm pain rating scale, with zero representing no pain at all and 10 representing worst imaginable pain. Knee pain was evaluated at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Western Ontario and McMaster University Osteoarthritis Index (WOMAC)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>WOMAC was used to assess knee functions. WOMAC is a patient-reported, lower extremity-specific questionnaire and includes 24 questions: 17 on physical function, 5 on pain, and 2 on stiffness. WOMAC was evaluated at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fortgotten Joint Score-12 (FJS-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Artificial joint awareness was evaluated with FJS-12. The FJS-12 is a patient-reported outcome scale designed to assess joint awareness in the hips and knees. A five-point Likert response format consisting of a total of 12 questions, with a raw score converted from zero to 100 points, is used. FJS-12 was evaluated at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>World Health Organization Quality of Life Instrument Short Form (WHOQOL-BREF)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life was evaluated with the World Health Organization Quality of Life Instrument, Short Form (WHOQOL-BREF). The WHOQOL-BREF questionnaire is a test used to evaluate the quality of life of healthy individuals and patients and consists of four subscales: physical health, psychological health, social relations and environmental areas. WHOQOL-BREF was evaluated at baseline (third month postoperatively) and after an 8-week intervention (fifth month postoperatively).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Total Knee Arthroplasty</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Supervised progressive resistance training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Supervised PRT was conducted face-to-face at the clinic</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Home-based progressive resistance training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Home-based PRT was conducted at home without supervision</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Supervised progressive resistance training</intervention_name>
    <description>Exercises were performed with cable resistance training machine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Supervised progressive resistance training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Home-based progressive resistance training</intervention_name>
    <description>In the first session, with the help of a physiotherapist, strengthening exercises were shown and taught to the patients. Two weeks after the beginning of the home-based PRT program, patients were called to check whether they were doing the exercises in the home program correctly. After the checking for exercise training, the patients were called by phone every two weeks for follow-up.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Home-based progressive resistance training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  being a woman between the ages of 50-70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  underwent unilateral primary TKA surgery due to knee osteoarthritis three months ago&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  understanding verbal and written instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  revision TKA surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neurological disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  rheumatoid arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  psychiatric problems&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe limitation of knee ROM (knee flexion range &lt; 90°)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  regular hypnotic or anxiolytics usage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  dementia.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gökhan BAYRAK, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Pamukkale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pamukkale University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denizli</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Jakobsen TL, Kehlet H, Husted H, Petersen J, Bandholm T. Early progressive strength training to enhance recovery after fast-track total knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2014 Dec;66(12):1856-66. doi: 10.1002/acr.22405.</citation>
    <PMID>25074397</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Li D, Yang Z, Kang P, Xie X. Home-Based Compared with Hospital-Based Rehabilitation Program for Patients Undergoing Total Knee Arthroplasty for Osteoarthritis: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2017 Jun;96(6):440-447. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000000621.</citation>
    <PMID>27584144</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lopez-Liria R, Padilla-Gongora D, Catalan-Matamoros D, Rocamora-Perez P, Perez-de la Cruz S, Fernandez-Sanchez M. Home-Based versus Hospital-Based Rehabilitation Program after Total Knee Replacement. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:450421. doi: 10.1155/2015/450421. Epub 2015 Apr 16.</citation>
    <PMID>25961017</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Pamukkale University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>UMMUHAN BAS ASLAN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

