<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05610891</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DCL-17-001-pHGG</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>13460625</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05610891</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Novel Targeted Radiotherapy in Pediatric Patients With Inoperable Relapsed or Refractory HGG</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b, Open-Label, Study of a Novel Targeted Radiotherapy in Children, Adolescents and Young Adults With Inoperable Relapsed or Refractory High-Grade Glioma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cellectar Biosciences, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cellectar Biosciences, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this dose finding study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of 2 different&#xD;
      dose levels of CLR 131 in children, adolescents and young adults with relapsed or refractory&#xD;
      high-grade glioma (HGG).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to further evaluate the safety and tolerability of CLR 131 at the&#xD;
      selected doses in children, adolescents and young adults with relapsed or refractory&#xD;
      malignant high-grade glioma. It will also determine the therapeutic activity defined as&#xD;
      progression free survival and overall survival, antitumor activity (treatment response)&#xD;
      defined as the reduction in tumor volume and identify the recommended Phase 2/3 dose of CLR&#xD;
      131 in children, adolescents and young adults with relapsed or refractory HGG.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Drug: CLR 131 is a radio-iodinated therapy comprising a core phospholipid ether (PLE) analogue radiolabeled with iodine-131. CLR 131 exploits the tumor-targeting properties of PLEs to provide targeted delivery of radiation to malignant tumor cells and minimizes radiation exposure to normal tissues.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Evaluation of CLR 131</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed throughout the study to 1-year post-infusion follow-up period through 3 years following completion of treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed by physical examination, performance status, vital signs, laboratory changes over time, and adverse events. Evaluations will use a nonparametric Wilcoxon Signed Rank test and a linear mixed effects modeling will be conducted to evaluate longitudinal changes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy Evaluation for Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 84 post-infusion follow-up period through 3 years following completion of treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the therapeutic activity defined as Progression Free Survival (PFS) using Kaplan Meier estimator. PFS is defined as the time from treatment initiation until disease progression or death.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy Evaluation for Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 84 post-infusion follow-up period through 3 years following completion of treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the therapeutic activity defined as Overall Survival (OS) using log-rank test or Cox Hazard model for comparisons. OS is defined as the duration from first infusion of CLR 131 until death due to any reason.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment Response of CLR 131</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 84 post-infusion follow-up period</time_frame>
    <description>Determine antitumor activity (treatment response) defined as the reduction in tumor volume, measured by MRI scans acquired as FLAIR images and based on the RANO criteria for responses.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose Determination for CLR 131</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 84 post-infusion follow-up period</time_frame>
    <description>Identify the recommended Phase 2/3 dose of CLR 131 in relapsed pHGG patients based on both safety and efficacy assessments as defined by the primary endpoints concluded from this study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dosimetry Evaluation for Total Body and Organ</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours post-infusion and concluding 4 weeks post-initial imaging</time_frame>
    <description>To determine total body and organ dosimetry, together, of CLR 131 in relapsed pHGG patients, measured by conjugate planar whole-body imaging and/or blood collection drawn for radiologic dosimetry analysis for a subset of patients.Organ time/activity integrals will be entered into OLINDA/EXM software57 to produce total body and organ dosimetry values for CLR 131.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor Response to CLR 131</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours post-infusion and concluding 4 weeks post-initial imaging</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the tumor uptake of CLR 131 and utility of SPECT/CT as a potential diagnostic for response. Images will be reconstructed using quantitative SPECT reconstruction methods with compensation for attenuation, scatter and the full collimator-detector response including septal penetration and scatter. A registered CT image will be used as the attenuation map for the SPECT images. Image data will be converted to activity per cubic centimeters using a sensitivity measurement made using a point source in air.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>High-Grade Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pediatric High-Grade Glioma Patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Two dosing cohorts will be explored, 20 mCi/m2 and 25 mCi/m2 and will be administered as two doses separated by 14 days for one cycle. Patients will be eligible to receive a second cycle at the same dose 60 days after receiving the first dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CLR 131</intervention_name>
    <description>CLR 131 will be administered IV (intravenously) at a fixed dose based on patients BSA</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pediatric High-Grade Glioma Patients</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>iopofosine I 131</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously confirmed (histologically or cytologically) high grade glioma that is&#xD;
             clinically or radiographically suspected to be relapsed, refractory, or recurrent for&#xD;
             which there are no standard treatment options with curative potential&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 2 years of age and ≤ 25 years of age at time of consent/assent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If ≥ age 16 years, Karnofsky performance status of ≥ 60. If &lt; age 16 years, Lansky&#xD;
             performance status ≥ 60&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets ≥ 75,000/μL (last transfusion, if any, must be at least 1 week prior to&#xD;
             study registration, and, unless deemed medically necessary, no transfusions are&#xD;
             allowed between registration and dosing)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 750/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL (last transfusion must be at least 1 week prior to study&#xD;
             registration, and, unless deemed medically necessary, no transfusions are allowed&#xD;
             between registration and dosing)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Using the bedside Schwartz formula, estimated GFR (creatinine clearance) &gt; 60&#xD;
             ml/min/1.73m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase &lt; 3 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin &lt; 2 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients enrolling at total dose levels &gt; 30 millicurie (mCi)/m2 must have&#xD;
             availability or ability to collect an autologous hematopoietic stem cell back-up&#xD;
             product prior to CLR 131 administration. At minimum, 2 x 10^6/kg cryopreserved CD34+&#xD;
             cells must be available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient or his or her legal representative is judged by the Investigator to have the&#xD;
             initiative and means to be compliant with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient or his or her legal representative has the ability to read, understand, and&#xD;
             provide written informed consent for the initiation of any study-related procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at&#xD;
             screening and within 24 hours of dosing. It is recommended that female caregivers of&#xD;
             childbearing potential have a negative pregnancy test within one week of dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of childbearing potential must practice an effective method of birth control&#xD;
             while participating on this study to avoid possible damage to the fetus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 1 measurable lesion with longest diameter of at least 10 mm on any imaging&#xD;
             sequence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with previously known neurological deficits must be clinically stable at time&#xD;
             of enrollment and able to complete all study related procedures. Patients with&#xD;
             documented or newly diagnosed neurological deficits will be enrolled at the&#xD;
             investigator's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If patient receives steroids for neurological symptom control, the dose must be stable&#xD;
             (unchanged for three weeks prior to screening) or on a steroid tapering regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antitumor therapy or investigational therapy, within 2 weeks of registration. For&#xD;
             certain types of radiation (craniospinal, total abdominal, whole lung [spot&#xD;
             irradiation to skull-based metastases is not considered craniospinal radiation for the&#xD;
             purposes of this study]), at least 3 months must have elapsed. n.b. Patients&#xD;
             participating in non-interventional clinical trials (i.e., non-drug) are allowed to&#xD;
             participate in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to iodine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other concomitant serious illness or organ system dysfunction (including cardiac&#xD;
             and pulmonary dysfunction) that in the opinion of the Investigator would either&#xD;
             compromise patient safety or interfere with the evaluation of the safety of the test&#xD;
             drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 6 weeks of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of human immunodeficiency virus or uncontrolled, serious, active&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breast-feeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jarrod Longcor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Chief Operating Officer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kate Oliver</last_name>
    <phone>608-327-8125</phone>
    <email>clinical@cellectar.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Children's Cancer Center, Baylor College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Foster, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin, Carbone Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mario Otto, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 7, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 7, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 8, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The IPD will be made available upon request of NCI, the funding agency partner. This has not yet been decided.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

