<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05790200</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AK104-IIT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05790200</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cadonilimab (AK104) in the Treatment of Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Clinical Study of Cadonilimab (AK104) Combined With Chemotherapy in the Treatment of PD-1 Inhibitor Resistant Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wuhan Union Hospital, China</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wuhan Union Hospital, China</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a phase II clinical study of Cadonilimab (AK104) combined with chemotherapy in&#xD;
      the treatment of PD-1 inhibitor-resistant nasopharyngeal carcinoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of Cadonilimab combined with&#xD;
      chemotherapy in the treatment of PD-1 inhibitor-resistant nasopharyngeal carcinoma as the&#xD;
      second line and above. This study is a single-arm, phase II clinical study. It is planned to&#xD;
      enroll about 30 patients with PD-1 inhibitor resistant nasopharyngeal carcinoma. PD-Ll CPS&#xD;
      (&lt;50% vs&gt;50%, subjects whose PD-Ll expression could not be evaluated were classified as&lt;50%)&#xD;
      was used as the stratification factor. The study will set up a safety induction period. It is&#xD;
      planned to enroll about 6 PD-1 inhibitor resistant subjects first, and the researchers will&#xD;
      conduct a preliminary safety assessment. If the safety and tolerability are good, and the&#xD;
      preliminary curative effect signal is observed, it will enter the extended group period. When&#xD;
      about 15 subjects are selected, effectiveness analysis will be carried out. If 6 of the 15&#xD;
      subjects with severe side effects can not tolerate, the researcher may stop the group of&#xD;
      subjects after discussion. In case of poor safety, the researcher decided to revise or stop&#xD;
      the study after discussion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 22, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 22, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Event(AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization to the end of the study，the evaluation lasts for 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The type, frequency, severity, timing, seriousness, and relationship to study therapyclinical significance</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate，ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>The last subject completes at least 24 weeks of follow-up (or disease progression)</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of patients whose tumor volume is reduced to 30% and can be maintained for more than 4 weeks,Based on RECIST v i I Assessed ORR</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival，PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>The last subject completes at least 24 weeks of follow-up (or disease progression)</time_frame>
    <description>The time from the beginning of the patient's treatment to the disease progression or death for any reason.Based on RECIST v i I Assessed PFS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival,OS</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The time from the patient receiving treatment to the death of the patient for any reason,OS evaluated according to RECIST vi. I</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progress，TTP</measure>
    <time_frame>The last subject completes at least 24 weeks of follow-up (or disease progression)</time_frame>
    <description>The time from the beginning of the patient's treatment to the occurrence and progression of the tumor</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cadonilimab (AK104) combined with chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cadonilimab (200 mg, administered on the first day of each cycle, Q3W, until there is no clinical benefit)+platinum-based chemotherapy, Q3W, 4-6 cycles), every 3 weeks (21 days) is a treatment cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cadonilimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Cadonilimab (200 mg, administered on the first day of each cycle, Q3W, until there is no clinical benefit)+platinum-based chemotherapy, Q3W, 4-6 cycles), every 3 weeks (21 days) is a treatment cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cadonilimab (AK104) combined with chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AK104</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The age at the time of enrollment is more than 18 years old and less than 75 years&#xD;
             old, both male and female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The Eastern Cancer Cooperation Organization (ECOG) physical fitness score was 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The expected survival period is more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Nasopharyngeal carcinoma confirmed by histology or cytology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subject has previously received treatment with PD-1 inhibitor and failed without&#xD;
             indication of radical local treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        According to the evaluation standard of curative effect of solid tumor, RECIST v l L At&#xD;
        least one measurable lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Except for nasopharyngeal carcinoma, the subjects had other malignant tumors within 2&#xD;
             years before enrollment. Subjects with other tumors that have been cured by local&#xD;
             treatment, such as basal or cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, superficial bladder&#xD;
             cancer, cervical or breast cancer in situ, are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. He participated in the treatment of experimental drugs within 4 weeks before the first&#xD;
             study administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with active autoimmune diseases that require systematic treatment in the past&#xD;
             two years (such as the use of disease improvement drugs, corticosteroids,&#xD;
             immunosuppressive therapy), and replacement therapy (such as thyroxine, insulin, or&#xD;
             physiological corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary&#xD;
             insufficiency) are not considered as a systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have a history of immune deficiency; HIV antibody test positive; At present, systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids or other immunosuppressants are being used for a long time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active tuberculosis (TB) is known. Subjects suspected of active TB should be excluded&#xD;
             from active TB.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The history of allogeneic organ transplantation and allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell&#xD;
             transplantation are known.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The untreated active hepatitis B subjects (HBsAg positive and HBV-DNA more than 1000&#xD;
             copies/ml (200 IU/ml) or higher than the lower detection limit, whichever is higher)&#xD;
             are required to receive anti hepatitis B virus treatment during the study treatment&#xD;
             period; Active hepatitis C subjects (HCV antibody positive and HCV-RNA level higher&#xD;
             than the lower limit of detection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Major surgical operation or serious injury occurred within 30 days before the first&#xD;
             administration, or major surgical operation planner (determined by the researcher)&#xD;
             within 30 days after the first administration; Minor local operations (excluding&#xD;
             central venous catheterization via peripheral vein puncture) were performed within 3&#xD;
             days before the first administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. There is central nervous system metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. There are currently uncontrolled concomitant diseases, including but not limited to&#xD;
             symptomatic congestive heart failure (grade 2 and above determined according to the&#xD;
             functional classification of the New York Heart Association), unstable angina&#xD;
             pectoris, acute myocardial ischemia, poorly controlled arrhythmia, decompensated liver&#xD;
             cirrhosis, nephrotic syndrome, uncontrolled metabolic disorder, severe active peptic&#xD;
             ulcer disease or gastritis, Mental illness/social condition that may limit the&#xD;
             subject's compliance with the research requirements or affect the subject's ability to&#xD;
             provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. There was a history of myocarditis, cardiomyopathy and malignant arrhythmia in the&#xD;
             past. Unstable angina pectoris, congestive heart failure or vascular disease (such as&#xD;
             aortic aneurysm or peripheral venous thrombosis requiring surgical repair) that needs&#xD;
             hospitalization within 12 months before the first administration of the drug, or other&#xD;
             cardiac damage that may affect the safety evaluation of the study drug (such as poorly&#xD;
             controlled arrhythmia, myocardial infarction or ischemia); There is a history of&#xD;
             esophageal and gastric varices, serious ulcer, wound healing, gastrointestinal&#xD;
             perforation, abdominal pain, gastrointestinal obstruction, abdominal abscess or acute&#xD;
             gastrointestinal bleeding within 6 months before the first administration; Any&#xD;
             arterial thromboembolic event occurred within 6 months before the first&#xD;
             administration, including venous thromboembolic generation of NC I CTCAE 5.0 grade 3&#xD;
             and above, transient ischemic attack, cerebrovascular accident, hypertensive crisis or&#xD;
             hypertensive encephalopathy; Acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
             disease occurred within 1 month before the first administration; There is currently&#xD;
             hypertension and after treatment with oral antihypertensive drugs, the systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure is more than 160 mmHg or the diastolic blood pressure is less than 100 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Have a history of severe bleeding tendency or coagulation dysfunction; One month&#xD;
             before the first administration, there were blood symptoms with significant clinical&#xD;
             significance, including but not limited to gastrointestinal bleeding, hemoptysis,&#xD;
             screening imaging showed that the tumor wrapped around important blood vessels or had&#xD;
             obvious necrosis and cavity, and the researcher believed that participating in the&#xD;
             study might cause bleeding risk;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The toxicity of previous anti-tumor treatment has not been relieved, which is defined&#xD;
             as that the toxicity has not returned to the level 0 or 1 of NC l CTCAE 5.0, or the&#xD;
             level specified in the inclusion/exclusion criteria, except for the sequelae of hair&#xD;
             loss and previous lead treatment related neurotoxicity. Subjects (such as hearing&#xD;
             loss) who have irreversible toxicity and are not expected to worsen after&#xD;
             administration of the study drug may be included in the study after consultation with&#xD;
             the medical examiner. Subjects with long-term toxicity caused by radiotherapy that&#xD;
             cannot be recovered according to the judgment of the researcher may be included in the&#xD;
             study after consultation with the medical supervisor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. The live vaccine was vaccinated within 30 days before the first administration, or was&#xD;
             planned to be vaccinated during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Known allergy to any component of any study drug; A history of severe hypersensitivity&#xD;
             to other monoclonal antibodies is known.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Known history of mental illness, drug abuse, alcohol or drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any previous or current disease, treatment, or laboratory test abnormality may confuse&#xD;
             the results of the study, affect the full participation of the subject in the study,&#xD;
             or participation in the study may not be in the best interests of the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Local or systemic diseases caused by non-malignant tumors, or diseases or symptoms&#xD;
             secondary to tumors, which can lead to higher medical risk and/or uncertainty of&#xD;
             survival evaluation, such as tumor-like leukemia reaction (white blood cell count&gt;20 X&#xD;
             109/L or cachexia performance (such as known weight loss of more than 10% in the 3&#xD;
             months before screening), etc&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yang Kunyu, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>13995595360</phone>
    <email>yangkunyu@hust.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuhan</city>
        <state>Hubei</state>
        <zip>430000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yang Kunyu, doctor</last_name>
      <phone>13995595360</phone>
      <email>yangkunyu@hust.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 1, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 27, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 27, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 27, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Wuhan Union Hospital, China</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>kunyu yang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 18, 2022</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/00/NCT05790200/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

