<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05629117</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>No.1738/UN25.8/KEPK/DL/2022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05629117</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) Combined With Peer Support Education in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) Combined With Peer Support Education in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Taipei Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Taipei Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study to investigate the effects of personalized diabetes text messaging&#xD;
      (DB-TEXT) combined with PSE in patients with type 2 diabetes. This study is an&#xD;
      assessor-blinded, three-arm, parallel randomized controlled trial. Additionally, the&#xD;
      investigators will use the CONSORT guidelines to report of trial finding. A diabetes&#xD;
      management centers in East Java Province will be recruited for the participants from December&#xD;
      2022 to March 2023. The investigators will include participants who had been diagnosed with&#xD;
      poorly controlled type 2 diabetes (having HbA1C level of &gt; 7% in the past three months), and&#xD;
      who were 17 years or older (the legal age to provide informed consent in Indonesia) and&#xD;
      having their own mobile phone. People who could not read or write Indonesian; had medical&#xD;
      diagnostic with cognitive impairments, psychiatric disorders, or were diagnosed with cancer&#xD;
      before the study will be excluded from the study. The outcomes of the study including&#xD;
      demographic and disease characteristic, clinical outcomes, fatigue, sleep quality,&#xD;
      depression, and quality of life. For the clinical outcomes, will be measured in laboratory&#xD;
      test in diabetes management centers. Fatigue level will be measured using the&#xD;
      Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory-20 (MFI-20), sleep quality will be measured using a&#xD;
      Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), the Beck Depression Inventory-Second Edition (BDI-II)&#xD;
      will be used to measure the depression level, and the Diabetes Quality of Life-Brief Clinical&#xD;
      Inventory (The DQoL-BCI) will be used to assess the quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our early component network meta-analysis (CNMA) study showed that short message service&#xD;
      (SMS) and peer support education (PSE) are the most effective component of digitally assisted&#xD;
      intervention in improving HbA1C level in type 2 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purposes:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study to investigate the effects of personalized diabetes text messaging&#xD;
      (DB-TEXT) combined with PSE in patients with type 2 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is an assessor-blinded, three-arm, parallel randomized controlled trial (RCT).&#xD;
      Additionally, the investigators will use the CONSORT guidelines to report of trial finding. A&#xD;
      diabetes management centers in East Java Province will be recruited for the participants from&#xD;
      December 2022 to March 2023. The investigators will include participants who had been&#xD;
      diagnosed with poorly controlled type 2 diabetes (having HbA1C level of &gt; 7% in the past&#xD;
      three months), and who were 17 years or older (the legal age to provide informed consent in&#xD;
      Indonesia) and having their own mobile phone. People who could not read or write Indonesian;&#xD;
      had medical diagnostic with cognitive impairments, psychiatric disorders, or were diagnosed&#xD;
      with cancer before the study will be excluded from the study.The outcomes of the study&#xD;
      including demographic and disease characteristic, clinical outcomes, fatigue, sleep quality,&#xD;
      depression, and quality of life. For the clinical outcomes, will be measured in laboratory&#xD;
      test in diabetes management centers. Fatigue level will be measured using the&#xD;
      Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory-20 (MFI-20), sleep quality will be measured using a&#xD;
      Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), the Beck Depression Inventory-Second Edition (BDI-II)&#xD;
      will be used to measure the depression level, and the Diabetes Quality of Life-Brief Clinical&#xD;
      Inventory (The DQoL-BCI) will be used to assess the quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 26, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 19, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 19, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in HbA1C level</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1C level of participants will be assessed in the laboratory test in hospital</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in fasting blood glucose level</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, week 1 to week 12 (during the intervention), 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood glucose level of participants will be assessed using glucometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Lipids level including total cholesterol, Low Density Lipoprotein (LDL), High Density Lipoprotein (HDL) , and triglycerides</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The total cholesterol, LDL, HDL, and triglycerides of the participants will assessed in the laboratory test in hospital</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Blood Pressure Level including Systolic blood pressure (SBP) and Diastolic blood pressure (DBP)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Blood pressure of participants will be measured using sphygmomanometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fatigue levels of participants will be assessed using a Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory-20 (MFI-20). MFI-20 contains 20 items and five subscales, general fatigue, physical fatigue, reduced motivation, reduced activity, and mental fatigue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Sleep Quality</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep quality of the participants will be measured using The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI). PSQI assesses self-reported sleep quality and sleep disturbance in the preceding month.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The depression levels of participants will be assessed using the Beck Depression Inventory-Second Edition (BDI-II). There are 21 items on the BDI-II that measure subjective depression symptoms over the preceding 2 weeks</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life of the participants will be measured using the Diabetes Quality of Life-Brief Clinical Inventory (The DQoL-BCI). DQoL-BCI contains 15 questions. Using a Likert scale of 5 points, participants can assess their satisfaction with each DQoL-BCI item (1=Very Dissatisfied/All the Time, 2=Moderately Dissatisfied/Sometimes, 3=Neither/Sometimes, and 4=Moderately Satisfied/Very Seldom).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">83</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) combined with Peer Support Education Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who are assigned to the DB-TEXT+PSE group will receive personalized short text message services twice weekly at approximately noon on Monday and Thursday for three months (12 weeks). Additionally they will receive peer support education weekly during three month.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants in the Personalized DB-TEXT group will receive the personalized short text message twice weekly at approximately noon on Monday and Thursday for three months (12 weeks).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Health education related to diabetes management will be provided to the control group once a month during three months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) combined with Peer Support Education</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients who are assigned to the DB-TEXT+PSE group will receive personalized short text message services twice weekly at approximately noon on Monday and Thursday for three months (12 weeks). Furthermore, they will receive the peer support education weekly from the peer supporter by telephone during three months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) combined with Peer Support Education Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Personalized Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT) Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who had been diagnosed with poorly controlled type 2 diabetes (having&#xD;
             HbA1C level of &gt; 7% in the past three months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants ho were 17 years or older (the legal age to provide informed consent in&#xD;
             Indonesia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having their own mobile phone&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People who could not read or write Indonesian&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had medical diagnostic with cognitive impairments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric disorders, or were diagnosed with cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taipei Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei City</city>
        <state>Xinyi District</state>
        <zip>100</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 28, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Taipei Medical University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hsiao-Yean Chiu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes Text Messaging (DB-TEXT), peer support education, type 2 diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

