<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796401</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D22-P006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796401</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficiency of a Composite Personalised Care on Functional Outcome in Early Psychosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>PSYCARE</acronym>
  <official_title>PsyCARE Trial - &quot;Efficiency of a Composite Personalised Care on Functional Outcome in Early Psychosis : A Prospective Randomised Controlled Trial &quot;</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier St Anne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier St Anne</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic psychosis, including schizophrenia is now viewed as a progressive disorder where&#xD;
      cognitive deficits predate the clinical onset. Early intervention programs improve the&#xD;
      general outcome with staged care strategies, supporting the view that the period before and&#xD;
      around the first episode of psychosis is a window of opportunity for improving its functional&#xD;
      recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pioneering epigenetic analyses indicate that psychosis onset involves oxidative stress and&#xD;
      inflammation suggesting that neuroprotective strategies could limit or even prevent the onset&#xD;
      of or the transition into a chronic disorder. Several biological factors associated with the&#xD;
      emergence of psychosis can all be rectified by using safe and easily accepted supplements&#xD;
      including alterations folate deficiency/hyperhomocysteinemia; redox imbalance and deficit in&#xD;
      polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA). The prevalence of these anomalies (20-30%) justifies a&#xD;
      systematic detection and could guide personalised add-on strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cognitive remediation improves quality of life (QoL) and functional outcome in patients with&#xD;
      chronic psychosis. It would even be more efficacious in the early phase of psychosis by&#xD;
      tackling the negative impact of psychosis on education achievement and employment. However,&#xD;
      cognitive dysfunctions are often overlooked in patients at ultra-high risk (UHR) for&#xD;
      psychosis and patient with a first episode of psychosis (FEP) and cognitive remediation is&#xD;
      not always accessible. New technologies can provide us with youth-friendly, non-stigmatising&#xD;
      tools, such as applications with cognitive strategies, motivational tools and functioning&#xD;
      guidance personalised according to the need of each individual. Patients can have access to&#xD;
      it, wherever they live.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Early psychosis can be associated with inflammation, metabolic deficiency, as well as early&#xD;
      structural brain anomalies that reflect brain plasticity abilities and could influence the&#xD;
      prognosis and response to cognitive training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study hypothesis is that promoting neuroplasticity by cognitive training and personalised&#xD;
      virtual psychoeducation guidance could attenuate or reverse early cognitive deficits and&#xD;
      improve the overall functional outcome in young patients UHR or FEP and that this effect is&#xD;
      modulated by individual brain plasticity abilities. The overall objective of PsyCARE_trial is&#xD;
      to improve early intervention in psychosis by providing a composite personalised care (CPC)&#xD;
      that will enable personalised cognitive training and psychoeducation guidance, adapted to&#xD;
      individuals' needs, cognitive abilities and biological background.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 15, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 15, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 15, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Phase III, Prospective Randomised Open, Blinded End-point (PROBE) controlled trial stratified according to the developmental burden and centre, with 2x2 factorial designs (equivalent to a 4-arms clinical trial) in a 1:1:1:1 ratio.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Global functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>3 to 4 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Global functioning will be assessed using the Personal and Social Performance Scale (PSP), a well-validated tool for the measurement of social functioning previously used in early psychosis.&#xD;
PSP is a 100-point single-item rating scale (minimum value 1; maximum value: 100). The scale evaluates four main areas: 1) socially useful activities; 2) personal and social relationships; 3) self-care; and 4) disturbing and aggressive behaviours during a determined reference period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Persistence of efficacy on global functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Score on the Personal and Social Performance Scale (PSP)&#xD;
PSP is a 100-point single-item rating scale (minimum value 1; maximum value: 100). The scale evaluates four main areas: 1) socially useful activities; 2) personal and social relationships; 3) self-care; and 4) disturbing and aggressive behaviours during a determined reference period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Persistence of efficacy on global functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Scores at Global Functioning Scale-Social and Role [120], measured at V2 and V3. This scale provides a 1 to 10 score separately for social role and for functioning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (1)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Comprehensive Assessment of At Risk Mental State (CAARMS) CAARMS evaluates seven dimensions of symptomatology. It provides operational criteria to categorise subjects as 'at-risk' or as psychotic (psychosis threshold) on the basis of the first subscale (10 min), 'positive symptoms' encompassing four sub-scales (Unusual Thought Content, Non-Bizarre Ideas, Perceptual Abnormalities, Disorganised Speech)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (2)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>- SOFAS (Social and Occupational Functioning Assessment Scale or EFSP. SOFAS specifically estimates social functioning on a scale between 0 and 100.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (3)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>- MADRS (Montgomery-Asberg depression scale). MADRS is a 10 -item scale that evaluates different aspects of depressive symptomatology. It provides a good estimation of the severity of depression and is sensitive to change.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (4)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>- Brief Psychiatric Rating Scale (BPRS). BPRS is a scale that evaluates general psychiatric symptomatology.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (5)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>PANSS (Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale) PANSS is a 30-item scale widely used in schizophrenia research to assess positive and negative psychotic dimensions as well as general symptomatology</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (6)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Global Impression (CGI) scale. CGI estimates the current severity, of illness on a 7-point scale, as well as evolution and therapeutic index in reference to the clinicians past experiences of similar patients (3 items).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care (CPC) on clinical outcome (7)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, then 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Global Impression (CGI) scale. CGI estimates the current severity, of illness on a 7-point scale, as well as evolution and therapeutic index in reference to the clinicians past experiences of similar patients (3 items).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of Composite Personalised Care on linguistic and discourse markers</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The recording of the interview will allow to extract reliable linguistic metrics that will be processed semi-automatically.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on neurological soft signs (1)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Neurological Soft Signs rating scale (NSS) assesses five factors: motor coordination, motor integration, sensory integration, quality of lateralization and involuntary movements or posture; as well as extrapyramidal symptoms (Simpson Angus Scale) and lateralization (Edinburgh questionnaire).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on neurological soft signs (2)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Electronic Neurological Soft Signs (eNNS) This device incorporates a new, tablet-based and clinically suitable app (behavioral tasks), including tasks designed to probe balance of excitation/inhibition (multi-finger tapping task), body scheme tasks where finger posture recognition is measured and visuomotor sequence learning under variable cognitive load (using visual attentional distractors).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive complaints</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective Scale to Investigate Cognition in Schizophrenia (SSTICS) is a 21-item Likert-type scale that allows a quantitative approach of cognitive complaint.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Verbal learning and memory)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Hopkins Verbal Learning Test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Flexibility)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>TMT A/B (Reitan, 1959)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Social cognition)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Consensus autour de la COgnition Sociale (CLACOS) (PerSo)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Selective attention)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 to 4 Month and 6 to 8 Month after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>D2-R test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Verbal long-term memory)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Hopskins Verbal Learning Test (HVLT) delayed recall</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Visuospatial learning and memory)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 to 4 Month and 6 to 8 Month after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Brief Visuospatial Memory test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Planning abilities)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Shopping test (Martin 1972)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Speed processing)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale (WAIS) (code)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Inhibition control)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Stroop (Incompatibility)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Visuospatial long-term memory)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 to 4 Month and 6 to 8 Month after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Brief Visuospatial Memory test (BVMT) delayed recall</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on cognitive functions (Working Memory)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale (WAIS) (Digit span)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficiency of composite personalised care on motivation</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral inhibition system (BIS) and behavioral activation system (BAS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Embodiment ability in virtual reality environment</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Embodiment ability in virtual reality environment will be assessed using a simulation of two districts of a lively city via the Vive Pro virtual reality kit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of Composite Personalised Care on Health-related quality-of-life (1)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Short Form -12 items quality of life questionnaire (SF-12) SF-12 is a multipurpose self-report measure of both physical and mental health status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of Composite Personalised Care on Health-related quality-of-life (2)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>European Quality of Life - 5 Dimensions - 5 Levels (EQ-5D-5L)&#xD;
EQ-5D-5L investigates 5 dimensions: mobility, self care, usual activities, pain/discomfort, anxiety/depression. These 5 dimensions are rated on 5 levels ranging from no problems to extreme problems.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of Composite Personalised Care on medication adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline, 3 to 4 months and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Medication adherence (MARS) is a short assessement (5 items) of the adherence to medication</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of the program for the e-Health application</measure>
    <time_frame>3 to 4 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>amount of time spent on the application</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient's satisfaction with the e-health application</measure>
    <time_frame>3 to 4 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>satisfaction score measured by the User Version of the Mobile Application Rating Scale (uMARS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level and changes of biological markers (metabolism of monocarbon compounds)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>dosage of folates, B12 vitamin, homocysteine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level and changes of biological markers (lipid membranes)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>lipid composition of the red blood cells membrane, including the major lipid classes, such as phosphatidylcholine (PC), phosphatidylserine (PS), sphingomyelin (SM), phosphatidylethanolamine (PE), PE plasmalogen and their molecular species)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Longitudinal epigenetic and seric changes associated with outcome (1)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of RNA (messenger RNA, microRNA, long non-coding RNA) will be assessed using next generation sequencing methods.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Longitudinal epigenetic and seric changes associated with outcome (2)</measure>
    <time_frame>at baseline and 6 to 8 months after the beginning of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of RNA (messenger RNA, microRNA, long non-coding RNA) will be assessed using next generation sequencing methods.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-effectiveness of Composite Personalised Care</measure>
    <time_frame>at the end of the follow-up, up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Incremental cost-effectiveness ratios (ICER) will assess the efficiency of CPC vs. TAU (overall and by component). They will be expressed in cost per quality-adjusted life-years (QALY) gained and in cost per PSP point gained.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Budgetary impact analysis of the generalization of Composite Personalised Care</measure>
    <time_frame>at the end of the follow-up, up to 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Total costs and health benefits associated with generalizing CPC will be assessed and compared to TAU over a 5-year period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Psychosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive training</intervention_name>
    <description>Cognitive reinforcement using digital applications (PSYCARE application) during 12 weeks&#xD;
+/- virtual reality based cognitive remediation application : 24 sessions over 12 weeks (only for patients who have a higher cognitive deficits (TMTB score &gt;110s))</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Personalized neuroprotective strategies : Vitamin B12, folinic acid, Omega 3, NAC</intervention_name>
    <description>Personalised neuroprotective medication adapted to the individual's biological profile :&#xD;
Vitamin B12 : 500 micrograms per day&#xD;
Folinic acid : 50 mg per day&#xD;
Omega 3 : 1380 mg EicosaPentaenoic Acid (EPA) + 1140 mg DocosaHexaenoic Acid (DHA) per day&#xD;
N-acetyl-cysteine (NAC) : 2400 mg per day&#xD;
duration of supplementation(s) : 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment as usual (TAU)</intervention_name>
    <description>Treatment as usual (TAU), including a standardised psycho-education program with a group cognitive behavioural therapy (e.g. I_Care - You Care) and, in FEP only, second generation antipsychotic from a restricted list (following the recommendations www.orygen.org.au)</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAU + personalized neuroprotective strategies + cognitive training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescent and young adults, both sexes, aged 15 to 30 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  From Community or academic clinics,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Characterised as UHR or FEP according to the first four items of the Comprehensive&#xD;
             Assessment of At Risk Mental State (CAARMS) (first subscale for psychosis) [8] during&#xD;
             the last 12 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed and written signed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with regular health insurance&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe and unstabilised medical conditions,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient level in reading and/or French language,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current participation in another intervention trial,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enforced hospitalization ,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intellectual Deficiency (i.e. Intelligence Quotient&lt;70), and / or sensorimotor&#xD;
             deficits incompatible with the cognitive training,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Former treated episode of psychosis, chronic schizophrenia, schizoaffective, or&#xD;
             Bipolar disorder,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current severe depression (i.e. MADRS &gt; 34),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving therapeutic levels of antipsychotics for more than 12 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current medication with benzodiazepine &gt;30 mg per day equivalent diazepam&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current daily use of substance of abuse (higher than an average equivalent of daily&#xD;
             number of 5 cannabis cigarettes). Current severe substance use disorder except for&#xD;
             nicotine (SUD, Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders version V (DSMV&#xD;
             criteria) during the last 6 months and/or former severe SUD or dependence DSMIV during&#xD;
             more than 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current cognitive remediation programme,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women, parturients, and lactating women,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals deprived of their liberty by a judicial or administrative decision,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals of legal age who are the subject of a legal protection measure or unable&#xD;
             to express their consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marie-Odile KREBS</last_name>
    <phone>+33 1 45 65 74 97</phone>
    <email>marie-odile.krebs@inserm.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Khaoussou SYLLA</last_name>
    <phone>+331.45.65.73.35</phone>
    <email>K.SYLLA@ghu-paris.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU Brest</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brest</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christophe LEMEY</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christophe LEMEY</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Esquirol - CHU CAEN</name>
      <address>
        <city>Caen</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sonia DOLLFUS</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sonia DOLLFUS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Clermont Ferrand</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-Ferrand</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Isabelle JALENQUES</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Isabelle JALENQUES</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier La Chartreuse</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dijon</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Fontan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Renaud JARDRI</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Renaud JARDRI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital La Colombière - CHU Montpellier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Diane PURPER OUAKIL</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Diane PURPER OUAKIL</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Eldorado - Maison des Adolescents de Meurthe et Moselle</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nancy</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vincent LAPREVOTE</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Vincent LAPREVOTE</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CH Orsay</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orsay</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julie BOURGIN</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Julie BOURGIN</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GHU Paris Neurosciences Psychiatrie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marie-Odile KREBS</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marie-Odile KREBS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nineteen GHU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gilles MARTINEZ</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gilles MARTINEZ</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Poitiers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poitiers</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nematollah JAAFARI</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nematollah JAAFARI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>C.H. Guillaume Regnier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rennes</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Purpan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jean-Philippe RAYNAUD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jean-Philippe RAYNAUD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 26, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 26, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamin B 12</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

