<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798936</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>US in benign Thyroid cysts</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798936</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparative Study of Polidocanol and Absolute Alcohol for Percutaneous us Guided Treatment of Benign Thyroid Cyst</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparative Study of Polidocanol and Absolute Alcohol for Percutaneous Ultrasound Guided Treatment of Benign Thyroid Cyst</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to compare the efficacy and safety of ultrasound-guided percutaneous ethanol&#xD;
      injection and percutaneous polidocanol injection for the treatment of benign cystic and&#xD;
      predominantly cystic thyroid nodules.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Thyroid nodules are characterized by excessive structural growth, functional transformation,&#xD;
      and/or cystic degeneration of one or several areas within the gland. According to various&#xD;
      studies, 15-30% of thyroid nodules are cystic or predominantly cystic. Around 5% of patients&#xD;
      with thyroid nodules may experience compressive symptoms or cosmetic concerns, and treatment&#xD;
      may be required in these cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Simple aspiration is generally the initial management for the purpose of diagnosis and cyst&#xD;
      volume reduction. However, the recurrence rate has been reported to be high (40% to 59%),&#xD;
      depending on the number of aspirations and extent of fluid evacuation. After simple&#xD;
      fine-needle aspiration, most cystic lesions (around 80%) refill and enlarge over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery is a long-established therapeutic option for benign thyroid nodules. However, the&#xD;
      cost of thyroid surgery, risk of temporary or permanent complications, and impact on quality&#xD;
      of life remain relevant concerns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasound-guided percutaneous ethanol injection (PEI) The mechanism of ethanol sclerotherapy&#xD;
      is that ethanol induces cellular dehydration and protein denaturation, which are followed by&#xD;
      coagulation necrosis, reactive fibrosis, and small-vessel thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As regard (PEI)Pain is the most common side effect, other mild side effects or complications&#xD;
      occurred in small numbers of patients like: Facial flushing, Mild dizziness, Intracystic&#xD;
      haemorrhage, drunken sense, Perithyroidal leakage. There are other side effects, including&#xD;
      transient vocal cord palsy, respiratory distress requiring emergency surgical treatment, and&#xD;
      venous thrombosis, in sporadic cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Percutaneous Polidocanol sclerotherapy (PPI) may be a potential alternative to ethanol for&#xD;
      the treatment of benign cystic and predominantly cystic thyroid nodules.Polidocanol is a&#xD;
      liquid detergent sclerosant developed in 1936 as a topical and local anaesthetic consisting&#xD;
      of 95% hydroxy poly ethoxydodecane and 5% ethyl alcohol. It has been used as a treatment for&#xD;
      hemorrhoidal disease, venous malformations, symptomatic hepatic cysts, renal cysts, gastric&#xD;
      varices, and digital mucous cysts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The mechanism of treating cyst is probably destroying endothelial cells of capsular wall&#xD;
      which causes aseptic inflammation; thus endothelial tissue atrophies and cyst cavity adhere&#xD;
      and occlude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The side effects are mild including mild localized pain and mild or moderate fever after PPI.&#xD;
      So, PPI could be a safe and effective alternative to treat benign cystic or predominant&#xD;
      cystic thyroid nodules.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Based on determining the main outcome variable, the estimated minimum required sample size is 30 patients (15 patient in each group).&#xD;
The sample was calculated using G*power software 3.1.9.2., based on the following assumptions: Main outcome variable is the difference between mean value of:&#xD;
Group (A): 15 patients will be treated by Ultrasound-Guided Percutaneous Polidocanol Injection Group (B): 15 patients will be treated by Ultrasound-Guided percutaneous ethanol injection</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Size of the thyroid cystic nodule after sclerosing agent injection (polidocanol versus alcohol)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Size of the thyroid cyst is measured by ultrasound after 3 months of sclerosing agent injection</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Benign Thyroid Nodule</condition>
  <condition>Thyroid Lump</condition>
  <condition>Thyroid Cyst</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Polidocanol group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Polidocanol is injected in the thyroid cyst under ultrasound guidance.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Alcohol group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Alcohol is injected in the thyroid cyst under ultrasound guidance.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Polidocanol</intervention_name>
    <description>Polidocanol is injected under complete aseptic conditions. Before the treatment the diameter and volume of each nodule is calculated. To prevent serious hemorrhage, vessels located along the approach route will be carefully evaluated by using Doppler US.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Polidocanol group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Polidocanol solution</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alcohol</intervention_name>
    <description>Alcohol is injected under complete aseptic conditions. Before the treatment the diameter and volume of each nodule is calculated. To prevent serious hemorrhage, vessels located along the approach route will be carefully evaluated by using Doppler US.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Alcohol group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Alcohol Ethyl</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Single cystic or predominantly cystic nodules.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pressure symptoms or cosmetic problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No malignant or indeterminate cytologic results after ultrasound-guided fine-needle&#xD;
             aspiration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal serum thyroid hormone levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Association of a nodules showing malignant features on us examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignant or indeterminate cytologic results after ultrasound-guided fine-needle&#xD;
             aspiration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal serum thyroid hormone levels&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amna Ahmed</last_name>
    <phone>01095339383</phone>
    <email>amnabkar76@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Hany Seif</last_name>
    <phone>01005618665</phone>
    <email>hanyseifrad@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 14, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amna Ahmed Ali Ahmed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cysts</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Nodule</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Polidocanol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

