<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05622149</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>011638</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05622149</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Is Strength Training a Viable Exercise Modality for Fat Loss?</brief_title>
  <official_title>Is Strength Training a Viable Exercise Modality for Fat Loss?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>George Washington University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City University of New York</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>George Washington University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether strength training can be used as a viable&#xD;
      exercise modality for the purpose of inducing fat loss.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aerobic exercise (AE) is commonly recommended as the most effective exercise modality for&#xD;
      weight loss. The Centers for Disease Control (CDC) recommends 150 minutes of AE for weight&#xD;
      maintenance, and an unspecified greater amount required for weight loss. Similarly, the&#xD;
      American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) position stand on physical activity for weight&#xD;
      loss recommends 150-250 minutes per week of moderate intensity physical activity. While the&#xD;
      ACSM promotes resistance training (RT) as a means of increasing fat free mass, which should&#xD;
      lead to improved body composition, it does not promote RT for losing significant amounts of&#xD;
      body fat. Similarly, the CDC physical activity guidelines for weight loss do not mention RT&#xD;
      at all as a viable exercise modality for weight loss. This is not surprising, as there is a&#xD;
      paucity of research examining the effects of RT on weight loss. Furthermore, the few studies&#xD;
      that have explored RT for weight loss generally show that it is ineffective. The&#xD;
      effectiveness of any weight loss program is dependent on the size of the caloric deficit that&#xD;
      is created over time, and since AE generally burns more calories per unit of time than RT, it&#xD;
      stands to reason that AE would be the most commonly prescribed type of exercise for weight&#xD;
      loss. Contributing to the exclusion of RT for weight loss is a widespread belief among&#xD;
      dietitians, nutritionists and exercise professionals that it is not possible to induce muscle&#xD;
      growth while in a caloric deficit, and since the creation of a caloric deficit is essential&#xD;
      for fat loss, the use of RT for muscle growth in a caloric deficit is counter intuitive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, RT has been shown to elevate resting metabolism for an extended period of time&#xD;
      following cessation of the training session. Additionally, having a greater muscle mass&#xD;
      should lead to a greater resting metabolism. Unlike RT, chronic AE performed in a caloric&#xD;
      deficit (which is often the recommendation for effective weight loss) has the potential to&#xD;
      lead to significant decreases in muscle mass, thereby hampering improvements in body&#xD;
      composition. Ideally, a program designed to improve body composition should do so through fat&#xD;
      losses alone, with muscle mass being maintained or increased.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several reasons could exist for the lack of effectiveness of RT shown in most studies. These&#xD;
      reasons include, but are not limited to, 1) Body mass being the measured outcome and not body&#xD;
      composition, 2) lack of control and/or measurement of caloric intake, 3) failure to adjust&#xD;
      dietary protein needs to support muscle growth, 4) ineffective RT program design. Case&#xD;
      studies of clients from our lab have routinely shown that profound decreases in bodyfat can&#xD;
      be induced with RT as the exclusive form of exercise. Furthermore, these decreases in bodyfat&#xD;
      occur with concomitant increases in muscle mass, while in a caloric deficit. Therefore, the&#xD;
      specific aims of this proposal are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine whether RT combined with dietary intervention (RT+DIET) results in greater&#xD;
           decreases in fat mass than (RT) or dietary intervention (DIET) alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine whether RT combined with dietary intervention (RT+DIET) results in greater&#xD;
           improvements in body composition than (RT) or dietary intervention (DIET) alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To determine whether concomitant increases in muscle mass and decreases in fat mass can&#xD;
           occur while in a caloric deficit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this project is to serve to generate pilot data to determine whether RT can be&#xD;
      used as a viable exercise mode for fat loss and muscle gain. We will then pursue funding for&#xD;
      a subsequent study that compares the effects of RT versus AE on body composition and fat loss&#xD;
      when 1) the caloric intake is monitored to ensure the creation of a caloric deficit, and 2)&#xD;
      dietary protein is appropriately increased to support muscle retention/growth.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 18, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 1, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 1, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Fat Free Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fat Free Mass as measured from DXA and recorded in Kg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Fat Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>0, 4, 8, 12, 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fat Mass as measured from DXA and recorded in Kg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Resting Metabolic Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>0 and 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Resting Metabolic Rate measured via indirect calorimetry and recorded in kcal / day</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Visceral Fat</measure>
    <time_frame>0, 4, 8, 12, 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fat in the Visceral Depot measured from DXA and recorded in Kg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Overweight and Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diet Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects were given calorie and macronutrient intake goals and were told to hit those goals as closely as possible on a daily basis for 16 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Training Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects were given a 3 times per week supervised resistance training program for 16 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diet plus Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects were given calorie and macronutrient intake goals and were told to hit those goals as closely as possible on a daily basis for 16 weeks. Subjects were given a 3 times per week supervised resistance training program for 16 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diet Only</intervention_name>
    <description>Food tracking based on macronutrient goals.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diet Only</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Training Only</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects completed 16 weeks of supervised resistance training</description>
    <arm_group_label>Training Only</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diet plus Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Food tracking plus resistance training.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diet plus Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI 25-29.9 normally menstruating bodyfat &gt;30%&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  currently dieting to lose weight currently engaged in structured exercise using&#xD;
             dietary weight loss supplements Resting Metabolic Rate not within 10% of predicted&#xD;
             value&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Todd A Miller, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>George Washington University SPH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 19, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>George Washington University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Todd Miller</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prinicipal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>resistance training; metabolism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

