<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05628025</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022-10107</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05628025</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Simulation-Based Enucleation Training: Initial Experience Using 3D-printed Organ Phantoms</brief_title>
  <official_title>Simulation-Based Enucleation Training: Initial Experience Using 3D-printed Organ Phantoms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There are many possible surgical treatments when a patient presents with lower urinary tract&#xD;
      symptoms due to an enlarged prostate, termed benign prostatic hyperplasia or BPH. One&#xD;
      technique consists of using a laser to remove prostatic tissue through the penis, called&#xD;
      laser enucleation of the prostate or LEP. LEP also has excellent properties to reduce blood&#xD;
      loss and results in shorter hospital stays. Trainees must observe and perform several&#xD;
      procedures before mastering the LEP technique. Different models have been used to mimic the&#xD;
      LEP experience for surgeon trainees, such as virtual simulators or synthetic models. While&#xD;
      these simulators offer an alternative to LEP procedures on real patients, they may lack&#xD;
      realism which renders the simulator less representative than the real procedure.The&#xD;
      3D-printed prostate model of the present study mimics the properties of real-life prostatic&#xD;
      tissue. In the setting of the MasterClass, trainees will perform LEP on the 3D models under&#xD;
      the supervision of three experts. While the 3D organ phantom has been used to practice&#xD;
      performing other procedures, this is the first time it will evaluated for LEP training. For&#xD;
      this reason, the investigators will be assessing this model as a training tool.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Numerous surgical treatment options exist for benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH). Laser&#xD;
      enucleation of the prostate (LEP) was introduced in the therapeutic arsenal about twenty&#xD;
      years ago, and has become a popular treatment due to its excellent hemostatic properties.&#xD;
      Moreover, LEP is associated with less blood loss and shorter hospital stays. One disadvantage&#xD;
      however may be the longer learning curve for trainees compared to transurethral resection of&#xD;
      the prostate (TURP), which is the current gold standard for treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is estimated that a surgeon can safely and efficiently perform holmium LEP after about 50&#xD;
      cases. Simulator-based training has been widely proposed as a training tool for surgeons to&#xD;
      learn LEP. Integrating simulators in surgical training allows surgeons to develop skills in&#xD;
      LEP without negative consequences on real patients. Simulators range from virtual reality to&#xD;
      synthetic bench models, and all face the same challenge of creating a realistic experience&#xD;
      that accurately mimics real-life LEP, and helps surgeons develop skills they can transfer to&#xD;
      the operating room.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The prostate organ phantom in the present study is composed of hydrogels and uses 3D molds to&#xD;
      recreate prostatic tissue and anatomy. This model has successfully been used to practice TURP&#xD;
      procedures, however has not yet been validated for LEP training. This observational,&#xD;
      prospective and comparative study aims to validate the 3D prostate organ for LEP training. In&#xD;
      the setting of a MasterClass, trainees will perform LEP on two 3D models under the&#xD;
      supervision of three experts in LEP. The content and face validity of the organ phantoms will&#xD;
      be evaluated by the MasterClass participants through a questionnaire. Performance outcomes of&#xD;
      trainees will also be collected by visually examining the models and weighing the models pre-&#xD;
      and post-operatively. By validating this simulator for LEP training, the investigators hope&#xD;
      to elucidate the role of simulators, and specifically the role of a 3D organ phantom, in&#xD;
      future training programs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 24, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 24, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Content and face validity of the organ phantom model in LEP training.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year post-workshop</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with validated questionnaire using a Likert scale.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Verify the reproducibility of each 3D printed model.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year post-workshop</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with validated questionnaire using a Likert scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the surgical performance outcomes of trainees based on level of expertise, and compared with LEP experts (construct validity).</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year post-workshop</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of prostatic tissue resected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the perceived difficulty of each step of LEP by trainees.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year post-workshop</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with validated questionnaire using a Likert scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gauge the feasibility and acceptability of integrating simulators in LEP training.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year post-workshop</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with validated questionnaire using a Likert scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>BPH</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Trainees</arm_group_label>
    <description>Residents in urology or urologists with little LEP experience. Trainee group will be stratified by level of experience.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experts</arm_group_label>
    <description>Urologists with at least 5 years LEP experience.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Organ phantom of prostate</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will operate on a 3D printed model of the prostate.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Trainees</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Urologists in training seeking to improve skills in LEP and experts in LEP.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participate in LEP MasterClass&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Simulator</keyword>
  <keyword>Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Laser Enucleation</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

