<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615688</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>55656</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615688</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pain and Activity Levels After Orthodontic Separators</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pain Intensity Following the Placement of Orthodontic Separators in Healthy Volunteers and How it Correlates to Different Levels of Physical Activity?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lina Sharab</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Kentucky</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary aim of this study is to evaluate the reported pain intensity following placement&#xD;
      of Orthodontic separators on healthy volunteers aged 18-49 in relation to their recorded&#xD;
      physical activity level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1: The investigators hypothesize that participants with higher daily step counts&#xD;
      and physical activity levels will report significantly less pain intensity from orthodontic&#xD;
      separators than their less active peers following separator placement. Null hypothesis is&#xD;
      that participants with higher daily step counts will report the same pain intensity from&#xD;
      orthodontic separators than their less active peers following separator placement&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary aim is to describe the course of pain, at 24 hr intervals, over the next seven&#xD;
      days following separator placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 2: The investigators hypothesize that more physically active participants will&#xD;
      report ratings of zero pain intensity faster (sooner) than their less active peers throughout&#xD;
      the one week study. Secondary null hypothesis is that more physically active participants&#xD;
      will report ratings of zero pain intensity at the same rate as their less active peers&#xD;
      throughout the one week study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute pain or discomfort during orthodontic treatment is commonly reported. A study done in&#xD;
      2002 found that 87% of patients experienced pain after orthodontic visits. Additionally,&#xD;
      &quot;feeling pain&quot; has been identified as the primary treatment concern for many patients prior&#xD;
      to orthodontic treatment. More so, it can negatively affect patient compliance and attitude&#xD;
      toward treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Numerous studies have shown that pain varies in intensity and duration among orthodontic&#xD;
      patients. The placement of orthodontic separators is a standard procedure to facilitate&#xD;
      placement of orthodontic bands by creating a small amount of space between posterior teeth.&#xD;
      Separator placement reliably produces acute discomfort to patients. Pain generated from&#xD;
      orthodontic separator placement originates in the periodontal ligament (PDL) as compression&#xD;
      forces are applied to the PDL unequally to open a small space (less than 0.5 mm) between the&#xD;
      teeth. This compression triggers sterile necrosis or hyalinization in some areas of the PDL,&#xD;
      leading to acute pain. The course of pain generated from orthodontic separators typically&#xD;
      begins 4 hours after placement, reaching highest pain intensity approximately 24 hours after&#xD;
      placement, and continuing to decrease in intensity until returning to pre-placement baseline&#xD;
      after seven days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variation in reported pain intensity across orthodontic patients is of interest to any&#xD;
      practitioner who desires to improve patient outcomes. In an attempt to enhance the&#xD;
      orthodontist ability to understand pain and its predicting factors, researchers have examined&#xD;
      pain from orthodontic treatment relative to patient demographics, personality traits,&#xD;
      psychological factors, perceived need and attitude toward treatment, among others. Okeson&#xD;
      asserts that pain is not directly related to the extent of tissue injury. Noxious stimuli&#xD;
      originating in peripheral neurons (such is the case with separators) are subject to&#xD;
      modulation at multiple levels through a complex central inhibitory system, where many other&#xD;
      factors participate in decreasing or increasing the pain experience. Hence, an individual's&#xD;
      emotional state, pain expectation and perception of control, as well as activities or&#xD;
      distractions that will differ brain attention (Gate Control) can significantly influence the&#xD;
      pain experience. Perceived stress, or the degree to which situations in an individual's life&#xD;
      exceed their ability to cope, could be a good predictor of experienced pain. The Perceived&#xD;
      Stress Scale is the most widely used screening form to evaluate perceived stress and asks&#xD;
      subjects to recall the frequency of feeling overloaded and overwhelmed in the past month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, more attention has been given to the role of physical activity (PA) in reducing&#xD;
      pain in patients that undergo orthodontic treatment. Physical activity has been shown to be&#xD;
      an effective mediator of acute pain tolerance and pain sensitivity, an effect known as&#xD;
      Exercise Induced Hypoalgesia (EIH). One study reported that a 1-mile run decreased pain&#xD;
      intensity evoked from a weight being placed on the index finger. A similar decrease in pain&#xD;
      response to pressure applied to the finger was found in subjects in another study who&#xD;
      performed 30 minutes of aerobic exercise. It has also been demonstrated that exercise&#xD;
      increased dental pain thresholds in response to electrical stimulation of the pulp. The exact&#xD;
      mechanism involved in EIH remains elusive. Still, several pathways have been implicated&#xD;
      including activation of the endogenous opioid pathway, increased Adrenocorticotropic Hormone&#xD;
      release, and a conditioned pain the pain perceived in another area of the body.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers have demonstrated that higher self-reported physical activity reduced the pain&#xD;
      levels generated by placement of orthodontic separators when compared to patients with low&#xD;
      physical activity. Self-reported measurements of physical activity carry limitations. The&#xD;
      Physical Activity Questionnaire (PAQ) used in previous studies have demonstrated an only&#xD;
      moderate correlation with direct activity observation (r=0.45), and with an activity&#xD;
      monitoring device (r=0.57). The PAQ asks participants to report pain in the last seven days,&#xD;
      and if given before treatment was performed, provides no data on physical activity during the&#xD;
      week when subjects are experiencing pain. To further explore the correlation between physical&#xD;
      activity and acute pain during orthodontic treatment, a more reliable measure of physical&#xD;
      activity is warranted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Actigraphy sensors provide an objective measure of physical activity. Actigraphy sensors&#xD;
      include pedometers, which count steps over a defined time interval, and accelerometers, which&#xD;
      measure acceleration in &quot;activity counts&quot; that are then extrapolated to the Metabolic&#xD;
      Equivalent of Task (METS) to measure energy expenditure. No other paper has evaluated the&#xD;
      effect of physical activity measured with pedometers on acute pain following separators&#xD;
      placement during orthodontic treatment. Because not all patients experience pain at the same&#xD;
      level, it would be beneficial for clinicians to identify which patients are likely to&#xD;
      experience more intense pain before beginning treatment. To this end, the purpose of this&#xD;
      study is to test the effect of physical activity measured by pedometer on acute pain produced&#xD;
      by the placement of separators.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 14, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 13, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 13, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Elastomeric separators will be placed on the mesial and distal of lower first permanent molars for a total of four separators per subject.&#xD;
Activity monitors will be provided and participants instructed to wear 24/7 unless showering or swimming to measure and collect level of physical activity&#xD;
Baseline data will be collected via questionnaires that include: Medical History, Demographics, and Perceived Stress Scale.&#xD;
Subjects will also complete a Recurrent Questionnaire at 2-4 hrs post placement and every evening for days 2-7 to report Pain Intensity using a Visual Analog Scale</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Pain Intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Subjects will be given an activity monitor to wear full time following the placement of the orthodontic spacers. They will report their level of pain to on a recurrent Pain Intensity questionnaire (using a Visual Analog Scale in REDCap) at 2-4 hrs after placement, and again at 24 hour intervals for the next 7 days following separator placement. The left of the digital Visual Analog Scale will be labeled &quot;no pain&quot; and the right will be labeled &quot;worst pain imaginable&quot;. REDCap assigns a value of 0 on the left side of the scale and increased to100 on the right of the scale.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Proportion of patients reporting ZERO Pain over time</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Subjects will be given an activity monitor to wear full time following the placement of the orthodontic spacers. They will report their level of pain on a recurrent Pain Intensity questionnaire (using a Visual Analog Scale in REDCap) at 2-4 hrs after placement, and again at 24 hour intervals for the next 7 days following separator placement. The left of the digital Visual Analog Scale will be labeled &quot;no pain&quot; and the right will be labeled &quot;worst pain imaginable&quot;. REDCap assigns a value of 0 on the left side of the scale and increased to100 on the right of the scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">94</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Malocclusion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Orthodontic Separators Placed</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Elastomeric separators will be placed on the mesial and distal of the lower first permanent molars for a total of four separators per subject.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pain Intensity following Placement of Orthodontic Separators</intervention_name>
    <description>Elastomeric separators will be placed on the mesial and distal of lower first permanent molars for a total of four separators per subject. Subjects will wear receive an activity monitor prior to placement of elastic separators and instructed to wear it 24/7 unless showering or swimming. Subjects will complete a recurrent Pain Scale Questionnaire 2-4 hrs after placement of elastics and every 24 hrs from day 2- 7.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Orthodontic Separators Placed</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Student, resident, or staff at the University of Kentucky&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18-49 at time of enrollment in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Erupted permanent first and second molars with interproximal contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of antagonist teeth in the opposite arch with no open bite&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Voluntary participation in study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a smartphone, tablet, or computer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Valid email address&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any chronic pain condition (examples include trigeminal neuralgia, migraines,&#xD;
             fibromyalgia, arthritis, neuropathies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of pain medication (analgesics, opioids, nerve pain medications) for any&#xD;
             condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically evident interproximal decay in the site where separators will be placed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Missing teeth, variations in tooth anatomy, existing space, and or restorations that&#xD;
             would keep separators from being placed or retained&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If you do not have access to a computer, smartphone, or tablet with internet access&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lina Sharab, DDS, MS, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistant Professor, Orthodontics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lina Sharab, DDS, MS, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>859-323-7638</phone>
    <email>lsh232@uky.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Dawn G Dawson, RDH, CCRC</last_name>
    <phone>859-323-5409</phone>
    <email>ddaws1@uky.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kentucky</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40536</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lina Sharab, DDS, MS, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>859-323-7638</phone>
      <email>lsh232@uky.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Dawn Dawson, RDH, CCRC</last_name>
      <phone>859-323-5409</phone>
      <email>ddaws1@uky.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bergius M, Berggren U, Kiliaridis S. Experience of pain during an orthodontic procedure. Eur J Oral Sci. 2002 Apr;110(2):92-8. doi: 10.1034/j.1600-0722.2002.11193.x.</citation>
    <PMID>12013568</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sergl HG, Klages U, Zentner A. Pain and discomfort during orthodontic treatment: causative factors and effects on compliance. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 1998 Dec;114(6):684-91. doi: 10.1016/s0889-5406(98)70201-x.</citation>
    <PMID>9844209</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abu Alhaija ES, Aldaikki A, Al-Omairi MK, Al-Khateeb SN. The relationship between personality traits, pain perception and attitude toward orthodontic treatment. Angle Orthod. 2010 Nov;80(6):1141-9. doi: 10.2319/012710-59.1.</citation>
    <PMID>20677967</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beck VJ, Farella M, Chandler NP, Kieser JA, Thomson WM. Factors associated with pain induced by orthodontic separators. J Oral Rehabil. 2014 Apr;41(4):282-8. doi: 10.1111/joor.12144. Epub 2014 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24483937</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Campos LA, Santos-Pinto A, Maroco J, Campos JADB. Pain perception in orthodontic patients: A model considering psychosocial and behavioural aspects. Orthod Craniofac Res. 2019 Aug;22(3):213-221. doi: 10.1111/ocr.12315. Epub 2019 May 15.</citation>
    <PMID>31021044</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rakhshan H, Rakhshan V. Pain and discomfort perceived during the initial stage of active fixed orthodontic treatment. Saudi Dent J. 2015 Apr;27(2):81-7. doi: 10.1016/j.sdentj.2014.11.002. Epub 2015 Jan 27.</citation>
    <PMID>26082574</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sandhu SS, Leckie G. Orthodontic pain trajectories in adolescents: Between-subject and within-subject variability in pain perception. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2016 Apr;149(4):491-500.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.ajodo.2015.10.020.</citation>
    <PMID>27021453</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sandhu SS, Sandhu J. Orthodontic pain: an interaction between age and sex in early and middle adolescence. Angle Orthod. 2013 Nov;83(6):966-72. doi: 10.2319/030113-174.1. Epub 2013 May 24.</citation>
    <PMID>23705940</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ngan P, Kess B, Wilson S. Perception of discomfort by patients undergoing orthodontic treatment. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 1989 Jul;96(1):47-53. doi: 10.1016/0889-5406(89)90228-x.</citation>
    <PMID>2750720</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bondemark L, Fredriksson K, Ilros S. Separation effect and perception of pain and discomfort from two types of orthodontic separators. World J Orthod. 2004 Summer;5(2):172-6.</citation>
    <PMID>15615136</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 19, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Kentucky</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lina Sharab</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malocclusion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

