<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05614908</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AarhusUH-MFenger</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05614908</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Outcome After Conservatively Treated Achilles Tendon Rupture</brief_title>
  <official_title>Patient-reported Outcomes After Non-operative Treatment of Acute Achilles Tendon Rupture: a Prospective Cohort Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aarhus University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aarhus University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main purpose of the study is to investigate self-reported functional ability of patients&#xD;
      undergoing conservatively treated achilles tendon rupture at 6, 12 and 24 months from the&#xD;
      date of injury.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The achilles tendon is the most injured tendon in the lower extremity. An achilles tendon&#xD;
      rupture (ATR) is treated either surgically or non-surgically. Previous studies have&#xD;
      investigated early controlled motion and weight-bearing for non-surgically treated ATR. Early&#xD;
      motion may cause tendon elongation, which leads to decrease in push off strength, and thus&#xD;
      potentially a poorer functional outcome. Conversely, delayed initiation of mobilisation and&#xD;
      weight-bearing may similarly hinder or delay optimal recovery of function and return to work&#xD;
      and sports. The correct treatment and rehabilitation, including the timing of rehabilitation&#xD;
      initiation, may therefore be crucial to ensure the patients' functional ability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most hospitals in Denmark treating patients with ATR, provide a regime of 8 weeks&#xD;
      immobilization for conservatively treated patients with ATR. At Aarhus University Hospital&#xD;
      (AUH), however, a more restrictive regime is provided for these patients, requiring&#xD;
      immobilization for 11 weeks after injury. Typically, a late initiation of mobilization is&#xD;
      defined as mobilization beginning in week 8, i.e. 3 weeks sooner than the standard regime at&#xD;
      AUH. Furthermore, many &quot;late&quot; mobilization regimes allows for some non-weightbearing&#xD;
      exercises prior to week 8, but at AUH patients are recommended to limit any movement during&#xD;
      the first 11 weeks after injury. This is primarily to reduce the risk of a re-rupture, the&#xD;
      rate of which is lower at AUH than on a national level (i.e. &lt;5% versus 7-8% re-rupture&#xD;
      rate). However, this delayed onset of mobilization and weight-bearing may have a negative&#xD;
      effect on return to normal function, sports and work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since 2012, a number of Danish hospitals, treating patients with ATR, have reported&#xD;
      re-rupture rates, and self-reported functional ability and working status, etc. is reported&#xD;
      at 6, 12 and 24 months. This data are published in a report, enabling comparison with other&#xD;
      populations. At present, AUH does not report these data into to the database, and the data&#xD;
      published in the early report may therefore serve as comparison group in this quality&#xD;
      assurance study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose: The aim of this quality assurance study is therefore to investigate to what extent&#xD;
      the stricter regime at AUH following conservatively treated ATR affects the patients'&#xD;
      functional ability after 6, 12 and 24 months after injury, compared to patients treated at&#xD;
      other Danish hospitals with less strict regimes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design and participants:This is a cohort study, using self-reported data collected&#xD;
      prospectively from approximately 100 consecutive patients (18+) recruited at AUH with a&#xD;
      non-surgically treated ATR. These data will be compared with self-reported data from the&#xD;
      Danish Achilles tendon Database (DAB) i.e. an existing cohort of patients with ATR treated at&#xD;
      other Danish Hospitals. The data is freely available in yearly reports at&#xD;
      (https://www.hvidovrehospital.dk/sorc-c/projects/Pages/The-Danish-Achilles-tendon-Database-(D&#xD;
      ADB).aspx).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard mobilization procedure: As part of standard care at AUH, all patients treated&#xD;
      non-surgically for ATR are immobilized in scotch cast during weeks 0-4. Next, the scotch cast&#xD;
      is replaced by a ROM-WALKER for the next 7 weeks (week 5-11 after injury), but without weight&#xD;
      bearing weeks 5-10. At week 11 the patients are allowed weight bearing up to 30 kg, after&#xD;
      which there is no longer weight bearing restrictions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection: Patients will receive a digital letter with a link to an online&#xD;
      questionnaire to be completed at 6 months, 12 months and 24 months from the date of injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are asked to fill out the patient-reported outcome measure Achilles tendon Total&#xD;
      Rupture Score, as well as additional questions regarding job status, return to sport,&#xD;
      incidence of deep venous thrombosis, if they have had a re-rupture of the same achilles&#xD;
      tendon and their satisfaction with treatment they received at the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ATRS is a 10-item questionnaire, with a score of 0 to 10 (worst-best), which has been&#xD;
      found valid, reliable and responsive in this population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is ATRS score at 12 months, which will be compared to the 12 month ATRS&#xD;
      score in the 2021 report of the Danish Achilles Tendon Database (DADB), including app. 2000&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The needed sample size to find a minimal clinical important difference of 10 points (SD 18)&#xD;
      between our population and the population of DADB is 51 patients in each group, to achieve a&#xD;
      power of 80% and alpha set at 5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected outcomes and perspectives: this study will bring knowledge about patient-reported&#xD;
      outcomes on achilles function, physical acitivity and work status in patients with&#xD;
      conservatively treated ATR, following an immobilization protocol of 11 weeks duration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-reported functional ability at 12 months after injury</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post-injury</time_frame>
    <description>Achilles tendon Total Rupture Score is a self-reported questionnaire with 10 items, summing up to a score of 0-100 points, with 100 points reflecting no disability. The primary outcome will be ATRS score at 12 months, but data will also be collected at 6 and 24 months to describe any changes over time.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants who have returned to previous working status at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post-injury</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported return to previous work (if at working age)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants who have returned to previous sports activities at 24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months post-injury</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported return to sport</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants with re-rupture at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post-injury</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported re-rupture</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Achilles Tendon Rupture</condition>
  <condition>Achilles Tendon Injury</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>11 weeks of immobilization</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients wear a scotch cast for the first 4 weeks. After that they are provided with a ROM-WALKER to be worn for the next 7 weeks, during which the ROM-walker is slowly moved from 30 degrees of plantarflexion up to 0 degrees. During the first 10 weeks, patients are not allowed any weight-bearing on the injured leg.&#xD;
From week 11 they are allowed 30 kg of weight-bearing in the ROM WALKER, and from week 12 full weight-bearing with a 1 cm heel lift in their shoes.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population consists of 100 consecutive achilles tendon rupture patients, treated&#xD;
        conservatively at Aarhus University Hospital during 2022.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an acute achilles tendon rupture treated conservatively at AUH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Patients who have not followed the regime at AUH (e.g. terminated use of the ROM- walker&#xD;
        prematurely or similar).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nanna Rolving, Ph.d.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Aarhus University Hospital, Department of physiotherapy and occupational therapy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Per Gundtoft, Ph.d.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Aarhus University Hospital, Department of Orthopaedics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mette F Fenger, BA</last_name>
    <phone>40321618</phone>
    <email>Mette.Frank@auh.rm.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Louise Mortensen, Msc</last_name>
    <phone>+45 61629524</phone>
    <email>louimr@rm.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aarhus University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aarhus</city>
        <zip>8200</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Aarhus University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mette Frank Fenger</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Achilles tendon rupture</keyword>
  <keyword>Functional ability</keyword>
  <keyword>Immobilization</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tendon Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

