<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623436</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ATATURKU-SEVGİ</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623436</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Virtual Reality Technology in Ventrogluteal Injection Training</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Ventrogluteal Injection Training Provided With Virtual Reality Technology on Knowledge, Skill, Motivation, and Anxiety Levels of Student: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ataturk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ataturk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Intramuscular injections are one of the nursing functions frequently used in clinical&#xD;
      practice. Sites used for the purpose of intramuscular injection; dorsogluteal, ventrogluteal,&#xD;
      deltoid region, vastus lateralis muscle and rectus femoris muscle . Intramuscular injections&#xD;
      can cause many complications. The most important complication is sciatic nerve injury, which&#xD;
      may occur as a result of injection especially in the dorsogluteal region. In order to prevent&#xD;
      complications that may develop as a result of intramuscular injection, it should be&#xD;
      emphasized that the ventrogluteal region should be preferred in the selection of&#xD;
      intramuscular injection site and students should be provided with the necessary knowledge and&#xD;
      skills regarding injection from this region. In nursing education, many different methods are&#xD;
      used with technological developments. One of them is simulation applications. There are&#xD;
      various types of simulation applications. One of these simulation applications is virtual&#xD;
      reality technology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this interventional research is to evaluate the effect of ventrogluteal injection&#xD;
      training developed by researchers and given to students through virtual reality glasses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The universe of the study consisted of first-year students enrolled in the &quot;Basic Nursing and&#xD;
      Clinical Skills&quot; course in the nursing Turkish undergraduate program of Atatürk University&#xD;
      Faculty of Nursing in the spring semester of the 2021-2022 academic year. The sample of the&#xD;
      study consisted of students who had the research criteria and agreed to participate in the&#xD;
      research. Prior to the study, a priori power analysis was performed to determine the sample&#xD;
      size in this study. In the power analysis, it was determined that the sample size should be&#xD;
      128, 64 interventional and 64 control, at a significance level of 0.05, with a confidence&#xD;
      interval of 95%, for power of 80%. Considering the data losses, it was decided to collect&#xD;
      data from a total of 142 students by including 10% reserve sample in this number.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have not received previous application training for intramuscular injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lack of experience in administering intramuscular injections&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participation in the theoretical lecture presentation on intramuscular injection given&#xD;
           by the instructor in the course &quot;Basic Nursing and Clinical Skills&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Absence of a health condition that prevents him from wearing virtual reality glasses and&#xD;
           performing the study (Advanced vision problem, vertigo problem, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have not taken the Fundamentals of Nursing or Basic Nursing Care and Clinical Skills&#xD;
           course before&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Understand the questions in forms and scales&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Willingness to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The student does not participate in at least one of the research phases&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Receive of the student practical training for intramuscular injection from another&#xD;
           instructor during the research process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variables of the research:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dependent Variable: After the application training with virtual reality simulation and&#xD;
           intramuscular injection model, the knowledge evaluation scores, skill evaluation scores,&#xD;
           motivation levels and anxiety levels of the students are dependent on the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Independent Variable: Virtual reality simulation and application training with&#xD;
           intramuscular injection model are independent variables of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Control Variable: The knowledge evaluation scores of the students before the application&#xD;
           training are the control variable of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection tools:&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;Introductory Questionnaire Form&quot;, &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application to the Ventrogluteal&#xD;
      Region Information Evaluation Form&quot;, &quot;Motivation Scale for Teaching Material&quot;, &quot;Status&#xD;
      Anxiety Inventory&quot; were used in data collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Introductory Questionnaire Form: The form prepared by the researcher includes 9&#xD;
           questions including sociodemographic characteristics of the students such as age, gender&#xD;
           and information about ventrogluteal region injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intramuscular Injection Application Information Evaluation Form in the Ventrogluteal&#xD;
           Region: This form has been prepared by the researcher in line with the literature by&#xD;
           taking expert opinions. The Information Evaluation Form is a form consisting of 22&#xD;
           propositions in total that students can answer as &quot;True&quot;, &quot;False&quot; and &quot;I do not know&quot;.&#xD;
           The form contains an equal number of &quot;True&quot; and &quot;False&quot; propositions. The form contains&#xD;
           propositions that measure knowledge for ventrogluteal injection. The lowest score from&#xD;
           the form is 0 and the highest score is 22. High scores obtained from the scale indicate&#xD;
           that the level of information of the students is high.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intramuscular Injection to the Ventrogluteal Region Application Skill Evaluation Form:&#xD;
           This form was prepared by the researcher based on the literature by taking expert&#xD;
           opinions in order to evaluate the students' ability to apply intramuscular injection to&#xD;
           the ventrogluteal region. The form includes intramuscular injection steps to the&#xD;
           ventrogluteal region. The form contains 33 trading steps. The lowest score to be&#xD;
           obtained from the form is 0 and the highest score is 100. High scores obtained from the&#xD;
           scale indicate that the level of skill of the students is high.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Motivation Scale for Instructional Material: The Cronbach alpha value of this scale,&#xD;
           which consists of 33 items, has no inverse propositions and is of the five-point likert&#xD;
           type, was found to be 0.97. The highest score that can be obtained from the scale is&#xD;
           165, while the lowest score is 33 points. A high overall score means that their level of&#xD;
           motivation for the teaching material is high.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Situational Anxiety Inventory: Situational Anxiety Inventory, consists of a total of&#xD;
           twenty items. In the Situational Anxiety Inventory, the answers are grouped under 4&#xD;
           headings: &quot;None&quot;, &quot;A little&quot;, &quot;Many&quot;, &quot;Completely&quot;. Scores from the scale range from&#xD;
           20-80. The high score received is the high anxiety; If the score is low, it means that&#xD;
           the anxiety is low. The analysis of scores in order of percentage is done in a similar&#xD;
           way. A low percentage rank indicates that anxiety is low; A high percentage rank&#xD;
           indicates that anxiety is high. The average score range determined in the application of&#xD;
           the scale is between 36-41.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-Application Phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-application was made to 6 students randomly selected from the universe who agreed to&#xD;
      participate in the study. Students who participated in the pre-practice were not included in&#xD;
      the actual implementation phase of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection: The data were collected in the spring semester of the 2021-2022 academic&#xD;
      year. The necessary explanations were made to the students who formed the sample of the&#xD;
      research and their consent was obtained. Students whose consent was obtained were asked to&#xD;
      fill out the &quot;Introductory Questionnaire Form&quot; and the &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application&#xD;
      Evaluation Form in the Ventrogluteal Region&quot;. All students who filled out these forms were&#xD;
      shown the &quot;Intramuscular Drug Administration Skill Video&quot;. According to the results of the&#xD;
      students' knowledge evaluation scores, intervention and control groups were determined by&#xD;
      randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determination of Research Groups by Randomization: Students who met the criteria for&#xD;
           inclusion in the study, who volunteered to participate in the research, who participated&#xD;
           in the theoretical course presentation on intramuscular injection given by the&#xD;
           instructor of the course in the &quot;Basic Nursing and Clinical Skills&quot; course were selected&#xD;
           by randomization (n= 142) and included in the study. In the study, stratified sampling&#xD;
           method was used for sample selection. In order to ensure that the students constituting&#xD;
           the sample had similar characteristics, the knowledge levels of the students were&#xD;
           determined by using the &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application Information Evaluation Form&#xD;
           in the Ventrogluteal Region&quot; prepared by the researcher by taking expert opinions.&#xD;
           According to the level of knowledge of the students; It was stratified into three groups&#xD;
           as low , medium and high. First, students in the same group (Low, medium or high) with&#xD;
           equal scores were randomly assigned to the intervention and control groups by lottery,&#xD;
           respectively. After the students with equal scores were assigned to the groups, the&#xD;
           remaining students were randomized first within the group and then between the groups.&#xD;
           An equal number of intervention (n=71) and control groups (n=71) were created.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The students, who were divided into intervention and control groups, participated in the&#xD;
      training of intramuscular injection administration from the ventrogluteal region.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The intervention group received its practical training with virtual reality glasses. In&#xD;
           the training content, the procedure steps for intramuscular injection from the&#xD;
           ventrogluteal region were explained and first shown 1 time by the researcher. Then, each&#xD;
           of the researchers was enabled to practice with virtual reality glasses and the&#xD;
           necessary feedback was made. Students who completed their education were asked to fill&#xD;
           out the &quot;Contract for Compliance with Student Research Rules&quot; and &quot;Motivation Scale for&#xD;
           Teaching Material&quot;. After the training, an analysis session was held with the students.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The control group performed the application training in intramuscular injection model.&#xD;
           Later, the students participated in the practical training in groups of 5 people. The&#xD;
           students in the control group were given the necessary training by the researcher on the&#xD;
           intramuscular injection model by demonstration method. In the training content, the&#xD;
           procedure steps for intramuscular injection from the ventrogluteal region were explained&#xD;
           and first shown 1 time by the researcher. Then, each of the researchers was made to&#xD;
           apply on the model and the necessary feedback was given. Students who completed their&#xD;
           education were asked to fill out the &quot;Contract for Compliance with Student Research&#xD;
           Rules&quot; and &quot;Motivation Scale for Teaching Material&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After all students' practical training in both the experimental and control groups was over,&#xD;
      an exam (Objective Structured Clinical Exam/OSCE) was conducted to determine the students'&#xD;
      anxiety, knowledge and skill status. &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application Information&#xD;
      Evaluation Form for Ventrogluteal Region&quot; and &quot;Status Anxiety Inventory&quot; were applied to the&#xD;
      students. The skill status of the students was evaluated by the researcher and recorded in&#xD;
      the &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application Skill Evaluation Form in the Ventrogluteal Region&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 1 month the 1st OSCE exam, students were subjected to the 2nd OSCE exam again. In this&#xD;
      exam, which constitutes the follow-up stage, the procedures in the 1st OSCE exam were applied&#xD;
      and evaluated by the researcher and recorded in the &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application&#xD;
      Skill Evaluation Form to the Ventrogluteal Region&quot;. In this exam, which constitutes the&#xD;
      follow-up stage, the procedures in the 1st OSCE exam were applied and evaluated by the&#xD;
      researcher and recorded in the &quot;Intramuscular Injection Application Skill Evaluation Form to&#xD;
      the Ventrogluteal Region&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluation of the data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the evaluation of the data obtained from the research, the Statistical Package for Social&#xD;
      Sciences (SPSS) 22.0 package program will be used. The normal distribution of the data will&#xD;
      be looked at by the Shapiro Wilk test. Mean, standard deviation, median, min, max, number and&#xD;
      percentages will be used to evaluate the data. In the comparison of the mean between two&#xD;
      independent groups, if the variable is normally distributed, the independent sample t test;&#xD;
      If it does not fall apart normally, Mann Whitney will be examined with a U test. In&#xD;
      statistical comparisons, if the variable is normally distributed in the comparison of the&#xD;
      mean between the two dependent groups, the paired sample t test; If it does not fall apart&#xD;
      normally, it will be examined by Wilcoxon test. Chi-square test will be used in the&#xD;
      comparisons between the two categorical groups. Statistical significance level will be&#xD;
      accepted as p&lt;0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Difficulties and limitations of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The limitation of this research is that it is carried out only with 1nd year nursing students&#xD;
      studying at a university's nursing faculty.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 22, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 27, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 27, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Triple blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intramuscular Injection Application to the Ventrogluteal Region Information Evaluation Form</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Information Evaluation Form is a form consisting of 22 propositions in total that students can answer as &quot;True&quot;, &quot;False&quot; and &quot;I do not know&quot;. The form contains an equal number of &quot;True&quot; and &quot;False&quot; propositions. The form contains propositions that measure knowledge for ventrogluteal injection. The lowest score from the form is 0 and the highest score is 22. High scores obtained from the scale indicate that the level of information of the students is high.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intramuscular Injection to the Ventrogluteal Region Application Skill Evaluation Form</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>The form includes intramuscular injection steps to the ventrogluteal region. The form contains 33 trading steps. The lowest score to be obtained from the form is 0 and the highest score is 100. High scores obtained from the scale indicate that the level of skill of the students is high.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Motivation Scale for Teaching Material</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The Cronbach alpha value of this scale, which consists of 33 items, has no inverse propositions and is of the five-point likert type, was found to be 0.97. The highest score that can be obtained from the scale is 165, while the lowest score is 33 points. A high overall score means that their level of motivation for the teaching material is high.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Situational Anxiety Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Situational Anxiety Inventory, consists of a total of twenty items. Scores from the scale range from 20-80. The average score range determined in the application of the scale is between 36-41. High scores obtained from the scale indicate that the level of anxiety of the students is high.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">136</enrollment>
  <condition>Nursing Caries</condition>
  <condition>Nursing Education</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ventrogluteal injection training given by virtual reality technology is effective in increasing the knowledge and skill levels of students. It also has an impact on students' motivation and anxiety levels.&#xD;
Intervention: Behavioral: Education</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ventrogluteal injection training given by virtual reality technology doesn't effective in increasing the knowledge and skill levels of students. It also hasn't an impact on students' motivation and anxiety levels.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nursing students will be trained through virtual reality.</intervention_name>
    <description>Nursing students will be trained through virtual reality.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have not received previous application training for intramuscular injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of experience in administering intramuscular injections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in the theoretical lecture presentation on intramuscular injection given&#xD;
             by the instructor in the course &quot;Basic Nursing and Clinical Skills&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of a health condition that prevents him from wearing virtual reality glasses&#xD;
             and performing the study (Advanced vision problem, vertigo problem, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have not taken the Fundamentals of Nursing or Basic Nursing Care and Clinical Skills&#xD;
             course before.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understand the questions in forms and scales.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The student does not participate in at least one of the stages of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receive practical training for intramuscular injection from another instructor during&#xD;
             the research process.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>SEVGİ DOGAN</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>ATATURK UNİVERSİTY</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Atatürk University Faculty of Nursing, Department of Nursing Fundamentals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Erzurum</city>
        <zip>25240</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Öner N, Le Compte A. Status and constant anxiety inventory handbook. Boğaziçi University Press. 1983; Istanbul.</citation>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dinçer S, Doğanay A. Motivation scale for teaching material (ÖMMÖ) Turkish Adaptation Study. Elementary Education Online, 2016; 15(4).</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 1, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ataturk University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>SEVGI DOGAN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>intramuscular injection</keyword>
  <keyword>nursing</keyword>
  <keyword>simulation</keyword>
  <keyword>virtual reality</keyword>
  <keyword>ventrogluteal injection</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

