<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05626647</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-21-505</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05626647</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Etiology of Anemia Among Preschool Children in Ethiopia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Etiology of Anemia Among Preschool Children and Its Public Health Implication in Selected Regions of Ethiopia: A Community-Based Longitudinal Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oklahoma State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ethiopian Public Health Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Addis Ababa University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oklahoma State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to determine the etiology of anemia among preschool children in selected&#xD;
      regions of Ethiopia. The study is a longitudinal observational study to assess the&#xD;
      determinant factors of anemia in two different seasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What is the prevalence and etiology of anemia in the two different (Post and&#xD;
           Pre-harvest) seasons?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What is the strength of the interaction between anemia and each of the determinant&#xD;
           factors being considered?&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participant's dietary intake and anthropometric measurement have been assessed, and&#xD;
      biological samples (Blood and Stool) were collected to determine the prevalence of anemia and&#xD;
      the factors contributing to it.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Although the country made a significant change in the burden of malnutrition in&#xD;
      all its forms in the past two decades, the issue remains unacceptably high across all regions&#xD;
      of Ethiopia. The national prevalence of anemia among children 6-59 months was very high 57%&#xD;
      and one of the public health concerns in 2016. Although the country is known as a data-rich&#xD;
      country, in some specific indicators, there is a lack of data and evidence to alleviate the&#xD;
      nutritional gaps through an informed decision-making process. In this particular case, there&#xD;
      is a lack of evidence relating to child anemia in Ethiopia, especially since there is no&#xD;
      comprehensive information about the determinant factors of anemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: The objective of the current survey is to determine the etiology of anemia and its&#xD;
      public health implications among under-five children in selected ecological zones of Ethiopia&#xD;
      at different seasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: This survey will be a community-based, longitudinal panel study and will be conducted&#xD;
      in two different (post-harvest and pre-harvest) seasons in the 2014 Ethiopian calendar year.&#xD;
      A nationally representative sample was calculated and allocated to three purposely selected&#xD;
      regions (Amhara, Southern Nation, Nationalities, and Peoples' Region (SNNPR), and Somali) in&#xD;
      consideration of three different ecological zones (lowlands, midlands, and highlands). The&#xD;
      study population will be children aged 6 - 59 months with caregivers/mothers with a sample&#xD;
      size of 1212 under-five children from 1212 households. The indicators collected for the&#xD;
      survey are dietary intake, anthropometric measurement, and biological samples (Blood and&#xD;
      Stool).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected benefit: The findings of this survey will provide information on the etiology of&#xD;
      anemia that will inform short-term policy decisions, especially for case-specific&#xD;
      nutrition-sensitive interventions, and that will contribute to long-term policy decisions for&#xD;
      comprehensive nutrition intervention programs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 4, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 4, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of anemia among preschool children in selected regions of Ethiopia in the two different (Post and Pre harvest) seasons?</measure>
    <time_frame>From November 2021 to September 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Blood hemoglobin level below 11mg/dL</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors contributing to anemia anemia among preschool children in selected regions of Ethiopia in the two different (Post and Pre harvest) seasons?</measure>
    <time_frame>From November 2021 to September 2022</time_frame>
    <description>Micronutrient deficiency, presence of infectious disease, and genetic problems contributing to low hemoglobin concentration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">590</enrollment>
  <condition>Anemia</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      The hemoglobinopathies test will be performed to assess the genetic alteration of the&#xD;
      individual hemoglobin synthesis status.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children at the age of 6 to 59 months in each randomly selected eligible household of the&#xD;
        Amhara or SNNPR or Somali regions of Ethiopia were the study population for this study but,&#xD;
        during the baseline survey, we found children 6 to 53 months to retain the same child at&#xD;
        the endline survey below five years old.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children 6-53 months during the baseline survey and who have stayed more than 6 months&#xD;
             in the selected household of the Amhara or SNNPR or Somali regions of Ethiopia and&#xD;
             have no plan to move from the study area during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children older than the youngest child between 6-53 months of age (If more than one&#xD;
             eligible child is in the Household) during the baseline survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with severe illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Guests&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If participants lose their willingness to participate in this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Barbara J Stocker, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Oklahoma State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ethiopian Public Health Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Addis Ababa</city>
        <country>Ethiopia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ethiopia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Anemia prevalence among preschool children in 2016 is 57%. EDHS, &quot;Ethiopian Demography and Health Survey 2016, Central Statistical Agency (CSA).,&quot; Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2016.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 23, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 23, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oklahoma State University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Solomon Hailu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Etiology</keyword>
  <keyword>Anemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Preschool</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual Participant Data (IPD) can be shared upon request and signing of an agreement between the Ethiopian Public Health Institute and the interested party.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

