<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623800</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC/05/2022 (ST/MR/85)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623800</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HIV Education Kit for Adolescents (Pencegahan HIV di Kalangan Remaja), PREM-Kit</brief_title>
  <acronym>PREM-Kit</acronym>
  <official_title>HIV Education Kit for Adolescents (Pencegahan HIV di Kalangan Remaja), PREM-Kit</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universiti Teknologi Mara</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universiti Teknologi Mara</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this community trial is to provide HIV education based on the newly developed HIV&#xD;
      education kit (PREM-Kit) and evaluate the knowledge, attitude and practices related to HIV&#xD;
      prevention among the late adolescents (aged 18 to 19 years old) in Malaysia. The main&#xD;
      question it aims to answer is does the PREM-Kit improve the knowledge, attitude and practices&#xD;
      related to HIV prevention among the adolescent?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  answer a questionnaire as a baseline screening to determine their knowledge, attitude&#xD;
           and practices related to HIV prevention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Using PREM-Kit, they will participate in a series of health education sessions. There&#xD;
           will be three sessions in total which will be delivered two weekly apart. Each of the&#xD;
           sessions will take approximately 20 minutes duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Following the last session (third session), participants will have to complete the same&#xD;
           questionnaire twice; once immediately after the last session and once 12 weeks later.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers will compare participants who received the existing Basic Science and Biology&#xD;
      module to see if there is any improvement in the knowledge, attitude and practices related to&#xD;
      HIV prevention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in knowledge score related to HIV prevention</measure>
    <time_frame>Time point 1: Measurement of knowledge score at baseline (before intervention). Time point 2: Measurement of knowledge score at week 6 (immediately post-intervention). Time point 3: Measurement of knowledge score at week 18 (12 weeks post-intervention).</time_frame>
    <description>Knowledge score will be determined by using 15 questions related to HIV/AIDS transmission and prevention. The participants will be asked to respond on the individual statement using &quot;Yes&quot; or &quot;No&quot; or &quot;I do not know&quot; response. Each correct answer will be credited with 1 point, whereas wrong answers and ''I don't know'' answers will be assigned 0 points. The sum calculated to determine a total score for this scale. The possible range of total score is 0 to 15, where higher score indicates higher level of knowledge.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in attitude score related to HIV prevention</measure>
    <time_frame>Time point 1: Measurement of attitude score at baseline (before intervention). Time point 2: Measurement of attitude score at week 6 (immediately post-intervention). Time point 3: Measurement of attitude score at week 18 (12 weeks post-intervention).</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the attitude score, eight items are used to assess the participants' attitude toward HIV/AIDS prevention. It consists of 5-point Likert scale (strongly agree, agree, undecided, disagree and strongly disagree). The scale given to the answers which is positive or agreeable is in the order of 5, 4, 3, 2, and 1. The scale given to the negative answers is in the reverse order. The possible range of the total score is 8 to 40, where higher score indicates higher positive attitude related to HIV prevention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in practice score related to HIV prevention</measure>
    <time_frame>Time point 1: Measurement of practice score at baseline (before intervention). Time point 2: Measurement of practice score at week 6 (immediately post-intervention). Time point 3: Measurement of practice score at week 18 (12 weeks post-intervention).</time_frame>
    <description>Practice score will be assessed by six questions. All practice items are measured by &quot;Yes&quot;, &quot;No&quot; and &quot;I do not know&quot; response. For questions such as (i) Do you watch any form of pornography?, (ii) Do you smoke?, (iii) Have you ever drink alcohol?, (iv) Have you ever tried any narcotic drugs?, and (v) Have you ever had sexual intercourse?, the &quot;Yes&quot; and &quot;I do not know&quot; responses will be scored as 0 point and &quot;No&quot; response will be scored as 1. On the other hand, the question of (vi) Have you ever talked about AIDS or HIV infection with your parents or other adults in your family?, &quot;Yes&quot; response will score 1 point, whereas, &quot;No&quot; and &quot;I do not know&quot; response will score 0. The possible range of total score of this practice measure is between 0 to 6, where higher score is indicative for more good practices related to HIV prevention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">184</enrollment>
  <condition>Human Immunodeficiency Virus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PREM-Kit group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PREM-Kit</intervention_name>
    <description>The PREM-Kit, which was created based on the Information-Motivation-Behavioral Skills model, is used in a series of HIV education sessions as part of the intervention. Over the course of three sessions, there will be a total of six weeks (one session for every two weeks). Three sub-modules, namely HIV facts and information, motivation for HIV preventive behavior, and behavioral skills for HIV prevention, will be emphasized in each session to the participants via flip chart and health educational videos. Additionally, participants will receive a QR code that gives them access to the PREM-Kit's e-flip chart, which they can see at a later time.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PREM-Kit group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  late adolescents aged 18 - 19 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  student who attends Health Science Diploma course in the year 2023&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malaysian citizen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  student who refused to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  student who is absent on the first session of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  student who does not understand the Malay language&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wan Nur Syamimi N Wan Mohamad Darani</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wan Nur Syamimi N Wan Mohamad Darani</last_name>
    <phone>+60126370747</phone>
    <email>wnsyamimi3007@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universiti Teknologi MARA (Dengkil Campus)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dengkil</city>
        <state>Selangor</state>
        <zip>43800</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wan Nur Syamimi N Wan Mohamad Darani</last_name>
      <phone>+60126370747</phone>
      <email>wnsyamimi3007@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wan Nur Syamimi N Wan Mohamad Darani</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universiti Teknologi Mara</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Wan Nur Syamimi Binti Wan Mohamad Darani</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Human Immunodeficiency Virus</keyword>
  <keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
  <keyword>Information-Motivation-Behavioral Skills Model</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

