<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623007</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DIVINE</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623007</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dietary Modulation of Gut Microbiota in Overweight/Obese Adolescents and COVID-19 Infection</brief_title>
  <acronym>DIVINE</acronym>
  <official_title>Dietary Modulation of Gut Microbiota on Nutritional Status and COVID-19 Infection in Adolescents: Gut-Lung-Axis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indonesia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Gadjah Mada University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universitas Airlangga</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Melbourne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Indonesia Endowment Funds for Education, Ministry of Finance Indonesia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indonesia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Probiotic intervention has been currently suggested to provide supportive benefits in&#xD;
      promoting health, including alleviating disease symptoms, protecting against diarrhea and&#xD;
      respiratory infection, affecting growth and modulating the immune system by improving the&#xD;
      beneficial gut microbiota colonization, giving direction on the gut-lung-axis pathway. This&#xD;
      indicates that probiotics may become alternative to improve nutrition and reduce the risk of&#xD;
      viral infections which may reduce the risk against Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Corona&#xD;
      Virus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). Introduction to probiotics during adolescence can alleviate&#xD;
      inflammation and invert dysbiosis. However, evidence on the effect of probiotic&#xD;
      supplementation on enhancing antibody response to SARS COV-2 in adolescents is lacking.&#xD;
      Moreover, previous studies showed the potential effect of probiotic supplementation to&#xD;
      improve overweight and obesity in adolescents. A bi-directional relationship exists among&#xD;
      nutrition, infection, and immunity as changes in one element will affect the others. The main&#xD;
      objective of this study is to investigate the effect of dietary modulation of overweight and&#xD;
      obese adolescent's gut microbiota through probiotic supplementation combined with healthy&#xD;
      eating and physical activity counseling and psychosocial stimulation on nutritional status&#xD;
      and antibody response to COVID-19 vaccination. This trial will conduct a 20-week intervention&#xD;
      for overweight and obese adolescents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The adolescence period is the transition from childhood to adulthood. Adolescents are&#xD;
      vulnerable to many biomedical exposures, such as a low-quality diet, fewer fruits and&#xD;
      vegetable intake, low physical activities, smoking habits, and alcohol consumption; and&#xD;
      non-biomedical aspects such as mental depression, parental distress, and household income,&#xD;
      which were known to be associated with increased risk of many health outcomes. Obese&#xD;
      adolescents are vulnerable to many infections, poor disease outcomes and complications, and&#xD;
      lower antibody response to vaccinations. Studies that have investigated Covid-19 incidence in&#xD;
      overweight and obese individuals are still scarce. Adolescence is also a sensitive period to&#xD;
      microbial change or dysbiosis due to practicing poor diet, low physical activity, inadequate&#xD;
      sleep, stress, and substance use (smoking, drugs, and alcohol). Despite the existing&#xD;
      prevalence of SARS-COV-2 infections is increasing in adolescents, and the vaccine program is&#xD;
      not prioritized in this population, making the prevention strategy for SARS-COV-2 infection&#xD;
      may become less effective in this population. Besides, low-quality diet and lifestyle habits&#xD;
      and family cluster transmission at home are often not fully addressed in the policy. These&#xD;
      factors may be the contributors to the potential highest COVID-19 exposure for children and&#xD;
      adolescents. Since exposure among adolescents is linked to serious adverse health effects,&#xD;
      effective interventions to improve nutritional outcomes and reduce the risk of COVID-19&#xD;
      infection will provide substantial long-term returns. However, such interventions for&#xD;
      adolescents in Indonesia and globally are lacking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a randomized clinical trial (RCT) and placebo parallel controlled study. The&#xD;
      research will be conducted in junior and senior high schools in Jakarta, Surabaya, and&#xD;
      Yogyakarta, Indonesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In light of COVID-19 outbreak, if face-to-face activities are permitted by (1) national&#xD;
      government (Indonesian Ministry of Health), (2) local government (DKI Jakarta), (3) the&#xD;
      university, (4) Data Safety Monitoring Board, and (5) by consent of the subject, then the&#xD;
      activities need to be strictly adjusted with the COVID-19 prevention measures for both&#xD;
      personnel and subjects. All personnel and subjects who will be involved in the activities are&#xD;
      required to fill out the COVID-19 symptom screening form prior to the visit and have been&#xD;
      vaccinated with a complete dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The product will be given to 440 overweight/obese adolescents, 220 adolescents as an intervention group, and 220 overweight/obese adolescents as a control group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Quadruple (Participant, Enumerator, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor) Participant, enumerator, investigator, and outcomes assessor do not know which one is the intervention product or placebo.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>BMI-for-age z-scores (BAZ)</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in BAZ obtain from anthropometric measurements, i.e., weight (kg) and height (m) converted to BMI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunoglobulin G (IgG) specific to SARS-COV-2 titer concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>10 and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in IgG specific to SARS-COV-2 titer concentrations assessed by electro chemiluminescence immunoassay (ECLIA)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>α-gut microbiota diversity</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in α-diversity measured by 1) Chao1, 2) phylogenetic diversity, and 3) the Shannon index.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>β-gut microbiota diversity</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in β -diversity: as the variability in community composition (the identity of taxa observed) among samples</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Monoclonal antibody affinity against SARS-COV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>10 and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in equilibrium dissociation constant (KD) of monoclonal antibody against SARS-COV-2 spike protein measured by competitive ELISA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secretory Immunoglobulin A (sIgA) specific to SARS-COV-2 titer concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>10 and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in sIgA specific to SARS-COV-2 titer concentrations assessed by competitive ELISA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dietary quality</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in score of dietary quality assessed by Healthy Eating Index 2015 from 24 hour recalls data</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-COV-2 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in proportion of symptomatic COVID-19 and positive PCR</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Body height</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in height-for-age z-score by anthropometric measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Abdominal obesity (waist circumference)</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in waist circumference by anthropometric measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Abdominal obesity (waist-hip ratio)</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in waist-hip ratio by anthropometric measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Middle upper arm circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in middle upper arm circumference by anthropometric measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Immunoglobulin M (IgM) against SARS-Cov-2</measure>
    <time_frame>10 and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in IgM titer concentrations assessed by electro chemiluminescence immunoassay (ECLIA)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Neutralizing antibody against SARS-Cov-2</measure>
    <time_frame>10 and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in total neutralizing antibody titer assessed by Surrogate Virus Neutralization Test (sVNT)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Gut integrity</measure>
    <time_frame>10 and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in level of zonulin assessed by ELISA</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Gut microbiota profiling</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in composition of gut microbiota assessed by next-generation sequencing (NGS)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Short Chain Fatty Acids (SCFA)</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in concentration of the SCFA by gas chromatograph</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in International Physical Activity Questionnaire for Adolescent (IPAQ-A) score, the minimum is 0 metabolic equivalents of task (MET) minutes/week, and the maximum score is 3000 MET minutes/week. Higher score means better outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Body image</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in Body Shape Questionnaire-34 (BSQ-34) score. The minimum score is 34, and the maximum is 204. Higher score means worse outcome</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in Patient Health Questionnaire for Adolescents (PHQ-A) score. The minimum score is 0, and the maximum is 27. Higher scores mean worse outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Self-esteem</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in Rosenberg Self Esteem Scale. The minimum score is 0, and the maximum score is 37. Higher scores mean better outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life score</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the score of Youth Quality of Life for adolescents-Research version (YQOL-R). The minimum score is 0, and the maximum score is 100. Higher scores mean better outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Morbidity</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Type and frequency of illness</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 10, 15, and 20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Type and frequency of illness</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children score</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children (WISC). The minimum score is 70, and the maximum score is 159. Higher scores mean better outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Brain Derived Neurotropic Factor level</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in level of Brain Derived Neurotropic Factor (BDNF) assessed by ELISA</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Anemia status</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in hemoglobin concentration</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">440</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Child Development</condition>
  <condition>Adolescent Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>220 overweight/obese adolescents will be given Probiotics and counselling on healthy eating, physical activity, and psychosocial stimulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>220 overweight/obese adolescents will be given placebo probiotics and counselling on healthy eating, physical activity, and psychosocial stimulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Probiotics</intervention_name>
    <description>Combination of 3 probiotic strains: Lactobacillus rhamnosus (LGG), Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. lactis (BB-12), and Lactobacillus acidophilus (LA-5)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Counselling on healthy eating, physical activity, and psychosocial stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Counselling on healthy eating, physical activity, and psychosocial stimulation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo probiotics</intervention_name>
    <description>Maltodextrin</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. living in Jakarta, Surabaya, and Yogyakarta City for at least 6 months permanently;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. apparently healthy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. male and female, age 12-17 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. overweight or obese (BMI-for-age z-score &gt;+1SD);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. have completed at least two dosages of COVID-19 vaccine, the vaccine must be&#xD;
             CoronaVac® (Sinovac);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. minimal 6 months post vaccinated prior to recruitments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. parents willing to sign the informed consent and adolescents give informed assent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Must have an active health insurance, for instance BPJS or similar health insurance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. having a history of COVID-19 infection within the last month confirmed by PCR or&#xD;
             antigen from health care facilities or independent laboratory;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. having a history of chronic and non-communicable diseases, congenital diseases, and&#xD;
             disabilities;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. reported current diagnosed as suspected active Tuberculosis (primary lung TB, miliary&#xD;
             TB, bleeding cough bone TB, meningitis TB);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. having a history of gastrointestinal or malabsorption disorder (such as celiac disease&#xD;
             and inflammatory bowel disease) within the last three months or during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. taking antibiotics during 2 weeks before the start of the study (adolescents will be&#xD;
             included after 3 weeks of last antibiotic intake);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. taking other medications or having diseases that may influence the immune response -&#xD;
             i.e. immune deficiencies, immunosuppressants medications, blood transfusion or other&#xD;
             blood products;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. taking insulin and/or anti-dyslipidemia medication;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. being pregnant and/or breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rina Agustina, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Human Nutrition Research Center, IMERI; Dep of Nutrition, Fac.of Medicine UI</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rina Agustina, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+622129189160</phone>
    <phone_ext>201052</phone_ext>
    <email>dr.rinaagustina@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rahyussalim Rahyussalim, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+62 21 291 891 60</phone>
    <phone_ext>201908</phone_ext>
    <email>manajer.riset.fkui1@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Nutrition (FKUI-RSCM); and Human Nutrition Research Center, Indonesian Medical Education Research Institute (HNRC-IMERI) Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jakarta Pusat</city>
        <state>DKI Jakarta</state>
        <zip>10430</zip>
        <country>Indonesia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rina Agustina, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+6221 2912477</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rina Agustina, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Julie Bines, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Susan Sawyer, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Murdani Abdullah, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erfi Prafianti, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dwiana Ocviyanti, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karina R Ekawidyani, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dian N Chandra, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Okky L Sari, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Deviana S Siregar, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alfi R Putri, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Triska S Nindya, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mira Mutiyani, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rizqy A Pamungkas, SGz</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juffrie Juffrie, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Emy Huriyati, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wahyu Damayanti, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ainun Nisa, SGz</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Purwo S Rejeki, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lilik Djuari, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dwi Susanti, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Adi Pranoto, MKes</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fhadilla Amelia, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Indonesia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Petta I, Fraussen J, Somers V, Kleinewietfeld M. Interrelation of Diet, Gut Microbiome, and Autoantibody Production. Front Immunol. 2018 Mar 6;9:439. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2018.00439. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>29559977</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rajput S, Paliwal D, Naithani M, Kothari A, Meena K, Rana S. COVID-19 and Gut Microbiota: A Potential Connection. Indian J Clin Biochem. 2021 Jul;36(3):266-277. doi: 10.1007/s12291-020-00948-9. Epub 2021 Jan 21.</citation>
    <PMID>33495676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agustina R, Kok FJ, van de Rest O, Fahmida U, Firmansyah A, Lukito W, Feskens EJ, van den Heuvel EG, Albers R, Bovee-Oudenhoven IM. Randomized trial of probiotics and calcium on diarrhea and respiratory tract infections in Indonesian children. Pediatrics. 2012 May;129(5):e1155-64. doi: 10.1542/peds.2011-1379. Epub 2012 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>22492764</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abenavoli L, Scarpellini E, Colica C, Boccuto L, Salehi B, Sharifi-Rad J, Aiello V, Romano B, De Lorenzo A, Izzo AA, Capasso R. Gut Microbiota and Obesity: A Role for Probiotics. Nutrients. 2019 Nov 7;11(11):2690. doi: 10.3390/nu11112690.</citation>
    <PMID>31703257</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indonesia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rina Agustina</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>adolescent</keyword>
  <keyword>probiotics</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>obese</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

