<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05624229</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PPI-AVB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05624229</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Proton Pump Inhibitors in Cirrhotic Patients With Acute Variceal Bleeding</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Proton Pump Inhibitors in Cirrhotic Patients With Acute Variceal Bleeding</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>West China Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>West China Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acute Variceal Bleeding (AVB) in patients with liver cirrhosis is a common clinical critical&#xD;
      disease.There is little evidence for the effect of PPI use in patients with AVB in liver&#xD;
      cirrhosis, and there is no study on the efficacy of PPI combined with standard therapy in&#xD;
      patients with AVB.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute Variceal Bleeding (AVB) in patients with liver cirrhosis is a common clinical critical&#xD;
      disease, with a 6-week mortality rate as high as 20%. Currently, many guidelines recommend&#xD;
      the use of vasoactive drugs (terlipressin, somatostatin or octreotide) combined with&#xD;
      endoscopic therapy (Endoscopic Variceal Ligation (EVL), endoscopic injection sclerotherapy&#xD;
      (EIS) and the use of prophylactic antibiotics for patients with AVB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proton pump inhibitor (PPI) is a commonly used antacid agent, which has a significant antacid&#xD;
      effect, protects the gastrointestinal mucosa, promotes blood coagulation, healing ulcers,&#xD;
      effectively stops bleeding and prevents rebleeding. There is a consensus that PPI should be&#xD;
      used before and after endoscopic therapy in patients with non-variceal acute bleeding.&#xD;
      However, studies on the efficacy of PPI after EVL are still limited and lack sufficient&#xD;
      convincing. In the 2005 Shrestha et al. randomized controlled study, pantoprazole treatment&#xD;
      was found to be associated with significantly smaller varicular ulcers 10 days after elective&#xD;
      EVL in secondary prevention patients with cirrhosis. Lo et al. 's randomized controlled study&#xD;
      in 2013 found that patients with cirrhosis and AVB treated with PPI for 19 days after&#xD;
      endoscopic hemostasis had smaller ulcers and fewer overall side effects, but there was no&#xD;
      statistically significant difference in 5-day treatment failure, 6-week rebleeding rate and&#xD;
      6-week mortality. In 2017, Chuah et al. included 637 patients with acute bleeding from liver&#xD;
      cirrhosis, 80% of whom were treated with acid suppression therapy, and the study found that&#xD;
      acid suppression therapy had no significant effect on long-term bleeding and mortality.&#xD;
      However, negative effects of PPI have been reported in patients with cirrhosis, such as&#xD;
      spontaneous bacterial peritonitis and hepatic encephalopathy. Jepsen et al. found that&#xD;
      patients with cirrhosis and ascites had an increased risk of first hepatic encephalopathy&#xD;
      with PPI use, and Riggio et al. also found that patients with cirrhosis had an increased risk&#xD;
      of hepatic encephalopathy and death with PPI use. Therefore, PPI use in patients with&#xD;
      cirrhosis should be more cautious. However, the duration of PPI use in these studies was&#xD;
      long, and there are no data to clarify the effect of short-term PPI use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At present, there is no consensus among the major guidelines on the use of PPI in patients&#xD;
      with acute AVB in liver cirrhosis, and the UK guidelines do not recommend the use of PPI&#xD;
      unless accompanied by gastrointestinal ulcer. The use of PPI was not mentioned in the&#xD;
      guidelines of the American Endoscopic Society and the European Endoscopic Society. The 2021&#xD;
      Baveno 7 guideline clearly proposes that PPI should be stopped immediately once AVB is&#xD;
      identified as cirrhosis. The latest meta-analysis in 2022 showed that the use of PPI before&#xD;
      endoscopy may reduce the need for endoscopic hemostasis in patients with upper&#xD;
      gastrointestinal tract, but there was no sufficient evidence to confirm the effect on&#xD;
      clinical outcomes including 30-day mortality and rebleeding. It can be concluded that there&#xD;
      is no consensus on the use of PPI in patients with AVB in cirrhosis, and the recommendations&#xD;
      of guidelines lack high-quality studies to improve the convincing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, there is little evidence for the effect of PPI use in patients with AVB in liver&#xD;
      cirrhosis, and there is no study on the efficacy of PPI combined with endoscopic therapy in&#xD;
      patients with AVB in liver cirrhosis. Therefore, we planned to design a multicenter&#xD;
      prospective randomized controlled trial to explore the efficacy of PPI in cirrhotic patients&#xD;
      with AVB. In this study, the following questions were investigated: 1. Can PPI reduce the&#xD;
      5-day treatment failure rate in cirrhotic patients with AVB; 2. Can it reduce the 6-week&#xD;
      rebleeding rate, mortality, and complications in patients with liver cirrhosis and AVB.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>5-day treatment failure rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Failure of initial hemostasis Initial hemostasis was defined as not achieving a 24h bleeding-free period within the first 48h after treatment together with stable vital signs based on Baveno consensus criteria.&#xD;
UGI bleeding occurred after initial hemostasis and within 5 days after enrollment was defined as early rebleeding. UGI bleeding was proven to be from esophageal varices.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rebleeding within 42 days</measure>
    <time_frame>42 days</time_frame>
    <description>Rebleeding within 42 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality within 42 days</measure>
    <time_frame>42 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mortality within 42 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rescure treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>42 days</time_frame>
    <description>TIPs, re-endoscopy, surgery, etc</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compilcations</measure>
    <time_frame>42 days</time_frame>
    <description>Chest pain, reflux, nausea, vomiting, dysphagia, ulcer perforation, diarrhea, abdominal pain, headache, hepatic encephalopathy, spontaneous peritonitis, etc</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">672</enrollment>
  <condition>Control of Bleed</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Early treatment is mainly aimed at correcting hypovolemic shock, preventing gastrointestinal bleeding-related complications (infection, electrolyte acid-base disorder, hepatic encephalopathy, etc.), effective control of bleeding, monitoring vital signs and urine output.&#xD;
Medical treatment included initiation and maintenance of vasoactive agents (terlipressin, somatostatin, octreotide, depending on the participating institution) as soon as possible for 2 to 5 days, and prophylactic antibiotics (preferably ceftriaxone sodium or quinolones) by intravenous infusion for 5 days.&#xD;
Endoscopic intervention was performed within 12 hours after presentation and generally no longer than 24 hours. PPI was stopped immediately after endoscopic treatment.&#xD;
Early TIPS is determined according to the technology and concept of each unit. Child-pugh score 7 points with active bleeding under endoscopy or Child-pugh score ≤13 points can be considered.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard group+PPI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PPI was continued after endoscopic therapy for 5 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Proton Pump Inhibitors</intervention_name>
    <description>PPI infusion stopped in standard group after endoscopy while continue to use for 5 days in experimental group</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard group+PPI</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Omeprazole</other_name>
    <other_name>Esomeprazole</other_name>
    <other_name>Rabeprazole</other_name>
    <other_name>Pantoprazole</other_name>
    <other_name>Ilaprazole</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Liver cirrhosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The etiology of portal hypertension is cirrhosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients presenting with acute esophageal variceal bleeding proven by emergency&#xD;
             endoscopy within 24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Be willing to participate in this clinical study, comply with the study requirements&#xD;
             and sign the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. non-cirrhotic portal hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. the time from admission to endoscopy was more than 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. patients with peptic ulcer or gastroesophageal reflux disease requiring PPI therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. PPI use for more than 2 weeks before admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. received endoscopic or interventional therapy within the previous 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. PPI allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Chronic renal insufficiency (CKD stage 3-5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Severe cardiopulmonary dysfunction (such as heart failure grade 3-4, respiratory&#xD;
             failure, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Hepatocellular carcinoma (Barcelona Clinic Liver Cancer (BCLC) stage C and D)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. other advanced malignancies (life expectancy less than 6 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 12, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>West China Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>luo xuefeng</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Proton Pump Inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Variceal Bleeding</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver Cirrhosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Endoscopic Variceal Ligation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Esomeprazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Omeprazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rabeprazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pantoprazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Proton Pump Inhibitors</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

