<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792878</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DTXY26</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792878</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of COVID-19 Infection and Its Clinical Prognosis in Chronic Hepatitis B Patients With Antiviral Therapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Observational Study of COVID-19 Infection and Its Clinical Prognosis in Chronic Hepatitis B Patients With Antiviral Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beijing Ditan Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beijing Ditan Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a two-way (retrospective and prospective) study of COVID-19 infection in an&#xD;
      observational cohort of patients with chronic hepatitis B treated with antiviral therapy.&#xD;
      Patients with chronic hepatitis B who received anti-HBV treatment in the Second Department of&#xD;
      Hepatology, Beijing Ditan Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University from February&#xD;
      2022 to December 2023 were enrolled. After enrollment, demographic data of patients,&#xD;
      information on antiviral treatment of chronic hepatitis B, COVID-19 vaccination, COVID-19&#xD;
      infection and COVID-19 incidence and treatment from January 2022 to pre enrollment, and data&#xD;
      on HBV virus and serology, clinical biochemistry, liver and lung imaging, COVID-19 nucleic&#xD;
      acid and COVID-19 antibody examination of patients were collected. After enrollment,&#xD;
      prospective anti-HBV treatment, HBV virology, clinical biochemistry, liver imaging and&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection and morbidity were observed. The patients with COVID-19 infection during&#xD;
      the prospective observation period were observed for COVID-19 infection, onset and treatment,&#xD;
      including body temperature, clinical symptoms, signs, cardiac examination, pulmonary imaging,&#xD;
      COVID-19, clinical biochemistry, disease severity, time of virus negative conversion,&#xD;
      hospital stay and outcome. The influence of COVID-19 infection on liver disease and the&#xD;
      influence of interferon anti-HBV treatment on COVID-19 infection, its pathogenesis and&#xD;
      prognosis were studied.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a two-way (retrospective+prospective) study of COVID-19 infection in an observational&#xD;
      cohort of patients with chronic hepatitis B treated with antiviral therapy. Patients with&#xD;
      chronic hepatitis B who received anti-HBV treatment in the Department of Hepatology Division&#xD;
      2, Beijing Ditan Hospital, Capital Medical University from February 2022 to December 2023&#xD;
      were enrolled. After enrollment, demographic data of patients, information on antiviral&#xD;
      treatment of chronic hepatitis B, COVID-19 vaccination, COVID-19 infection and COVID-19&#xD;
      incidence and treatment from January 2022 to pre enrollment, and data on hepatitis B virus&#xD;
      and serology, clinical biochemistry, liver and lung imaging, COVID-19 nucleic acid and&#xD;
      COVID-19 antibody examination of patients were collected. After enrollment, prospective anti&#xD;
      hepatitis B virus treatment, HBV virology, clinical biochemistry, liver imaging and COVID-19&#xD;
      infection and morbidity were observed. The patients with COVID-19 infection during the&#xD;
      prospective observation period were observed for COVID-19 infection, onset and treatment,&#xD;
      including body temperature, clinical symptoms, signs, cardiac examination, pulmonary imaging,&#xD;
      COVID-19, clinical biochemistry, disease severity, time of virus negative conversion,&#xD;
      hospital stay and outcome. The influence of COVID-19 infection on liver disease and the&#xD;
      influence of interferon anti hepatitis B virus treatment on COVID-19 infection, its&#xD;
      pathogenesis and prognosis were explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of COVID-19 infection.</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks after therapy</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of chronic hepatitis B patients infected with COVID-19 after initial antiviral treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of severe disease after COVID-19 infection.</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks after therapy</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of severe disease after COVID-19 infection for chronic hepatitis B patients after initial antiviral treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The hospitalization rate and duration of COVID-19.</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks after therapy</time_frame>
    <description>The hospitalization rate and duration of COVID-19 for chronic hepatitis B patients after initial antiviral treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Hepatitis B</condition>
  <condition>COVID-19 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interferon treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with chronic hepatitis B who received antiviral treatment with Interferon at the Second Department of Hepatology, Beijing Ditan Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University from February 2022 to December 2023 were enrolled.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>nucleoside analogues treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with chronic hepatitis B who received antiviral treatment with nucleoside analogues at the Second Department of Hepatology, Beijing Ditan Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University from February 2022 to December 2023 were enrolled</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interferon</intervention_name>
    <description>The naive treated patients with chronic hepatitis B were given antiviral treatment with interferon according to their condition.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interferon treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>peg-interferon alpha</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>nucleoside analogues</intervention_name>
    <description>The naive treated patients with chronic hepatitis B were given antiviral treatment with nucleoside analogues according to their condition.</description>
    <arm_group_label>nucleoside analogues treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>NAs</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        During 48 weeks of the prospective observation period, the treated patients continuously&#xD;
        use the original treatment. After the initial treatment patients are enrolled, they receive&#xD;
        antiviral treatment with interferon or nucleoside analogues according to the needs of the&#xD;
        disease. During the treatment period, the corresponding virology, serology, clinical&#xD;
        biochemistry and liver imaging examinations of hepatitis B antiviral treatment were carried&#xD;
        out every 3-6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        During COVID-19 infection, the patient shall be checked for clinical symptoms, clinical&#xD;
        biochemistry, blood routine, pulmonary imaging, COVID-19 and antibodies, as well as other&#xD;
        organs and functional indicators required by clinical needs.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1) HBsAg positive for 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2) Patients undergoing initial or ongoing antiviral treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3) HBeAg status and HBV DNA level are not limited.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1) Patients with decompensated liver cirrhosis or previous decompensated liver&#xD;
             cirrhosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2) At the same time, it is associated with other viral infections, such as hepatitis A&#xD;
             virus, hepatitis C virus, hepatitis D virus, hepatitis E virus, HIV, etc. - 3)&#xD;
             Accompanied with other serious physical and mental diseases, including uncontrolled&#xD;
             primary kidney, heart, lung, vascular, nervous, digestive, severe metabolic diseases&#xD;
             (such as uncontrolled hyperthyroidism, diabetes, serious complications, adrenal&#xD;
             diseases, etc.), immunodeficiency disease, and accompanied with serious infection;&#xD;
             History of active or suspected malignant tumors or malignant tumors.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yao Xie, Doctor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beijing Ditan Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yao Xie, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>8610-84322200</phone>
    <email>xieyao00120184@sina.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Hepatology Division 2, Beijing Ditan Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>100015</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yao Xie, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>8610-84322200</phone>
      <phone_ext>2489</phone_ext>
      <email>xieyao00120184@sina.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 28, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 28, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 28, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 28, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Beijing Ditan Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yao Xie</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Department of Hepatology Division 2, Beijing Ditan Hospital, Capital Medical University</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>chronic hepatitis</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19 infection</keyword>
  <keyword>interferon</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

