<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619315</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Charcoal based whitening</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619315</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enamel Abrasion and Stain Removal Efficacy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Enamel Abrasion and Stain Removal Efficacy of Two Whitening Toothpastes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Enamel abrasion and stain removal efficacy of two whitening toothpastes&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Statement of the problem:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Access to in-office treatments is restricted to a lot of population. Therefore, there has&#xD;
      been an interest in developing methods so that patients can remove stains and apply tooth&#xD;
      whitening at home. Accordingly, toothpastes, due to their ease of use and low cost, have been&#xD;
      used as vehicles for whitening agents as an alternative to home/office whitening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hydrogen peroxide is the most commonly used agent for whitening teeth, which is used in&#xD;
      various concentrations according to various techniques at home and office. Bleaching of teeth&#xD;
      in office is done at a high concentration of Hydrogen peroxide for a specified period of&#xD;
      time. In addition to conventional whitening treatments, over-the-counter products, including&#xD;
      gels, toothpastes, bleaching strips, mouthwashes, and pens with different Hydrogen peroxide&#xD;
      levels, have been developed. In-office teeth whitening is one of the more costly forms of&#xD;
      teeth whitening and the concentration of the bleaching element is higher, it is better&#xD;
      monitored by a professional.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Whitening toothpaste is probably the one of the most affordable options for someone looking&#xD;
      to whiten their teeth at home, which contain abrasive and chemical agents and have the&#xD;
      ability to remove external stains from the tooth. The abrasiveness of toothpastes depends on&#xD;
      the hardness, size, and shape of abrasive particles. Furthermore, factors such as the&#xD;
      brushing technique, brushing pressure, toothbrush hardness, and the number of brush strokes&#xD;
      affect tooth abrasion. Abrasive agents include silica, phosphates, carbonates, and&#xD;
      bicarbonates Chemical agents present in whitening toothpastes are sodium citrate, phosphate&#xD;
      salt, which react with chromogenic molecules of superficial dental stains and eliminate them&#xD;
      from the tooth surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Whitening toothpastes include different active ingredients in their composition. It normally&#xD;
      contain a higher amount of abrasives and detergents than do conventional toothpastes In this&#xD;
      sense, it is important to point out that toothpastes with higher amounts of abrasives may&#xD;
      produce increased surface roughness in dental tissues, or restorations, or even tooth&#xD;
      sensitivity, especially if they are used routinely&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Today, active charcoal is added to toothpastes which are marketed as charcoal toothpastes.&#xD;
      The first report on the use of charcoal in oral and dental hygiene has been attributed to&#xD;
      Hippocrates in ancient Greece. Charcoal is used as powder, soot, coal, and ash in different&#xD;
      countries. Charcoal-based products are used in medical treatments, such as its use as an&#xD;
      antidote for acute poisoning, drug overdose, skin infections, Charcoal is used legally for&#xD;
      the coloring of food in China, Japan, and Korea to improve health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Activated charcoal is produced as a natural method of the partial oxidation of various&#xD;
      materials. High-porosity activated charcoal has the ability to exchange ion in the mouth&#xD;
      through nanopores and can attach to tooth enamel and remove tooth-coloring agents (because of&#xD;
      its capacity of adsorbing pigments, chromophores, and stains from the tooth surface). The&#xD;
      application of this product has been suggested to eliminate some dental coloring agents.&#xD;
      Charcoal can help tooth whitening through tooth abrasion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stain score</measure>
    <time_frame>T0: Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>mcpherson modification of the stain index and area x intensity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stain score</measure>
    <time_frame>T1: 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>mcpherson modification of the stain index and area x intensity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surface roughness</measure>
    <time_frame>T0: Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Atomic Force Microscopy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surface roughness</measure>
    <time_frame>T1: 3 minutes equivalent to 2 times a day for one month.</time_frame>
    <description>Atomic Force Microscopy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Abrasion</condition>
  <condition>Discoloration, Tooth</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Charcoal -based whitening toothpaste.</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The labial surface of anterior teeth will be brushed by the circular brushing technique twice daily (morning and after 6 hours) for at least 1 minute using charcoal containing toothpaste. Soft bristles toothbrushes will provided to all patients. After 1 month, re-evaluation of the stains will be performed and the data will be recorded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Calcium carbonate /perlite containing whitening toothpaste.</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The labial surface of anterior teeth will be brushed by the circular brushing technique twice daily (morning and after 6hours) for at least 1 minute using (calcium carbonate /perlite) containing toothpaste. Soft bristles toothbrushes will provided to all patients. After 1 month, re-evaluation of the stains will be performed and the data will be recorded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Charcoal -based whitening toothpaste</intervention_name>
    <description>The labial surface of anterior teeth will be brushed by the circular brushing technique twice daily (morning and after 6 hours) for at least 1 minute using charcoal containing toothpaste. Soft bristles toothbrushes will provided to all patients. After 1 month, re-evaluation of the stains will be performed and the data will be recorded.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Charcoal -based whitening toothpaste.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Calcium carbonate /perlite containing whitening toothpaste.</intervention_name>
    <description>The labial surface of anterior teeth will be brushed by the circular brushing technique twice daily (morning and after 6hours) for at least 1 minute using (calcium carbonate /perlite) containing toothpaste. Soft bristles toothbrushes will provided to all patients. After 1 month, re-evaluation of the stains will be performed and the data will be recorded.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Calcium carbonate /perlite containing whitening toothpaste.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In vivo:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients inclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Adult male and female patients ≥18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Good oral and general health and oral hygiene have at least eight natural&#xD;
                  anterior teeth (incisors and canines) assessable for extrinsic stain and be&#xD;
                  available for all study appointments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Tooth inclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Vital anterior maxillary and mandibular teeth free of caries or restorations, no cervical&#xD;
        lesions and no periodontal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In vitro:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Teeth inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Intact, free of caries or restorations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No cervical lesions .&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In vivo:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Uncooperative behavior.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients allergic to tooth paste material.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient with history of medical disease, drug therapies or any other serious relevant&#xD;
             problem.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with fixed orthodontic appliances&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients who had professional tooth whitening, within the last six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients who had significant amounts of calculus on facial surfaces of the&#xD;
             incisors/canines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who had undergone professional periodontal treatment within the previous six&#xD;
             months or used mouth rinses for the treatment/ control of a periodontal condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients who had advanced periodontal disease on anterior teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Xerostomic patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients who used medications which could affect saliva flow or cause staining.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients who had undergone dental prophylaxis within 8 weeks of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients who used minocycline or doxycycline within 30 days of screening or between&#xD;
             screening and baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
        Tooth exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Intrinsically Discolored teeth caused by tetracycline, fluorosis, hypocalcification&#xD;
             hyperplasia, endodontic treatment (or requiring endodontic treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Restorations in anterior teeth, parafunctional habits or tooth sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Non- vital teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
        In vitro:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Teeth exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Intrinsically Discolored teeth caused by tetracycline, fluorosis, hyperplasia,&#xD;
             endodontic treatment .&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Restorations in teeth&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Iman Ibrahim El Sayad, prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Cairo University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mohamed Osama Metwally</last_name>
    <phone>00201008488587</phone>
    <email>Mohamedelbadry@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mohamed Refaat El-Bialy, phd</last_name>
    <phone>00201202552666</phone>
    <email>mohamed.refaat@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ghassemi A, Hooper W, Vorwerk L, Domke T, DeSciscio P, Nathoo S. Effectiveness of a new dentifrice with baking soda and peroxide in removing extrinsic stain and whitening teeth. J Clin Dent. 2012;23(3):86-91.</citation>
    <PMID>23210419</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Watts A, Addy M. Tooth discolouration and staining: a review of the literature. Br Dent J. 2001 Mar 24;190(6):309-16. doi: 10.1038/sj.bdj.4800959.</citation>
    <PMID>11325156</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lima DA, Silva AL, Aguiar FH, Liporoni PC, Munin E, Ambrosano GM, Lovadino JR. In vitro assessment of the effectiveness of whitening dentifrices for the removal of extrinsic tooth stains. Braz Oral Res. 2008 Apr-Jun;22(2):106-11. doi: 10.1590/s1806-83242008000200003.</citation>
    <PMID>18622478</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kalyana P, Shashidhar A, Meghashyam B, Sreevidya KR, Sweta S. Stain removal efficacy of a novel dentifrice containing papain and Bromelain extracts--an in vitro study. Int J Dent Hyg. 2011 Aug;9(3):229-33. doi: 10.1111/j.1601-5037.2010.00473.x. Epub 2010 Jul 1.</citation>
    <PMID>21356017</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Collins LZ, Naeeni M, Schafer F, Brignoli C, Schiavi A, Roberts J, Colgan P. The effect of a calcium carbonate/perlite toothpaste on the removal of extrinsic tooth stain in two weeks. Int Dent J. 2005;55(3 Suppl 1):179-82. doi: 10.1111/j.1875-595x.2005.tb00056.x.</citation>
    <PMID>16004250</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Patil PA, Ankola AV, Hebbal MI, Patil AC. Comparison of effectiveness of abrasive and enzymatic action of whitening toothpastes in removal of extrinsic stains - a clinical trial. Int J Dent Hyg. 2015 Feb;13(1):25-9. doi: 10.1111/idh.12090. Epub 2014 Jul 21.</citation>
    <PMID>25046241</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zafar MS, Ahmed N. Nanomechanical characterization of exfoliated and retained deciduous incisors. Technol Health Care. 2014;22(6):785-93. doi: 10.3233/THC-140852.</citation>
    <PMID>25134963</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Litonjua LA, Andreana S, Bush PJ, Tobias TS, Cohen RE. Noncarious cervical lesions and abfractions: a re-evaluation. J Am Dent Assoc. 2003 Jul;134(7):845-50. doi: 10.14219/jada.archive.2003.0282.</citation>
    <PMID>12892441</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Johannsen G, Tellefsen G, Johannsen A, Liljeborg A. The importance of measuring toothpaste abrasivity in both a quantitative and qualitative way. Acta Odontol Scand. 2013 May-Jul;71(3-4):508-17. doi: 10.3109/00016357.2012.696693. Epub 2012 Jul 2.</citation>
    <PMID>22746180</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carey CM. Tooth whitening: what we now know. J Evid Based Dent Pract. 2014 Jun;14 Suppl:70-6. doi: 10.1016/j.jebdp.2014.02.006. Epub 2014 Feb 13.</citation>
    <PMID>24929591</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ozkan P, Kansu G, Ozak ST, Kurtulmus-Yilmaz S, Kansu P. Effect of bleaching agents and whitening dentifrices on the surface roughness of human teeth enamel. Acta Odontol Scand. 2013 May-Jul;71(3-4):488-97. doi: 10.3109/00016357.2012.696691. Epub 2012 Jul 2.</citation>
    <PMID>22747485</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barbieri GM, Mota EG, Rodrigues-Junior SA, Burnett LH Jr. Effect of whitening dentifrices on the surface roughness of commercial composites. J Esthet Restor Dent. 2011 Oct;23(5):338-45. doi: 10.1111/j.1708-8240.2011.00426.x. Epub 2011 May 9.</citation>
    <PMID>21977958</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gerlach RW, Barker ML, Tucker HL. Clinical response of three whitening products having different peroxide delivery: comparison of tray, paint-on gel, and dentifrice. J Clin Dent. 2004;15(4):112-7.</citation>
    <PMID>15794456</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Joiner A. Review of the extrinsic stain removal and enamel/dentine abrasion by a calcium carbonate and perlite containing whitening toothpaste. Int Dent J. 2006 Aug;56(4):175-80. doi: 10.1111/j.1875-595x.2006.tb00091.x.</citation>
    <PMID>16972390</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brooks JK, Bashirelahi N, Reynolds MA. Charcoal and charcoal-based dentifrices: A literature review. J Am Dent Assoc. 2017 Sep;148(9):661-670. doi: 10.1016/j.adaj.2017.05.001. Epub 2017 Jun 7.</citation>
    <PMID>28599961</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pintado-Palomino K, Vasconcelos CV, Silva RJ, Fressatti AL, Motta BJ, Pires-DE-Souza FC, Tirapelli C. Effect of whitening dentifrices: a double-blind randomized controlled trial. Braz Oral Res. 2016 Oct 10;30(1):e82. doi: 10.1590/1807-3107BOR-2016.vol30.0082.</citation>
    <PMID>27737352</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Joiner A. Whitening toothpastes: a review of the literature. J Dent. 2010;38 Suppl 2:e17-24. doi: 10.1016/j.jdent.2010.05.017. Epub 2010 May 24.</citation>
    <PMID>20562012</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wulknitz P. Cleaning power and abrasivity of European toothpastes. Adv Dent Res. 1997 Nov;11(4):576-9. doi: 10.1177/08959374970110042701.</citation>
    <PMID>9470519</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Joiner A, Philpotts CJ, Alonso C, Ashcroft AT, Sygrove NJ. A novel optical approach to achieving tooth whitening. J Dent. 2008;36 Suppl 1:S8-14. doi: 10.1016/j.jdent.2008.02.005.</citation>
    <PMID>18646364</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Macpherson LM, Stephen KW, Joiner A, Schafer F, Huntington E. Comparison of a conventional and modified tooth stain index. J Clin Periodontol. 2000 Nov;27(11):854-9. doi: 10.1034/j.1600-051x.2000.027011854.x.</citation>
    <PMID>11073329</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Black MA, Bayne SC, Peterson CA. Effect of power toothbrushing on simulated wear of dental cement margins. J Dent Hyg. 2007 Fall;81(4):79. Epub 2007 Oct 1.</citation>
    <PMID>18173893</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hattab FN, Qudeimat MA, al-Rimawi HS. Dental discoloration: an overview. J Esthet Dent. 1999;11(6):291-310. doi: 10.1111/j.1708-8240.1999.tb00413.x.</citation>
    <PMID>10825865</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mohamed Osama Metwally</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>bachelor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>abrasion</keyword>
  <keyword>toothpaste</keyword>
  <keyword>stain</keyword>
  <keyword>whitening</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tooth Discoloration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Calcium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Charcoal</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

