<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05610943</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2977</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05610943</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of The Quadratus Lumborum Block and Ilioinguinal Iliohypogastric Nerve Block</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of The Postoperative Analgesic Effectiveness of Ultrasound-Guided Quadratus Lumborum Block and Ilioinguinal Iliohypogastric Nerve Block in Pediatric Inguinal Hernia Operation, Prospective Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sisli Hamidiye Etfal Training and Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sisli Hamidiye Etfal Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Perioperative and postoperative pain control in pediatric patients is a frequently neglected&#xD;
      issue. Regional anesthesia applications reduce adverse drug events by minimizing opioid&#xD;
      consumption and provide effective and safe analgesia. In recent years, quadratus lumborum&#xD;
      block has emerged as an alternative regional anesthesia technique and it has been shown to&#xD;
      provide analgesia as effectively as caudal block in children, and in a limited number of&#xD;
      studies it has been said that it is more effective than transversus abdominis plane block.&#xD;
      There are few studies in the literature comparing ilioinguinal iliohypogastic nerve block and&#xD;
      quadratus lumborum block in children.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Perioperative and postoperative pain control in pediatric patients is a frequently neglected&#xD;
      issue. Providing effective perioperative analgesia reduces surgical stress, making the&#xD;
      postoperative period more comfortable both physiologically and psychologically, effective&#xD;
      postoperative pain control reduces the length of stay in the hospital, and also contributes&#xD;
      to the long-term positive personality development of children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiological, pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic differences in children delay the&#xD;
      metabolism and excretion of systemic analgesics, resulting in a prolonged effect and an&#xD;
      increased risk of apnea. Regional anesthesia applications reduce adverse drug events by&#xD;
      minimizing opioid consumption and provide effective and safe analgesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Caudal block, which is a common regional anesthesia practice in inguinal hernia surgery in&#xD;
      children, has disadvantages such as motor block and urinary retention. With the introduction&#xD;
      of ultrasonography, peripheral block techniques such as transversus abdominis plane block and&#xD;
      ilioinguinal iliohypogastric nerve block have been shown to provide effective and safe&#xD;
      analgesia and have replaced central blocks. In recent years, quadratus lumborum block has&#xD;
      emerged as an alternative regional anesthesia technique and it has been shown to provide&#xD;
      analgesia as effectively as caudal block in children, and in a limited number of studies it&#xD;
      has been said that it is more effective than transversus abdominis plane block. There are few&#xD;
      studies in the literature comparing ilioinguinal iliohypogastric nerve block and quadratus&#xD;
      lumborum block in children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study to compare the postoperative analgesic effectiveness of quadratus&#xD;
      lumborum block and ilioinguinal iliohypogastric block in pediatric patients who underwent&#xD;
      unilateral inguinal hernia operation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FLACC score</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Face, Legs, Activity, Cry, Consolability (FLACC) Behavioral Pain Scale. FLACC is a behavioral pain assessment scale used for nonverbal or preverbal patients who are unable to self-report their level of pain. Pain is assessed through observation of 5 categories including face, legs, activity, cry, and consolability. The increase in the pain felt by the patient also increases the flacc score. Each category is scored on the 0-2 scale which results in a total score of 0-10.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>systemic analgesic administration times</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hour</time_frame>
    <description>the first postoperative systemic analgesic administration time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>frequency of systemic analgesic use</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hour</time_frame>
    <description>the frequency of systemic analgesic use in the first 24 hours postoperatively</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>complications</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hour</time_frame>
    <description>the complications related to the use of postoperative systemic analgesics and/or nerve block application</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Post Operative Pain</condition>
  <condition>Inguinal Hernia</condition>
  <condition>Quadratus Lumborum Nerve Block</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>quadratus lumborum nerve block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Group Q; The patient was placed in the lateral position with the side to be blocked on top. After providing skin antisepsis with 5% povidone iodine, sterile dressing was applied. After the USG probe was covered with a sterile sheath, it was placed transversely between the iliac crest and the costa edge. After imaging the external-internal oblique and transversus abdominis muscles, the probe was advanced posteriorly. Quadratus lumborum, Psoas Major and Erector Spina muscles were visualized. The needle was advanced towards the middle thoracolumbar fascia between the Quadratus lumborum muscle and the Erector Spina muscle with the in-plane technique, and the location was confirmed by injecting 1 ml of 0.9 saline. 0.25% Bupivacaine was injected at a dose of 0.5 mL/kg after negative aspiration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ilioinguinal Iliohypogastric Nerve Block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Group I; The patient was placed in the supine position. After providing skin antisepsis with 5% povidone iodine, sterile dressing was applied. After the USG probe was covered with a sterile sheath, it was placed on the anterior abdominal wall parallel to the imaginary line between the umbilicus and the anterior superior iliac wing. After imaging the external-internal oblique and transversus abdominis muscles, the ilioinguinal-iliohypogastric nerve was visualized as two small hypoechoic areas between the internal oblique muscle and the transversus abdominis muscle. The location was confirmed by injecting 1 ml of 0.9 saline by advancing the needle with the in-plane technique close to the nerve structures. 0.25% Bupivacaine was injected at a dose of 0.5 mL/kg after negative aspiration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ultrasound-guided quadratus lumborum nerve block</intervention_name>
    <description>The patient was placed in the lateral position with the side to be blocked on top. After providing skin antisepsis with 5% povidone iodine, sterile dressing was applied. After the USG probe was covered with a sterile sheath, it was placed transversely between the iliac crest and the costa edge. After imaging the external-internal oblique and transversus abdominis muscles, the probe was advanced posteriorly. Quadratus lumborum, Psoas Major and Erector Spina muscles were visualized. The needle was advanced towards the middle thoracolumbar fascia between the Quadratus lumborum muscle and the Erector Spina muscle with the in-plane technique, and the location was confirmed by injecting 1 ml of 0.9 saline. 0.25% Bupivacaine was injected at a dose of 0.5 mL/kg after negative aspiration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>quadratus lumborum nerve block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ultrasound-guided Ilioinguinal Iliohypogastric Nerve Block</intervention_name>
    <description>The patient was placed in the supine position. After providing skin antisepsis with 5% povidone iodine, sterile dressing was applied. After the USG probe was covered with a sterile sheath, it was placed on the anterior abdominal wall parallel to the imaginary line between the umbilicus and the anterior superior iliac wing. After imaging the external-internal oblique and transversus abdominis muscles, the ilioinguinal-iliohypogastric nerve was visualized as two small hypoechoic areas between the internal oblique muscle and the transversus abdominis muscle. The location was confirmed by injecting 1 ml of 0.9 saline by advancing the needle with the in-plane technique close to the nerve structures. 0.25% Bupivacaine was injected at a dose of 0.5 mL/kg after negative aspiration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ilioinguinal Iliohypogastric Nerve Block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  who were scheduled for unilateral inguinal hernia operation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical score I-II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged 2-7 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  skin infection at the block application site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  bupivacaine allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neuropsychiatric disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>sebnem turk</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sisli Hamidiye Etfal Training and Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sisli Hamidiye Etfal Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sisli</city>
        <state>Istanbul</state>
        <zip>34376</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Samerchua A, Leurcharusmee P, Panichpichate K, Bunchungmongkol N, Wanvoharn M, Tepmalai K, Khorana J, Chantakhow S. A Prospective, randomized comparative study between ultrasound-guided posterior quadratus lumborum block and ultrasound-guided ilioinguinal/iliohypogastric nerve block for pediatric inguinal herniotomy. Paediatr Anaesth. 2020 Apr;30(4):498-505. doi: 10.1111/pan.13837. Epub 2020 Feb 21.</citation>
    <PMID>32030845</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Priyadarshini K, Behera BK, Tripathy BB, Misra S. Ultrasound-guided transverse abdominis plane block, ilioinguinal/iliohypogastric nerve block, and quadratus lumborum block for elective open inguinal hernia repair in children: a randomized controlled trial. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2022 Apr;47(4):217-221. doi: 10.1136/rapm-2021-103201. Epub 2022 Jan 17. Erratum In: Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2022 Jun;47(6):e2.</citation>
    <PMID>35039439</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 2, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 2, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sisli Hamidiye Etfal Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mustafa Altınay</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>quadratus lumborum nerve block</keyword>
  <keyword>postoperative pain</keyword>
  <keyword>inguinal herniae</keyword>
  <keyword>ilio-inguinal iliohypogastric nerve block</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hernia, Inguinal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

