<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618743</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MADC/IEC-I/023/2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618743</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>NSPT on Calprotectin and Periostin Levels</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Non Surgical Therapy on Calprotectin and Periostin Levels in Patients With Periodontitis and Cardiovascular Diseases - An Interventional Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Meenakshi Ammal Dental College and Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Meenakshi Ammal Dental College and Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Periodontitis is a chronic inflammatory disease is initiated by the oral microbial biofilm&#xD;
      where in the response to this infection is mediated by various intracellular signalling&#xD;
      pathways leading to the production of numerous bio-molecules. .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Calprotectin is major cytoplasmic protein expressed in majority by neutrophils and as well&#xD;
      seen in gingival epithelial cells, activated macrophages and vascular endothelial cells in&#xD;
      minor amounts. Calprotectin is regarded as acute phase protein that increases during a&#xD;
      variety of inflammatory diseases like periodontitis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes,&#xD;
      rheumatoid arthritis and inflammatory bowel disease. Periostin is a marked anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      protein belonging to fascilin family which actively contributed to tissue injury, fibrosis,&#xD;
      atherosclerosis and inflammatory diseases Hence this study aims to determine the expression&#xD;
      of Calprotectin and Periostin as biomarkers and also as putative risk indicators in&#xD;
      generalized chronic periodontitis subjects with or without cardiovascular disease before and&#xD;
      after non-surgical therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Periodontitis is a chronic inflammatory disease is initiated by the oral microbial biofilm&#xD;
      where in the response to this infection is mediated by various intracellular signalling&#xD;
      pathways leading to the production of numerous bio-molecules. The emerging era of molecular&#xD;
      analysis has paved the way to quantify and study the disease markers to which plays a vital&#xD;
      role in disease progression. This, in turn, has marked the advent of various studies which&#xD;
      employ the use of serum, saliva, gingival crevicular fluid, plaque and tissue samples, etc.,&#xD;
      to study various diseases in the oral cavity and its relation with systemic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several epidemiological studies support an association between high levels of inflammatory&#xD;
      biomarkers due to periodontal infections and increased risk and progression of cardio&#xD;
      vascular disease. Both periodontitis and cardio vascular disease share various biomarkers&#xD;
      expressed in common present in saliva, serum and gingival crevicular fluid which correlates&#xD;
      the link of periodontitis with cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Calprotectin is major cytoplasmic protein expressed in majority by neutrophils and as well&#xD;
      seen in gingival epithelial cells, activated macrophages and vascular endothelial cells in&#xD;
      minor amounts. Calprotectin is regarded as acute phase protein that increases during a&#xD;
      variety of inflammatory diseases like periodontitis, cardiovascular disease, diabetes,&#xD;
      rheumatoid arthritis and inflammatory bowel disease. Calprotectin have been detected in GCF&#xD;
      and oral tissues where in initial periodontal therapy can reduce the levels of Calprotectin,&#xD;
      but their clinical signiﬁcance has never been investigated in patients with chronic&#xD;
      periodontitis and cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among the various matricellular proteins expressed in saliva and GCF, Periostin is a marked&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory protein belonging to fascilin family which actively contributed to tissue&#xD;
      injury, fibrosis, atherosclerosis and inflammatory diseases. Periostin is commonly found in&#xD;
      collagen rich tissues thereby it is thought to affect the production of collagen fibrils. The&#xD;
      defensive role of Periostin in periodontal tissues and its expression in periodontitis and&#xD;
      cardio vascular disease correlating with before and after non-surgical therapy is less&#xD;
      studied which on further exploration might be a potent risk assessment tool linking&#xD;
      periodontal and cardiovascular diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While there are studies which have demonstrated the expression of Calprotectin and Periostin&#xD;
      in gingival crevicular fluid (GCF) of periodontal patients separately, there are no studies&#xD;
      which correlate their interrelationship in periodontitis and cardiovascular disease. Hence&#xD;
      this study aims to determine the expression of Calprotectin and Periostin as biomarkers and&#xD;
      also as putative risk indicators in generalized chronic periodontitis subjects with or&#xD;
      without cardiovascular disease before and after non-surgical therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Three arm clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in periodontal parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in Periodontal Probing Depth (measured in mm)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in periodontal variables</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in Clinical Attachment Level (measured in mm)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in periodontal criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in Plaque Index (measured in numericals)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in periodontal variables</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction in Gingival index (mesured in numericals)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Periodontal Inflammation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Periodontally and systemically healthy participants (Control group)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Periodontitis without Cardiovascular disease</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Periodontitis participants without cardiovascular disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Periodontitis with cardiovascular disease</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Periodontitis participants with cardiovascular disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non Surgical Periodontal Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Scaling and root planing using scalers and periodontal curettes will be done</description>
    <arm_group_label>Periodontitis with cardiovascular disease</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Periodontitis without Cardiovascular disease</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Patients willing to participate in the study. Patients within the age group of 30-65&#xD;
        years. Patients should have ≥ 20 remaining natural teeth. For Group I Systemically healthy,&#xD;
        Periodontally healthy subjects with Probing pocket depth (PD) less than 4mm, bleeding on&#xD;
        probing (BOP) at ≤15% of tooth sites, no periodontal treatment (Scaling and root planing or&#xD;
        periodontal surgery) within the previous 6 months and without evident clinical signs of&#xD;
        gingival inflammation. .&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Group II Generalized chronic periodontitis subjects with 30% or more sites with&#xD;
        clinical attachment loss (CAL) ≥ 2mm, radiographic evidence of alveolar crestal bone loss ≥&#xD;
        2mm from the cemento-enamel junction along with cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Group III Systemically healthy, Generalized chronic periodontitis subjects with 30% or&#xD;
        more sites with clinical attachment loss (CAL) ≥ 2mm, radiographic evidence of alveolar&#xD;
        crestal bone loss ≥ 2mm from the cemento-enamel junction.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects with systemic conditions such as type I and type II diabetes mellitus, respiratory&#xD;
        diseases, renal disease, liver disease, rheumatoid arthritis, allergy, advanced&#xD;
        malignancies and HIV infection will be excluded from the present investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Group III, subjects on drugs such as corticosteroids, antibiotics, within 6 months of&#xD;
        investigation will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Current smokers and individuals who quit smoking less than 6 months. Patients who have&#xD;
        undergone periodontal therapy within the previous 6 months. Pregnant women (pregnancy may&#xD;
        alter the oral flora)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Only male participants are included belonging to 30-65 years of age</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jaideep Mahendra, MDS,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Meenakshi Ammal Dental College and Hospitals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jaideep Mahendra, MDS, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>09444963973</phone>
    <email>jaideep_m_23@yahoo.co.in</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Janani Muralidharan, BDS</last_name>
    <phone>08939394241</phone>
    <email>janani.harini718@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jaideep Mahendra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chennai</city>
        <state>Tamilnadu</state>
        <zip>600095</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jaideep Mahendra, MDS;PhD</last_name>
      <phone>9444963973</phone>
      <phone_ext>9444963973</phone_ext>
      <email>jaideep_m_23@yahoo.co.in</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Janani Muralidharan, BDS</last_name>
      <phone>8939394241</phone>
      <email>janani.harini718@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Janani Muralidharan, BDS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kaner D, Bernimoulin JP, Dietrich T, Kleber BM, Friedmann A. Calprotectin levels in gingival crevicular fluid predict disease activity in patients treated for generalized aggressive periodontitis. J Periodontal Res. 2011 Aug;46(4):417-26. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0765.2011.01355.x. Epub 2011 Apr 13.</citation>
    <PMID>21488873</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arslan R, Karsiyaka Hendek M, Kisa U, Olgun E. The effect of non-surgical periodontal treatment on gingival crevicular fluid periostin levels in patients with gingivitis and periodontitis. Oral Dis. 2021 Sep;27(6):1478-1486. doi: 10.1111/odi.13664. Epub 2020 Oct 23.</citation>
    <PMID>33012041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Meenakshi Ammal Dental College and Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr.Jaideep Mahendra</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Research and Post Graduate Studies, Professor, Department of Periodontics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

