<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619809</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB2022-933</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619809</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chronic Thermogenic Dietary Supplement Consumption</brief_title>
  <official_title>Chronic Thermogenic Dietary Supplement Consumption: Effects on Body Composition, Anthropometrics, Metabolism, and Subjective Variables</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Texas Tech University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>EHP Labs</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Texas Tech University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Healthy, exercising adult&#xD;
      males and females will be recruited for participation. After providing informed consent, each&#xD;
      participant will be randomized to one of three groups: 1) OxyShred thermogenic fat burner; 2)&#xD;
      Placebo (PL); and 3) Control. All participants will complete a baseline laboratory visit&#xD;
      consisting of assessments of body composition, anthropometry, metabolism, hemodynamics,&#xD;
      dietary intake, exercise habits, and subjective variables. Participants in the two&#xD;
      intervention groups (i.e., OxyShred and PL) will then be given dietary supplements for daily&#xD;
      consumption, including OxyShred/PL and protein powder. Participants in all groups will&#xD;
      complete the 4-week study and follow their usual training and nutrition habits - besides&#xD;
      increased protein intake in the OxyShred and PL groups - along with questionnaires to assess&#xD;
      compliance with the study protocol and potential side effects of supplementation. Following&#xD;
      this 4-week period, participants will complete a second laboratory visit, where all baseline&#xD;
      assessments will be repeated. The effects of group (OxyShred, PL, and control) and time&#xD;
      (baseline, 4 weeks) will be statistically examined using linear models, along with&#xD;
      appropriate post-hoc tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Overview. This study is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Healthy,&#xD;
      exercising adult males and females will be recruited for participation. After providing&#xD;
      informed consent, each participant will be randomized to one of three groups: 1) OxyShred&#xD;
      thermogenic fat burner; 2) Placebo (PL); and 3) Control. All participants will complete a&#xD;
      baseline laboratory visit consisting of assessments of body composition, anthropometry,&#xD;
      metabolism, hemodynamics, dietary intake, exercise habits, and subjective variables.&#xD;
      Participants in the two intervention groups (i.e., OxyShred and PL) will then be given&#xD;
      dietary supplements for daily consumption, including OxyShred/PL and protein powder.&#xD;
      Participants in all groups will complete the 4-week study and follow their usual training and&#xD;
      nutrition habits - besides increased protein intake in the OxyShred and PL groups - along&#xD;
      with questionnaires to assess compliance with the study protocol and potential side effects&#xD;
      of supplementation. Following this 4-week period, participants will complete a second&#xD;
      laboratory visit, where all baseline assessments will be repeated. The effects of group&#xD;
      (OxyShred, PL, and control) and time (baseline, 4 weeks) will be statistically examined using&#xD;
      linear models, along with appropriate post-hoc tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants. Eligible participants who provide consent will be stratified based on exercise&#xD;
      training (resistance-trained, endurance-trained, or concurrently-trained), sex (male and&#xD;
      female), and body composition (males: 10 to 20% vs. &gt;20%; females: 15 to 25% vs. &gt;25%), then&#xD;
      randomly assigned to one of the three experimental groups (OxyShred, PL, or control) in a&#xD;
      2:2:1 ratio. Based on preliminary power analysis and comparison with previous studies, the&#xD;
      target sample size is 50 participants (20 Oxyshred, 20 PL, and 10 control), with&#xD;
      approximately equal representation of males and females.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory Visits. Participants will report to the laboratory at baseline and after 4 weeks&#xD;
      of the assigned intervention. At both laboratory visits, participants will be interviewed to&#xD;
      confirm adherence with pre-testing guidelines, such as fasting overnight and abstaining from&#xD;
      food and fluid ingestion. Participants will then undergo body composition testing using the&#xD;
      methods listed below. Anthropometric variables, such as waist circumference and wasit:hip&#xD;
      ratio, will be collected via 3-dimensional optical scanning. Resting energy expenditure and&#xD;
      substrate oxidation (respiratory quotient) will be assessed using indirect calorimetry, and&#xD;
      resting heart rate and blood pressure will be quantified using an automated blood pressure&#xD;
      monitor. Questionnaires will be used to assess physical activity levels, sleep, mood, and&#xD;
      hunger related variables. The specific body composition assessment methods to be used are ADP&#xD;
      (air displacement plethysmography), DXA (dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry), several&#xD;
      bioelectrical impedance techniques, several 3-dimensional scanning techniques, ultrasound,&#xD;
      and standard assessments of height and weight. All equipment will be calibrated as&#xD;
      recommended by the device manufacturers each day prior to use. Metabolism will be assessed&#xD;
      using indirect calorimetry. For the on-site surveys, the following questionnaires/surveys&#xD;
      will be used: Demographics, Exercise Habits, and Caffeine Questionnaire; the International&#xD;
      Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ); the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index; the Mood and&#xD;
      Feelings Questionnaire; the Three-Factor Eating Questionnaire (R18); ASA24; and menstrual&#xD;
      cycle questionnaire for female participants. For the daily online compliance surveys, one of&#xD;
      two forms will be used, depending on the group assignment of the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention. Participants randomized to the control group will be asked to continue their&#xD;
      normal exercise and nutrition habits without making any modification for the duration of the&#xD;
      study. However, as an incentive and to promote equity between conditions, control group&#xD;
      participants will receive the protein supplement provided to the other groups after&#xD;
      completion of the study. Participants in the OxyShred and PL group will be provided their&#xD;
      assigned supplement (OxyShred or PL powder) along with supplemental protein, all provided by&#xD;
      EHP labs. Oxyshred is a commercially available product, and the placebo will include the same&#xD;
      flavoring agents and ingredients but without the active ingredients. The protein product is&#xD;
      also commercially available. Participants will be asked to consume one dose of the&#xD;
      OxyShred/PL supplement for the first week, either upon waking or 15 minutes prior to&#xD;
      exercise, as indicated on product directions. After the first week, participants will be&#xD;
      asked to consume two doses per day, one upon waking and one 15 minutes prior to exercise,&#xD;
      which is also according to product directions. On days exercise is not performed,&#xD;
      participants will be asked to consume one dose upon waking and a second dose in the early&#xD;
      afternoon. Protein supplements will be provided to support body composition improvements.&#xD;
      Participants with a baseline body mass between 50 and 59.9 kg will be asked to consume one&#xD;
      serving (providing ~25 g protein) per day; participants with a baseline body mass between 60&#xD;
      and 89.9 kg will be asked to consume two servings per day (providing ~50 g protein); and&#xD;
      participants with a baseline body mass between 90 and 110 kg will be asked to consume three&#xD;
      servings per day (providing ~75 g protein). Besides the OxyShred/PL and protein&#xD;
      supplementation, participants in the OxyShred and PL groups will be asked to generally&#xD;
      continue their normal nutritional practices, including the types of foods they eat and eating&#xD;
      frequency. However, all participants will be asked to refrain from consuming additional&#xD;
      sports supplements and weight loss supplements throughout the trial. Consumption of general&#xD;
      health support supplements, such as multivitamins, will be allowed if they were regularly&#xD;
      consumed prior to study commencement (typically for ≥1 month). Daily caffeine intake, beyond&#xD;
      that provided by the supplements, will be limited to ~100 mg per day, and participants will&#xD;
      be provided with information about quantities of common foods or beverages providing this&#xD;
      amount (e.g., one cup of coffee, two diet sodas, etc.). Throughout the intervention,&#xD;
      compliance and potential side effects will be monitored via questionnaire. All participants&#xD;
      will be asked to continue their typical exercise regimen and complete questionnaires&#xD;
      documenting their frequency, duration, and type of exercise sessions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 17, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total body fat percentage</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Total body fat percentage from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Segmental body fat percentage</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Segmental body fat percentage from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total fat mass</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Total fat mass from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Segmental fat mass</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Segmental fat mass from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Waist circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Waist circumference from 3-dimensional optical imaging</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Waist-to-hip ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Waist-to-hip ratio from 3-dimensional optical imaging</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Body mass</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Body mass from scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resting energy expenditure</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Resting energy expenditure from indirect calorimetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory quotient</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory quotient from indirect calorimetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resting heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Resting heart rate from automated sphygmomanometer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resting blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Resting blood pressure from automated sphygmomanometer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep quality as assessed by the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood ratings</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Mood ratings as assessed by the Mood and Feelings Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eating behaviors</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Eating behaviors as assessed by the Three-Factor Eating Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dietary intake</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Dietary intake as assessed by the ASA24 recall method</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total lean soft tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Total lean soft tissue from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Segmental lean soft tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Segmental lean soft tissue from dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Limb circumferences</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Limb circumferences from 3-dimensional optical imaging</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported side effects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Body Composition Changes</condition>
  <condition>Body Weight Changes</condition>
  <condition>Anthropometric Changes</condition>
  <condition>Metabolism Changes</condition>
  <condition>Hemodynamic Changes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Thermogenic Dietary Supplement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Arm in which the thermogenic dietary supplement is consumed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Dietary Supplement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Arm in which the placebo supplement is consumed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control arm with no intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thermogenic dietary supplement</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily ingestion of OxyShred thermogenic dietary supplement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Thermogenic Dietary Supplement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Protein supplement</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily ingestion of protein supplement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Dietary Supplement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Thermogenic Dietary Supplement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo supplement</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily ingestion of a placebo dietary supplement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Dietary Supplement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Between the ages of 18 and 40&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Non-smoker&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Generally healthy based on self-report, defined as no known presence of uncontrolled&#xD;
             disease or disorder, such as cardiovascular disease, metabolic disease, cancer, or&#xD;
             musculoskeletal disorders; no major surgeries within the past 6 months; and no history&#xD;
             of hypertension, coronary heart disease, angina, heart attack, stroke, or diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For those taking prescription medication, no changes in medication in the last month,&#xD;
             nor any known limitations on consumption of caffeine or other supplements/substances&#xD;
             contained in the dietary supplement alongside current medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Weight stable, defined as no changes in body weight greater than 4.5 kg in the past&#xD;
             three months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Exercise-trained, defined as performing exercise at least 2 times per week, on&#xD;
             average, for the previous 6 months. Resistance-trained, endurance-trained, and&#xD;
             concurrently-trained individuals will be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Moderate caffeine consumers, defined as an average daily intake of ~40 to 200 mg/d.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Body mass between 50 and 110 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Body fat percentage ≥10% in males and ≥15% in females.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Willingness to comply with the experimental protocol, including consumption of dietary&#xD;
             supplements and adherence to other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Willingness to abstain from consumption from other sports supplements and weight loss&#xD;
             supplements for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Failure to meet the aforementioned inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. They self-report sensitivity to caffeine or other stimulants, including feelings of&#xD;
             nervousness, jitteriness, and shakiness following consumption of doses of caffeine&#xD;
             used in this study (i.e., 150 to 300 mg).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. They are pregnant, currently trying to become pregnant, or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. They report allergy to any ingredient or component of any of the dietary supplements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. They self-report any other medical condition or consideration that the researchers&#xD;
             believe could reasonably make participation unsafe, including the presence of a&#xD;
             pacemaker or other electrical implant, claustrophobia, or other relevant conditions.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Grant M Tinsley, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>8068345895</phone>
    <email>grant.tinsley@ttu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Kinesiology &amp; Sport Management</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lubbock</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>79409</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Grant M Tinsley, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>806-834-5895</phone>
      <email>grant.tinsley@ttu.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 12, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 12, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Body Weight Changes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

