<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05070260</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ACT-CS-005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05070260</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adaptive Efficacy and Safety Study of Glenzocimab Used as an add-on Therapy on Top of Standard of Care un the 4.5 Hours Following an Acute Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
  <acronym>ACTISAVE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double Blind, Multicenter, Multinational, Placebo Controlled, Parallel Group, Single Dose, Adaptive Efficacy and Safety Study of Glenzocimab Used as an add-on Therapy on Top of Standard of Care un the 4.5 Hours Following an Acute Ischemic Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Acticor Biotech</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Acticor Biotech</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A randomized, double blind, multicenter, multinational, placebo controlled, parallel group,&#xD;
      single dose, adaptive phase II/III study (respectively Part 1 and 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study evaluates the efficacy and safety of a fixed dose of glenzocimab (1000 mg IV over 6&#xD;
      hrs including initial bolus of 15 minutes) on top of the best standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      -  A randomized, double blind, multicenter, multinational, placebo controlled, parallel&#xD;
           group, single dose, adaptive phase II/III study. The study will be conducted in 3&#xD;
           consecutive parts, each separated from the preceding one by an interim analysis to allow&#xD;
           the Independent Data Monitoring Committee (IDMC) to issue recommendations on study&#xD;
           conduct, potential early termination or protocol adjustments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The First study part analysis aims to review both safety and efficacy data. The analysis&#xD;
           will be performed when at least 100 patients in the MT+ subgroup patients have completed&#xD;
           the Day 90 mRS assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  With regard to the efficacy assessment, this analysis is a futility analysis only, i.e.,&#xD;
           stopping for an early efficacy claim is not allowable. Rules for claiming the trial&#xD;
           futile will be detailed in the SAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Likewise, a second analysis will be carried out with the aim to review both safety and&#xD;
           efficacy data. A SAP for this IA will be finalized before this IA takes place. This&#xD;
           analysis will be performed when at least 250 patients in the MT+ subgroup of patients&#xD;
           have completed the Day 90 mRS assessment. Assuming a prevalence of 50% of the MT+&#xD;
           patients in the overall population, this second analysis will be performed when around&#xD;
           500 patients have completed the Day 90 mRS assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  With regard to the efficacy assessment, the second analysis has three different aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. This is the second futility analysis only, i.e., stopping for an early efficacy&#xD;
                claim is not allowable. Rules for claiming the trial futile will be detailed in the&#xD;
                SAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Adaptive selection of the population : i.e., either continue to enroll in the&#xD;
                overall population or restrict enrolment to the MT+ subgroup. Rules for selecting&#xD;
                the population will be further detailed in the SAP of the second interim analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Adaptive increase in sample size given the estimated difference between glenzocimab&#xD;
                and placebo on each of the dual endpoints at the second IA in the selected&#xD;
                population (either the OP or MT+ subgroup). Rules to consider an adaptive increase&#xD;
                in the sample size will be further detailed in the Second IA SAP. The method to&#xD;
                control the type I error rate at its usual nominal level will be detailed as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The Third part will embrace the total study population (500 in each treatment arm, and&#xD;
           in each type of SoC).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study evaluates the efficacy and safety of a fixed dose of glenzocimab (1000 mg IV&#xD;
           over 6 hrs including initial bolus of 15 minutes) on top of the best standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In all patients, the IVT should have been initiated prior to/at randomization, and in&#xD;
           any case within 4.5 hrs post onset of acute ischemic stroke symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Eligible patients will be randomized and the infusion of glenzocimab or of its matching&#xD;
           placebo should be administered as soon as possible but no later than one hour of the end&#xD;
           infusion/injection of the thrombolytic agent. Transferring the patient to the&#xD;
           catheterization room should not delay the Investigational Medicinal Product (IMP)&#xD;
           administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients will be randomized 1:1 between groups (glenzocimab or placebo). In addition, a&#xD;
           1:1 stratification will allow for an equal balance of treatment allocation in each SoC&#xD;
           (thrombolysis alone versus thrombolysis + mechanical thrombectomy (MT+). This&#xD;
           stratification will be completed with a centralized capping at 250 patients per SoC for&#xD;
           the second futility analysis, so that the final balance between SoCs will be achieved at&#xD;
           the study level, whether investigating sites are comprehensive stroke centers or primary&#xD;
           stroke centers. In addition, a minimization program will account for the following&#xD;
           factors: baseline severity (NIHSS &lt;10 vs. ≥ 10), age group (&lt;65, 65-79, ≥80 years) in&#xD;
           order to balance each treatment group composition.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The allocation of each patient in all centers to an active treatment or placebo will&#xD;
           strictly follow the central randomization/stratification scheme. Clinical supplies&#xD;
           allocation to centers should provide the necessary material so that any eligible patient&#xD;
           can receive the assigned treatment. A central randomization system (IRT - Interactive&#xD;
           Response Technology) will be used to manage randomization/stratification and drug&#xD;
           shipment. The whole process will be handled in a manner that it is blinded for the&#xD;
           treatment received to all involved study personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The IDMC will be composed of 5 independent members (at least 2 clinicians and 1&#xD;
           statistician).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  IDMC members will process the information and will issue their recommendations as per&#xD;
           the IDMC Charter.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A specific Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP) per each analysis (2 interim and one final)&#xD;
           will be made available to the IDMC for each of the 2 interim and final analyses as well&#xD;
           as for the safety analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Four IDMC meetings are pre-scheduled: 2 of them for a safety evaluation exclusively&#xD;
           (after 100 and 750 patients recruited) and 2 of them for efficacy and safety evaluation&#xD;
           (after 200 and 500 patients recruited). In case of any urgent safety concern, ad-hoc&#xD;
           meetings will be triggered.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study being adaptive in nature, at the second futility analysis, more precise&#xD;
           decision rules will be proposed to the IDMC in the event there would be a clear&#xD;
           imbalance in the benefit-to-risk assessment that would warrant focusing on a particular&#xD;
           population subset of interest and/or avoiding the undue exposure of some patient&#xD;
           categories. In this case, the final sample size should be reassessed accordingly.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Competent Authorities / Agencies should be notified at the end of the First study part.&#xD;
           Any advice from these agencies may be likely to alter the following part of the study as&#xD;
           presented here.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A randomized, double blind, multicenter, multinational, placebo controlled, parallel group, single dose, adaptive phase II/III study (respectively Part 1 and 2).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ordinal modified Rankin Scale (mRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>To show the efficacy of glenzocimab vs. placebo, on at least one of the 2 dual endpoints, i.e. the ordinal modified Rankin Scale (mRS) assessed at Day 90 or the binary poor outcome defined as a mRS score of 4-6 assessed at Day 90, either in the overall population (denoted as OP) or in the subgroup of patients who received Mechanical Thrombectomy (denoted as MT+).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Binary Poor Outcome on the mRS scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>Binary Poor Outcome on the mRS scale defined by a score of 4-6 at Day 90</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of glenzocimab vs. placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>To show the efficacy of glenzocimab vs. placebo on the all-cause mortality at day-90 either in the OP or in the subgroup of patients who received MT+.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ordinal modified Ranking Scale (mRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the favorable responses defined as mRS score of 0-1 To assess the good responses defined as mRS score 0-2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Utility Weighted mRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the utility weighted mRS (UW-mRS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurological Status Change as assessed by NIHSS value compared to pre-IVT value</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Response defined by a relative decrease (%) in NIHSS value at 24 hours compared to pre-IVT value higher than 30%.&#xD;
Relative change (%) in NIHSS value at 24 hrs compared to pre-IVT value</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recanalization rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>To assess recanalization in patients undergoing thrombectomy by eTICI score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cerebral tissue reperfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>To assess Cerebral tissue reperfusion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infarct volume progression and hemorrhagic transformation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hrs</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the impact on follow up imaging (follow up infarct volume, infarct growth and volume of hemorrhagic transformation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Quality of Life by EuroQol-5 Dimension-5 Level (EQ-5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Life as assessed by the EuroQol-5 Dimension-5 Level. A Quality-of-Life Scale (EQ-5D-5L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Deaths</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>Deaths within the first 24 hours and over the whole study period until Day 90 (Kaplan-Meier curve)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Symptomatic intracranial hemorrhages</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Symptomatic intracranial hemorrhages, defined by both anatomical imaging (according to Heidelberg's classification) AND an increase in NIHSS score by 4 points or greater, or death that is not explained otherwise (according to ECASS III study definition)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Non-symptomatic hemorrhages</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Non-symptomatic hemorrhages, seen on 24-hours plain CT-Scan, not present at baseline assessment, once other diagnoses are excluded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Adverse Events, SAEs, bleeding-related events, and Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence, nature and severity of Adverse Events, SAEs, bleeding-related events, and Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vital signs (Blood Pressure) at any visit or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Blood Pressure will be assessed every 30 minutes during the 6 hours (infusion) then every 3 hours up to 24 hours.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vital signs (Heart Rate) at any visit or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Heart Rate will be assessed every 30 minutes during the 6 hours (infusion) then every 3 hours up to 24 hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: RBC (Red Blood Cell Count) at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in RBC (Red Blood Cell Count) in million/mm3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: RBC (Red Blood Cell Count) at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in RBC (Red Blood Cell Count) in million/mm3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Hemoglobin at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Hemoglobin in g/100ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Hemoglobin at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Hemoglobin in g/100ml</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Hematocrit at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Hematocrit in %</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Hematocrit at 24 hours at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Hematocrit in %</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Mean Corpuscular Hemoglobin Volume (MCV) at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Mean Corpuscular Hemoglobin Volume (MCV) in µ3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Mean Corpuscular Hemoglobin Volume (MCV) at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Mean Corpuscular Hemoglobin Volume (MCV) in µ3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Mean corpuscular hemoglobin content (MCHC) at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Mean corpuscular hemoglobin content (MCHC) in pg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Mean corpuscular hemoglobin content (MCHC) at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Mean corpuscular hemoglobin content (MCHC) in pg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (CHC) at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (CHC) in %</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (CHC) at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (CHC) in %</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Leucocytes(/mm3) at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Leucocytes in /mm3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Leucocytes(/mm3) at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Leucocytes in /mm3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Platelets x 10^9 /L at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Platelets x 10^9 /L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in hematology assessments: Platelets x 10^9 /L at 24 hours at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Platelets x 10^9 /L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : SGPT (Sérum Glutamate Pyruvate Transaminase) at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in SGPT in UI/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : SGPT at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in SGPT in UI/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : SGOT at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in SGOT in UI/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : SGOT at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in SGOT in UI/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments: LDH at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in LDH in UI/l</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : LDH at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in LDH in UI/l</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Cholesterol at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Cholesterol in g/L or mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Cholesterol at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Cholesterol in g/L or mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Triglycerid at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Triglycerid in g/L or mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Triglycerid at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Triglycerid in g/L or mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Urea at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Urea in g/L or mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Urea at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Urea in g/L or mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Creatinin at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Creatinin in mg/L or µM/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Creatinin at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Creatinin in mg/L or µM/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : GFR at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in GFR in mL/min/1,73 m²</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : GFR at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change inGFR in mL/min/1,73 m²</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Serum Glucose at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Serum Glucose in g/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Serum Glucose at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Serum Glucose in g/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : D-Dimer at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in D-Dimer in µg/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : D-Dimer at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in D-Dimer in µg/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Fibrinogen at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Fibrinogen in g/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : Fibrinogen at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Fibrinogen in g/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : INR score at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in INR Score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : INR score at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in INR Score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : PT score at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in PT in sec</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : PT score at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in PT in sec</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : aPTT score at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in aPTT in sec</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change biochemistry assessments : aPTT score at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in aPTT in sec</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick urinalysis assessments: Turbidity at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick urinalysis assessments: pH at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick urinalysis assessments: Glucose at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick urinalysis assessments: Proteins at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick urinalysis assessments: Blood at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick urinalysis assessments: Leucocytes at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dipstick clinical laboratory assessments (urinalysis) at Day 7 or discharge as compared to Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>% of patient with change in Change in urinalysis assessments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in coagulation parameters (INR, PT, a PTT)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Change in coagulation parameters (INR, PT, aPTT) at 24 hrs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ECG changes</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>ECG change from baseline on QT, QTc, PR, ST and QRS intervals at 24 hours as compared to Baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ECG changes</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>ECG change from baseline on QT, QTc, PR, ST and QRS intervals at Day 7 as compared to Baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ECG changes</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 90</time_frame>
    <description>ECG change from baseline on QT, QTc, PR, ST and QRS intervals at discharge as compared to Baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Imaging for exploratory endpoints</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>• Acute ischemic stroke diagnosis and occluded cerebral vessel identification assessed by CTA or MRA/MRI with Time of Flight (TOF) sequence at Baseline</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Imaging for exploratory endpoints</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Non Symptomatic and Symptomatic intracranial hemorrhage detection assessed by a plain CT-scan or MRI at 24h</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Ischemic Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous glenzocimab (ACT017) 1000 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intravenous glenzocimab (ACT017) 1000 mg to be added to thrombolysis +/- mechanical thrombectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intravenous Placebo to be added to thrombolysis +/- mechanical thrombectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intravenous glenzocimab (ACT017) 1000 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Add-on therapy to the standard of Care in the treatment of the acute ischemic stroke symptoms</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous glenzocimab (ACT017) 1000 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Thrombolysis +/- thrombectomy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intravenous Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Add-on therapy to the standard of Care in the treatment of the acute ischemic stroke symptoms</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Thrombolysis +/- thrombectomy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult male or female patients ≥ 18 years (i.e., at least 18 years old at time of&#xD;
             randomization)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Having given their own written consent, or legal representative consent, and in any&#xD;
             case, in strict accordance with country-specific legal requirements,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presenting with an acute disabling ischemic stroke either in the anterior or in&#xD;
             posterior circulation, with or without visible occlusion, with a known time of onset,&#xD;
             that is ≤ 4.5 hrs&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presenting with a pre-IVT NIHSS ≥ 6&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. In whom IVT is or has been initiated, whether or not patients are additionally&#xD;
             eligible to mechanical thrombectomy (MT+ IVT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum/urine pregnancy&#xD;
             test at baseline. Women of childbearing potential, i.e., fertile, are defined as women&#xD;
             following menarche and until becoming post-menopausal unless permanently sterile,&#xD;
             i.e., having undergone hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy and bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Post-menopausal women defined as not having menses for 12 months without an&#xD;
             alternative medical cause. For WOCBP, a highly effective birth control method should&#xD;
             be in place that can achieve a failure rate of less than 1% per year that should last&#xD;
             for at least 2 months after IMP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Birth control methods which may be considered as highly effective in WOCBP include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  combined (estrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception associated&#xD;
                  with inhibition of ovulation (intravaginal, transdermal),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation&#xD;
                  (injectable, implantable)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  intrauterine device (IUD),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  intrauterine hormone-releasing system (IUS),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  bilateral tubal occlusion,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  vasectomized partner,&#xD;
&#xD;
             Birth control methods which may be considered as highly effective for men and that&#xD;
             should last for 4 months after IMP administration include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  vasectomy,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  use of condom combined with a highly effective birth control method for their&#xD;
                  WOCBP partner.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Please note that hormonal contraception is a risk factor for thromboembolic events and&#xD;
             attention should be called to reconsider it passed the acute stroke phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients affiliated to a health insurance - modality depending on country legal&#xD;
             requirement&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Coma, or NIHSS &gt;25,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients &lt; 18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Protected adults under guardianship or curatorship,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior ischemic stroke within the past 3 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. mRS pre-stroke known to be ≥ 2,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Large (more than 1/3 of the middle cerebral artery) regions of clear hypodensity on&#xD;
             Baseline Computed Tomography Angiography (CTA) or Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) or&#xD;
             with vascular injection (MRA),&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Significant mass effect with midline shift,&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Stroke of hemorrhagic origin,&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients likely to require dual antiplatelet therapy (DAPT) within the first 24 hrs&#xD;
             after cessation of glenzocimab or placebo infusion for e.g., carotid stenting,&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known renal insufficiency (Grades 4-5 - severe or terminal with a creatinine clearance&#xD;
             &lt; 30 mL/min using Cockroft formula),&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Known allergic reaction to contrast agents,&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients under anti-coagulant therapy, except preventative doses of injectable low&#xD;
             molecular weight heparin (LMWH),&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known ongoing treatment with a mAb,&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Prior cardiopulmonary resuscitation &lt; 10 days,&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Childbirth within &lt; 10 days,&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Seizures at stroke onset if it precludes obtaining an accurate baseline (pre-IVT)&#xD;
             NIHSS,&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Life expectancy (except for stroke) &lt; 3 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Pregnancy or breastfeeding,&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Females of childbearing potential not using effective birth control methods,&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Known current participation in another clinical investigation with experimental drug.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrea Comenducci, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Acticor Biotech</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrea Comenducci, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33631003997</phone>
    <email>andrea.comenducci@acticor-biotech.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Yannick PLETAN, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33685946370</phone>
    <email>yannick.pletan@acticor-biotech.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Hermann Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>James Grotta, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Clinic Essen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Essen</city>
        <zip>45147</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martin Köhrmann, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19420862.2017.1336592</url>
    <description>Design, development and characterization of ACT017, a humanized Fab that blocks platelet's glycoprotein VI function without causing bleeding risks</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Voors-Pette C, Lebozec K, Dogterom P, Jullien L, Billiald P, Ferlan P, Renaud L, Favre-Bulle O, Avenard G, Machacek M, Pletan Y, Jandrot-Perrus M. Safety and Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of ACT017, an Antiplatelet GPVI (Glycoprotein VI) Fab. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2019 May;39(5):956-964. doi: 10.1161/ATVBAHA.118.312314.</citation>
    <PMID>31017822</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Renaud L, Lebozec K, Voors-Pette C, Dogterom P, Billiald P, Jandrot Perrus M, Pletan Y, Machacek M. Population Pharmacokinetic/Pharmacodynamic Modeling of Glenzocimab (ACT017) a Glycoprotein VI Inhibitor of Collagen-Induced Platelet Aggregation. J Clin Pharmacol. 2020 Sep;60(9):1198-1208. doi: 10.1002/jcph.1616. Epub 2020 Jun 4.</citation>
    <PMID>32500636</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Haemorrhages GPVI</keyword>
  <keyword>Thrombolysis</keyword>
  <keyword>Thrombectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-platelet</keyword>
  <keyword>glenzocimab</keyword>
  <keyword>ACT017</keyword>
  <keyword>stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>GPVI</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemic Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glenzocimab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

