<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05625763</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>koshy</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05625763</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>State of Coagulation in Pre-eclampsia: Comparing Sonoclot Signature Analysis With Conventional and Specific Haemostasis Assays</brief_title>
  <official_title>State of Coagulation in Pre-eclampsia: Comparing Sonoclot Signature Analysis With Conventional and Specific Haemostasis Assays</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      -  Detection of the presence or absence of coagulopathy in cases with pre-eclampsia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Investigate the value of global hemostasis studies (Sonoclot signature analysis) in&#xD;
           cases of pre-eclampsia and if there a correlation between it and the specific&#xD;
           traditional assays of hemostasis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pre-eclampsia remains a major cause of morbidity and mortality in pregnant women, as well in&#xD;
      their newborns (1). Despite intense study, preeclampsia remains poorly understood and a major&#xD;
      cause of maternal and foetal morbidity and mortality. It's clear that vascular endothelial&#xD;
      dysfunction, which may lead to hypertension by imbalance between vasoactive, and vasodilator&#xD;
      agents, is an important component of this disorder. The induction of endothelial dysfunction&#xD;
      is probably multifactorial (2). Some researchers suggested that hereditary and acquired&#xD;
      thrombophilia has been associated with recurrent pregnancy loss and gestational vascular&#xD;
      complications, such as early-onset pre-eclampsia and placental abruption (3). Despite it is&#xD;
      widely known that pregnancy induces a state of hypercoagulability (4), publications failed to&#xD;
      demonstrate a uniform pattern of pathology that can carry the association between&#xD;
      thrombophilia and adverse pregnancy outcomes, as between factor V Leiden mutation, MTHFR&#xD;
      C677T mutation, G20210A Prothrombin gene mutation, Anti-thrombin III deficiency, Protein C,S&#xD;
      deficiency and other causes of thrombophilia, different researchers claimed different causes&#xD;
      of the previously mentioned as the one responsible for maternal thrombophilia (2, 3, 5).&#xD;
      Others claimed racial variations were associated with the state of thrombophilia (6).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other than standard routine and specific tests, various other methods are used to record&#xD;
      coagulation profile. One of them is estimation by sonoclot, which is a viscoelastic&#xD;
      hemostatic assays device (7). Sonoclot have practical advantages as point-of-care device for&#xD;
      monitoring major hemorrhage including a set of parameters that assesses a global coagulation&#xD;
      profile and can indicate the presence of hypercoagulable state (8). Establishing correlations&#xD;
      between Sonoclot parameters and conventional hemostasis assays could open a path of better&#xD;
      monitoring of patients with suspected coagulopathies, and can be helpful in guiding&#xD;
      management of preeclampsia and preventing severe maternal outcomes (7).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 29, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 29, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>sonoclot signature analysis in pre-eclampsia</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate the value of global hemostasis studies (Sonoclot signature analysis) in cases of pre-eclampsia and if there a correlation between it and the specific traditional assays of hemostasis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">55</enrollment>
  <condition>Pre-Eclampsia</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sonoclot signature analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Investigate the value of global hemostasis studies (Sonoclot signature analysis) in cases of pre-eclampsia and if there a correlation between it and the specific traditional assays of hemostasis.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  Pregnant pre-eclamptic patients with blood pressure &gt; 140/90 mm hg and proteinuria &gt;&#xD;
             0.39/24 hrs., with gestational age between 20-42 weeks (second &amp; third trimester).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant normotensive females with no pregnancy complications and gestational age&#xD;
             20-42 weeks to act as controls.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant pre-eclamptic patients with blood pressure &gt; 140/90 mm hg and proteinuria &gt;&#xD;
             0.39/24 hrs., with gestational age between 20-42 weeks (second &amp; third trimester).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant normotensive females with no pregnancy complications and gestational age&#xD;
             20-42 weeks to act as controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with gestational age &lt; 20 weeks (First trimester).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients in labour.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with foetal malformations, history of chronic hypertension, diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus, renal diseases, collagen vascular disease, anaemia, cardiovascular diseases&#xD;
             and patients known to be thrombophilic before pregnancy (acquired or inherited).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mennatallah Nashat Abd El-Hafiz Ali, Master</last_name>
    <phone>01097009552</phone>
    <email>menna_nashat@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lalic-Cosic S, Dopsaj V, Kovac M, Pruner I, Littmann K, Mandic-Markovic V, Mikovic Z, Antovic A. Evaluation of global haemostatic assays and fibrin structure in patients with pre-eclampsia. Int J Lab Hematol. 2020 Jun;42(3):322-330. doi: 10.1111/ijlh.13183. Epub 2020 Mar 19.</citation>
    <PMID>32190981</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Osmanagaoglu MA, Topcuoglu K, Ozeren M, Bozkaya H. Coagulation inhibitors in preeclamptic pregnant women. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2005 Mar;271(3):227-30. doi: 10.1007/s00404-003-0596-4. Epub 2004 Jan 21.</citation>
    <PMID>14735372</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Greer IA, Aharon A, Brenner B, Gris JC. Coagulation and placenta-mediated complications. Rambam Maimonides Med J. 2014 Oct 29;5(4):e0034. doi: 10.5041/RMMJ.10168. eCollection 2014 Oct.</citation>
    <PMID>25386350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Simcox LE, Ormesher L, Tower C, Greer IA. Thrombophilia and Pregnancy Complications. Int J Mol Sci. 2015 Nov 30;16(12):28418-28. doi: 10.3390/ijms161226104.</citation>
    <PMID>26633369</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alfirevic Z, Roberts D, Martlew V. How strong is the association between maternal thrombophilia and adverse pregnancy outcome? A systematic review. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2002 Feb 10;101(1):6-14. doi: 10.1016/s0301-2115(01)00496-1.</citation>
    <PMID>11803092</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Philipp CS, Faiz AS, Beckman MG, Grant A, Bockenstedt PL, Heit JA, James AH, Kulkarni R, Manco-Johnson MJ, Moll S, Ortel TL. Differences in thrombotic risk factors in black and white women with adverse pregnancy outcome. Thromb Res. 2014 Jan;133(1):108-11. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2013.10.035. Epub 2013 Nov 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24246297</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saxena P, Bihari C, Rastogi A, Agarwal S, Anand L, Sarin SK. Sonoclot signature analysis in patients with liver disease and its correlation with conventional coagulation studies. Adv Hematol. 2013;2013:237351. doi: 10.1155/2013/237351. Epub 2013 Dec 11.</citation>
    <PMID>24396346</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Min J, Wan P, Liu G, Yu M, Su L. Sonoclot Signature Analysis: A New Point-of-Care Testing Method for Defining Heat Stroke-Induced Coagulopathy. Int J Gen Med. 2021 Oct 20;14:6925-6933. doi: 10.2147/IJGM.S321982. eCollection 2021.</citation>
    <PMID>34707386</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>menna nashat</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assiut- elgomhoriaa</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

