<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05613504</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022JC-55-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05613504</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Acupuncture in the Treatment of Hot Flashes in Patients With Hormone Receptor-positive Breast Cancer.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Controlled Trial Study of Acupuncture in the Treatment of Hot Flashes in Patients With Hormone Receptor-positive Breast Cancer.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nanjing University of Traditional Chinese Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Health Science Center of Xi'an Jiaotong University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hanzhong Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Xiang'an Hospital of Xiamen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dongzhimen Hospital of Beijing University of Traditional Chinese Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nanjing University of Traditional Chinese Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study intends to further evaluate the efficacy of acupuncture by comparing the&#xD;
      intervention effects of different acupuncture treatment regimens on hot flashes in breast&#xD;
      cancer ; and to explore the central effect regulation mechanism of acupuncture intervention&#xD;
      on hot flashes based on integrated PET/MRI technology.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This topic combines the theory of &quot;unblocking the governor and warming the yang&quot; with the&#xD;
      important findings of modern research, that is, the important mechanism of the spine in the&#xD;
      pathogenesis of breast cancer, and innovatively proposes the technique of unblocking the&#xD;
      governor and treating the spine. Prospective clinical intervention research in&#xD;
      rehabilitation, objectively evaluate the clinical efficacy, advantages and disadvantages of&#xD;
      this technology, so as to effectively break through the current application dilemma of&#xD;
      acupuncture and bone-setting manipulation in tumor diseases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cancer therapy functional assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 8, 12，24 weeks later</time_frame>
    <description>Cancer therapy functional assessment scores will be assessed with Cancer Therapy Functional Assessment-Breast cancer, version 4.The minimum value is 0 , and the maximum value is 185. The higher scores mean a worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in acupuncture efficacy expectation assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 8, 12，24 weeks later</time_frame>
    <description>Acupuncture efficacy expectation assessment scores will be assessed with acupuncture efficacy expectation assessment. The minimum value is 0 , and the maximum value is 20. The higher scores mean a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of functional connectivity of whole brain</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 8, 12，24 weeks later</time_frame>
    <description>Functional connectivity will be measured with magnetic resonance imaging based on blood oxygen level dependence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of metabolism of glucose in the brain</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 8, 12，24 weeks later</time_frame>
    <description>Accumulation of 18F-fluorodeoxyglucose(18F-FDG) will be analyzed by time-related Positron emission tomography.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of hot flash severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 8, 12，24 weeks later</time_frame>
    <description>Hot flash severity will be assessed with hot flash scores each week. There are four levels of severity： Mild: Duration: Less than five minutes. Symptoms: warmth, discomfort, flushing. Moderate: Duration: Up to fifteen minutes. Symptoms: warmth in head, neck, ears, or body; tense, tight muscles; clammy skin; change in heart rate or rhythm; light sweating; dry mouth.&#xD;
Severe: Duration: Up to twenty minutes. Symptoms: Fever, sometimes like a crucible or burning sensation; change in heart rate or rhythm; feeling faint; headache; heavy sweating.&#xD;
Very severe: Duration: Up to forty-five minutes. Symptoms: boiling heat; constant sweating; trouble breathing; feeling faint, dizzy; leg cramps or feeling cramps; change in heart rate; stomach upset.&#xD;
The greater severity mean a worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 8, 12，24 weeks later</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep scores will be assessed with Pittsburgh sleep quality index.The minimum value is 9, and the maximum value is 36. The higher scores mean a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Hot Flashes</condition>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Acupuncture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment group A was given endocrine and acupuncture treatment for 8 weeks (24 times in total, 3 times a week); followed up for 16 weeks, no acupuncture treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment group B was given endocrine and sham acupuncture treatment for 8 weeks, followed up for 16 weeks, no acupuncture during the period, and after 16 weeks, received standardized acupuncture for 8 weeks (24 times in total, 3 times a week).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group was given conventional adjuvant endocrine therapy, premenopausal patients received tamoxifen therapy, and postmenopausal patients received aromatase inhibitor or tamoxifen therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acupuncture treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Acupoint selection: 4 general points + syndrome differentiation acupoints (select or replace 2-4 acupoints according to symptom 1, select 1-2 acupoints according to symptom 2 and symptom 3), and adjust acupoints according to symptoms every week.&#xD;
Frequency: 3 times a week (once every other day) for a total of 8 weeks of continuous treatment.&#xD;
Operation: Use a one-time sterile acupuncture needle (0.30×40mm, Huatuo brand), insert the needle 0.5 inch along the anatomical position, level up and relieve the qi, and keep the needle for 20 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham acupuncture treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Acupoint selection: According to the selected acupoints of the electroacupuncture group, 5-7 positions were selected at the non-meridian and non-acupoint points(points with less nerve distribution, sparseness, and rich muscles).&#xD;
Frequency: 3 times a week (once every other day) for a total of 8 weeks of continuous treatment.&#xD;
Operation: ① Shallow needling scheme: use a disposable sterile acupuncture needle, insert the needle 0.2 inch, without twisting, and keep the needle for 20 minutes. ②Non-invasive acupuncture plan: choose a special comfort needle with no needle tip at the top of the needle, paste a disposable sterile foam pad on the non-acupoint, and use a disposable sterile flat head The acupuncture needles were pierced into the foam pad, lightly touching but not piercing the skin, and not breathing; the needles were kept for 20 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 30-75 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adjuvant hormone therapy (eg, tamoxifen and/or aromatase inhibitors) with or without&#xD;
             ovarian function suppression has been administered for at least 4 weeks and is&#xD;
             currently on treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with persistent hot flashes for at least 4 weeks and with a frequency of more&#xD;
             than 14 hot flashes per week (2 times per day) in the week before inclusion in the&#xD;
             study, the weekly average hot flash composite score is 3-4;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients after surgery and chemotherapy (if any);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group score of 0-1 points.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sign the informed consent and participate in the clinical observation voluntarily.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumor metastases, undergoing chemoradiotherapy or planning surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pharmacological intervention for hot flashes with hot flash treatment drugs such as&#xD;
             selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and/or anticonvulsants for at least 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to study initiation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving phytoestrogens, tibolone or analogs, verapril, or specific&#xD;
             homeopathic medicines;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Started or changed adjuvant hormone therapy within the past week, or who planned to&#xD;
             start or change adjuvant hormone therapy in the past 14 weeks, pregnant or&#xD;
             breastfeeding patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding or coagulation disorders with obvious uncontrolled infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric illness or family history; neurological disorder or family history;&#xD;
             seizure possibility or history of seizures.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lijun Bai</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Health Science Center of Xi'an Jiaotong University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lijun Bai, phd</last_name>
    <phone>0086-15129034948</phone>
    <email>bailijun@xjtu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jiangsu Province Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medcine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nanjing</city>
        <state>Jiangsu</state>
        <zip>210029</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lijun Bai, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>0086-15129034948</phone>
      <email>bailijun@xjtu.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 6, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nanjing University of Traditional Chinese Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Qianyan Liu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investgator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Acupuncture</keyword>
  <keyword>Integrated PET/MRI technology</keyword>
  <keyword>Hot flashes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hot Flashes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

