<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05614505</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RUTF_2021_Impact</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05614505</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Acceptability of RUTFs in Indonesia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Acceptability of Ready-to-use Therapeutic Foods (RUTFs) in Indonesia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut de Recherche pour le Developpement</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Savica</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UNICEF</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut de Recherche pour le Developpement</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Severe wasting or Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM) continues to be a major public health&#xD;
      problem in Indonesia, affecting more than 2 million children under 5 years old. A new&#xD;
      approach to treat SAM is called Community-based management of acute malnutrition (CMAM),&#xD;
      which has been designed to maximize the coverage and successful treatment of children with&#xD;
      SAM, by providing Ready to Use Therapeutic Food (RUTF) through out-patient treatment. Since&#xD;
      2019, UNICEF has been working intensively to facilitate the local production of RUTF. This&#xD;
      present study aims to assess the acceptability and efficacy of three locally produced RUTFs&#xD;
      compared to the standard peanut based RUTF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be implemented in Bogor district. A total of 300 children with uncomplicated&#xD;
      SAM, aged 6-59 months old, meeting the inclusion criteria will be included in the study. This&#xD;
      study is designed as a randomized controlled trial. The children will be allocated to one of&#xD;
      the five intervention (1 control, 4 experimental) arms. Each child will receive one type of&#xD;
      RUTF product for eight consecutive weeks. The ration given to a child will be based on the&#xD;
      need for an intake of ~ 170 kcal/kg BW/day. Data will be collected at baseline, at weekly&#xD;
      intervals and at exit. The primary outcome of interest for the efficacy study is the relative&#xD;
      weight gain of children consuming each of the local RUTFs compared with those consuming the&#xD;
      standard RUTF. The primary outcome of the acceptability of the RUTFs will be the amount of&#xD;
      product consumed during the eight-week efficacy trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Differences in weight and height gain will be analyzed using ANCOVA, controlling for age,&#xD;
      gender, food intake, and morbidity. Repeated measurement statistics will be used to analyze&#xD;
      differences in growth patterns over the eight-week intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES This study aims to assess the acceptability and efficacy to increase weight and&#xD;
      mid upper arm circumference of children aged 6-59 months with severe acute malnutrition&#xD;
      (SAM), of three locally produced RUTFs compared to the standard peanut based RUTF. The study&#xD;
      will be implemented in Bogor district.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY Subjects inclusion criteria are reported elsewhere.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size Calculation If the Indonesian RUTFs fulfil the WHO requirement of an average&#xD;
      increase of 4 g/kg BW/day, a sample size of 60 children per group would allow detecting a 20%&#xD;
      difference between control and intervention products, assuming a SD of 1.6 g/kg BW, a study&#xD;
      design effect of 1.0, a significance of 0.05, a power of 0.80. If children fail to reach this&#xD;
      4 g/kg BW target and only gain 2 g/kg BW/day, the sample size would still allow detection of&#xD;
      a 30% difference between the control product and the local product. Since it will be a&#xD;
      five-armed intervention, a total of 300 SAM children will be recruited in Bogor district.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anthropometric and Hemoglobin Measurements Training The training on anthropometric&#xD;
      measurements will include repeated practice and comparison of intra- and inter-observer&#xD;
      variation to ensure that the field team will have excellent skills in conducting the&#xD;
      anthropometric measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hemoglobin concentration will be measured using Hemocue 201+ device by (or under direct&#xD;
      supervision of) a medical doctor, trained in the use of the equipment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design This study is designed as an individually randomised controlled trial. Parents&#xD;
      will be informed of the purpose, risks and benefits of the study and asked to sign the&#xD;
      informed consent prior to inclusion of their child in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each child will be randomly allocated to one of the five intervention arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acceptability Study The primary outcome of the acceptability of the RUTFs will be the amount&#xD;
      of product consumed during the 8-week efficacy trial (long-term acceptability). An average&#xD;
      consumption of at least 50% of the offered product during the 8-week efficacy trial will be&#xD;
      considered acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary outcome of the acceptability study will be the consumption velocity of the&#xD;
      RUTFs during the appetite test (short-term acceptability; see below).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy Study The primary outcome of interest for the efficacy study is the relative weight&#xD;
      gain of children consuming each of the local RUTFs compared with those consuming the standard&#xD;
      RUTF. A difference of 20% in weight gain will be considered as physiologically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization Prior to the appetite test, selected children with uncomplicated SAM will be&#xD;
      randomized to one of the five intervention arms. The randomization list is made prior to&#xD;
      recruitment by a member of the research team not present in the field (FTW). Children&#xD;
      randomized to one arm will receive the standard RUTF product, and the other four arms will&#xD;
      each receive one of four local RUTFs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Appetite Test The day after the screening, selected children will need to pass an appetite&#xD;
      test prior to enrolment in the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design Each child will receive one type of RUTF products for eight consecutive weeks. Data&#xD;
      will be collected at baseline, at weekly intervals and at exit. Children who completely&#xD;
      refuse to eat the RUTF they have been allocated to for more than 4 days/week, for 2&#xD;
      consecutive weeks, or children who lose or do not gain weight during 2 consecutive weekly&#xD;
      visits, and/or develop allergic reaction and clinical symptoms during the course of the study&#xD;
      will be dropped from the study and will be referred to the Puskesmas for treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A weekly supply of RUTF will be supplied during each of the weekly check-up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline data General information on socio-economic status of the family, ethnicity,&#xD;
      educational level of both parents, household food security, IYCF including 24 h food recall,&#xD;
      use of micronutrient supplements (vitamin A, iron, syrup) and supplementary foods (PMT/Local&#xD;
      PMT), morbidity history and current morbidity, duration of pregnancy, birth weight,&#xD;
      immunization status, deworming, sex and age of the child, will be collected at baseline, in&#xD;
      addition to height/length, weight, MUAC and hemoglobin concentration. All data will be&#xD;
      recorded using a digital questionnaire on tablet computers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring The daily amount of RUTF intake of each child will be recorded by the&#xD;
      mother/caregiver in a monitoring book provided by the study team. The field team will visit&#xD;
      each child on a weekly basis to monitor the feeding and intake recording by the&#xD;
      mother/caregiver, as well as any intra-household sharing of the RUTF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the weekly home visits, the PL will maintain regular daily communication with&#xD;
      the mothers/caregivers through text messages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis The baseline, monitoring, and endline data will be entered in a digital&#xD;
      questionnaire by the field workers. The researcher will extract data from digital&#xD;
      questionnaire into SPSS format. Data analyses will be done using SPSS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 25, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>randomized controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Given the very different characteristics of the RUTFs, full masking is not possible. Caregivers/mothers are only given 1 product, and do not know of the existence of the other intervention products</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>short-term acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>consumption of at least 50% of RUTF provided in a 30 minute period</time_frame>
    <description>Passing the appetite test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>long-term acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of children not finishing the 8 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>drop-out during the intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>weight gain over the 8 week intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>weight gain expressed as weight gain (g)/kg body weight per day over the 8 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>weight gain (in g) over 8 week intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>recovery rate</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to end of the 8 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of children having WHZ&gt;-2 and/or MUAC &gt;125 mm</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>increase in height for age Z scores (HAZ)</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to the end of the 8 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>changes in length growth among the intervention arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>length of stay in the treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 week intervention or shorter</time_frame>
    <description>Average number of day in treatment to reach recovery or drop-out</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Morbidity during the intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to 8 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>number of sick days based on the weekly recall data</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception</measure>
    <time_frame>based on the interview with the caregiver after the 8 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability of the product by caregivers</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Severe Acute Malnutrition</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF standard</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>PlumpyNut</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Soybean RUTF</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mungbean-thick RUTF</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mungbean-thin RUTF</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Wafer RUTF</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ready to use therapeutic foods</intervention_name>
    <description>locally produced therapeutic foods</description>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF local_4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RUTF standard</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with uncomplicated SAM (WHZ &lt; -3 and/or MUAC &lt;115 mm) qualified for&#xD;
             outpatient treatment, or nutritional edema regardless of anthropometry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 6-59 months old upon enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pass appetite test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Never received in- and outpatient treatment on SAM (including not having consumed&#xD;
             RUTF, F75, F100 or special medical specialty food1 in the last two months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate in the study (parent signed the informed consent)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &lt; 4.0 kg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled or untreatable systemic opportunistic infection, such as active TB, HIV;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obvious dysmorphic features, general mental health problems (e.g., Down syndrome,&#xD;
             etc.), other conditions interfering with normal growth;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participating in another clinical trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any congenital disorder that interferes with normal nutrient intake; chronic&#xD;
             conditions including but not exclusively disorders of heart, kidney or liver (children&#xD;
             to be screened by a physician);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SAM with complications requiring hospital treatment (including edema +3);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe anemia (Hb&lt;7g/dL);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is a twin or multiple;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to milk, nuts, legumes and/or antibiotics (Amoxicillin and Ampicillin)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frank Wieringa, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute de Recherche pour le Développement</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Savica</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jakarta</city>
        <country>Indonesia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Indonesia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institut de Recherche pour le Developpement</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Frank Wieringa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ready to use therapeutic food (RUTF)</keyword>
  <keyword>acceptability</keyword>
  <keyword>local</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Yes, IP data will be available upon request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

