<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619627</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY4510</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619627</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oral Dexmedetomidine in Pediatric MRI</brief_title>
  <official_title>Utility of Oral Dexmedetomidine as the Sole Sedative Agent in Pediatric Population Undergoing MRI</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's Mercy Hospital Kansas City</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's Mercy Hospital Kansas City</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this preliminary study is to assess the utility of oral dexmedetomidine as&#xD;
      the sole sedative agent in pediatric population undergoing MRI&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      MRI is an important and robust medical imaging technique that has become the cornerstone for&#xD;
      radiologic studies. Superior image quality and resolution especially for soft tissue imaging,&#xD;
      without the use of ionizing radiation has made MRI one of the most dominant imaging&#xD;
      modalities in pediatrics. Despite its many advantages, MRI is not child friendly. Lengthy&#xD;
      scan times, the need for lying motionless in a confined space, excessive noise and vibration&#xD;
      during image acquisition, are all factors that have made anesthesia an integral part of&#xD;
      pediatric MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General anesthesia is a state of medically induced unconsciousness, analgesia and muscle&#xD;
      relaxation which is required for most invasive medical procedures. Despite being painless,&#xD;
      imaging tests such as MRI scans are highly susceptible to motion artifact and require a state&#xD;
      of immobility that may not be obtainable in awake uncooperative patients such as pediatrics.&#xD;
      While very safe, general anesthesia carries potential risk of serious morbidity and mortality&#xD;
      secondary to aspiration during instrumentation of the airway, hypoxia and hypoventilation&#xD;
      secondary to laryngospasm/bronchospasm and hemodynamic instability. Therefore, sedation may&#xD;
      be an appropriate technique to offer anxiolysis, amnesia and immobility while maintaining&#xD;
      airway reflexes with limited impact on ventilation and hemodynamics for non-stimulating&#xD;
      procedures such as imaging. Aside from having a more favorable risk/benefit profile compared&#xD;
      to general anesthesia when it comes to radiologic studies, sedation is also less costly and&#xD;
      burdensome on anesthesia departments and could provide immense cost-saving measures for&#xD;
      healthcare institutions at large.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While there are many intravenous (IV) sedatives, establishing an awake IV access could be&#xD;
      very traumatizing and leave a lasting negative impression of the healthcare environment in a&#xD;
      child's mind. Hence, enteral medications may be more acceptable and child friendly. This is&#xD;
      especially valuable in patients who require repeated surveillance imaging and who demonstrate&#xD;
      heightened level of anxiety and fear with each visit. Among sedative agents that could be&#xD;
      administered enterally, dexmedetomidine may be superior due to minimal respiratory depression&#xD;
      while providing anxiolysis and analgesia. Of note, dexmedetomidine is a highly selective&#xD;
      alpha2-adrenoreceptor agonist that exerts its hypnotic action through activation of central&#xD;
      pre- and postsynaptic alpha2-receptors in the locus coeruleus, mimicking natural sleep.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective Pilot Study, Single-site, open-label, phase I dose escalation trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MRI motion artifact</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the MRI scan completion</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is qualitative evaluation of MRI motion artifact. Each MRI sequence will be graded 1-3. 1: no-mild motion artifact; 2: moderate motion artifact; 3: severe motion artifact (non-diagnostic)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ramsay Sedation Score (RSS) of 4</measure>
    <time_frame>During and immediately after the intervention procedure. Assessments will cease once RSS return to 3</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary outcome is achieving a minimum Ramsay Sedation Score (RSS) of 4</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine 12 mcg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group One: Subjects will receive oral dexmedetomidine 12 mcg/kg 2 hours prior to MRI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine 18 mcg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group Two: Subjects will receive oral dexmedetomidine 18 mcg/kg 2 hours prior to MRI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine 24 mcg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group Three: Subjects will receive oral dexmedetomidine 24 mcg/kg 2 hours prior to MRI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>General anesthesia control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group: Subjects will receive general anesthesia for their MRI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive oral dexmedetomidine as the sole sedative agent for undergoing MRI</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine 12 mcg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine 18 mcg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine 24 mcg/kg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>General anesthetic</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive inhalational anesthetic to provide general anesthesia for undergoing MRI</description>
    <arm_group_label>General anesthesia control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects ages 4 months to 6 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Undergoing a clinically indicated MRI with anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Refusal to take oral dexmedetomidine&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Inability to take dexmedetomidine at least 90 minutes prior to start of the MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known allergy to dexmedetomidine&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Medical contraindication to administration of dexmedetomidine&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable cardiac status including life threatening arrhythmias, abnormal cardiac&#xD;
                  anatomy, significant cardiac dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current use of digoxin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moya Moya disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  New onset stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status classification system &gt; II&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Contraindications to administering sedation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active and uncontrolled gastroesophageal reflux&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active and uncontrolled vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current or recent history of apnea&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active respiratory disease including pneumonia, bronchitis, respiratory syncytial&#xD;
                  virus infection, asthma exacerbation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Craniofacial anomaly&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Unable to have MRI&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Soroush Merchant, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Mercy Hospital Kansas City</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Soroush Merchant, MD, MS</last_name>
    <phone>816-3018595</phone>
    <email>smerchant@cmh.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Mercy Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Soroush Merchant, MD, MS</last_name>
      <phone>816-301-8595</phone>
      <email>smerchant@cmh.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Soroush Merchant, MD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kristin Leland, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sajid B, Mohamed T, Jumaila M. A comparison of oral dexmedetomidine and oral midazolam as premedicants in children. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2019 Jan-Mar;35(1):36-40. doi: 10.4103/joacp.JOACP_20_18.</citation>
    <PMID>31057237</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weerink MAS, Struys MMRF, Hannivoort LN, Barends CRM, Absalom AR, Colin P. Clinical Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Dexmedetomidine. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2017 Aug;56(8):893-913. doi: 10.1007/s40262-017-0507-7.</citation>
    <PMID>28105598</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anttila M, Penttila J, Helminen A, Vuorilehto L, Scheinin H. Bioavailability of dexmedetomidine after extravascular doses in healthy subjects. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2003 Dec;56(6):691-3. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2125.2003.01944.x.</citation>
    <PMID>14616431</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mason KP, Zurakowski D, Zgleszewski SE, Robson CD, Carrier M, Hickey PR, Dinardo JA. High dose dexmedetomidine as the sole sedative for pediatric MRI. Paediatr Anaesth. 2008 May;18(5):403-11. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-9592.2008.02468.x. Epub 2008 Mar 18.</citation>
    <PMID>18363626</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lin L, Guo X, Zhang MZ, Qu CJ, Sun Y, Bai J. Pharmacokinetics of dexmedetomidine in Chinese post-surgical intensive care unit patients. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2011 Mar;55(3):359-67. doi: 10.1111/j.1399-6576.2010.02392.x.</citation>
    <PMID>21288220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Iirola T, Ihmsen H, Laitio R, Kentala E, Aantaa R, Kurvinen JP, Scheinin M, Schwilden H, Schuttler J, Olkkola KT. Population pharmacokinetics of dexmedetomidine during long-term sedation in intensive care patients. Br J Anaesth. 2012 Mar;108(3):460-8. doi: 10.1093/bja/aer441. Epub 2012 Jan 25.</citation>
    <PMID>22277665</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee S, Kim BH, Lim K, Stalker D, Wisemandle W, Shin SG, Jang IJ, Yu KS. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of intravenous dexmedetomidine in healthy Korean subjects. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2012 Dec;37(6):698-703. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2710.2012.01357.x. Epub 2012 May 31.</citation>
    <PMID>22650799</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hannivoort LN, Eleveld DJ, Proost JH, Reyntjens KM, Absalom AR, Vereecke HE, Struys MM. Development of an Optimized Pharmacokinetic Model of Dexmedetomidine Using Target-controlled Infusion in Healthy Volunteers. Anesthesiology. 2015 Aug;123(2):357-67. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0000000000000740.</citation>
    <PMID>26068206</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Potts AL, Anderson BJ, Warman GR, Lerman J, Diaz SM, Vilo S. Dexmedetomidine pharmacokinetics in pediatric intensive care--a pooled analysis. Paediatr Anaesth. 2009 Nov;19(11):1119-29. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-9592.2009.03133.x. Epub 2009 Aug 25.</citation>
    <PMID>19708909</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chamadia S, Pedemonte JC, Hobbs LE, Deng H, Nguyen S, Cortinez LI, Akeju O. A Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Study of Oral Dexmedetomidine. Anesthesiology. 2020 Dec 1;133(6):1223-1233. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0000000000003568.</citation>
    <PMID>32986820</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dashiff CJ, Weaver M. Development and testing of a scale to measure separation anxiety of parents of adolescents. J Nurs Meas. 2008;16(1):61-80. doi: 10.1891/1061-3749.16.1.61.</citation>
    <PMID>18578110</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keles S, Kocaturk O. Comparison of oral dexmedetomidine and midazolam for premedication and emergence delirium in children after dental procedures under general anesthesia: a retrospective study. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2018 Mar 28;12:647-653. doi: 10.2147/DDDT.S163828. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>29636599</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weldon BC, Watcha MF, White PF. Oral midazolam in children: effect of time and adjunctive therapy. Anesth Analg. 1992 Jul;75(1):51-5. doi: 10.1213/00000539-199207000-00010.</citation>
    <PMID>1616162</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shukry M, Clyde MC, Kalarickal PL, Ramadhyani U. Does dexmedetomidine prevent emergence delirium in children after sevoflurane-based general anesthesia? Paediatr Anaesth. 2005 Dec;15(12):1098-104. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-9592.2005.01660.x.</citation>
    <PMID>16324031</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Oral dexmedetomidine</keyword>
  <keyword>Precedex</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics, General</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All IPD that underlie results</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Starting 6 months after publication</ipd_time_frame>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

