<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05626283</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FMBSUREC/050722022/Mohiee</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05626283</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Transforaminal Epidural Steroid Injection in Lumbar Disc Prolpse on Micro RNA-155 Serum Level</brief_title>
  <official_title>Transforaminal Epidural Steroid Injection in Lumbar Disc Prolpse: Impact on Pain Intensity and Cognitive Function in Relation to Micro RNA-155 Serum Level</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beni-Suef University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beni-Suef University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic pain could be considered a brain disease as it can affect multiple aspects of brain&#xD;
      function, chemistry, neural networks and structure. Pain is associated with impaired&#xD;
      cognitive function (1). Around 45-50% of these patients report cognitive deficits such as&#xD;
      forgetfulness (23.4%), minor accidents (23.1%), difficulty finishing tasks (20.5%), and&#xD;
      difficulty maintaining attention (18.7%) (2,3). Many studies emphasized an impairment in the&#xD;
      cognitive tests assessing executive functioning, attention abilities, processing speed, and&#xD;
      memory in patients with chronic pain (4,5). Studies of community-dwelling older adults found&#xD;
      that pain, particularly widespread or severe pain, was associated with mobility Limitations&#xD;
      in physical performance (e.g., walking speed, stair climbing, and activities of daily living)&#xD;
      (6-9) in individuals with chronic pain and correspond to the pain level (10,11). Finally,&#xD;
      both pain and impaired cognition affect mobility status in older adults, and mobility is&#xD;
      affected to a greater extent when both are present (12).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent data indicate that miR-155 has a typical multifunctional miRNA and plays a crucial&#xD;
      role in various physiological and pathological processes such as immunity, inflammation,&#xD;
      cognitive dysfunction and neuropathies (13). The available experimental evidence indicating&#xD;
      that miR-155 is up-regulated in neuropathies allows us to include this miRNA in the list of&#xD;
      genes of paramount importance in chronic low back pain diagnosis and prognosis. Exogenous&#xD;
      molecular control in vivo of miR-155 expression could open up new ways to restore cognitive&#xD;
      outcome or attenuate the pain intensity (14).&#xD;
&#xD;
      No study searched the role of intervention (epidural steroid injection) on cognitive function&#xD;
      reserve, whether it is a better substitution or not for the conservative medical treatment.&#xD;
      Since exogenous steroid is a part of epidural injection, the systemic effect of a single dose&#xD;
      of steroids does not affect cognitive function, giving superiority to the intervention&#xD;
      modality on the conservative medical therapy approach (15).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the work This work aims to study the impact of transforaminal epidural steroid&#xD;
      injection in lumbar disc prolapse on pain intensity and cognitive function in relation to&#xD;
      Micro RNA-155 serum level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study design and Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted in two stages:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stage (1): It will be a case control study that will include 46 patients diagnosed as having&#xD;
      symptomatic lumbar disc prolapse and 46 age and sex matched healthy controls. Both patients&#xD;
      and control groups will be subjected to measurement of baseline miR-155 expression level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stage (2): It will be an interventional non-experimental study that will include only the 46&#xD;
      patients who had symptomatic lumbar disc prolapse. Those patients will be subjected to&#xD;
      transforaminal epidural steroid injection. Assessment of pain intensity, functional&#xD;
      disability, cognitive function, depression, and miR-155 expression level will be done for the&#xD;
      included patients before and 1 month after transforaminal epidural steroid injection to&#xD;
      clarify the effect steroid injection on these variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The included patients will be recruited from the neurology and pain clinics of Beni-Suef&#xD;
      University Hospital, in the period from August 2022 to August 2023.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will include patients with clinical evidence of disc bulge in the form of disc&#xD;
      related radicular pain of &gt;3 months duration, not responding to conservative treatment and&#xD;
      interfering with daily activities. The selected patients should have radiological evidence of&#xD;
      posterolateral lumbar disc bulge by MRI lumbosacral.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following patients will be excluded from our study: patients with a history of spinal&#xD;
      trauma, spinal surgery or spinal deformities, patients with radiological evidence of any&#xD;
      inflammatory or neoplastic lesion affecting the vertebral column or spinal cord, patients&#xD;
      with facet or hip osteoarthritis or sacroiliitis, patients with severe lumbar disc prolapse&#xD;
      causing lower limb weakness or sphincteric troubles, patients with contraindications to&#xD;
      interventions (sepsis, coagulopathy, or allergy from the used drugs), and patients with&#xD;
      central or metabolic disorder known to cause cognitive dysfunction. Pregnant patients will be&#xD;
      also excluded from our study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection History will be taken from the selected patients regarding the demographics&#xD;
      and the duration of lumbar disc related radicular pain. The imaging findings regarding the&#xD;
      number of prolapsed discs and the degree of the most prolapsed disc will be also obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of pain intensity and functional disability Assessment of the pain intensity and&#xD;
      functional disability will be done before and 1 month after the interventional pain&#xD;
      management procedure. Assessment will be done using Numeric Rating Scale (NRS) and Oswestry&#xD;
      Disability Index (ODI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Numeric Rating Scale (NRS) is a single 11-point numeric scale for assessment of intensity of&#xD;
      pain. It ranged from 0 to 10, where 0 indicates no pain and 10 indicates the worst pain. [16]&#xD;
      Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) is a questionnaire used to quantify the disability from low&#xD;
      back pain. It includes the following items: pain intensity, the level of disability of&#xD;
      personal care, lifting, walking, sitting, standing, sleeping, traveling, sexual and social&#xD;
      life. Each question is scored on a scale of 0-5 with 0 representing no limitation, and 5&#xD;
      representing maximal limitation. The scores for all questions answered are summed, then&#xD;
      multiplied by two to obtain the index (range 0 to 100). [17] Cognitive assessment Cognitive&#xD;
      assessment will be done before and 1 month after the interventional pain management&#xD;
      procedure. Assessment will be done using Paired Associate Learning test (PALT), Paced&#xD;
      Auditory Serial Addition Test (PASAT), and Controlled Oral Word Association Test (COWAT).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Paired Associate Learning test (PALT) will be used to assess auditory verbal memory. In this&#xD;
      test, the examiner says 6 semantically related pairs of words and 4 semantically unrelated&#xD;
      pairs. After few minutes, the examiner says the first word of each of these pairs to the&#xD;
      patient, and the patient was asked to recall the other word. The test must be performed three&#xD;
      times. Each correct compatible pair takes a score 0.5, while each correct incompatible pair&#xD;
      takes a score 1. The range of the total score was between 0 to 21. [18] Paced Auditory Serial&#xD;
      Addition Test (PASAT) will be used for assessment of attention and auditory working memory.&#xD;
      In this test, a series of 61 single digit numbers are spoken on an audiotape (or CD) at a&#xD;
      rate of one every 3 seconds. The subject is asked to add each number to the one immediately&#xD;
      preceding it and not to give a running total. The subject has to report the sum orally. Total&#xD;
      score is the sum of correct responses and it ranges from 0 to 60. [19] Controlled Oral Word&#xD;
      Association Test (COWAT) is a verbal fluency test that assess attention and executive&#xD;
      function. The participant is usually asked to name words beginning with a letter, excluding&#xD;
      proper nouns, for one minute. [20] Assessment of depression Assessment of depression will be&#xD;
      done before and 1 month after the interventional pain management procedure using Beck&#xD;
      depression inventory (BDI). It is a self-rated questionnaire consisting of 21 items, in which&#xD;
      four response options are presented on a scale of 0 to 3. [21]&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventional pain Procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The selected patients will be brought to the preparation room where reassurance will be done.&#xD;
      Intravenous midazolam 0.2 mg/kg will be given to them, then they will be placed in the prone&#xD;
      position on fluoroscopy table and draped in a sterile manner. They will be connected to a&#xD;
      monitor (SPO2, NIBLP, and ECG) and given supplemental oxygen through a nasal cannula (3&#xD;
      L/min) to maintain the oxygen saturation. A 22-gauge, 3.5-inch spinal needle will be used in&#xD;
      the injection procedure. With each insertion of the spinal needle, 1 ml with 20 mg of local&#xD;
      anesthetic lidocaine 2% will be injected intradermally.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients will be given transforaminal epidural injection of steroids with local&#xD;
      anesthetic (7 mg Betamethasone preceded by a test dose of 1 milliliter 2% lidocaine).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory assessment Estimation of miR-155 expression level: Blood samples (5 mL) will be&#xD;
      collected from the patients (before and 1 month after the interventional procedure) and&#xD;
      controls. The samples will be centrifuged at 3000 rpm for 10 min and plasma and/ or serum&#xD;
      will be stored at -80 C till analysis. Total RNA will be extracted. Quantitative real-time&#xD;
      polymerase chain reaction (PCR) will be performed. miR-155 expression level will be&#xD;
      calculated by the difference in threshold cycle method.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Numeric Rating Scale (NRS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of functional disability</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Oswestry Disability Index (ODI)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of miR-155 expression level</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in miR-155 expression level</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Memory assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Paired Associate Learning test (PALT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attention assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Paced Auditory Serial Addition Test (PASAT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of depression</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Beck depression inventory (BDI).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">92</enrollment>
  <condition>Lumbar Disc Herniation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lumbar disc prolapse group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>46 patients diagnosed as having symptomatic lumbar disc prolapse</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>46 age and sex matched healthy controls</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>transforaminal epidural injection.</intervention_name>
    <description>transforaminal epidural steroid injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>lumbar disc prolapse group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>micro RNA-155 serum level</intervention_name>
    <description>Estimation of miR-155 expression level:</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>lumbar disc prolapse group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinical evidence of disc bulge in the form of disc related radicular&#xD;
             pain of &gt;3 months duration, not responding to conservative treatment and interfering&#xD;
             with daily activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The selected patients should have radiological evidence of posterolateral lumbar disc&#xD;
             bulge by MRI lumbosacral.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of spinal trauma, spinal surgery or spinal deformities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with radiological evidence of any inflammatory or neoplastic lesion affecting&#xD;
             the vertebral column or spinal cord.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with facet or hip osteoarthritis or sacroiliitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with severe lumbar disc prolapse causing lower limb weakness or sphincteric&#xD;
             troubles.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with contraindications to interventions (sepsis, coagulopathy, or allergy&#xD;
             from the used drugs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with central or metabolic disorder known to cause cognitive dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients will be also excluded from our study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mona Hussein</name>
      <address>
        <city>Banī Suwayf</city>
        <state>Beni-Suef</state>
        <zip>62511</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mona Hussein</last_name>
      <phone>01005131318</phone>
      <email>mona.neuro@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 19, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 19, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 19, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Beni-Suef University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mona Hussein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor of Neurology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Displacement</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

