<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05617859</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZZUSC-20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05617859</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lenvatinib for Advanced Bone and Soft Tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open, One-arm Phase II Study of Ranvastinib Mesylate Capsules in the Treatment of Advanced Bone and Soft Tissue Sarcoma After Chemotherapy Failure</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Henan Cancer Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Henan Cancer Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A total of 60 patients with metastatic/surgically unresectable bone and soft tissue sarcomas&#xD;
      who had previously received multi-target TKI therapy and failed were enrolled to evaluate the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the efficacy and safety of lenvatinib mesylate capsule in patients with&#xD;
      metastatic/surgically unresectable bone and soft tissue sarcomas who had previously received&#xD;
      multitarget TKI therapy and failed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 24months</time_frame>
    <description>From the start of treatment to the onset of disease progression or death of the patient</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 24months</time_frame>
    <description>Until the tumor progresses or the patient dies or is lost to follow-up or cannot tolerate it</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Effectiveness</condition>
  <condition>Sexuality</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib mesylate capsule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Eligible subjects with bone and soft tissue sarcoma were selected and treated with the following treatment regimens:Subjects will receive Lenvatinib mesylate capsules, 8mg (body weight ≤60kg) or 12mg (body weight &gt;60kg) orally once daily. Take the medicine about half an hour after meals (the time of taking the medicine should be the same as possible every day) and take it with warm water.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenvatinib mesylate capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>Lenvatinib mesylate capsule, 8mg (body weight ≤60kg) or 12mg (body weight &gt;60kg), orally, once daily. Take the medicine about half an hour after meals (the time of taking the medicine should be the same as possible every day) and take it with warm water.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib mesylate capsule</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ages 10-70, both male and female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The Eastern Collaborative Oncology Group (ECOG) physical status score was 0-1.&#xD;
             Subjects with amputation can be relaxed up to 2 points.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The expected survival time was ≥3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with bone and soft tissue sarcomas with distant metastases or locally&#xD;
             advanced disease who were not considered suitable for surgical treatment by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who had been treated with apatinib or anlotinib in the past, and the efficacy&#xD;
             was evaluated as CR\PR\SD\PD, and had no response to other systemic therapy after drug&#xD;
             resistance, or had reprogression after more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. There were measurable lesions that met RECIST1.1 criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. All acute toxicities from previous antitumor therapy or surgery resolved to grade 0-1&#xD;
             (according to NCI-CTCAE, version 4.03) or to enrollment/exclusion criteria by day 1 of&#xD;
             the first cycle (C1D1), except for toxicities such as hair loss that the investigator&#xD;
             considered to pose no safety risk to the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate organ and bone marrow function is defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Blood routine (no blood transfusion, no G-CSF, no medication correction within 14 days&#xD;
             before screening) :&#xD;
&#xD;
             Neutrophil count (ANC)≥1,500/mm3(1.5×109/L); Platelet count&#xD;
             (PLT)≥100,000/mm3(100×109/L); Hemoglobin (Hb)≥9g/dL(90g/L);&#xD;
&#xD;
             Blood biochemical:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Serum creatinine (Cr)≤1.5× upper limit of normal (ULN) or creatinine clearance&#xD;
             (Cockroft-Gault formula)≥60ml/min; Total bilirubin (TBIL)≤1.5×ULN; Aspartate&#xD;
             aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) levels ≤2.5×ULN, and subjects&#xD;
             with liver metastases should ≤5×ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
             Blood coagulation function:&#xD;
&#xD;
             International normalized ratio (INR)≤1.5, prothrombin time (PT) and activated partial&#xD;
             thromboplastin time (APTT)≤1.5×ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Urine routine: urinary protein &lt;2+; If urine protein ≥2+, 24-hour urine protein&#xD;
             quantification must show protein ≤1g;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Thyroid function: Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH)≤ULN; FT3(T3) and FT4(T4) levels&#xD;
             should be examined if they are abnormal, and normal FT3(T3) and FT4(T4) levels can be&#xD;
             selected.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Female subjects of reproductive age must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
             days prior to medication and be willing to use a medically approved highly effective&#xD;
             contraceptive (e.g., intrauterine device, birth control pill, or condom) during the&#xD;
             study period and within 3 months after the last administration of the study drug; Male&#xD;
             subjects with a female partner of reproductive age were required to undergo surgical&#xD;
             sterilization or consent to use an effective method of contraception during the study&#xD;
             period and for 3 months after the last study dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. I have AGREED and signed the informed CONSENT, and I am willing AND ABLE TO comply&#xD;
             with the planned visit, study treatment, laboratory tests and other trial procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. C1D1 received the following treatments in the previous 4 weeks:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Radiotherapy, surgery, chemotherapy, immunotherapy for tumors. Other investigational&#xD;
             drugs. Get live attenuated vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Surgery and/or radiation therapy for bone and soft tissue sarcomas were planned during&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous use of immunosuppressive drugs within 14 days prior to C1D1, excluding nasal&#xD;
             spray and inhaled corticosteroids or physiological doses of systemic steroid hormones&#xD;
             (i.e., no more than 10mg/ day of prednisolone or an equivalent physiological dose of&#xD;
             another corticosteroid).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Severe infection (such as the need for intravenous antibiotic, antifungal, or&#xD;
             antiviral medication) within 4 weeks prior to C1D1, or unexplained fever &gt;38.5°C&#xD;
             during the screening period/before the first dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Hypertension that is not well controlled with antihypertensive medication (systolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &gt; 140 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;90mmHg).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Significant bleeding symptoms or clear bleeding tendency occurred within 3 months&#xD;
             before C1D1, such as gastrointestinal bleeding, hemorrhagic gastric ulcer, baseline&#xD;
             fecal occult blood ++ and above, vasculitis, etc. Or arteriovenous thrombotic events&#xD;
             occurring within 6 months before C1D1, such as cerebrovascular accidents (including&#xD;
             transient ischemic attack, cerebral hemorrhage, cerebral infarction), deep vein&#xD;
             thrombosis and pulmonary embolism; Long-term anticoagulant therapy with warfarin or&#xD;
             heparin or long-term antiplatelet therapy (aspirin ≥300mg/ day or clopidogrel ≥75mg/&#xD;
             day) may be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active heart disease in the 6 months prior to C1D1, including myocardial infarction&#xD;
             and severe/unstable angina pectoris. Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;50% on&#xD;
             echocardiography, poorly controlled arrhythmias (including QTcF interval &gt;450ms in men&#xD;
             and &gt;470ms in women).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. C1D1 had been diagnosed with any other malignancy within 3 years prior to C1D1, except&#xD;
             adequately treated basal or squamous cell skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the&#xD;
             cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known allergy to the study drug or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, active hepatitis B (hepatitis B surface&#xD;
             antigen positive and HBVDNA≥500IU/ml), and hepatitis C (hepatitis C antibody positive&#xD;
             and HCV-RNA above the detection limit of the assay).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Concomitant diseases (e.g., poorly controlled hypertension, severe&#xD;
             diabetes,neurological or mental disorders, etc.) or any other conditions that, in the&#xD;
             judgment of the investigator, seriously endanger the safety of the subjects, may&#xD;
             confounding the results of the study, or interfere with the completion of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Bone and Soft Tissue ,Henan Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zhengzhou</city>
        <state>Henan</state>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tian Zhichao, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+8618737187831</phone>
      <email>tianzhichhaoyy@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 22, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Henan Cancer Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Wang Jiaqiang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>associate chief physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lenvatinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

