<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618834</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00021256</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618834</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Promoting Positive Care Interactions (PPCI) in Assisted Living</brief_title>
  <acronym>PPCI</acronym>
  <official_title>Optimizing Daily Care Interactions Between Staff and Assisted Living Residents With Alzheimer's Disease and Related Dementias</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Penn State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Penn State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall aim of this study is to pilot test Promoting Positive Care Interactions (PPCI)&#xD;
      with the goal of establishing a feasible and culturally responsive approach to optimize care&#xD;
      interactions between staff (nursing, activity, housekeeping, and dining service staff) and&#xD;
      residents with ADRD in assisted living facilities (ALFs), and further improve select&#xD;
      resident, staff, and facility outcomes. PPCI is a non- pharmacological four-step approach&#xD;
      consisting of (1) stakeholder engagement in developing facility specific goals; (2)&#xD;
      environment and policy assessments; (3) flexible staff education; and (4) ongoing mentorship,&#xD;
      motivation, and support (in-person visits and text messages) for staff to optimize care&#xD;
      interactions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nearly one million individuals living in 28,900 assisted living facilities (ALFs) in the U.S.&#xD;
      participate in daily care interactions, defined as any verbal or nonverbal exchange between&#xD;
      staff and residents during physical and social care activities. While there are positive care&#xD;
      interactions, poor care interactions also persist with prevalence as high as 25% in long-term&#xD;
      care including ALFs. Individuals with Alzheimer's disease and related dementias (ADRD) are&#xD;
      especially at risk for poor care interactions due to ineffective staff approaches such as&#xD;
      negative touching (e.g., quickly removing clothes to bathe a resident), being overprotective&#xD;
      (e.g., restricting activity for safety concerns), and lack of verbal or non-verbal contact&#xD;
      during care. Persistent poor care interactions can negatively affect both residents and&#xD;
      staff. Thus, there is a need to replace poor care interactions with positive care&#xD;
      interactions, now more than ever given the worsening staff retention related to COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic, and constant need to train new employees.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positive care interaction refers to care interactions where staff use positive approaches&#xD;
      such as honoring resident's abilities and preferences, recognizing resident's&#xD;
      responses/non-verbal cues, acknowledging resident's effort, providing role modeling and&#xD;
      verbal cues, managing self-responses, and using a calm respectful approach for appropriate&#xD;
      delivery of care. It has been long known that use of positive approaches benefits both&#xD;
      residents (e.g., less behavioral distress) and staff (e.g., greater competence in care). Yet,&#xD;
      poor interactions continue in ALFs due to interlocking barriers associated with residents'&#xD;
      ADRD-related communication and other difficulties and behaviors of distress (e.g.,&#xD;
      agitation), as well as staff's knowledge and training deficits in ADRD care; ALFs have fewer&#xD;
      licensing and training mandates for staff. Lack of cultural concordance can also contribute&#xD;
      to poor interactions. The ALF staff, often younger (mean age=38.3 yrs.) females (83.8%) with&#xD;
      almost half representing racial minorities (47.6%) care for largely non-Hispanic white&#xD;
      (81.4%) resident population &gt;=65 years (93.4%). Additionally, there are systemic barriers&#xD;
      including limited organizational engagement in implementing and sustaining these approaches,&#xD;
      lack of environmental infrastructure (e.g., controlled noise and availability of augmentative&#xD;
      devices such as pocket talker) and policies (e.g., consistent assignments) to support&#xD;
      positive care interactions, and lack of adequate mentoring and support for staff. It is&#xD;
      crucial to address these issues and barriers and train ALF staff on positive care&#xD;
      interactions, particularly since prior work has targeted nursing homes and focused on social&#xD;
      interactions or verbal communication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, this study proposes Promoting Positive Care Interactions (PPCI), a four-step&#xD;
      approach, based on Social Ecological Model (SEM) and Social Cognitive Theory (SCT), to&#xD;
      optimize daily care interactions between staff and residents with ADRD in ALFs. The four&#xD;
      steps include: 1) stakeholder engagement in developing facility specific goals; (2)&#xD;
      environment and policy assessments; (3) flexible staff education; and (4) ongoing mentorship,&#xD;
      motivation, and support (in-person visits and text messages) for staff to optimize care&#xD;
      interactions. These four steps are based on prior work implementing function &amp; behavior&#xD;
      focused intervention studies but have never been used in a care interaction-focused&#xD;
      intervention nor been tested for cultural responsiveness. This study will follow a cluster&#xD;
      randomized trial in a sample of 60 residents and 60 staff in four ALFs in central PA (approx.&#xD;
      15 residents, 15 staff/ALF) who agree and consent to participate in this study. The treatment&#xD;
      group will receive all four steps of PPCI while the control arm will receive education only.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The degree to which the intervention can be implemented as intended assessed by Feasibility of Intervention Measure (FIM) Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>six-months post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>4 items answered on a 5-point ordinal scale ranging from 'completely disagree' to 'completely agree'; range = 4 to 20 and higher scores are better</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The degree to which the intervention is acceptable assessed by Acceptability of Intervention Measure (AIM) Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>six-months post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>4 items answered on a 5-point ordinal scale ranging from 'completely disagree' to 'completely agree'; range = 4 to 20 and higher scores are better</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Well-being assessed by Quality of Life in Late-stage Dementia (QUALID) Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>11 items on a 5-point scale, range = 11 to 55 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of agitation assessed by Cohen-Mansfield Agitation Inventory (CMAI-short form)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>14 items answered on a 5-point scale, range = 14 to 70 and lower scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and intensity of resistive behaviors assessed by Resistiveness to Care (RTC) Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>13 items answered on a 3-point scale for intensity and a number provided for frequency, range = 13 to 39 for intensity and lower scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge of person-centered behavioral approaches for managing behavioral symptoms of distress assessed by Knowledge of Person-Centered Behavioral Approaches for BPSD</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>10 items with four responses (1 correct, 3 distracters), range = 0 to 10 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived competence in dementia care assessed by Sense of Competence in Dementia Care Staff (SCIDS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>17 items on a 4-point scale, range = 17 to 68 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of stress assessed by Health Professions Stress Inventory (HPSI)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>12 items on a 5-point scale, range = 0 to 48 and lower scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Staff-resident relationship quality assessed by Positive Affect Index (PAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>5 items on a 6-point scale, range = 5 to 30 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Staff-resident care interactions assessed by Quality of Care Interactions Schedule (QuIS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>5 items answered on a 3-point scale, range = 0 to 7 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Provision of facility policies pertaining to promoting positive care interactions (PPCI) assessed by Assessment of Policies for PPCI</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>24 items answered as yes (1) or no (0), range = 0 to 24 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Provision of facility environment pertaining to promoting positive care interactions (PPCI) assessed by Assessment of Environment for PPCI</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>23 items answered as yes (1) or no (0), range = 0 to 23 and higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cultural responsiveness assessed by a questionaire based on the ecological model (EM) domains: language, persons, metaphors, goals, content, concepts, methods, &amp; context of PPCI</measure>
    <time_frame>six-months post intervention</time_frame>
    <description>12 interview questions</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Alzheimer Disease and Related Dementias</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PPCI Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The ALF/PCH assigned as treatments will receive the four steps of PPCI including, stakeholder engagement and facility goal development, environment and policy assessment, staff education, and ongoing mentorship/motivation and support over a period of six-months by a research nurse facilitator (RNF), a registered nurse (RN) with prior experience in long-term care. The RNF will work with an identified internal/facility champion monthly to implement the four steps of PPCI.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PPCI-Staff Education Only Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The ALF/PCH assigned as controls will receive PPCI-staff education only (EO). The EO will include a 30-45 min in-service session and monthly f/u visits for booster education. The education content and process will be the same as outlined in Step 3 of the PPCI for treatment sites.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Promoting Positive Care Interactions (PPCI)</intervention_name>
    <description>The PPCI consists of four steps: (1) stakeholder engagement in developing facility specific goals; (2) environment and policy assessments; (3) flexible staff education; and (4) ongoing mentorship, motivation, and support (in-person visits and text messages) for staff to optimize care interactions.&#xD;
A research nurse facilitator (RNF), a registered nurse (RN) with prior experience in long-term care will work with an identified internal champion monthly to implement the four steps of PPCI. The PPCI intervention comprehensively focuses on intrapersonal, interpersonal, organizational, and environmental/policy factors to bring together evidence and key stakeholders to optimize daily care interactions in assisted living.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PPCI Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PPCI-Staff Education Only (EO)</intervention_name>
    <description>The EO will include a 30-45 min in-service session and monthly f/u visits for booster education. The education content and process will be the same as outlined in Step 3 of the PPCI for treatment sites.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PPCI-Staff Education Only Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Assisted Living Facility (ALF) will be included in the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. have at least 20 or more beds&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. are able to identify a facility champion, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. express a willingness to actively partner in an initiative to change practice at their&#xD;
             institution&#xD;
&#xD;
        Staff will be included in the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. are able to communicate in English, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. work at least 16 hours a week at the facility at the time of recruitment in nursing,&#xD;
             activities, housekeeping, or dining service roles&#xD;
&#xD;
        Residents will be included in the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. are 65 years old or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. are living at the facility at the time of recruitment, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. have a diagnosis of ADRD and Saint Louis University Mental Status Exam (SLUMS) score&#xD;
             of 20 or less (high school education)/ 19 or less (less than high school education)&#xD;
             suggesting ADRD&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Assisted Living Facility (ALF) will be excluded from the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. have less than 20 beds&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. are unable to identify a facility champion, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. do not express a willingness to actively partner in an initiative to change practice&#xD;
             at their institution&#xD;
&#xD;
        Staff will be included in the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. are unable to communicate in English, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. work less than16 hours a week at the facility at the time of recruitment in nursing,&#xD;
             activities, housekeeping, or dining service roles&#xD;
&#xD;
        Residents will be included in the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. are less than 65 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. are not living at the facility at the time of recruitment, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. do not have a diagnosis of ADRD and Saint Louis University Mental Status Exam (SLUMS)&#xD;
             score of 20 or less (high school education)/ 19 or less (less than high school&#xD;
             education) suggesting ADRD&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anju Paudel, Assistant Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Penn State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anju Paudel, Assistant Professor</last_name>
    <phone>2026992632</phone>
    <email>aqp6003@psu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Pennsylvania State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>University Park</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>16802</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anju Paudel</last_name>
      <phone>202-699-2632</phone>
      <email>aqp6003@psu.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 27, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 27, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 28, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Penn State University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Anju Paudel, PhD, MGS, RN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dementia</keyword>
  <keyword>Care Interactions</keyword>
  <keyword>Communication</keyword>
  <keyword>Assisted Living</keyword>
  <keyword>Long-Term Care</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

