<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05622136</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NP3005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05622136</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dose-escalation of Regorafenib in Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <acronym>STRAT-aHCC</acronym>
  <official_title>Dose-escalation Strategy of Regorafenib in Patients With Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Instituto do Cancer do Estado de São Paulo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Instituto do Cancer do Estado de São Paulo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present protocol (STRAT-aHCC trial) aims to prospectively evaluate the tolerability,&#xD;
      quality of life and efficacy of an alternative regimen of regorafenib in patients with&#xD;
      advanced hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) after progression to first-line. Patients will&#xD;
      receive increasing dose of regorafenib in the first 2 treatment cycles (initial dose of 80mg,&#xD;
      with weekly increments of 40mg up to 160mg in the first 2 treatment cycles). From the 3rd&#xD;
      cycle on, the maximum tolerated dose during the first 2 cycles will be maintained. The&#xD;
      maximum tolerated dose will be considered the highest dose in which the patient does not&#xD;
      present grade ≥3 adverse events. The primary endpoint is the proportion of evaluable patients&#xD;
      completing cycle 4. Radiologic response rate, quality of life, time to progression and&#xD;
      overall survival will be evaluated as secondary endpoints.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In patients who are refractory to first-line treatment with sorafenib, regorafenib was tested&#xD;
      in the phase III RESORCE study. In this study, a standard dose of 160mg/day was used (in&#xD;
      cycles of 4 weeks, with 3 weeks on treatment and 1 week off) until tumor progression or&#xD;
      limiting toxicity. Regorafenib was superior to placebo with a significant increase in overall&#xD;
      survival and became a sequential treatment option.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, regorafenib is associated with relevant adverse events such as fatigue, hand-foot&#xD;
      reaction, diarrhea and hypertension. Such events are more frequent in the first 2 cycles. In&#xD;
      the RESORCE trial, 54% of patients had adverse events requiring interruption or dose&#xD;
      reduction, and treatment discontinuation was required in 10% of patients. This toxicity&#xD;
      profile limits the wide adoption of this drug in clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dose escalation strategies for regorafenib have been evaluated in patients with colorectal&#xD;
      cancer and have resulted in better tolerability with comparable efficacy. However, there are&#xD;
      no prospective studies with alternative doses of regorafenib in patients with advanced HCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present protocol (STRAT-aHCC trial) aims to prospectively evaluate the tolerability,&#xD;
      quality of life and efficacy of an alternative regimen of regorafenib in patients with&#xD;
      advanced HCC. Patients will receive increasing dose of regorafenib in the first 2 treatment&#xD;
      cycles (initial dose of 80mg, with weekly increments of 40mg up to 160mg in the first 2&#xD;
      treatment cycles - Figure 1). From the 3rd cycle on, the maximum tolerated dose during the&#xD;
      first 2 cycles will be maintained. The maximum tolerated dose will be considered the highest&#xD;
      dose in which the patient does not present grade ≥3 adverse events. The primary endpoint is&#xD;
      the proportion of evaluable patients completing cycle 4. Radiologic response rate, quality of&#xD;
      life, time to progression and overall survival will be evaluated as secondary endpoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical visits will be carried out weekly in the first 2 treatment cycles and every 4 weeks&#xD;
      after the 3rd cycle. Laboratory tests will be performed every 2 weeks during the first 2&#xD;
      cycles and every 4 weeks after the 3rd cycle. Response assessment by imaging exams will be&#xD;
      performed every 8 weeks. Quality of life assessments will be performed every 4 weeks using&#xD;
      the EuroQol EQ-5D-5L7 questionnaire. The planned sample size is 28 patients with an expected&#xD;
      duration of 25-30 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients who complete 4 cycles of treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with disease control after 4 treatment cycles;</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients with partial response or stable disease after 4 cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median overall survival: time from treatment initiation to death;</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time from treatment initiation to death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median progression-free survival: time from treatment initiation to progression or death</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time from treatment initiation to progression or death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Score in the The 5-level EuroQol EQ-5D-5L questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>- 0.532 (worst health state) and 1 (most optimal health state)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Liver Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Regorafenib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cycles 1 and 2:&#xD;
Week 1: 80mg/day&#xD;
Week 2: 120mg/day&#xD;
Week 3: 160mg/day&#xD;
Week 4: off-treatment Cycles 3 on (up to treatment discontinuation)&#xD;
Weeks 1 to 3: Maximum dose tolerated daily, defined as the highest dose at which the patient had no adverse events grade ≥3 by CTCAE version 5.0 during cycles 1 and 2.&#xD;
Week 4: off treatment&#xD;
Dose adjustments may be required. Appendix 11.1 guide dose adjustments. Individual decisions at the occurrence of particular adverse events may be discussed individually within the study team and investigators.&#xD;
Treatment will be administered until any of the following events occur:&#xD;
Both radiological and clinical progression according to definition of mRECIST or clinical deterioration that prevents treatment continuation according to the judgment of the attending physician&#xD;
Limiting toxicity as defined by a grade 3 adverse event that does not resolve to grade &lt; 3 within 7 days; adverse event grade 4 or 5.&#xD;
Subject decision.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Regorafenib Oral Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose escalation strategy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Regorafenib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 years or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hepatocellular carcinoma with histological or cytological confirmation or that meet&#xD;
             radiological criteria for the diagnosis of HCC21;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. BCLC-B stage not candidate for locoregional treatment or BCLC-C;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have been previously treated with at least 1 line of systemic treatment with&#xD;
             sorafenib, levantinib, atezolizumab plus bevacizumab or other immunotherapy-based&#xD;
             regimen;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have received the last dose of first-line systemic treatment between 2 and 6 weeks&#xD;
             before starting study treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Recovery to baseline or ≤ grade 1 from toxicities related to any previous treatments,&#xD;
             unless the adverse event is not clinically significant as determined by the&#xD;
             investigator (according to the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE)&#xD;
             v522);&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Not having received previous treatment with regorafenib;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Child-Pugh A or B7 (in the absence of clinical ascites);&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Measurable disease as defined by the RECIST 1.1 criteria. Target lesions must not have&#xD;
             undergone previous local or locoregional treatment (example: ablation, transarterial&#xD;
             chemoembolization, radiotherapy or selective internal radiotherapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Performance status: ECOG 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Adequate hematologic, hepatic and renal functions as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Hemoglobin ≥ 8.5 g/dl ii. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,000 /mm3 iii. Platelet&#xD;
             count ≥ 50,000 /mm3 iv. Total bilirubin &lt; 2.0 x upper limit of normality (ULN) v. ALT&#xD;
             or AST &lt;5 x LSN vi. Creatinine clearance (CrCI) ≥ 30 mL/min (according to&#xD;
             Cockroft-Gault formula) vii. Serum albumin ≥ 2.8 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Ability to understand informed consent and comply with the treatment protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Informed consent form and clarification signed by the patient, impartial witness or&#xD;
             legal representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Sexually active patients of childbearing potential and their partners must agree to&#xD;
             use highly effective methods of contraception that result in a rate of less than 1%&#xD;
             per year when used consistently and correctly throughout the study and 6 months after&#xD;
             treatment discontinuation;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Female participants of childbearing potential cannot be pregnant at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Fibrolamellar carcinoma, sarcomatoid HCC or mixed hepatocellular cholangiocarcinoma;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previous use of regorafenib;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hepatic encephalopathy or medication requirement to control hepatic encephalopathy in&#xD;
             the last 60 days before randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinically significant ascites (ie, ascites that requires parcentesis or increased&#xD;
             dose of diuretics) within 30 days prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who have received local therapies (ablation, transarterial chemomebolization&#xD;
             or surgery) within 28 days prior to randomization. Radiation treatments with the aim&#xD;
             of pain control of bone metastases are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known or suspected brain metastasis or cranial epidural disease unless adequately&#xD;
             treated with surgery or radiotherapy and stable for at least 8 weeks from&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any participant who cannot be submitted neither to computed tomography (CT) nor&#xD;
             magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) due to contra-indication to contrast media used.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The participant has an uncontrolled disease, or a significant complication in the last&#xD;
             28 days of randomization, such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cardiovascular disorders:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  i. Class III or IV congestive heart failure as defined by the New York Heart&#xD;
                       Association, unstable angina pectoris, or symptomatic arrhythmias;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  ii. Uncontrolled hypertension (defined as systolic blood pressure greater&#xD;
                       than 160 mmgHg or diastolic pressure &gt; 95 mmHg despite antihypertensive&#xD;
                       therapy);&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  iii. Stroke, myocardial ischemia, or any ischemic event within the 6-month&#xD;
                       period prior to randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Gastrointestinal disorders, including those associated with a high risk of&#xD;
                  perforation:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  i: active peptic ulcer disease, inflammatory bowel disease, tumors invading&#xD;
                       the gastrointestinal tract, diverticulitis, cholecystitis, appendicitis,&#xD;
                       acute pancreatitis and cholangitis;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  ii: Abdominal fistula, gastro-intestinal perforation or abdominal abscess in&#xD;
                       the last 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  iii: Esophageal varices that have not been adequately treated or that have&#xD;
                       been incompletely treated with bleeding or high risk of bleeding.&#xD;
                       Participants treated with adequate endoscopic therapy with no bleeding in&#xD;
                       the past 6 months are eligible;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Clinically detected hematuria, hematemesis, melena, hemoptysis (&gt;2.5 ml) or other&#xD;
                  clinically significant bleeding within the last 3 months of randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Cavitating pulmonary lesion or known manifestation of endobronchial disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Other clinically significant diseases, at the discretion of the attending&#xD;
                  physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Majority surgery within 28 days of randomization. Minor surgeries within 10 days of&#xD;
             randomization. Participants must have complete healing of the procedures prior to&#xD;
             randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of psychiatric illness that is likely to interfere with the ability to&#xD;
             understand the study procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or breastfeeding women;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Inability to swallow pills;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known allergies to study drug components;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Any other known malignancy active at the time of randomization or diagnosis of another&#xD;
             malignancy within two years of randomization, except superficial skin carcinomas or&#xD;
             low-grade localized tumors considered cured and not treated with systemic therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Leonardo Fonseca, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+55 11 3893-2000</phone>
    <phone_ext>2673</phone_ext>
    <email>l.fonseca@hc.fm.usp.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 27, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 27, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Instituto do Cancer do Estado de São Paulo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Leonardo Gomes da Fonseca</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator,</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Regorafenib</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Dose</keyword>
  <keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

