<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05628155</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>35RC21_9884_MAÏA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05628155</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MAÏA - MAintain the Level of Independence Through Alimentation</brief_title>
  <acronym>MAÏA</acronym>
  <official_title>MAÏA - MAintain the Level of Independence Through Alimentation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rennes University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rennes University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Malnutrition has serious consequences: increased risk of falls, hospitalization and&#xD;
      mortality. Malnutrition may accompany or aggravate another geriatric syndrome. The loss of&#xD;
      muscle mass and function, called &quot;sarcopenia&quot; can itself lead to a loss of physical activity&#xD;
      and therefore of independence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It has been reported that changes in the quantity or quality of food intake could influence&#xD;
      the onset or progression of sarcopenia. Thus, an optimized oral diet covering the energy and&#xD;
      protein needs of the elderly people living in a nursing home is a key element of the&#xD;
      malnutrition prevention strategy. It could help slow down the loss of independence and have a&#xD;
      direct impact on the occurrence of the complications mentioned above, and therefore on the&#xD;
      use of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the elderly, as in the general population, the consumption of linoleic acid (LA),&#xD;
      precursor of the omega 6 line, is too high, and that of alpha-linolenic acid (ALA), precursor&#xD;
      of the omega 3 line, insufficient. The French National Institute against Cancer (INCA) 3&#xD;
      survey results indicate for the 65-79 year old population average ALA intakes of 0.9 g/d&#xD;
      whereas the recommendation is 2 g/d. The same is true for long-chain n-3 PUFAs&#xD;
      (eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), docosahexaenoic acid (DHA)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are currently no recommendations specifically concerning nursing home populations. Only&#xD;
      recommendations for non-frail people, over the age of 65, exist (ANSES, 2019). Experts&#xD;
      recommend maintaining or even slightly increasing the consumption of portions of meat, eggs,&#xD;
      fish, fruits and vegetables and dairy products.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the elderly, as in adults, an imbalance of n-6/n-3 PUFA intake or insufficient n-3 PUFA&#xD;
      intake could facilitate the occurrence of cardiovascular diseases and certain cancers. The&#xD;
      possible prevention of other pathologies more specific to the elderly, such as degenerative&#xD;
      diseases, makes the consumption of n-3 PUFAs relevant in this population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our approach aiming to cover the recommended dietary allowances (RDA) of n-3 PUFAs via the&#xD;
      oral diet is therefore very original.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An oral diet containing these different sources of fatty acid intake, of various origins, and&#xD;
      other essential nutrients for the elderly, would have the advantage of meeting the&#xD;
      nutritional objectives on the one hand, and of offering a wide range of tastes, flavors, and&#xD;
      texture, allowing to optimize their consumption by nursing home residents, on the other hand.&#xD;
      No study has yet evaluated the benefits of n-3 PUFA intake in dependent elderly people&#xD;
      residing in nursing homes, moreover, using loss of independence as the main endpoint.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of the trial is to evaluate the effect of an everyday diet containing n-3&#xD;
      PUFA intakes corresponding to the RDA (population &gt; 65 years) compared to the usual diet&#xD;
      (therefore uncontrolled) on the evolution of the loss of independence at 2 years of nursing&#xD;
      home residents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prospective, controlled, randomized, multicentre, open-label clinical study comparing two&#xD;
      groups of residents:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;Control&quot; group: nursing home residents will receive an oral diet covering their&#xD;
           nutritional needs in macronutrients as recommended for people over 70-65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;Intervention&quot; group: nursing home residents will receive an oral diet covering their&#xD;
           nutritional needs in macronutrients as recommended for people over 65-70 years of age&#xD;
           and including n-3 PUFA intake corresponding to the RDAs for people over 65 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Residents will be included in clusters corresponding to the nursing homes in which they&#xD;
      reside.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention will be delivered &quot;at the nursing home level&quot;, i.e. all the residents&#xD;
      included in the same nursing home will belong to the same &quot;control&quot; or &quot;intervention&quot; group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Notes: Note that a randomization of residents across the individual residents was not&#xD;
      possible from a logistical point of view in a context of collective feeding in an&#xD;
      institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Actimetry analyzes as a marker of frailty. The investigators will conduct an ancillary study&#xD;
      of actimetry analysis, on a sub-population of 60 residents (n=30 per group), in order to&#xD;
      quantify physical activity and try to identify a possible trajectory of frailty that The&#xD;
      investigators can correlate to the studied endpoints. To do this, the investigators will have&#xD;
      a device consisting of an accelerometer and a barometer which will be positioned in a case&#xD;
      around the neck (pendant) or failing that - if the resident expresses a preference - on the&#xD;
      wrist (bracelet) to monitor participants' activities for 24 months. The nursing homes&#xD;
      concerned will be selected for their proximity to Rennes and the homogeneity of the physical&#xD;
      activities routinely offered to residents. The measures will be performed one week per month&#xD;
      for 24 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main judgment criterion: Measurement of the level of independence by the ADL-LFS (Activities&#xD;
      of Daily Living - Long Form Score) at 2 years from the RAI-MDS 3.0 questionnaire (Resident&#xD;
      Assessment Instrument Minimum Dataset) LTCF (Long-Term Care Facilities).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluate the effect of an everyday diet containing n-3 PUFA intakes corresponding to the RDA&#xD;
      (population &gt; 65 years) compared to the usual diet (therefore uncontrolled) on the following&#xD;
      endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The evolution of anthropometric criteria and malnutrition&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The risk of falling&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The risk of an infection occurring&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The evolution of the quality of life&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Mortality&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Healthcare consumption (hospitalizations and visits to the emergency room)&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. In a sub-population of 60 residents (n=30 per group) randomly selected among the&#xD;
           participants of a few volunteer nursing homes and meeting the inclusion and&#xD;
           non-inclusion criteria of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The evolution of the quality of physical and sporting activity&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The evolution of the quality of sleep&#xD;
&#xD;
           Organic:&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. The biological profile of blood fatty acids and concentrations of ALA, EPA, DPA, DHA in&#xD;
           red blood cells&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Micro-CRP and albumin&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Evaluation of the cost of implementing the nutritional intervention from the perspective&#xD;
           of nursing homes vs the clinical benefits&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 5, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 5, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 5, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>independence level</measure>
    <time_frame>at 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of independence level of by the ADL-LFS (Activities of Daily Living - Long Form Score) at 2 years. The evaluation criterion used is the functional numerical scale from 0 to 28 (0 = independent, 28= total dependence)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">456</enrollment>
  <condition>Nursing Homes</condition>
  <condition>Clinical Trial</condition>
  <condition>Food</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral diet including n-3 PUFA intake</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral diet covering the nutritional requirements in macronutrients as recommended for people over 65 years of age (ANSES, 2019) and including intakes of n-3 PUFAs corresponding to the recommendations for people over 65 years of age</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oral diet including n-3 PUFA intake</intervention_name>
    <description>menus to cover the recommended intake of n-3 PUFAs (ALA =1% of total energy intake, i.e. 2.1 g/d, and EPA+DHA = 500 mg/d) (n-3 PUFA MENU), based on mass-market products that guarantee the n-3 PUFA RDAs and are available from the catering sector</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oral diet including n-3 PUFA intake</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents in permanent accommodation in participating nursing homes during the&#xD;
             inclusion period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents in accommodation in nursing homes with similar catering services and who are&#xD;
             not supplied with Bleu Blanc Coeur® food or who are supplied with at most 2 BBC&#xD;
             products per week;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliation to a social security scheme;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent signed by the resident or the person in charge of the representative&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ADL-LFS score on inclusion &gt;19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusive enteral nutrition;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Protection of effective justice;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of understanding of the French language;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estimated life expectancy of less than 12 months on inclusion, estimated by the&#xD;
             attending physician or, if there is one, the nursing home physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only for the ancillary actimetry study: residents under guardianship or unable to&#xD;
             self-manage.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ronan THIBAULT, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rennes University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ronan THIBAULT, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>02.99.28.96.46</phone>
    <phone_ext>33</phone_ext>
    <email>ronan.thibault@chu-rennes.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kristell COAT</last_name>
    <phone>0299282555</phone>
    <phone_ext>33</phone_ext>
    <email>kristell.coat@chu-rennes.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Les jardins d'Hermine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rennes</city>
        <zip>35000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Natacha LAMIRE</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Natacha LAMIRE</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 11, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 11, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>elderly</keyword>
  <keyword>nursing homes</keyword>
  <keyword>omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids</keyword>
  <keyword>malnutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>sarcopenia.</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

