<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05611736</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21-19-08</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05611736</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Intracanal Cryotherapy on Endodontic Postoperative Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Intracanal Cryotherapy on Postoperative Pain in Necrotic Teeth With Symptomatic Apical Periodontitis: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Qassim University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Qassim University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to evaluate the effect of cold saline (2.5 degrees&#xD;
      Celsius) irrigation on postoperative pain in patients who require root canal treatment in&#xD;
      molar teeth because of dead dental pulp and infection around the apex of the root of the&#xD;
      involved teeth. This cold saline irrigation will be done after standard irrigation of the&#xD;
      canal using a 5.25% sodium hypochlorite solution. The main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Is there any difference in postoperative pain when final irrigation is performed using a&#xD;
           cold saline solution compared to the irrigation using the saline solution at room&#xD;
           temperature in patients who require dental root canal treatment of molar teeth?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Because of cold saline irrigation, what type of adverse event/s may result?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to fill out a questionnaire before the start of the root canal&#xD;
      treatment and record the preoperative pain using the visual analog scale (VAS). Root canal&#xD;
      treatment will be completed in one visit. The standard procedure of root canal treatment will&#xD;
      be followed, including irrigation of the canal using 5.25% sodium hypochlorite. As a final&#xD;
      irrigation, either cold saline solution or a normal saline solution at room temperature will&#xD;
      be used. The participants will be asked to fill out another questionnaire and record the&#xD;
      presence, duration, and intensity of postoperative pain, and if painkiller medicine was taken&#xD;
      immediately after completion of root canal treatment and at 6 hours, 12 hours, 72 hours, and&#xD;
      1-week intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researcher will compare the effect of the final irrigation of a cold saline solution with&#xD;
      that of a normal saline solution at room temperature on postoperative pain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Postoperative pain in root canal therapy is multifactorial in nature, including changes in&#xD;
      periapical pressure, microbial factors, inflammatory mediators, and psychological factors.&#xD;
      Postoperative pain in endodontics between visits or after completion of the treatment is a&#xD;
      major concern to both patients and operators. Teeth presented with preoperative pain,&#xD;
      irreversible pulpitis, pulp necrosis, and apical periodontitis are the most susceptible to&#xD;
      postoperative pain The pharmacological management of pain using medications such as&#xD;
      nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, paracetamol, or corticosteroids, despite being&#xD;
      relatively safe, can have side effects such as gastrointestinal intolerance and renal,&#xD;
      hepatic, and respiratory disorders such as asthma which have been reported in the literature.&#xD;
      To avoid these secondary effects, intracanal medications, laser, and cryotherapy have been&#xD;
      suggested in the literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical and clinical evidence suggests that the application of cold may decrease pain&#xD;
      through the mechanism of decreasing the conduction velocity of nerve signals, hemorrhage,&#xD;
      edema, and local inflammation. An in vitro study showed that intracanal irrigation with cold&#xD;
      saline at 2.5 degrees Celsius reduced the external root surface temperature by more than 10&#xD;
      degrees Celsius, which would be enough to produce the anti-inflammatory effect in&#xD;
      peri-radicular tissues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are very few studies done to evaluate the effect of intracanal cryotherapy on&#xD;
      postoperative pain in root canal therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This clinical trial aims to assess if final irrigation using cold saline solution after&#xD;
      standard chemo-mechanical preparation (root canal instrumentation and irrigation using 5.25%&#xD;
      sodium hypochlorite) procedures results in any difference in the incidence and intensity of&#xD;
      postoperative pain in patients presenting with molar teeth with necrosis of pulp and&#xD;
      symptomatic apical periodontitis. This clinical trial will also assess the incidence of any&#xD;
      adverse event as a result of cold saline irrigation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 20, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 20, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative pain</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative pain will be measured using visual analog scale (VAS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative pain</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative pain will be measured using visual analog scale (VAS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative pain</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative pain will be measured using visual analog scale (VAS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative pain</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative pain will be measured using visual analog scale (VAS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>during the irrigation procedure</time_frame>
    <description>If any adverse event will occur, it will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately after the irrigation procedure</time_frame>
    <description>If any adverse event will occur, it will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>6 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>If any adverse event will occur, it will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>If any adverse event will occur, it will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>If any adverse event will occur, it will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>If any adverse event will occur, it will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">286</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Pulp Necroses</condition>
  <condition>Apical Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Post Operative Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cold saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After standard chemo-mechanical preparation of the root canal, final irrigation will be performed using 20 milliliters of cold (at 2.5 degrees Celsius temperature) saline solution.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>After standard chemo-mechanical preparation of the root canal, final irrigation of the root canal system will be performed using 20 milliliters of normal saline solution at room temperature.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cold saline</intervention_name>
    <description>After standard chemo-mechanical preparation of the root canal, final irrigation will be performed using 20 milliliters of cold (at 2.5 degrees Celsius temperature) saline solution.</description>
    <arm_group_label>cold saline</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>cold normal saline</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>saline</intervention_name>
    <description>After standard chemo-mechanical preparation of the root canal, final irrigation of the root canal will be done using normal saline solution at room temperature</description>
    <arm_group_label>saline</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>normal saline</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with maxillary or mandibular molar teeth that require root canal treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The diagnosis of pulp necrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of symptomatic apical periodontitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of normal occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously done root canal treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of any systemic disease or allergic reactions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any analgesic or antibiotic medications within the past three days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sinus tract or local gingival swelling around the affected tooth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periodontal pocket greater than 3 mm around the affected tooth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe periodontal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Internal or external root resorption&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Broken files&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over instrumentation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incomplete filling of the root canal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Overfilling of the root canal&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Muhammad Zubair Ahmad, BDS, FCPS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Qassim University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Muhammad Zubair Ahmad, BDS, FCPS</last_name>
    <phone>0163011111</phone>
    <phone_ext>10685</phone_ext>
    <email>m.muhammad@qu.edu.sa</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Muhammad Zubair Ahmad</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ar Rass</city>
        <state>Qassim</state>
        <zip>58883</zip>
        <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Muhammad Zubair Ahmad, BDS, FCPS</last_name>
      <phone>0163011111</phone>
      <phone_ext>10685</phone_ext>
      <email>m.muhammad@qu.edu.sa</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vera J, Ochoa-Rivera J, Vazquez-Carcano M, Romero M, Arias A, Sleiman P. Effect of Intracanal Cryotherapy on Reducing Root Surface Temperature. J Endod. 2015 Nov;41(11):1884-7. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2015.08.009. Epub 2015 Oct 1.</citation>
    <PMID>26433855</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alharthi AA, Aljoudi MH, Almaliki MN, Almalki MA, Sunbul MA. Effect of intra-canal cryotherapy on post-endodontic pain in single-visit RCT: A randomized controlled trial. Saudi Dent J. 2019 Jul;31(3):330-335. doi: 10.1016/j.sdentj.2019.03.004. Epub 2019 Mar 14.</citation>
    <PMID>31337936</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fayyad DM, Abdelsalam N, Hashem N. Cryotherapy: A New Paradigm of Treatment in Endodontics. J Endod. 2020 Jul;46(7):936-942. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2020.03.019. Epub 2020 May 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32386857</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sadaf D. Limited Quality Evidence Suggests that Application of Cryotherapy May Be Helpful in Reducing Postoperative Pain in Root Canal Therapy in Patients With Symptomatic Apical Periodontitis. J Evid Based Dent Pract. 2019 Jun;19(2):195-197. doi: 10.1016/j.jebdp.2019.05.005. Epub 2019 May 6.</citation>
    <PMID>31326055</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gundogdu EC, Arslan H. Effects of Various Cryotherapy Applications on Postoperative Pain in Molar Teeth with Symptomatic Apical Periodontitis: A Preliminary Randomized Prospective Clinical Trial. J Endod. 2018 Mar;44(3):349-354. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2017.11.002. Epub 2018 Feb 3.</citation>
    <PMID>29398090</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sadaf D, Ahmad MZ, Onakpoya IJ. Effectiveness of Intracanal Cryotherapy in Root Canal Therapy: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Randomized Clinical Trials. J Endod. 2020 Dec;46(12):1811-1823.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2020.08.022. Epub 2020 Sep 8.</citation>
    <PMID>32916207</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vera J, Ochoa J, Romero M, Vazquez-Carcano M, Ramos-Gregorio CO, Aguilar RR, Cruz A, Sleiman P, Arias A. Intracanal Cryotherapy Reduces Postoperative Pain in Teeth with Symptomatic Apical Periodontitis: A Randomized Multicenter Clinical Trial. J Endod. 2018 Jan;44(1):4-8. doi: 10.1016/j.joen.2017.08.038. Epub 2017 Nov 1.</citation>
    <PMID>29079057</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 27, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 27, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Qassim University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Muhammad Zubair Ahmad</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cryotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>endodontic pain</keyword>
  <keyword>molar teeth</keyword>
  <keyword>root canal treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Periapical Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dental Pulp Necrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

