<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05795803</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC 11/2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05795803</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of COVID-19 Forced Isolation Context on Adolescents With and Without Somatic Symptom Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of a Pandemic Forced Isolation Context on Adolescents With Somatic Symptom Disorder. A Panel Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>IRCCS Burlo Garofolo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>IRCCS Burlo Garofolo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether a forced isolation context (such provided by&#xD;
      the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic restrictive measures) could reduce the burden of somatic&#xD;
      symptoms among a group of patients with Somatic Symptom Disorder (SSD). Secondary objective&#xD;
      is to assess if a reduction in terms of depression tendency and anxiety occurs in this&#xD;
      specific population and which are the effect of such a context among a group of adolescents&#xD;
      without SSD. We want to compare these results with data obtained at the end of the pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to evaluate whether the forced isolation context provided by the ongoing&#xD;
      Covid-19 pandemic is providing an advantage in terms of reduction of somatic symptoms burden&#xD;
      among an Italian group of adolescents with SSD, assessed by the Patient Health Questionnaire&#xD;
      (PhQ15) administered during and at the end of the pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives of the study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the difference in anxiety and depression scores assessed by the&#xD;
           Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children (MASC2) and Child Development Inventory&#xD;
           (CDI-2) questionnaires among a group of SSD adolescents, during and after the pandemic&#xD;
           isolation context.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the difference in anxiety and depression scores assessed by the&#xD;
           Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children (MASC2) and Child Development Inventory&#xD;
           (CDI-2) questionnaires among a group of adolescents without SSD, during and after the&#xD;
           pandemic isolation context.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the difference in anxiety and depression scores time modification between the&#xD;
           two groups of adolescents.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore through tailored questions which adolescents' coping strategies are during a&#xD;
           pandemic isolation context among SSD patients and a group of controls without SSD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in mean PhQ15 scale scores between T0 and T1 in the SSD adolescents group.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>To SSD group, the Health Questionnaire Physical Symptoms (PhQ15) will be administrated to quantify the somatic symptom burden.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in mean MASC2 scores between T0 and T1 in the SSD group.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>SSD adolescents will receive the Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children (MASC 2), composed by 50 items, to quantify adolescents' anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in mean CDI-2 short questionnaire scores between T0 and T1 in the SSD group.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>SSD adolescents will receive the Children's Depression Inventory (CDI-2) self-report short questionnaire, composed by 12 items, to quantify adolescents' depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in mean MASC2 scores between T0 and T1 in the adolescents group without SSD diagnosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>Adolescents without SSD will receive the Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children (MASC 2), composed by 50 items, to quantify adolescents' anxiety</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in mean CDI-2 short questionnaires scores between T0 and T1 in the adolescents group without SSD diagnosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>Adolescents without SSD will receive the Children's Depression Inventory (CDI-2) self-report short questionnaire, composed by 12 items, to quantify adolescents' depression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison between the two groups of adolescents in the mean T1-T0 differences for MASC2 scores.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in the Multidimensional Anxiety Scale for Children (MASC 2), composed by 50 items</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison between the two groups of adolescents in the mean T1-T0 differences for CDI-2 short questionnaires scores.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic and within 6 months after the end</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in Children's Depression Inventory (CDI-2) self-report short questionnaire, composed by 12 items</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of adolescents' coping strategies during a pandemic isolation context among SSD and non-SSD adolescent</measure>
    <time_frame>During the pandemic</time_frame>
    <description>A general anonymous semi-structured survey will be administered to both the groups in order to investigate their habits, social media and videogames pattern of usage, and other leisure pattern of frequency. This will provide us a description of adolescents' general coping strategies during quarantine period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">115</enrollment>
  <condition>Somatic Symptom Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SSD group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adolescents with SSD diagnosis made within previously six months or before unless assessed and confirmed by a specialist within the last six months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Without SSD group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Control group: adolescents without diagnosis of SSD, matched with the SSD group by age and sex</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Forced isolation context</intervention_name>
    <description>Exposure to the forced isolation context provided by the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic restrictive measures</description>
    <arm_group_label>SSD group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Without SSD group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>COVID-19 lockdown</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  SSD group: Adolescents who received a diagnosis of SSD at the Institute for maternal&#xD;
             and child health &quot;Burlo Garofolo&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Without SSD group: Adolescents who accessed the Emergency Department for traumatic&#xD;
             injuries or the Pediatric Clinic/Day Hospital Service for oral immunotherapy because&#xD;
             of food allergies.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescents aged between 12 and 17 years old who received a diagnosis of SSD within&#xD;
             the last six months or before unless assessed and confirmed by a specialist within the&#xD;
             last six months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescents without a diagnosis of SSD, who previously accessed the Institute for&#xD;
             maternal and child health &quot;Burlo Garofolo&quot; Emergency Department for traumatic injuries&#xD;
             or the Pediatric Clinic/Day Hospital Service for oral immunotherapy because of food&#xD;
             allergies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescents experiencing a quarantine period during the Covid19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescents with cognitive impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescents with chronic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adolescents with other neuropsychiatric disorders according to the fifth edition of&#xD;
             the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorder (DSM V).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the group without SSD diagnosis, any access to Emergency Department for&#xD;
             unexplained chronic pain or any history of other psychiatric comorbidities.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Giuseppe Abbracciavento, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Institute for maternal and child health Burlo Garofolo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura De Nardi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute for maternal and child health Burlo Garofolo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrea Trombetta, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute for maternal and child health Burlo Garofolo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute for Maternal and Child Health - IRCCS Burlo Garofolo-</name>
      <address>
        <city>Trieste</city>
        <zip>34137</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SSD</keyword>
  <keyword>adolescents</keyword>
  <keyword>coping strategies</keyword>
  <keyword>social media</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Medically Unexplained Symptoms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

