<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618678</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>00020594</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618678</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pilot Testing Decision Making in Aging and Dementia for Autonomy Program in Nursing Homes</brief_title>
  <acronym>DIGNITY</acronym>
  <official_title>Pilot Testing Decision Making in Aging and Dementia for Autonomy for Preference-Based Care in Nursing Homes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Penn State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Penn State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to adapt, pilot test, and evaluate the feasibility,&#xD;
      acceptability, and preliminary effectiveness of DIGNITY (Decision-making In aGing and&#xD;
      demeNtIa for auTonomY) for Preference-Based Care in Nursing Homes as a new evidence-based&#xD;
      intervention to support nursing home staff to safely honor care and activity preferences of&#xD;
      residents' living with dementia in rural, typically under resourced nursing home communities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Of 6.5 million older Americans are living with Alzheimer's disease and related forms of&#xD;
      dementia (ADRD), two thirds will die in a nursing home (NH) where staff are not prepared to&#xD;
      deliver a minimal level of federally mandated care. Care in NHs is delivered by an&#xD;
      ever-changing workforce of 1.3 million staff members who are responsible to provide&#xD;
      person-centered care (PCC)- that is care based on knowing and honoring residents preferences&#xD;
      for care and activities of daily living. NH residents have reported they are not satisfied&#xD;
      with efforts to honor their preferences for everyday living and care activities. For&#xD;
      residents living with ADRD this can lead to a loss of dignity, anger, agitation, isolation,&#xD;
      depression, and negative social interactions between residents ultimately reducing quality of&#xD;
      life. A prominent, known barrier to honoring residents' preferences is the predominantly risk&#xD;
      adverse attitudes and behaviors of NH staff. DIGNITY (Decision-making in aging and dementia&#xD;
      for autonomy) is novel multi-level intervention based in theory and evidence aimed at&#xD;
      empowering nursing home staff to negotiate residents' risky preferences by addressing&#xD;
      intrinsic and system barriers to safely honoring a resident's preferences with decision aids,&#xD;
      care planning, and staff coaching/education. In the proposed project, we will implement&#xD;
      DIGNITY in a pilot cluster randomized trial of 80 nursing home staff and residents across&#xD;
      four rural nursing homes located in Pennsylvania. Our aims are to: 1.) To explore stakeholder&#xD;
      perspectives on the relevance and feasibility of implementing the DIGNITY intervention in&#xD;
      rural, underserved nursing home communities; and 2.) examine the feasibility, acceptability,&#xD;
      and preliminary effectiveness of DIGNITY within four rural, underserved nursing homes.&#xD;
      Outcomes will be evaluated at baseline and 12 weeks following baseline education on the&#xD;
      DIGNITY protocol. This study is a critical next step in developing evidence-based&#xD;
      interventions that target gaps in direct-care workforce skills needed to enhance quality of&#xD;
      care delivery to persons with ADRD living in NHs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Nursing homes are randomized to one of two groups: 1.) DIGNITY Protocol or 2.) DIGNITY Protocol plus ECHO Training</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after baseline education on DIGNITY protocol</time_frame>
    <description>Evidence of Feasibility (Feasibility of Intervention Measure)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Staff Behavioral Intent</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after baseline education on DIGNITY protocol</time_frame>
    <description>Evidence of Staff Intent to Honor Resident's Preference (Investigator developed survey item)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Resident Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after baseline education on DIGNITY protocol</time_frame>
    <description>Evidence of resident satisfaction with preference (Preferences for Everyday Living Inventory)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Fidelity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after baseline education on DIGNITY protocol</time_frame>
    <description>Evidence of staff fidelity to the DIGNTY Intervention (Investigator developed DIGNITY Intervention Fidelity Assessment Checklist)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Staff Self - Efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after baseline education on DIGNITY protocol</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in perceived self-efficacy in Person-Centered Risk Management (Investigator Developed Self Efficacy Survey for Person-Centered Risk Management)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks after baseline education on DIGNITY protocol</time_frame>
    <description>Staff rate intervention acceptability on the Acceptability of Intervention Measure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">4</enrollment>
  <condition>Dementia</condition>
  <condition>Staff Attitude</condition>
  <condition>Nurse's Role</condition>
  <condition>Nursing Homes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DIGNITY Protocol Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nursing homes randomized to this arm of the study receive an evidence based risk assessment and care planning protocol for supporting decision making and aging in dementia for autonomy (DIGNITY). Nursing home staff use this manual to implement risk assessment and care planning for resident preferences that they perceive to carry a risk to the resident's health and/or safety.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DIGNITY Protocol Plus ECHO Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nursing homes randomized to this arm of the study receive an evidence based risk assessment and care planning protocol for supporting decision making and aging in dementia for autonomy (DIGNITY). Nursing home staff use this manual to implement risk assessment and care planning for resident preferences that they perceive to carry a risk to the resident's health and/or safety. In addition nursing home staff participate in Extension for Community Healthcare Outcomes (ECHO) sessions via real-time interactive videoconferencing software to support the implementation of the DIGNITY protocol.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DIGNITY</intervention_name>
    <description>DIGNITY is a multi-component, multi-level intervention that guides shared decision-making in nursing homes to support person-centered dementia care. It includes an adapted care planning protocol and staff training to help direct-care staff negotiate intrinsic and cultural factors in preference situations that carry a risk to residents' health and safety. Based in theory, this intervention targets nursing home staff attitudes and behaviors around assessing and judging whether to engage in risk situations to support resident preferences for everyday living and care despite cognitive decline due to dementia.</description>
    <arm_group_label>DIGNITY Protocol Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>DIGNITY Protocol Plus ECHO Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for Nursing Homes:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Located in rural Pennsylvania per the Rural Health Information Hub54&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Administrator articulates commitment to delivering person-centered care&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. NH has a dedicated dementia care unit and/or a total bed capacity of 100 beds or more&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. NH has the capacity to participate in the study activities for the term of the study&#xD;
             as determined by nursing home leadership&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. NH has a dedicated quality improvement/safety team that meets regularly&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. NH has a stable internet connectivity for program delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nursing Home does not meet inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Convenience sampling will be used to recruit nursing home staff and residents within&#xD;
        nursing homes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Nursing Home Staff:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Employed by the participating nursing home for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Fluent in written and spoken English&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Provides and/or influences direct care delivery to older adults with dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Residents:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Resides in nursing home study site for at least 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Documented diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease or related dementia (ADRD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have a stated preference that nursing home staff indicated poses a risk to their&#xD;
             health and/or safety&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Provides consent/assent to be enrolled&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Liza Behrens, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Penn State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Liza Behrens, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>8148650743</phone>
    <email>llb237@psu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 22, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Penn State University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Liza Behrens, PhD, RN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Shared Decision Making</keyword>
  <keyword>Person-Centered Care</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

