<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05794386</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCARLET-AF</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05794386</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SCAR Burden of Left Atrium Guided cathEter Ablation sTrategy for Persistent Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
  <acronym>SCARLET-AF</acronym>
  <official_title>SCAR Burden of Left Atrium Guided cathEter Ablation sTrategy for Persistent Atrial Fibrillation (SCARLET-AF Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seoul National University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Seoul National University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, randomized controlled trial to compare the recurrence of 1-year atrial&#xD;
      arrhythmia after catheter ablation of atrial fibrillation (AF) between pulmonary vein&#xD;
      isolation (PVI) and PVI with additional left atrial (LA) substrate modification based on the&#xD;
      left atrial low-voltage area (LA LVA) in patients with persistent AF who had a moderate&#xD;
      burden of LVA in LA (1cm2 to &lt;30%).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      -  Sample size calculation To calculate the sample size needed to conduct the study, the&#xD;
           investigators used the test for two proportions. The participants will be 1:1&#xD;
           randomized. Group sample sizes of 91 in group 1 and 91 in group 2 achieve 80.318% power&#xD;
           to detect a difference between the group proportions of -0.20. The proportion in group 1&#xD;
           (the treatment group) is assumed to be 0.50 under the null hypothesis and 0.30 under the&#xD;
           alternative hypothesis. The proportion in group 2 (the control group) is 0.50. The test&#xD;
           statistic used is the two-sided Z-Test with unpooled variance. The significance level of&#xD;
           the test is 0.05. When the investigators set the expected drop-out rate as 10%, the&#xD;
           final sample size of each group is 102.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Part 1. Randomized controlled trial for LVA burden 1cm2 to &lt;30%&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Primary endpoint The survival analysis of AT/AF recurrence during 1-year&#xD;
                     follow-up after the procedure with 3-months of blanking period is performed by&#xD;
                     Kaplan-Meier survival analysis. The log-rank test compares the survival curve&#xD;
                     of two groups (PVI only vs. PVI with additional LA substrate modification). To&#xD;
                     evaluate the effect of LA substrate modification on the recurrence of AT/AF,&#xD;
                     Cox proportional hazard regression analysis with the log-rank test is&#xD;
                     performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Secondary endpoint Kaplan-Meier survival analysis is performed for the&#xD;
                     recurrence of AT/AF within 3 months, the recurrence of AF or AT between 3&#xD;
                     months and one year after the procedure, and a log-rank test will be used to&#xD;
                     compare the survival curves of the two groups. To evaluate the effect of LA&#xD;
                     additional substrate modification on the early recurrence of AT/AF within&#xD;
                     3-month, and the recurrence of AF or AT between 3 months and 1 year after the&#xD;
                     procedure, a Cox proportional hazard regression analysis with a log-rank test&#xD;
                     will be performed. The comparison of the EHRA symptom grade change before and&#xD;
                     after the procedure and the quality of life evaluation score according to the&#xD;
                     SF-36 questionnaire before and after the procedure will be analyzed using the&#xD;
                     paired t-test.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Part 2. Registry for LVA burden &lt;1cm2 or ≥30% Part 2 is classified into &lt;1cm2 group&#xD;
                and ≥30% group according to LVA burden, and primary/secondary endpoints are&#xD;
                collected in each group. The entire groups are&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. LVA burden 1cm2 to &lt;30%, PVI only group&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. LVA burden 1cm2 to &lt;30%, PVI + additional LA substrate modification group&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. LVA burden &lt;1cm2 with PVA only group&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. LVA burden ≥30% with PVI + additional LA substrate modification group The&#xD;
                investigators analyzed the difference in the occurrence of the primary and&#xD;
                secondary endpoints in the four groups using the Kaplan-Meier survival analysis and&#xD;
                log-rank test. In addition, factors related to the recurrence of AT/AF are analyzed&#xD;
                through univariable and multivariable Cox proportional hazard analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Study Procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Subject screening Patients with persistent AF are screened for study enrollment&#xD;
                during the outpatient clinic. Patients must receive appropriate anticoagulant&#xD;
                treatment for at least 1 month prior to AF catheter ablation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Informed consent After AF ablation, informed consent for the study is acquired.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Voltage mapping and randomization AF ablation is performed using a 3D mapping&#xD;
                system (CARTO). Before the ablation, LA voltage mapping was first performed in&#xD;
                sinus rhythm. If a patient's rhythm is not in AF, then electrical cardioversion is&#xD;
                performed to restore sinus rhythm and perform voltage mapping. To ensure a&#xD;
                sufficient quality of the voltage map, at least 2500 points should be acquired with&#xD;
                TPI(Tissue Proximity Index) function On.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the mapping, the LVA burden is calculated. If the LVA burden is between ≥1cm2 and &lt;30%,&#xD;
      the patient is randomized either to the control group (Group 1; PVI alone) or the&#xD;
      experimental group (Group 2; PVI alone + LVA burden guided substrate modification).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants with the LVA burden &lt;1cm2 or ≥30% will be excluded from the randomization&#xD;
      but allocated to the registry. They are not primarily involved in data analysis of the RCT,&#xD;
      but their data will be monitored for a further study. We recommend PVI alone for those with&#xD;
      the LVA burden &lt;1cm2. For the participants with the LVA burden ≥30%, additional ablation&#xD;
      beyond PVI is at physician's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ablation protocol The pre-defined ablation protocol for each group is as follows.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Group 1: PVI alone - The control group The participants in Group 1 received the&#xD;
                usual PVI alone. A detailed PVI protocol is as follows.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Point-by-point AI(ablation index) guided PVI is performed&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  AI target: 400~500 for roof/anterior sides, 300~400 for posterior/ inferior/&#xD;
                     carina sides&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Ablation power: 30~40 W for roof/anterior sides, 25~45 W for posterior/&#xD;
                     inferior/ carina sides&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Contact force: target 10~20 g&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  VisiTag setting: 2.5 mm, 5 s, 3 g&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Both exit and entrance blocks should be checked for successful PVI&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Esophageal temperature monitoring: Not mandatory. If performed, ablation&#xD;
                     should be immediately stopped if the temperature rises ≥38 ℃&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Definition of successful PVI: The ablation procedure will be considered&#xD;
                     successful when PVI, as confirmed by the bidirectional conduction block&#xD;
                     between PV and LA, has been achieved. A bidirectional conduction block is&#xD;
                     defined as the combination of an entrance block (the stable absence of&#xD;
                     conduction into the PV from the LA) and exit block (the stable absence of&#xD;
                     conduction from the PV into the LA, either spontaneous or during pacing from&#xD;
                     the circular mapping catheter positioned at the PV ostium).&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Group 2: PVI + LVA burden guided substrate modification - The experimental group&#xD;
                The participants in Group 2 received usual PVI plus additional LVA burden guided&#xD;
                substrate modification. A PVI procedure is same as in Group 1. A detailed protocol&#xD;
                for LVA burden guided ablation and its endpoints are as follows.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  LVA burden guided substrate modification&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Only LVA island(s) ≥1 cm2 should be ablated&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  LVA near PV ostium: PVI ablation should be designed to included the LVA&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  LVA at anterior side: Anterior linear ablation including the LVA is performed&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  LVA at posterior side: Posterior wall isolation including the LVA is performed. If&#xD;
                LVA island(s) is small such that focal ablation can be also considered, either&#xD;
                posterior wall isolation or focal ablation can be performed by the physician's&#xD;
                discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  LVA at septal or lateral side: Focal homogenization of the LVA is performed&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Endpoints for LVA burden-guided substrate modification&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Focal ablated LVA: Loss of capture by 10 V, 2 ms.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Linear ablation-related LVA: Bidirectional block across the line After the ablation&#xD;
                according to the pre-defined protocol, an AF induction test and AF trigger search&#xD;
                are performed. Additional ablation can be performed according to the results of the&#xD;
                tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow-up method 14-day ambulatory ECG monitoring (14-day for RCT, 1- or 3-day for&#xD;
           Registry participants).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study uses a single-lead ECG patch device for the detection of the recurrence of atrial&#xD;
      tachyarrhythmia during the follow up. The ECG patch device is capable of 14-day ambulatory&#xD;
      ECG monitoring. Compared to 24- or 72-hr Holter test, the use of 14-day ECG monitoring allows&#xD;
      for a more accurate examination of the efficacy of the treatment. Additionally, the patient&#xD;
      can activate the device manually to facilitate the analysis of heart rhythm during&#xD;
      symptomatic events. Arrhythmia events meeting these criteria are stored for independent&#xD;
      adjudication by an independent, blinded clinical endpoint committee.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow-up and procedure endpoint evaluation After the ablation, participants will be&#xD;
           discharged within 24 hours after the ablation procedure. Participants will be instructed&#xD;
           to record symptomatic episodes via the use of the patient activator. Scheduled follow-up&#xD;
           visits will occur at 3, 6, and 12 months from the first ablation procedure (within a&#xD;
           4-week margin). After the 90-days of the blanking period, any atrial tachyarrhythmias&#xD;
           will be followed up at 3, 6, and 12 months after the procedure. The recurrence can be&#xD;
           confirmed by 12-lead ECGs (3, 6, and 12 months) and ambulatory 14-day single-lead ECG&#xD;
           monitoring (3, 12 months). Arrhythmia recurrence during the first 90 days blanking&#xD;
           period can be treated with cardioversion and/or AADs. Where possible, repeat ablation&#xD;
           procedures will be deferred until after the 3-month blanking period due to the potential&#xD;
           for a delayed cure (as per standard practice and in accordance with HRS/ECAS/EHRA&#xD;
           recommendations). If AADs (except amiodarone) are used in the first 3 months&#xD;
           post-ablation, they will be discontinued five half-lives before the end of the 3-month&#xD;
           blanking period with the discretion of the operator. After a 3-month post-ablation, the&#xD;
           redo procedure would be decided on the discretion of the physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Study discontinuation and withdrawal criteria Research participants have the right to&#xD;
           refuse participation in research or to withdraw participation at any time for any&#xD;
           reason. In case of refusal or withdrawal from participation in the study, there is no&#xD;
           harm, and no future medical management is affected. The researcher may suspend or&#xD;
           exclude a participant from the study if at least one of the reasons described below&#xD;
           exists.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In case of withdrawal of the consent by participants or legal representatives&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In case of adverse effects related to the study make it difficult to continue the&#xD;
                study&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  In case of any violations of inclusion or exclusion criteria are found during the&#xD;
                study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  If a researcher judges that continuing the study is difficult&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Risks and Benefits Radiofrequency catheter ablation is commonly used for the treatment&#xD;
           of AF. However, different risks could be observed by different ablation strategies.&#xD;
           According to the ERASE-AF trial, additional LVA-guided ablation resulted in&#xD;
           complications as follows. The investigators assume similar complication rates will be&#xD;
           observed in our study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cardiac tamponade or pericardial effusion: 2.7%&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Sepsis: 0.3%&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Femoral arteriovenous fistula: 0.9%&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Femoral pseudoaneurysm: 2.2%&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  There was no reported stroke/TIA/arterial embolism, pericarditis, phrenic nerve&#xD;
                palsy, internal bleeding, atrioesophageal fistula, pulmonary vein stenosis, or&#xD;
                death.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Compared to the ERASE-AF trial, femoral puncture related complications can be&#xD;
                prevent in our study by using sono-guided procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a 1:1 randomized controlled trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Late recurrence of AT/AF</measure>
    <time_frame>From 3 months to 1 year after the catheter ablation</time_frame>
    <description>Recurrence of atrial tachyarrhythmia (AT/AF) from 3 months to 1 year after the index procedure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Early recurrence of atrial tachyarrhythmia</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 months from the catheter ablation</time_frame>
    <description>Early recurrence of atrial tachyarrhythmia within 3 months after the index procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Late recurrence of AF</measure>
    <time_frame>From 3 months to 1 year after the catheter ablation</time_frame>
    <description>AF recurrence from 3 months to 1 year after the index procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Late recurrence of AT</measure>
    <time_frame>From 3 months to 1 year after the catheter ablation</time_frame>
    <description>Atrial tachycardia (AT) recurrence from 3 months to 1 year after the index procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5. AF-related Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Before (at baseline) and after (at 1 year) the catheter ablation</time_frame>
    <description>AF-related quality of life was measured by a survey (AFEQT) performed before and after the index procedure. The AFEQT survey measures scores (lower scores for a better quality of life). The decrement in AFEQT survey scores after the index procedure confirms the better quality of life after the index procedure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">204</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PVI only group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive PVI alone regardless of LVA burden.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Additional LA substrate modification group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive PVI plus additional LA substrate modification according to their LVA burden.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LVA-guided LA substrate modification</intervention_name>
    <description>The LVA-guided additional LA ablation is included linear ablation or LVA zone border modification/isolation/ homogenization. The additional ablation strategies are finally selected at the physicians' discretion, considering LVA location and distribution.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Additional LA substrate modification group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Ages eligible for the study: 19 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with symptomatic persistent AF who undergo AF catheter ablation due to&#xD;
             continued AF even after anti-arrhythmic agents or&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with a burden of LA LVA (scar zone) of 1cm2 or more and less than 30% in 3D&#xD;
             voltage mapping before the index catheter ablation are included in the randomized&#xD;
             assignment group when performing catheter ablation in satisfaction with 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4) Patients with an LVA of &lt;1cm2 or ≥30% are recruited as a registry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with LA anteroposterior diameter of more than 55 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with prior AF-related catheter ablation or surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients whose exact LVA burden cannot be calculated because high-quality 3D voltage&#xD;
             mapping cannot be obtained during the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Inability or unwillingness to receive anticoagulation (heparin or oral&#xD;
             anticoagulation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known severe left ventricular systolic dysfunction (ejection fraction &lt;35%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with severe structural heart disease (severe mitral regurgitation,&#xD;
             hypertrophy cardiomyopathy, other severe valvular heart diseases)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with intracardiac thrombus&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with prior cardiac surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients who had a myocardial infarction or underwent percutaneous coronary&#xD;
             intervention within three months&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients who had a stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients who had a planned operation or procedure for the cardiovascular system&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients with intractable hypertension or uncontrolled thyroid disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients who need dialysis due to end-stage renal disease or who are scheduled for&#xD;
             dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients who are currently pregnant or are likely to be pregnant within the study&#xD;
             period&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients who are taking immunosuppressive drugs or had undergone chemotherapy for&#xD;
             cancer, autoimmune disease, transplant, etc&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patients whose life expectancy is less than 1 year&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eue-Keun Choi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Seoul National University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eue-Keun Choi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2-2072-0688</phone>
    <phone_ext>82</phone_ext>
    <email>choiek417@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <state>Jongno-gu</state>
        <zip>03080</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Eue-Keun Choi</last_name>
      <phone>82-2-2072-0688</phone>
      <email>choiek417@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 6, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 6, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 10, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Seoul National University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Eue-Keun Choi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Atrial fibrillation</keyword>
  <keyword>Catheter ablation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

