<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05629754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL82613.029.22</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05629754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>TTT Follow-up Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Long-term Outcomes and Development of Retropatellar Chondropathy After Tibial Tubercle Distomedialisation for Patellar Maltracking and Patella Alta Without Instability: 10 Year Follow-up of a Prospective Cohort</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre for Orthopaedic Research Alkmaar</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Noordwest Ziekenhuisgroep</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre for Orthopaedic Research Alkmaar</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patellofemoral pain is a common complaint especially in young adults. It can be caused by&#xD;
      patellar maltracking. Part of this is a patella alta. When patellar maltracking is the cause&#xD;
      of the problem and conservative therapy fails, surgery, a tibial tuberosity transposition,&#xD;
      may be considered. Most research has been done in patients with recurrent patella luxation.&#xD;
      However, in patients without luxation, research is scarce.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is known that patients with patella alta have an increased risk of developing&#xD;
      patellofemoral chondropathy due to increased pressure. With this study, we aim to investigate&#xD;
      whether and how a tibial tuberosity transposition in patients with patella alta and no&#xD;
      instability affects the degree of patellofemoral chondropathy and patient satisfaction after&#xD;
      10 years. This will allow us to educate patients regarding long-term outcomes better.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Anterior knee pain is a common complaint, especially in younger and active adults. An obvious&#xD;
      source for anterior knee pain is patellar maltracking, which is often associated with patella&#xD;
      alta (a high-riding patella). Due to maltracking, the cartilage of the patella can face a&#xD;
      greater amount of pressure, which can cause cartilage damage. When conservative treatment&#xD;
      fails, a surgical intervention can be considered. One of the surgical options is performing a&#xD;
      tibial tubercle transfer (TTT), where the patella is being distalized and medialized. As a&#xD;
      result, the improvement in patellar tracking will reduce the pressure on the retropatellar&#xD;
      cartilage. The TTT has been proven effective in patients with patellar instability but less&#xD;
      is known about patients without instability. Specifically, whether these patients face a&#xD;
      higher risk of developing retropatellar cartilage damage ('retropatellar chondropathy') due&#xD;
      to this intervention is currently unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim of this study is to determine the incidence and the degree of retropatellar&#xD;
      chondropathy 10 years after a TTT in patients with anterior knee pain without patellar&#xD;
      instability. The secondary aim is to evaluate the long-term patient reported outcomes (PROMs)&#xD;
      10 years after a TTT in patients with anterior knee pain without patellar instability.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Outerbridge Classification</measure>
    <time_frame>10-year follow-up assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Degree of retropatellar cartilage damage</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patellar height</measure>
    <time_frame>10-year follow-up assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Patellar height measured by radiological assessment lateral view</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knee injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score (KOOS) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>10-year follow-up assessment</time_frame>
    <description>KOOS consists of 5 subscales; Pain, other Symptoms, Function in daily living (ADL), Function in sport and recreation (Sport/Rec) and knee related Quality of life (QOL). The previous week is the time period considered when answering the questions. Standardized answer options are given (5 Likert boxes) and each question is assigned a score from 0 to 4. A normalized score (100 indicating no symptoms and 0 indicating extreme symptoms) is calculated for each subscale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kujala Anterior Knee Pain Score (AKPS) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>One measurement</time_frame>
    <description>The Kujala AKPS is a 13-item screening instrument designed to assess patellofemoral pain in adolescents and young adults, with a variable ordinal response format (e.g., no pain (5) to constant pain (0)). Total scores range from 0 to 100, with a higher score indicating less symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) for pain</measure>
    <time_frame>10-year follow-up assessment</time_frame>
    <description>The pain VAS is a unidimensional measure of pain intensity, scored from 0 (no pain) to 100 (highest possible pain intensity).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Anterior Knee Pain Syndrome</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MRI, radiological assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>MRI and radiological assessment of the involved knee</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients whom around 10 years ago presented with anterior knee pain and patella maltracking&#xD;
        without instability, where conservative therapy failed and a TTT was performed, and who&#xD;
        participated in the original cohort.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participated in an earlier cohort study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underwent a tibial tubercle transposition between 2012 and 2015&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preoperative MRI available&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No preoperative MRI is available&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patellar-related surgery after the initial surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients that are (expecting to be) pregnant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>KDS Boerma-Argelo</last_name>
    <phone>+31725482500</phone>
    <email>k.d.s.argelo@nwz.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>JL Benner</last_name>
    <email>jl.benner@nwz.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bayoumi T, van Duijvenbode DC, Benner JL, Boerma-Argelo KDS, Stavenuiter MHJ, van der List JP. Clinical Improvement Is Achieved Following Tibial Tubercle Distomedialization for Patellar Maltracking and Patella Alta Without Instability. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2021 Jun 15;3(3):e845-e853. doi: 10.1016/j.asmr.2021.01.027. eCollection 2021 Jun.</citation>
    <PMID>34195653</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Centre for Orthopaedic Research Alkmaar</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. J.L. Benner</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tibial tubercle transfer</keyword>
  <keyword>Long-term follow-up</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

