<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05794347</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC/RCR &amp; AHS/23/0116</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05794347</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Traction in Vertical Sitting Position Versus Supine Lying Position in Patients of Chronic Radicular Low Back Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Vertical Sitting Versus Supine Lying Traction on Pain, Range of Motion and Function in Patients With Chronic Radicular Low Back Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of the study is to determine the effects of vertical sitting versus&#xD;
      supine lying traction on pain, range of motion, and function in patients with chronic&#xD;
      radicular low back pain (CRLBP). CRLBP is one of the major types of lower back pain and&#xD;
      causes significant disability and reduction in quality of life in the human population. The&#xD;
      study will be a randomized controlled trial and the study setting will be Al-Barkat Hospital&#xD;
      Gojra . A total of 30 participants will be selected randomly employing a non-probability&#xD;
      convenient sampling technique. Two experimental groups will be made. Group A will be given&#xD;
      vertical traction in a sitting position and Group B will be given traction in supine lying.&#xD;
      Both groups will receive baseline physiotherapy treatment which includes Hot-pack, TENS, and&#xD;
      ultrasound. The Numeric Pain Rating Scale (NPRS) and Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) will be&#xD;
      used as outcome-measuring tools for pain intensity and functional disability respectively. An&#xD;
      inclinometer will be used to measure ROM. Measures will be taken at (0, 4th, 8th, and 12th&#xD;
      week). Data will be analyzed by using parametric/non-parametric tests after assessing the&#xD;
      normality. SPSS version 28.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CRLBP of the lumbosacral region is a disorder that is closely linked with socioeconomic&#xD;
      consequences. The incidence of lower back pain among workers is approximately 13%. Out of&#xD;
      which, CRLBP is responsible for 11%. In the lumbosacral region, radicular pain has an&#xD;
      occurrence rate of 10 % to 25%. Key interventions by physical therapists involve pain&#xD;
      relieving modalities, stretching, muscle conditioning, lumbar traction, and awareness about&#xD;
      correct postures that lead to useful exercises. As the reason behind the radicular low back&#xD;
      pain is the spinal nerve compression due to the spinal canal impingement, the lumbar traction&#xD;
      lightens the pain through vertebral separation producing decompression on the pressed nerve.&#xD;
      Radicular low back pain shows diverse symptoms, it can be self-limiting, staying only for a&#xD;
      short interval with no aftereffects, or can be a key concern behind long-term disability and&#xD;
      work loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The narrative on the effectiveness of vertical traction as a component of physical therapy&#xD;
      modalities is contradictory. Despite the fact that lumbar traction has been preferred over&#xD;
      other methods for the treatment of lumbar disk disorders, it is usually not advised in the&#xD;
      treatment of acute low back pain because of the efficiency of more active treatment options.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to determine the effects of vertical sitting versus supine lying&#xD;
      traction on pain, range of motion, and function in patients with radicular low back pain.&#xD;
      This study may help physiotherapists to have an estimate of the best possible position for&#xD;
      applying traction in patients with radicular low back pain. The conclusion of this study&#xD;
      might provide therapists with an optimum traction treatment protocol for CRLBP.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 15, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 25, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 10, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oswestry Disability Index</measure>
    <time_frame>follow up at 12th week</time_frame>
    <description>The Oswestry Disability Index (also known as the Oswestry Low Back Pain Disability Questionnaire) is an extremely important tool that researchers and disability evaluators use to measure a patient's permanent functional disability. The test is considered the 'gold standard' of low back functional outcome tools. It has 10 different sections. For each section the total possible score is 5. If all 10 sections are completed the score is calculated and interpreted in percentage measures</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Numeric Pain Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>follow up at 12th week</time_frame>
    <description>The NPRS is a segmented numeric scale in which the respondent selects a whole number (0-10 integers) that best reflects the intensity of his/her pain. The common format is a horizontal bar or line. NPRS is anchored by terms describing pain severity extremes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Low Back Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group-A (Vertical sitting traction)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This session will be followed by the application of the continuous mechanical traction in the vertical sitting position with a belt around the chest. A total of 30 minutes session per day with 5 sessions per week for 12 weeks will be provided to the participants in this group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group-B (supine lying traction)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following the conventional treatment, continuous mechanical traction will be applied in the supine lying position with a traction force equal to 50% of the total body weight. A total of 20 minutes session per day with 5 sessions per week will be provided to the participants in group B.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Traction</intervention_name>
    <description>Continuous mechanical traction will be applied to the lumbar area in 2 different positions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group-A (Vertical sitting traction)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group-B (supine lying traction)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both genders have an age range between 20-50 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronicity of radicular low back pain for at least 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Capable of attending physiotherapy sessions regularly (5 times a week for 12&#xD;
                  weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with indications of spinal cord involvement (For instance; Urine or Fecal&#xD;
             incontinency, Lack of sensation, or Limb paralysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant females will not be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a background of spinal trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting a history of systemic disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>uneeb ur Rehman, MS*</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Riphah International University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ghulam Fatima, PhD*</last_name>
    <phone>03034073057</phone>
    <email>ghulam.fatima@riphah.edu.pk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Imran Amjad, PhD*</last_name>
    <phone>051-5481826</phone>
    <email>imran.amjad@riphah.edu.pk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Al-Barkat Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gojra</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>54700</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ghulam Fatima, PhD*</last_name>
      <phone>03034073057</phone>
      <email>ghulam.fatima@riphah.edu.pk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Balague F, Nordin M, Sheikhzadeh A, Echegoyen AC, Brisby H, Hoogewoud HM, Fredman P, Skovron ML. Recovery of severe sciatica. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1999 Dec 1;24(23):2516-24. doi: 10.1097/00007632-199912010-00014.</citation>
    <PMID>10626315</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beurskens AJ, de Vet HC, Koke AJ, Lindeman E, Regtop W, van der Heijden GJ, Knipschild PG. Efficacy of traction for non-specific low back pain: a randomised clinical trial. Lancet. 1995 Dec 16;346(8990):1596-600. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(95)91930-9.</citation>
    <PMID>7500752</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bilgilisoy Filiz M, Kilic Z, Uckun A, Cakir T, Koldas Dogan S, Toraman NF. Mechanical Traction for Lumbar Radicular Pain: Supine or Prone? A Randomized Controlled Trial. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2018 Jun;97(6):433-439. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000000892.</citation>
    <PMID>29309314</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cai C, Pua YH, Lim KC. A clinical prediction rule for classifying patients with low back pain who demonstrate short-term improvement with mechanical lumbar traction. Eur Spine J. 2009 Apr;18(4):554-61. doi: 10.1007/s00586-009-0909-9. Epub 2009 Mar 3.</citation>
    <PMID>19255792</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carey TS, Freburger JK, Holmes GM, Castel L, Darter J, Agans R, Kalsbeek W, Jackman A. A long way to go: practice patterns and evidence in chronic low back pain care. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2009 Apr 1;34(7):718-24. doi: 10.1097/BRS.0b013e31819792b0.</citation>
    <PMID>19282797</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koldas Dogan S, Sonel Tur B, Kurtais Y, Atay MB. Comparison of three different approaches in the treatment of chronic low back pain. Clin Rheumatol. 2008 Jul;27(7):873-81. doi: 10.1007/s10067-007-0815-7. Epub 2008 Jan 11.</citation>
    <PMID>18188660</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fritz JM, Thackeray A, Childs JD, Brennan GP. A randomized clinical trial of the effectiveness of mechanical traction for sub-groups of patients with low back pain: study methods and rationale. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2010 Apr 30;11:81. doi: 10.1186/1471-2474-11-81.</citation>
    <PMID>20433733</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hahne AJ, Ford JJ, McMeeken JM. Conservative management of lumbar disc herniation with associated radiculopathy: a systematic review. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2010 May 15;35(11):E488-504. doi: 10.1097/BRS.0b013e3181cc3f56.</citation>
    <PMID>20421859</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hansen FR, Bendix T, Skov P, Jensen CV, Kristensen JH, Krohn L, Schioeler H. Intensive, dynamic back-muscle exercises, conventional physiotherapy, or placebo-control treatment of low-back pain. A randomized, observer-blind trial. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1993 Jan;18(1):98-108. doi: 10.1097/00007632-199301000-00015.</citation>
    <PMID>8434332</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 15, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>low back pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Traction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

