<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623332</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>16073</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623332</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of Integrin Expression in Endometriosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study of the Integrin Expression in Endometriosis by Novel in Vivo and in Vitro Assessment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Endometriosis is a common gynaecological disease affecting 10% of the female population due&#xD;
      to the presence of uterus-like tissue outside of the uterus, often in the pelvis. The disease&#xD;
      causes severe lower abdominal pain mostly during the monthly period, during or after sexual&#xD;
      intercourse, and when emptying the bowel and bladder. Currently, imaging methods such as&#xD;
      ultrasound are ineffective at diagnosing the most common type of endometriosis, pelvic&#xD;
      endometriosis. Therefore, we are heavily reliant on invasive surgery to make the diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to investigate the presence of binding proteins (integrins) in endometriotic&#xD;
      tissue which will expand our understanding of endometriosis and could be used as a target to&#xD;
      develop a non-invasive imaging test in the future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women with symptoms consistent with endometriosis, who are due to undergo surgery to diagnose&#xD;
      endometriosis at the EndoCare Unit in Oxford, will be eligible to participate. To attempt to&#xD;
      visualise the integrins, participants will be asked to attend 2-7 days before their surgery&#xD;
      to undergo an imaging scan with a molecular marker that has been found to highlight integrins&#xD;
      in other conditions. The possibility of machine learning enhancement of integrin expression&#xD;
      will be tested. The findings on the scan will be compared to the findings at surgery. Samples&#xD;
      during surgery of endometriosis tissues, the endometrium, and salty water that has been&#xD;
      flushed through the uterus, will be analysed in the lab to look for differences in the amount&#xD;
      of integrin present in women with and without endometriosis and whether factors such as the&#xD;
      phase of the menstrual cycle or hormonal treatment effect the amount seen.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is an open-label, exploratory research in the hospital setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During recruitment, women will be asked if they would like to complete a 3-5 min anonymous&#xD;
      survey investigating their experiences and preferences of diagnostic methods and the effect&#xD;
      the diagnostic delay of endometriosis has on fertility choices. Women will not be required to&#xD;
      complete this to participate in the study. Women who do not wish to participate in the study&#xD;
      will still be welcome to complete the questionnaire. They will be asked to complete a second&#xD;
      survey revisiting the same questions after the study if their diagnosis has been confirmed.&#xD;
      It will be clearly stated that by completing the survey consent is implied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once a date for the surgery is confirmed they will be booked to have their imaging scan 2-7&#xD;
      days before in the radiology department in Bath (Royal United Hospital) or Oxford (Churchill&#xD;
      Hospital). On the day of the scan, they will be asked to complete a questionnaire that will&#xD;
      provide us with information on their menstrual history, medical history, hormonal influences,&#xD;
      and other factors that may influence the results of the scan. They will have IV maraciclatide&#xD;
      (imaging marker) administered followed by a SPECT-CT scan(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As this is the first time AVB3 integrins in endometiosis lesions have been investigated using&#xD;
      this scan, the optimum timing of the scan is unknown and additional scans (maximum 6) for the&#xD;
      first cohort of participants will help determine the optimum timing (participants will be&#xD;
      reimbursement accordingly). After the scan(s) they will be free to go home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to complete an 'End of Study' anonymous survey after the scan&#xD;
      before they leave, this will evaluate their experiences of undergoing a SPECT-CT to diagnose&#xD;
      endometriosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the imaging, participants will be divided into two cohorts. Cohort 1 describes the&#xD;
      initial research participants who assist with identifying the optimum imaging time interval&#xD;
      following IV 99mTc-maraciclatide. Participants will undergo 1-6 imaging scans at 30 minutes,&#xD;
      90 minutes, 3-4 hours, 6 hours, or 18-24 hours post-administration. The timepoints the&#xD;
      participants are allocated to will be a joint decision between the participants and research&#xD;
      team depending on the availability of the participants, scanning slots and required&#xD;
      timepoints. For participants in Cohort 1, the first scan will include a localization CT as&#xD;
      part of SPECT-CT. Additional scans will include ultra-low dose CT. Depending on findings the&#xD;
      scanning time will be refined to provide the optimal timing for visualizing lesions&#xD;
      expressing αvβ3. The total protocol dose is 14 mSv for Cohort 1. This is equivalent to nearly&#xD;
      6 years of average natural background radiation in the UK. Once 4 participants with&#xD;
      surgically confirmed endometriosis have completed each time point, the study will progress to&#xD;
      cohort 2 using the optimum scanning. Cohort 2 describes the subsequent scans once the optimum&#xD;
      scanning time interval has been established. One localization CT as part of SPECT will be&#xD;
      conducted. The total protocol dose will be 9 mSv for these participants, which is equivalent&#xD;
      to nearly 4 years of average natural background radiation in the UK. 2-7 days after&#xD;
      participants will have their surgery as planned and if they consent they will also have&#xD;
      samples taken for analysis of AVB3 expression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples will be taken of the ectopic lesions, endometrium, and an endometrial flush (salty&#xD;
      water flushed through the uterus). Findings on the SPECT-CT scan will be compared to&#xD;
      laparoscopic findings to assess whether Maraciclatide can accurately detect alpha-V-beta-3&#xD;
      integrins in endometriotic lesions. Participants will have the opportunity to consent to&#xD;
      their SPECT-CT images and routine ultrasound images being sent to the Oxford Applied and&#xD;
      Theoretical Machine Learning Group. This will allow for the group to investigate whether&#xD;
      development of machine learning algorithms can enhance the ability of alpha-V-beta-3&#xD;
      expression detection and other endometriosis markers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to compare integrin expression in women with and without endometriosis, a control&#xD;
      group of 25 women will be recruited to provide endometrial tissue samples and an endometrial&#xD;
      flush sample during their planned operation. Women will be eligible to participate if they&#xD;
      are undergoing surgery for any condition other than endometriosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The correlation between locations of maraciclatide uptake identified on SPECT-CT.(described qualitatively by a radiologist) and the locations of endometriotic lesions detected during laparoscopy (described qualitatively by a surgeon)</measure>
    <time_frame>Single comparison, maraciclatide scan to precede laparoscopy (which will occur 2-7days later)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether alpha-v-beta-3 lesions integrins can be detected in endometriotic lesions using Maraciclatide and SPECT-CT imaging.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The single best timepoint described by two radiologists following the evaluation of SPECT-CT scans at multiple time points after injection of maraciclatide.</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will undergo 1- 6 imaging scans at 30minutes, 90 minutes, 3-4 hours, 6 hours, or 18-24 hours post administration</time_frame>
    <description>To identify the optimum imaging time interval and method following administration of intravenous maraciclatide.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The single preference of two radiologists when assessing SPECT-CT images before and after machine learning-enhancement.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether machine learning enhanced the ability to detect alpha-V-beta-3 integrin expression and whether this should be developed in later phase studies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The single preference of two radiologists when assessing SPECT-CT images with and without machine learning enhancement using ultrasound scans.</measure>
    <time_frame>All SPECT-CT images throughout study completion (average of 2 years) and any routine ultrasound images within 3 months of the scan.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether machine learning enhanced the ability to detect alpha-V-beta-3 integrin expression and whether this should be developed in later phase studies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The difference in alpha-V beta-3 integrin expression (using immunofluorescence) in endometrial biopsies from women with and without endometriosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the angiogenic propensity of endometrial tissue in women with endometriosis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The difference in alpha-V beta-3 integrin expression (using ELISA) in endometrial flushes from women with and without endometriosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the angiogenic propensity of endometrial tissue in women with endometriosis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The expression of alpha-V beta-3 integrin (using immunofluorescence) in the ectopic endometrial tissue samples.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether the phase of the cycle, hormonal influence or lesion activity affects the level of expression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The most frequently reported highest and lowest preference for diagnostic technique presented as a percentage.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>A national survey released via patient advocacy organisations and to those participating in the imaging study to explore the experiences and preferences of diagnostic methods in individuals undergoing investigation for endometriosis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>VAS satisfaction and acceptability rating (0 lowest - 100 highest) of participants who have undergone a SPECT-CT to detect alpha-v-beta-3 lesions in endometriotic tissue.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine whether SPECT-CT is received positively or negatively by participants undergoing investigation for endometriosis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of respondents who have experienced a diagnostic delay and the number of those who think this delay has affected their life decisions.</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time through the study completion, an average of 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine whether a delay in diagnosing endometriosis influences life decisions such as family planning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometriosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Maraciclatide imaging group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women referred to the endometriosis clinic for suspected endometriosis undergoing a maraciclatide imaging scan</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Control group (samples but no scan) - Women undergoing surgery for any other condition than endometriosis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Maraciclatide</intervention_name>
    <description>Imaging marker that binds to AVB3/5 lesions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Maraciclatide imaging group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Ectopic endometriosis lesions samples, endometrial samples, and endometrial flush&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women suspected of endometriosis due to have a diagnostic/therapeutic laparoscopy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female aged 18 years or above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms consistent with endometriosis and therefore due to undergo a laparoscopy for&#xD;
             diagnostic (+/- therapeutic) purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to comply with scheduled visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the Investigator's opinion, is able and willing to comply with all study&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women enrolling for the tissue sample comparison group: Women undergoing planned&#xD;
             surgery (including hysterectomy) for gynaecological disease except endometriosis e.g.,&#xD;
             fibroid-associated symptoms such as abdominal pain, abnormal uterine bleeding,&#xD;
             fertility investigation or for laparoscopic tubal sterilisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant who is pregnant, lactating or planning pregnancy during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known significant renal or hepatic impairment (E.g., eGFR &lt;50ml/min/1.73m2 on recent&#xD;
             blood tests).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any significant disease or disorder such as gynaecological cancers, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Investigator, may either put the participants at risk because of participation in&#xD;
             the study or may influence the result of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High dose intravenous or intramuscular steroid in the past 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a known allergy to technetium.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have recently participated in another research study, in the opinion&#xD;
             of the investigator will affect the results of the project.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Born female</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Radcliffe Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <state>Oxon</state>
        <zip>OX3 9DU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>non-invasive diagnosis</keyword>
  <keyword>SPECT-CT</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometriosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

