<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612685</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>22-001575</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612685</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Healthcare Providers as Trusted Messengers to Increase Receipt of Tax Credits Among Low-income Families</brief_title>
  <official_title>Healthcare Providers as Trusted Messengers to Increase Receipt of Tax Credits Among Low-income Families</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Los Angeles</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to pilot test the feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy of healthcare provider referrals to a tax filing app within parent-child health&#xD;
      programs to test whether such referrals can increase receipt of tax credits among low-income&#xD;
      parents. The study will use a single-group, pre/post test design with a sample of&#xD;
      approximately 100 women who have a child under 6 years of age. Participants will be recruited&#xD;
      from parental-child health programs and clinics in Los Angeles and will complete surveys at&#xD;
      baseline, immediately after tax filing season, and six months after tax filing season to&#xD;
      assess 1) frequency of tax filing after referral (Feasibility), 2) the acceptability of the&#xD;
      tax filing app from the perspective of users (Acceptability), and 3) pre/posttest changes to&#xD;
      parent and child health, child development, and healthcare utilization measures for users&#xD;
      (preliminary efficacy).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aims: The purpose of this study is to pilot test the feasibility, acceptability, and&#xD;
      preliminary efficacy of healthcare provider referrals to a tax filing app within&#xD;
      parental-child health programs whether such referrals can increase receipt of tax credits&#xD;
      among low-income parents. The study will use a single-group, pre/posttest design. The primary&#xD;
      outcome is feasibility, defined as whether or not participants filed taxes after referral.&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes are acceptability of the app and preliminary efficacy of the app on&#xD;
      improved parent and child health. Specific aims are to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. assess frequency of tax filing among parents referred to a tax filing app (Primary&#xD;
           outcome/Feasibility)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. examine the acceptability of a tax filing app from the perspective of users (Secondary&#xD;
           outcome/Acceptability), and&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. explore pre/posttest changes to parent and child health, child development, and&#xD;
           healthcare utilization measures for users the app after referral (Secondary&#xD;
           outcome/Preliminary efficacy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: This pilot study will use a single-group, pre/post-test design to assess the&#xD;
      feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary efficacy of healthcare provider referrals to a&#xD;
      tax filing app.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: Referrals to a tax filing app&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting: The setting for this study is maternal/child health programs and clinics in Los&#xD;
      Angeles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample: The target population is parents making less than $75,000 per year in income .&#xD;
      Parents will be eligible to participate in the study if they are within the income threshold,&#xD;
      have one or more children under six years of age, speak English or Spanish, have access to an&#xD;
      internet-enabled device (smart phone or tablet), and have a valid tax filing ID (SSN or&#xD;
      ITIN). Parents will be ineligible if they have already filed taxes during the study period or&#xD;
      are experiencing an acute mental health crisis (e.g., suicidality). We focus on children&#xD;
      under six years of age because this is a critical and sensitive developmental window when&#xD;
      interventions have potential for outsized impact on child health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures: Parents will be recruited during program visits/encounters early in tax season in&#xD;
      2023. Those that provide informed consent to participate in the study will complete a&#xD;
      baseline survey and receive the assigned intervention (referral to a tax filing app) the same&#xD;
      day or within the same week of their program visit. Parents will complete a follow-up survey&#xD;
      to assess outcome measures after they receive tax refunds. A second follow-up survey will be&#xD;
      sent 3-6 months later (depending on time of filing, and average time of receipt of tax credit&#xD;
      this season) to assess medium-term outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes. We will assess the following outcomes. The primary study outcome is feasibility;&#xD;
      acceptability and preliminary health efficacy are secondary outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Feasibility: Self-reported tax filing (items developed for this study) Acceptability: Health&#xD;
      app acceptability measure (Chen et al., 2022) Preliminary efficacy: We will assess&#xD;
      pre/posttest changes in the following health-related measures as indicators of preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy: 1a) parent health (PROMIS® Scale v1.2 - Global Health [Hays et al., 2009]; Patient&#xD;
      Health Questionnaire- 2 [Kroenke et al., 2003); Perceived Stress Scale [Cohen et al., 1994];&#xD;
      PROMIS®-29 Profile v2.1 [Hays et al., 2018]) and 1b) child health (PROMIS® Early Childhood&#xD;
      Parent Report Global Health [Forrest et al., 2014]); 2) child development (PEDS-DM [Pritchard&#xD;
      et al., 2012]); and 3) and 4) healthcare utilization (adapted from survey items by Patrick et&#xD;
      al,. 2020 for this study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographic and family health background information (see survey: age, gender,&#xD;
      race/ethnicity, income, social determinants of health, health background, other tax filing&#xD;
      characteristics) will be collected to identify characteristics of the sample. In future&#xD;
      studies, we intend to study in greater depth the physical health outcomes that might be&#xD;
      sensitive to this intervention with longer-term follow up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of tax filing at 3 months: Did you file taxes this year? YES/NO</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported tax filing status for the current year</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of tax filing at 9 months: Did you file taxes this year? YES/NO</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported tax filing status for the current year</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent depression at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Health Questionnaire- 2 (score range 0-6, higher scores indicate worse depression symptoms)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent depression at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Health Questionnaire- 2 (score range 0-6, higher scores indicate worse depression symptoms)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent depression at 9 months</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Health Questionnaire- 2 (score range 0-6, higher scores indicate worse depression symptoms)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Child socioemotional development at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>PEDS:DM (Parents' Evaluation of Developmental Status - Developmental Milestones): More 'yes' responses indicate more developmental milestones met</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Child socioemotional development at 9 months</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>PEDS:DM (Parents' Evaluation of Developmental Status - Developmental Milestones): More 'yes' responses indicate more developmental milestones met</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Child Development</condition>
  <condition>Stress</condition>
  <condition>Physical Illness</condition>
  <condition>Health Care Utilization</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive a healthcare provider referral to a tax filing app</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Healthcare provider referral to a tax filing app</intervention_name>
    <description>Healthcare providers offer a referral to a tax filing app and briefly describe the potential benefits of tax credit receipt</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Income &lt;$75,000 per year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One or more children under 6 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a valid tax filing ID (SSN or ITIN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has access to an internet-enabled device&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experiencing an acute mental health crisis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kristen R. Choi, PhD, RN, FAAN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

