<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05791279</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Kronoberg_HA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05791279</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Electrocardiography-based Estimation of Heart Age to Improve Blood Pressure - a Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Use of Electrocardiography-based Estimation of Heart Age to Improve Blood Pressure in a Primary Care Setting - a Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kronoberg County Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lund University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Sydney</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kronoberg County Council</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Successfully communicating cardiovascular risk to patients is essential for achieving&#xD;
      compliance to medication and lifestyle changes. An intuitive way to translate cardiovascular&#xD;
      risk is to present a Heart Age; an ECG-based age-estimation from ECG changes which can be&#xD;
      contrasted to a patient's chronological age. In this pilot study, the feasibility of a&#xD;
      randomized controlled study (RCT) in which hypertensive patients in primary care will receive&#xD;
      information about their ECG-based Heart Age in addition to standard care, or standard care&#xD;
      alone, will be assessed, in preparation for a larger RCT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease processes begin early and progress silently for many years.&#xD;
      Fortunately, several risk-factors are modifiable, and cardiovascular risk can therefore be&#xD;
      reduced for example by smoking cessation, dietary changes, increased physical activity in&#xD;
      sedentary people and adherence to pharmacological risk factor reduction. To accomplish this,&#xD;
      the patient must understand that he or she is at risk. One way to do this could be to present&#xD;
      the risk as a &quot;Heart Age&quot;, which can be contrasted to the patient's chronological age. In a&#xD;
      previous study, an accurate Heart Age could be obtained using conventional, 10-second ECG&#xD;
      recordings. The ECG analysis included conventional and basic ECG measurements such as heart&#xD;
      rate and waveform amplitudes and durations, but also combinations of advanced ECG measures&#xD;
      from 12-lead-ECG-derived vectorcardiography and waveform complexity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, it is not known whether the use of Heart Age can improve outcomes if applied in&#xD;
      clinical care. To address this issue, a study in which patients, in addition to standard&#xD;
      care, are randomized to either being presented with their Heart Age or not should be&#xD;
      performed. In order to check the feasibility of such a randomized controlled study (RCT), a&#xD;
      pilot study is necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will evaluate the feasibility of randomizing patients with hypertension to either&#xD;
      being presented with their Heart Age or not, in addition to standard care, by describing the&#xD;
      recruitment dropout rate, the quality of the recorded ECG and the tolerability of the&#xD;
      intervention (participant experience).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the baseline visit a standardized resting blood pressure, height, weight and waist&#xD;
      circumference will be measured. Baseline characteristics (age, sex, hypercholesterolemia,&#xD;
      diabetes, ischemic heart disease, cerebrovascular disease, renal failure, heart failure,&#xD;
      medications) will be recorded from the patient records. Unless a recent (&lt;1 month) ECG is&#xD;
      available, a new resting ECG recording will be performed, and blood sampling will be done&#xD;
      (total cholesterol, high-density lipoprotein [HDL], low-density lipoprotein [LDL] mmol/l,&#xD;
      triglyceride mmol/mol, Hba1c (IFCC) mmol/mL, P-Creatinine (µmol/L). The participant will also&#xD;
      receive a questionnaire for background information and information about tobacco and alcohol&#xD;
      use, level of physical activity, dietary habits, medication adherence, quality of life and&#xD;
      self-estimated health including estimating one's own risk of cardiovascular morbidity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ECG-based Heart Age will be estimated for all participants but presented only to patients in&#xD;
      the intervention arm. A follow-up visit will be performed 6 months after the baseline visit.&#xD;
      At follow-up, the same measurements including the same questionnaires will be obtained.&#xD;
      Participants in the intervention arm will also receive a questionnaire on their experience of&#xD;
      receiving information about their Heart Age (tolerability).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recruitment rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients being recruited within the specified time frame</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dropout rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who do not complete follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Heart Age estimations with adequate ECG signal quality</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of the intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Tolerability of the intervention assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in HbA1c</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in physical activity assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dietary habits</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in dietary habits assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tobacco</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in tobacco use assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in alcohol use assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in medication adherence assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk perception</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in risk perception assessed through questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body-mass index (BMI)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in BMI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart Age</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Heart Age</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants in the intervention group will receive information about their ECG-based Heart-Age and the Heart Age. The estimated Heart Age and Heart Age Gap will be presented in writing to the participants in the experimental arm within 2 weeks after the baseline visit. The presentation will include a brief and easy-to-understand description on how the Heart Age has been estimated. In addition, patients will receive information about general advice on how to improve blood pressure levels and reduce the risk of future cardiovascular disease by adopting a healthy lifestyle and adhering to the prescribed medication. This information will be the same for participants in the two study arms, and is based on recommendations from the European Society of Cardiology.&#xD;
For patients in the intervention group the ordinary primary care physicians will also be informed about the ECG-based Heart-Age.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will receive standard care according to routine care at the individual primary health care center, and receive the same general advice, on how to improve blood pressure levels and/or to reduce risks of future cardiovascular disease, as the participants in the intervention group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Heart age</intervention_name>
    <description>information about their ECG-based Heart-Age and the Heart Age gap, i.e. the difference between chronological and ECG-based Heart Age.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Eligibility: Patients with hypertension and systolic blood pressure &gt;140 mm Hg (measured&#xD;
        during the inclusion period by doctor or nurse at the primary health care center)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed hypertension (International classification of disease (ICD-10), I10.9)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  40 - 75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECG findings that are incompatible with or may significantly distort the Heart Age&#xD;
             estimation (left/right bundle branch block, atrial fibrillation/flutter, tachycardia&#xD;
             (≥100/min), abundant ventricular ectopic beats, misplaced ECG electrodes, missing&#xD;
             leads, excessive signal noise/baseline)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Short life expectancy (&lt;1 year)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, known secondary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Predicted inability to give informed consent due to either language difficulties,&#xD;
             cognitive impairment or other.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure &lt;120 mmHg at the baseline visit&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Lindow, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Region Kronoberg, Sweden; Lund University, Lund, Sweden</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thomas Lindow, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46470588000</phone>
    <email>thomas.akesson_lindow@med.lu.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Karin Svensson Söderberg, MD</last_name>
    <email>karin.svensson-soderberg@kronoberg.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lindow T, Palencia-Lamela I, Schlegel TT, Ugander M. Heart age estimated using explainable advanced electrocardiography. Sci Rep. 2022 Jun 14;12(1):9840. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-13912-9.</citation>
    <PMID>35701514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 17, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 17, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 17, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

