<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612321</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VaDe-4/2022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612321</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vacuum Delivery in All-fours Position vs Traditional Position</brief_title>
  <acronym>VaDe-4</acronym>
  <official_title>All-fours Position vs Traditional Position in Women Undergoing Vacuum-assisted Delivery: the VaDe-4 Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ospedale degli Infermi di Biella</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ospedale degli Infermi di Biella</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to investigate the safety, clinical efficacy and the&#xD;
      maternal/neonatal outcomes of vacuum application in all-fours position compared with supine&#xD;
      traditional position, in women undergoing vacuum-assisted delivery during the second stage of&#xD;
      labor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main question it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Does the rate of failure of vacuum delivery, measured as number of cup detachments and&#xD;
           the need of emergency caesarean section is lower if vacuum delivery is performed on a&#xD;
           woman in all-fours position?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Do maternal and fetal outcomes are better in case vacuum delivery in all-fours position?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly enrolled at the admission in two different groups, Control and&#xD;
      Experimental Group, and in case of need for vacuum-assisted vaginal delivery; women belonging&#xD;
      to Control Group will undergo vacuum-assisted delivery in traditional supine position, while&#xD;
      women in Experimental Group will experience vacuum application in all-fours position.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers will compare the Group A, composed by women who undergo vacuum-delivery in&#xD;
      traditional supine position, with Group B, in which women are in &quot;all-fours&quot; position, to see&#xD;
      if hands-and-knees position provides better outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the last decades, a decrease in operative vaginal delivery (OVD) rates occurred, resulting&#xD;
      in increase of caesarean sections (CS) during the second stage of labor. This attitude&#xD;
      reflects Clinicians' worries about operative vaginal delivery morbidity, together with a&#xD;
      consequent loss of clinical skills in this practice. However, vacuum delivery - when&#xD;
      correctly performed - requires less analgesia and gives women higher chances to have a&#xD;
      spontaneous vaginal birth in the following pregnancy, whereas emergency C-section is burdened&#xD;
      by different maternal and fetal complications. Moreover, should fetal compromise be&#xD;
      occurring, time to start the procedure is longer for CS than for vacuum application. Due to&#xD;
      the whole of these reasons, operative vaginal delivery is included in the main international&#xD;
      guidelines as the best option for the mother and baby, in case of arrest/delay of fetal head&#xD;
      descent during second stage of labor, with fetal head at mid/low-pelvic station.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although women in labor are usually asked to choose the position they prefer and to change&#xD;
      position frequently to facilitate the alignment of the fetal head with the birth canal, the&#xD;
      vacuum cup is usually applied to a woman lying in the &quot;traditional&quot; gynecological supine&#xD;
      position.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite several demonstrated advantages, fewer women choose non-recumbent positions, and&#xD;
      among them, the so-called &quot;all-fours position&quot; (or &quot;hands-and-knees&quot;) which has the higher&#xD;
      evidence of benefit. In all-fours, the woman is on her knees, leaning on her hands, with&#xD;
      abdomen suspended and hips at right angles to the floor or bed. As demonstrated in different&#xD;
      studies, the main advantage given by this posture is the increase of all posterior diameters&#xD;
      of the pelvis. This finding implies not only an easier descent of the fetal head, helped by&#xD;
      gravity, but also a wider space where fetal head could rotate in case of occiput posterior&#xD;
      position, preventing fetal malposition. Additionally, this position lets the sacrum to have&#xD;
      more posterior mobility (contra-nutation movement) furtherly widening the outlet no more&#xD;
      constricted by the standing surface and reducing sacral pain due to bed-contact. Moreover, as&#xD;
      the burden of trunk's weight on the sacrum is decreased in all-fours, women consider the&#xD;
      hands-and-knees position a pain-relieving postural choice, especially during the first stage&#xD;
      of labor. Regarding maternal outcomes, a recent large randomized controlled trial, involving&#xD;
      1400 women, demonstrated a lower incidence of second-degree perineal lacerations, episiotomy&#xD;
      and perineal swelling in hands-and-knees position, and a lower risk of emergency CS, compared&#xD;
      to other birth positions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the all-fours position, the vaginal space between the fetal head and the vaginal ostium is&#xD;
      not influenced by body weight, resulting wider, visible, and easily explorable. Moreover, the&#xD;
      risk of vacuum cup sliding is lower because the upward traction is allotted a wider space.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The widening of birth canal obtained with this technique has several, beneficial&#xD;
      implications. First, the risk of vaginal tear is lower, since there is no redundant vaginal&#xD;
      tissue that could be trapped inside the cup. Second, a wider space allows to constantly&#xD;
      maintain the vacuum wire perpendicular to the cup, thus determining a lower risk of&#xD;
      detachment, subsequent fetal scalp damage and cephalohematoma (e.g., in presence of caput&#xD;
      succedaneum).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, this position allows a better propulsive pushing, thanks to a more efficient Valsalva&#xD;
      maneuver, thus enabling the Clinician not to exert excessive traction on the fetal head.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since OVD has a known increased risk of shoulder dystocia, adopting the all-fours position&#xD;
      should be beneficial in preventing this fearsome complication, consistent with the point that&#xD;
      the hands-and-knees posture is required to perform the Gaskin maneuver, a rescue procedure&#xD;
      that easily releases the trapped shoulder by taking advantage of the greater posterior pelvic&#xD;
      space in this position.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A potential disadvantage might be the inability of the woman to keep this position for longer&#xD;
      than 10-15 minutes. Although OVD duration is routinely much shorter, it is of course&#xD;
      mandatory that the timing of OVD performance be carefully monitored.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators recently suggested the implementation of all-fours position in case of&#xD;
      operative vaginal delivery and we published a video-simulation of vacuum application on a&#xD;
      mannequin. At this time, no other prospective study so far assessed a putative effectiveness&#xD;
      of an alternative positioning strategy during OVD for women with arrest of fetal head&#xD;
      progression during the second stage of labor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Multicentre, prospective, randomized open trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vacuum detachments</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Vacuum detachments (Yes/No)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Emergency C-Section</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Emergency C-section (Yes/No)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perineal tears</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Perineal tears (1st-3rd grade) (Yes/No and Grade: 1st/2nd/3rd grade)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Obstetric anal sphincter injuries (OASIS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Obstetric anal sphincter injuries (OASIS, 4th grade) (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Episiotomy</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Episiotomy (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood loss</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Maternal blood loss (ml)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum haemorrhage</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Postpartum haemorrhage defined as a blood loss of &gt;1000milliliters (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Necessity of Blood Transfusions</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3</time_frame>
    <description>Blood Transfusions (Yes/no and n. bagged blood infused)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal infections</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3</time_frame>
    <description>Maternal infections (endometritis, sepsis, hyperpyrexia) (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of Hospital Stay</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Length of Hospital Stay (n. of days of hospitalization)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Short-form patient satisfaction questionnaire (PSQ-18) (18 and 90 are the minimum and maximum values, and higher scores mean a higher patient satisfaction).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>APGAR score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>APGAR score at 1 and 5 minutes (0-10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal acidosis</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>pH &lt; 7.10 at birth (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal hypoglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Neonatal Serum Glucose &lt; 45 mg/dL (&lt; 2.5 mmol/L) (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal cephalohematoma</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Neonatal cephalohematoma (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal scalp damages</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Neonatal scalp damages (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Shoulder Dystocia</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Shoulder Dystocia (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Admission to Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Admission to Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU) (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for Oxygen Supplementation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Neonatal need for supplementary oxygen (yes/no) and days of use (days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Prolonged Second Stage of Labor</condition>
  <condition>Prolonged Second Stage of Labor Due to Poor Maternal Effort</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional supine position</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants enrolled in the Control Group undergo vacuum-assisted delivery in traditional supine position (supine with 90 degrees bended legs on footrests)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All-fours position</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants enrolled in Experimental Group experience vacuum application in all-fours position.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vacuum application</intervention_name>
    <description>vacuum-assisted delivery</description>
    <arm_group_label>All-fours position</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional supine position</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  singleton&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cephalic presentation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  term pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  second stage of labor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  failure to progress&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  maternal weariness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  need for operative vaginal delivery by vacuum extraction&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  enrollment refusal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  absence of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication to operative vaginal delivery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>This study requires the enrollement of only female participants as it refers to delivery.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bianca Masturzo, Md, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ospedale degli Infermi di Biella</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bianca Masturzo, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 01515157001</phone>
    <email>bianca.masturzo@aslbi.piemonte.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Chiara Germano, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 01515157002</phone>
    <email>chiara.germano@aslbi.piemonte.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Merriam AA, Ananth CV, Wright JD, Siddiq Z, D'Alton ME, Friedman AM. Trends in operative vaginal delivery, 2005-2013: a population-based study. BJOG. 2017 Aug;124(9):1365-1372. doi: 10.1111/1471-0528.14553. Epub 2017 Feb 25.</citation>
    <PMID>28236337</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Spencer C, Murphy D, Bewley S. Caesarean delivery in the second stage of labour. BMJ. 2006 Sep 23;333(7569):613-4. doi: 10.1136/bmj.38971.466979.DE. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>16990297</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Guo C, Ma W, Fan D, Ma Y, Liu L. Non spontaneous vaginal delivery was associated with lower probability of subsequent fertility. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2020 May;248:30-36. doi: 10.1016/j.ejogrb.2020.03.009. Epub 2020 Mar 7.</citation>
    <PMID>32172023</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Operative Vaginal Birth: ACOG Practice Bulletin, Number 219. Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Apr;135(4):e149-e159. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000003764.</citation>
    <PMID>32217976</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>RANZCOG. The Women's Health Committee. The Royal Australian and New Zealand College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists. Instrumental vaginal birth; March 2016.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hobson S, Cassell K, Windrim R, Cargill Y. No. 381-Assisted Vaginal Birth. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2019 Jun;41(6):870-882. doi: 10.1016/j.jogc.2018.10.020.</citation>
    <PMID>31126436</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Murphy DJ, Strachan BK, Bahl R; Royal College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists. Assisted Vaginal Birth: Green-top Guideline No. 26. BJOG. 2020 Aug;127(9):e70-e112. doi: 10.1111/1471-0528.16092. Epub 2020 Apr 28. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>32346983</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Stremler R, Hodnett E, Petryshen P, Stevens B, Weston J, Willan AR. Randomized controlled trial of hands-and-knees positioning for occipitoposterior position in labor. Birth. 2005 Dec;32(4):243-51. doi: 10.1111/j.0730-7659.2005.00382.x.</citation>
    <PMID>16336365</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Siccardi M, Valle C, Di Matteo F. Dynamic External Pelvimetry Test in Third Trimester Pregnant Women: Shifting Positions Affect Pelvic Biomechanics and Create More Room in Obstetric Diameters. Cureus. 2021 Mar 1;13(3):e13631. doi: 10.7759/cureus.13631.</citation>
    <PMID>33816030</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Michel SC, Rake A, Treiber K, Seifert B, Chaoui R, Huch R, Marincek B, Kubik-Huch RA. MR obstetric pelvimetry: effect of birthing position on pelvic bony dimensions. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2002 Oct;179(4):1063-7. doi: 10.2214/ajr.179.4.1791063.</citation>
    <PMID>12239066</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hemmerich A, Bandrowska T, Dumas GA. The effects of squatting while pregnant on pelvic dimensions: A computational simulation to understand childbirth. J Biomech. 2019 Apr 18;87:64-74. doi: 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2019.02.017. Epub 2019 Feb 27.</citation>
    <PMID>30851977</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhang H, Huang S, Guo X, Zhao N, Lu Y, Chen M, Li Y, Wu J, Huang L, Ma F, Yang Y, Zhang X, Zhou X, Guo R, Cai W. A randomised controlled trial in comparing maternal and neonatal outcomes between hands-and-knees delivery position and supine position in China. Midwifery. 2017 Jul;50:117-124. doi: 10.1016/j.midw.2017.03.022. Epub 2017 Mar 31.</citation>
    <PMID>28414983</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bothou A, Apostolidi DM, Tsikouras P, Iatrakis G, Sarella A, Iatrakis D, Peitsidis P, Gerente A, Anthoulaki X, Nikolettos N, Zervoudis S. Overview of techniques to manage shoulder dystocia during vaginal birth. Eur J Midwifery. 2021 Oct 20;5:48. doi: 10.18332/ejm/142097. eCollection 2021.</citation>
    <PMID>34723155</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Masturzo B, Delogu G, Germano C, Ghi T, Rizzo G, Puppo A, Attini R, Revelli A, Manzoni P. Vacuum delivery in all-fours position: is it a valuable, brand-new option? Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2022 Jul 16:100691. doi: 10.1016/j.ajogmf.2022.100691. Online ahead of print.</citation>
    <PMID>35843544</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ospedale degli Infermi di Biella</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bianca Masturzo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Department of Gynaecology and Obstetrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Vacuum-assisted vaginal delivery</keyword>
  <keyword>All-fours position</keyword>
  <keyword>Arrest of descent</keyword>
  <keyword>Operative vaginal delivery</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All collected IPD</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>At the end of the study, for 6 months from the 1st Jan 2024 to 1st July 2024</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Participants centers</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

