<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05627778</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PUMCH-NM-11/041</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05627778</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>68Ga-P15-041 and 68Ga-PSMA-11 PET/CT Imaging in the Same Group of Prostate Bone Metastasis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Head-to-head Comparison of 68Ga-P15-041 and 68Ga-PSMA-11 PET/CT Imaging in the Same Group of Prostate Bone Metastasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Tumor bone metastasis refers to the metastasis of malignant tumors to the bone through lymph,&#xD;
      blood or direct invasion to generate daughter tumors, which is the most common bone tumor.&#xD;
      More than 40% of patients with malignant tumors will have bone metastasis, among which breast&#xD;
      cancer, prostate cancer is more common, once the tumor cells occur bone metastasis, it means&#xD;
      that the disease enters the advanced stage, posing a serious threat to the life safety of&#xD;
      patients, therefore, early diagnosis of various primary malignant tumor bone metastases, can&#xD;
      lay the foundation for clinical implementation of effective treatment measures. The&#xD;
      laboratory of Hank F. Kung at the University of Pennsylvania has developed a new generation&#xD;
      of 68Ga-labeled radiopharmaceutical P15-041 ([68Ga]Ga-HBED-CC-BP) based on existing&#xD;
      phosphonate-targeting molecular probes (Figure 1). Data from preclinical studies indicate&#xD;
      that P15-041 shows additional advantages in rapid and easy complex formation compared to&#xD;
      current [68Ga]Ga-BPAMD, [68Ga]Ga-NO2AP-BP, [68Ga]Ga-DOTA- (ZOL). In vivo experiments, P15-041&#xD;
      showed good bone resorption and rapid renal excretion in normal mice. Haiyan Hong et al. [13]&#xD;
      prepared multiple clinical doses of P15-041 and successfully evaluated it in patients,&#xD;
      followed by intravenous P15-041, followed by a whole body PET/CT scan. Robert K. Doot et al.&#xD;
      conducted dosimetric experiments on P15-041, analyzed the radioactive distribution of the&#xD;
      drug in normal organs and the dynamic change of the dose of the drug in the body over time,&#xD;
      and the results showed that P15-041 had high uptake in the bladder wall and bone cortex,&#xD;
      blood and other tissues cleared quickly, and there was obvious radioactive enrichment in the&#xD;
      myocardium in the early stage of imaging, and P15-041 had the potential to become a new&#xD;
      generation of excellent phosphonate molecular probes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tumor bone metastasis (Tumor Bone Metastasis) refers to the metastasis of malignant tumor to&#xD;
      the bone through lymphatic, blood or direct infiltration, resulting in sub-tumor, which is&#xD;
      the most common bone tumor. More than 40% of patients with malignant tumors will develop bone&#xD;
      metastasis, among which breast cancer and prostate cancer are more common. Once bone&#xD;
      metastasis occurs in tumor cells, it means that the disease has entered an advanced stage and&#xD;
      poses a serious threat to the life safety of patients. Therefore, early diagnosis Bone&#xD;
      metastases from various primary malignant tumors can lay the foundation for the clinical&#xD;
      implementation of effective treatment measures. At present, single photon emission&#xD;
      computer-aided tomography (SPECT) technetium-99 (99mTc)-methylenediphos-phonate (MDP) is the&#xD;
      preferred method for early diagnosis of tumor bone metastases , but benign bone Disease (such&#xD;
      as bone degeneration, trauma, inflammatory response) and reactive changes during treatment&#xD;
      ((scintillation phenomenon) can also be manifested as abnormal radioactive concentrations,&#xD;
      with the possibility of false positives . Positron emission tomography Imaging (PET)&#xD;
      technology is a nuclear medicine imaging method that integrates anatomical images of diseases&#xD;
      and functional metabolism. It combines radioisotopes with compounds to achieve the function&#xD;
      of imaging the metabolism of targeted substances. Compared with other imaging methods, PET&#xD;
      molecular probes have higher sensitivity. Clinically, [18F]F-FDG PET/CT is commonly used to&#xD;
      observe the metabolic status of bone metastases, which can show bone metastases that have not&#xD;
      yet undergone osteogenesis or osteolysis. Vine-labeled phosphonates are bone imaging agents&#xD;
      commonly used clinically to evaluate bone diseases such as infection (osteomyelitis),&#xD;
      noninfectious inflammation (arthritis), trauma, metabolic bone disease, benign and malignant&#xD;
      tumors, and metastases. ), the imaging agent reaches the bones of the whole body with the&#xD;
      blood flow through intravenous injection, and is distributed in the bone tissue through ion&#xD;
      exchange and chemical adsorption with the hydroxyapatite crystals in the bone, and the newly&#xD;
      formed collagen has a higher effect on the bone imaging agent. Recent studies have shown&#xD;
      that, the uptake mechanism of radionuclide-labeled phosphonates such as [99mTc]Tc-DPD,&#xD;
      [99mTc]Tc-HMDP and [99mTc]Tc-PYP in amyloid myocardial deposition It is not fully understood,&#xD;
      but some investigators have evaluated biopsies and found that microcalcifications are often&#xD;
      present in cardiac amyloid deposits and may be associated with positive phosphonate imaging.&#xD;
      However, [99mTc]Tc imaging agents are still not effective for Quantitative assessment of&#xD;
      amyloid deposition. Recently, with the successful application of 68Ga-somatostatin receptor&#xD;
      imaging agents in PET/CT, people have gradually shifted their attention to the &quot;new&#xD;
      generation&quot; positron nuclides 68Ga, 68Ge /68Ga radionuclide generator can prepare 68Ga based&#xD;
      PET tracer without adjacent cyclotron, in addition, 68Ga excellent physical properties (t1/2:&#xD;
      68min; 89%β+, 1.92mev maximum energy) Suitable for PET imaging, therefore, the development of&#xD;
      bisphosphonates labeled with 68Ga will meet the need for a source of PET tracers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the existing phosphonate-targeted molecular probes, the Hank F. Kung laboratory at&#xD;
      the University of Pennsylvania has developed a new generation of 68Ga-labeled&#xD;
      radiopharmaceutical P15-041 ([68Ga]Ga-HBED-CC-BP). Preclinical data show that P15-041&#xD;
      exhibits rapid and facile complex formation compared to current [68Ga]Ga-BPAMD,&#xD;
      [68Ga]Ga-NO2AP-BP, [68Ga]Ga-DOTA-(ZOL) an additional advantage. In in vivo experiments,&#xD;
      P15-041 exhibited good bone resorption and rapid renal excretion in normal mice. Haiyan Hong&#xD;
      et al. [13] prepared various clinical doses of P15-041 and successfully evaluated them in&#xD;
      patients who performed whole-body PET/CT scans after intravenous administration of P15-041.&#xD;
      Robert K. Doot et al conducted a dosimetry test on P15-041, and analyzed the radioactive&#xD;
      distribution of the drug in normal organs and the dynamic changes of the drug in vivo with&#xD;
      time. The cortical bone uptake is high, the blood and other tissues are cleared quickly, and&#xD;
      there is obvious radioactive enrichment in the myocardium in the early stage of imaging.&#xD;
      P15-041 has the potential to become a new generation of excellent phosphonate molecular&#xD;
      probes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>detection capability of bone metastasis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the bone metastasis number detected by 68Ga-P15-041 PET/CT for prostate cancer in comparison with 68Ga-PSMA-11 PET/ CT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SUVmax of bone metastasis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the tumor uptake on 68Ga-P15-041 PET/CT for prostate cancer in comparison with 68Ga-PSMA-11 PET/CT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PSMA expression and SUV</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between PSMA expression and SUV in PET</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer Metastatic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>68Ga-PSMA-11 and 68Ga-P15-041 PET/ CT scan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients of Prostate cancer PET/CT imaging: In two consecutive days each patient underwent a PET/ CT scan after intravenous administration of 68Ga- PSMA-11 and 68Ga-P15-041, respectively.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>68Ga-PSMA-11</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous injection of one dosage of 148-185 MBq (4-5 mCi) 68Ga-PSMA-11. Tracer doses of 68Ga- PSMA-11 will be used to image lesions of prostate cancer by PET/CT.</description>
    <arm_group_label>68Ga-PSMA-11 and 68Ga-P15-041 PET/ CT scan</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>68Ga-PSMA-11 injection</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>68Ga-P15-041</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous injection of one dosage of 148-185 MBq (4-5 mCi) 68Ga-P15-041. Tracer doses of 68Ga- 15-041 will be used to image lesions of prostate cancer by PET/CT.</description>
    <arm_group_label>68Ga-PSMA-11 and 68Ga-P15-041 PET/ CT scan</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>68Ga-P15-041 injection</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  confirmed suspected prostate bone metastasis patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  68Ga-PSMA-11 and 68Ga-P15-041 PET/CT within one week;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signed written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known allergy against PSMA;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any medical condition that in the opinion of the investigator may significantly&#xD;
             interfere with study compliance.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zhaohui Zhu, Doc.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zhaohui Zhu, Doc.</last_name>
    <phone>86-13611093752</phone>
    <email>13611093752@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jiarou Wang, MD.</last_name>
    <phone>13628477019</phone>
    <email>ChristinaWang97@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Peking Union Medical College Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Peking</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zhaohui Zhu, Doc.</last_name>
      <phone>86-13611093752</phone>
      <email>13611093752@163.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jiarou Wang, MD.</last_name>
      <phone>86-13628477019</phone>
      <email>ChristinaWang97@163.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 25, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 25, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 25, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gallium 68 PSMA-11</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

