<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623059</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15038</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>P01HL158507</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623059</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluate Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Slow Release DHEA</brief_title>
  <acronym>DHEA</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase IIa Clinical Trial to Evaluate Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Slow Release DHEA</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indiana University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a study to look at pharmacokinetic levels of different doses of slow release DHEA in&#xD;
      subjects with severe asthma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pharmacokinetic (PK) studies of DHEA in asthma in general, and severe asthma in particular,&#xD;
      have never been done. In many diseases, PK in subjects with disease differs from that of&#xD;
      control subjects and those with other conditions. Therefore, researchers are investigating if&#xD;
      PK levels of slow release DHEA are different in subjects with severe asthma who have the&#xD;
      HSD3B1 AA or AC phenotypes&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 20, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is an unblinded pharmacokinetic (PK) study to determine optimal dosing for future studies. This study will start with a one-time dose and progress to twice daily dosing for 3 days, every 12 hours. Study cohort will be 9 subjects with severe asthma and serum DHEA-S &lt;90 μg/dL in men and &lt;45 μg/dL in women. DHEA dose will be 50 mg via slow release capsules. Endpoints will be serum DHEA and DHEA-S levels at 10, 20, 30, 60 min &amp; 2, 4, 6, 8, 12h after administration. After a one-week washout period, the protocol will be repeated using 100 mg of SR-DHEA.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the dose level to be used in patients</measure>
    <time_frame>within 9 months of all subjects completing study</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to determine the dose of slow release DHEA in patients with severe asthma and AA or AC genotype in conjunction with low serum DHEA-s.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pulse rate from baseline to post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma by measuring the change in pulse rate from before treatment to after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pulse oximetry from baseline to post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma by measuring the change in pulse oximetry from before treatment to after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in respiratory rate from baseline to post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma by measuring the change in respiration rate from before treatment to after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in blood pressure from baseline to post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by measuring the change in blood pressure from before treatment to after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in physical exam results from baseline to post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by measuring changes in results of a standard-of-care physical exam performed by a physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of physical symptoms after treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by physical symptom monitoring - coordinator will be attentive to any respiratory responses or other physical responses following the treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of adverse events and serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by monitoring for adverse event and serious adverse event monitoring as defined by FDA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in DHEA levels in blood from baseline to post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by evaluating DHEA levels in blood drawn from subject after DHEA treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in FEV from baseline to post-treatment as measured by spirometry</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by performing pulmonary function test to obtain measurements of FEV (forced expiratory volume) in the patient.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of an asthma exacerbation event</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline through treatment completion, approximately 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of DHEA in asthma patients by recording any instance of asthma exacerbation event following the treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">9</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <condition>Genotype</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>50mg dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will start with a one-time dose and progress to twice daily dosing for 3 days, every 12 hours. Study cohort will be 9 subjects with severe asthma and serum DHEA-S &lt;90 μg/dL in men and &lt;45 μg/dL in women. DHEA dose will be 50 mg via slow release capsules. Endpoints will be serum DHEA and DHEA-S levels at 10, 20, 30, 60 min &amp; 2, 4, 6, 8, 12h after administration. After a one-week washout period, the protocol will be repeated using 100 mg of SR-DHEA.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>100mg dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will start with a one-time 100mg dose and progress to twice daily dosing for 3 days, every 12 hours. Study cohort will be same 9 subjects with severe asthma and serum DHEA-S &lt;90 μg/dL in men and &lt;45 μg/dL in women. DHEA dose will be 100mg via slow release capsules. Endpoints will be serum DHEA and DHEA-S levels at 10, 20, 30, 60 min &amp; 2, 4, 6, 8, 12h after administration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Slow Release DHEA</intervention_name>
    <description>DHEA is a hormone produced by the body's adrenal gland. In drug form, it is available as an over-the-counter supplement that is available on the market without prescription.</description>
    <arm_group_label>100mg dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>50mg dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Slow Release Dehydroepiandrosterone</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult male or female aged between 18 and 50 at time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of asthma demonstrated by either bronchodilator reversibility or methacholine&#xD;
             responsiveness either during the run-in or by historical evidence of either criterion&#xD;
             if testing was performed under either the 2017 ERS technical standard or the 1999 ATS&#xD;
             Guidelines or outside studies, provided that full sets of flow volume loops have been&#xD;
             reviewed and approved by the PI. These criteria are defined as one of the following:&#xD;
             increase in FEV1 less than or equal to 12 percent and 200 ml after up to 8 puffs of&#xD;
             albuterol; positive methacholine defined as PC20 greater than or equal to 16mg/ml, or&#xD;
             PD20 greater than or equal to 400 mcg; documented physician diagnosis of severe asthma&#xD;
             according to NHLBI guidelines; Consistent use of an ICS/LABA inhaler for the prior 2&#xD;
             months; Non smoker; females must not be pregnant or lactating; absence of non-allergic&#xD;
             comorbidities; baseline DHEA-S concentration &lt; 45 μg/dL in females and &lt; 90 μg/dL in&#xD;
             males; genotype testing positive for either HSD3B1 AA or AC specific variant&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or actively trying to become pregnant; breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  positive urine pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known lung disease other than asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute (non asthma-related) dyspnea, viral respiratory illness or asthma exacerbation&#xD;
             within 4 weeks of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic glucocorticoid dosing for maintenance &gt;10 mg/day of prednisone or equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with significant non-allergic comorbidities (e.g. cerebral palsy, heart&#xD;
             disease, kidney disease, liver disease, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any know central or peripheral endocrine abnormality such as precocious&#xD;
             puberty or diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any known previous adverse reaction to DHEA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current smoker or pack year history &gt; 5 years (includes vaping/nicotine inhalation&#xD;
             devices)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine cotinine test (&gt; 100 mg/mL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of prednisone or antibiotics in the last 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any performance-enhancing drugs in the last 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of DHEA in the last 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Androgen use for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HSD3B1 CC phenotype&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition or finding that would compromise the safety of the subject or the&#xD;
             quality of the study data, or otherwise interfere with achieving the study objectives,&#xD;
             as determined by the PI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Menopausal amenorrhea by history&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive PSA (&gt;4 ng/ml) (Prostate Specific Antigen)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on biologic treatments for asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior diagnosis of vocal cord dysfunction, bronchopulmonary dysplasia, cystic&#xD;
             fibrosis, chronic obstructive pulmonary disorder, or other lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure &gt; 150 mm Hg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt;90 mm Hg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart rates outside the range of 50 to 120 beats per minutes or with a pathologic&#xD;
             irregularity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients afflicted with any additional acute or chronic pathology that in the opinion&#xD;
             of the screening physician makes them unsuitable for study or increases the risks&#xD;
             associated with the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kenzie Mahan</last_name>
    <phone>3172748899</phone>
    <email>krmahan@iu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Riley Hospital for Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kenzie Mahan</last_name>
      <phone>317-274-8899</phone>
      <email>krmahan@iu.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kenzie Mahan</last_name>
      <phone>317-274-8899</phone>
      <email>krmahan@iu.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sadatsafavi M, Lynd L, Marra C, Carleton B, Tan WC, Sullivan S, Fitzgerald JM. Direct health care costs associated with asthma in British Columbia. Can Respir J. 2010 Mar-Apr;17(2):74-80. doi: 10.1155/2010/361071.</citation>
    <PMID>20422063</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Han MK, Arteaga-Solis E, Blenis J, Bourjeily G, Clegg DJ, DeMeo D, Duffy J, Gaston B, Heller NM, Hemnes A, Henske EP, Jain R, Lahm T, Lancaster LH, Lee J, Legato MJ, McKee S, Mehra R, Morris A, Prakash YS, Stampfli MR, Gopal-Srivastava R, Laposky AD, Punturieri A, Reineck L, Tigno X, Clayton J. Female Sex and Gender in Lung/Sleep Health and Disease. Increased Understanding of Basic Biological, Pathophysiological, and Behavioral Mechanisms Leading to Better Health for Female Patients with Lung Disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018 Oct 1;198(7):850-858. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201801-0168WS.</citation>
    <PMID>29746147</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zein JG, Erzurum SC. Asthma is Different in Women. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2015 Jun;15(6):28. doi: 10.1007/s11882-015-0528-y.</citation>
    <PMID>26141573</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zein J, Gaston B, Bazeley P, DeBoer MD, Igo RP Jr, Bleecker ER, Meyers D, Comhair S, Marozkina NV, Cotton C, Patel M, Alyamani M, Xu W, Busse WW, Calhoun WJ, Ortega V, Hawkins GA, Castro M, Chung KF, Fahy JV, Fitzpatrick AM, Israel E, Jarjour NN, Levy B, Mauger DT, Moore WC, Noel P, Peters SP, Teague WG, Wenzel SE, Erzurum SC, Sharifi N. HSD3B1 genotype identifies glucocorticoid responsiveness in severe asthma. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020 Jan 28;117(4):2187-2193. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1918819117. Epub 2020 Jan 13.</citation>
    <PMID>31932420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marozkina N, Zein J, DeBoer MD, Logan L, Veri L, Ross K, Gaston B. Dehydroepiandrosterone Supplementation May Benefit Women with Asthma Who Have Low Androgen Levels: A Pilot Study. Pulm Ther. 2019 Dec;5(2):213-220. doi: 10.1007/s41030-019-00101-9. Epub 2019 Oct 21.</citation>
    <PMID>32026412</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lahm T, Albrecht M, Fisher AJ, Selej M, Patel NG, Brown JA, Justice MJ, Brown MB, Van Demark M, Trulock KM, Dieudonne D, Reddy JG, Presson RG, Petrache I. 17beta-Estradiol attenuates hypoxic pulmonary hypertension via estrogen receptor-mediated effects. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012 May 1;185(9):965-80. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201107-1293OC. Epub 2012 Mar 1.</citation>
    <PMID>22383500</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bentley JK, Hershenson MB. Airway smooth muscle growth in asthma: proliferation, hypertrophy, and migration. Proc Am Thorac Soc. 2008 Jan 1;5(1):89-96. doi: 10.1513/pats.200705-063VS.</citation>
    <PMID>18094090</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang KH, Li R, Kuri B, Lotan Y, Roehrborn CG, Liu J, Vessella R, Nelson PS, Kapur P, Guo X, Mirzaei H, Auchus RJ, Sharifi N. A gain-of-function mutation in DHT synthesis in castration-resistant prostate cancer. Cell. 2013 Aug 29;154(5):1074-1084. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2013.07.029.</citation>
    <PMID>23993097</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hall SL, Baker T, Lajoie S, Richgels PK, Yang Y, McAlees JW, van Lier A, Wills-Karp M, Sivaprasad U, Acciani TH, LeCras TD, Myers JB, Kovacic MB, Lewkowich IP. IL-17A enhances IL-13 activity by enhancing IL-13-induced signal transducer and activator of transcription 6 activation. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2017 Feb;139(2):462-471.e14. doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2016.04.037. Epub 2016 Jun 11.</citation>
    <PMID>27417023</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bulitta JB, Jiao Y, Drescher SK, Oliver A, Louie A, Moya B, Tao X, Wittau M, Tsuji BT, Zavascki AP, Shin BS, Drusano GL, Sorgel F, Landersdorfer CB. Four Decades of beta-Lactam Antibiotic Pharmacokinetics in Cystic Fibrosis. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2019 Feb;58(2):143-156. doi: 10.1007/s40262-018-0678-x.</citation>
    <PMID>29936678</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hettel D, Zhang A, Alyamani M, Berk M, Sharifi N. AR Signaling in Prostate Cancer Regulates a Feed-Forward Mechanism of Androgen Synthesis by Way of HSD3B1 Upregulation. Endocrinology. 2018 Aug 1;159(8):2884-2890. doi: 10.1210/en.2018-00283.</citation>
    <PMID>29850791</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gaston B, Reilly J, Drazen JM, Fackler J, Ramdev P, Arnelle D, Mullins ME, Sugarbaker DJ, Chee C, Singel DJ, Loscalzo J, Stamler JS. Endogenous nitrogen oxides and bronchodilator S-nitrosothiols in human airways. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1993 Dec 1;90(23):10957-61. doi: 10.1073/pnas.90.23.10957.</citation>
    <PMID>8248198</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gaston B, Sears S, Woods J, Hunt J, Ponaman M, McMahon T, Stamler JS. Bronchodilator S-nitrosothiol deficiency in asthmatic respiratory failure. Lancet. 1998 May 2;351(9112):1317-9. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(97)07485-0.</citation>
    <PMID>9643794</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hunt JF, Fang K, Malik R, Snyder A, Malhotra N, Platts-Mills TA, Gaston B. Endogenous airway acidification. Implications for asthma pathophysiology. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2000 Mar;161(3 Pt 1):694-9. doi: 10.1164/ajrccm.161.3.9911005.</citation>
    <PMID>10712309</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carraro S, Doherty J, Zaman K, Gainov I, Turner R, Vaughan J, Hunt JF, Marquez J, Gaston B. S-nitrosothiols regulate cell-surface pH buffering by airway epithelial cells during the human immune response to rhinovirus. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2006 May;290(5):L827-32. doi: 10.1152/ajplung.00406.2005.</citation>
    <PMID>16603595</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chung KF, Wenzel SE, Brozek JL, Bush A, Castro M, Sterk PJ, Adcock IM, Bateman ED, Bel EH, Bleecker ER, Boulet LP, Brightling C, Chanez P, Dahlen SE, Djukanovic R, Frey U, Gaga M, Gibson P, Hamid Q, Jajour NN, Mauad T, Sorkness RL, Teague WG. International ERS/ATS guidelines on definition, evaluation and treatment of severe asthma. Eur Respir J. 2014 Feb;43(2):343-73. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00202013. Epub 2013 Dec 12. Erratum In: Eur Respir J. 2014 Apr;43(4):1216. Dosage error in article text. Eur Respir J. 2018 Jul 27;52(1): Eur Respir J. 2022 Jun 9;59(6):</citation>
    <PMID>24337046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Watson AC, Rosenfield RL, Fang VS. Recovery from glucocorticoid inhibition of the responses to corticotrophin-releasing hormone. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 1988 May;28(5):471-7. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2265.1988.tb03681.x.</citation>
    <PMID>2850875</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jollin L, Thomasson R, Le Panse B, Baillot A, Vibarel-Rebot N, Lecoq AM, Amiot V, De Ceaurriz J, Collomp K. Saliva DHEA and cortisol responses following short-term corticosteroid intake. Eur J Clin Invest. 2010 Feb;40(2):183-6. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2362.2009.02219.x. Epub 2009 Oct 29.</citation>
    <PMID>19874391</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Tarrah K, Moiemen N, Lord JM. The influence of sex steroid hormones on the response to trauma and burn injury. Burns Trauma. 2017 Sep 14;5:29. doi: 10.1186/s41038-017-0093-9. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>28920065</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Phipatanakul W, Mauger DT, Sorkness RL, Gaffin JM, Holguin F, Woodruff PG, Ly NP, Bacharier LB, Bhakta NR, Moore WC, Bleecker ER, Hastie AT, Meyers DA, Castro M, Fahy JV, Fitzpatrick AM, Gaston BM, Jarjour NN, Levy BD, Peters SP, Teague WG, Fajt M, Wenzel SE, Erzurum SC, Israel E; Severe Asthma Research Program. Effects of Age and Disease Severity on Systemic Corticosteroid Responses in Asthma. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017 Jun 1;195(11):1439-1448. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201607-1453OC. Erratum In: Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018 Apr 1;197(7):970-971.</citation>
    <PMID>27967215</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Coates AL, Wanger J, Cockcroft DW, Culver BH; Bronchoprovocation Testing Task Force: Kai-Hakon Carlsen; Diamant Z, Gauvreau G, Hall GL, Hallstrand TS, Horvath I, de Jongh FHC, Joos G, Kaminsky DA, Laube BL, Leuppi JD, Sterk PJ. ERS technical standard on bronchial challenge testing: general considerations and performance of methacholine challenge tests. Eur Respir J. 2017 May 1;49(5):1601526. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01526-2016. Print 2017 May.</citation>
    <PMID>28461290</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Crapo RO, Casaburi R, Coates AL, Enright PL, Hankinson JL, Irvin CG, MacIntyre NR, McKay RT, Wanger JS, Anderson SD, Cockcroft DW, Fish JE, Sterk PJ. Guidelines for methacholine and exercise challenge testing-1999. This official statement of the American Thoracic Society was adopted by the ATS Board of Directors, July 1999. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2000 Jan;161(1):309-29. doi: 10.1164/ajrccm.161.1.ats11-99. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>10619836</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Graham BL, Steenbruggen I, Miller MR, Barjaktarevic IZ, Cooper BG, Hall GL, Hallstrand TS, Kaminsky DA, McCarthy K, McCormack MC, Oropez CE, Rosenfeld M, Stanojevic S, Swanney MP, Thompson BR. Standardization of Spirometry 2019 Update. An Official American Thoracic Society and European Respiratory Society Technical Statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019 Oct 15;200(8):e70-e88. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201908-1590ST.</citation>
    <PMID>31613151</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hankinson JL, Odencrantz JR, Fedan KB. Spirometric reference values from a sample of the general U.S. population. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1999 Jan;159(1):179-87. doi: 10.1164/ajrccm.159.1.9712108.</citation>
    <PMID>9872837</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>National Asthma Education and Prevention Program. Expert Panel Report 3 (EPR-3): Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Management of Asthma-Summary Report 2007. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2007 Nov;120(5 Suppl):S94-138. doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2007.09.043. Erratum In: J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2008 Jun;121(6):1330.</citation>
    <PMID>17983880</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 19, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 19, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 23, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indiana University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kirsten Kloepfer</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Pediatrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dehydroepiandrosterone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

