<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615636</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022-0459</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2022-09576</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615636</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase II Trial of Mosunetuzumab, Polatuzumab, Tafasitamab, and Lenalidomide in Patients With Relapsed B-cell NHL</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Trial of Mosunetuzumab, Polatuzumab, Tafasitamab, and Lenalidomide in Patients With Relapsed B-cell NHL</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To learn if giving mosunetuzumab in combination with polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and&#xD;
      lenalidomide can help to control relapsed/refractory FL and DLBCL.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the safety of mosunetuzumab, polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and lenalidomide&#xD;
      in relapsed/refractory NHL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the best overall response rate (ORR) of the combination of mosunetuzumab, with&#xD;
      polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and lenalidomide in patients with relapsed/refractory&#xD;
      diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the complete response rate, duration of response, progression free survival, and&#xD;
      overall survival in patients with DLBCL following treatment with of mosunetuzumab,&#xD;
      polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and lenalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate changes in immune effector cells and the tumor microenvironment following&#xD;
      treatment with of mosunetuzumab, polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and lenalidomide.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 19, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 19, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The best overall response rate (ORR).</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion; an average of 1 year.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>B-Cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Relapsed B-cell NHL</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Run In</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>During the safety run-in, the study team will first test a recommended dose of mosunetuzumab, polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and lenalidomide.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive mosunetuzumab, polatuzumab vedotin, tafasitamab, and lenalidomide at the dose level that was found tolerated in the safety run-in.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mosunetuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given by IV (vein)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Run In</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>RO7030816</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Polatuzumab vedotin</intervention_name>
    <description>Given by IV (vein)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Run In</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tafasitamab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given by IV (vein)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Run In</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given by PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Run In</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CC-5013</other_name>
    <other_name>Revlimid</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients in safety run in must meet the following criteria for study entry:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of relapsed CD20+ Follicular Lymphoma grade 1-3a&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of relapsed CD20+ diffuse large B-cell lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients in dose expansion must meet the following criteria for study entry:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • A diagnosis of relapsed CD20+ diffuse large B-cell lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients in each component (safety run in and dose expansion) must meet the following&#xD;
        criteria for study entry:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Evidence of progression or lack of response following at least 1 prior treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able and willing to provide written informed consent and to comply with the study&#xD;
             protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age ≥ 18 years as these drugs have not yet established safety and efficacy in&#xD;
             pediatric patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least 1 node greater than 1.5cm in short axis diameter&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Adequate hematologic function (unless abnormalities are related to NHL), defined as&#xD;
             follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.0 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 75 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Serum bilirubin &lt;1.5x ULN except in patients with Gilbert's syndrome as defined by &gt;&#xD;
             80% unconjugated bilirubin who must have a serum bilirubin of &lt;4x ULN; AST (SGOT) and&#xD;
             ALT (SGPT) ≤ 3x ULN or &lt; 5x ULN if hepatic metastases are present&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Renal function assessed by calculated creatinine clearance:&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 30ml/min by Cockcroft-Gault formula. See section&#xD;
             below, &quot;Dosing Regimen&quot;, regarding lenalidomide dose adjustment for calculated&#xD;
             creatinine clearance ≥ 30ml/min and &lt; 60ml/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients must be willing to receive transfusions of blood products.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. For men who are not surgically sterile, agreement to use a barrier method of&#xD;
             contraception for ≥ 3 months after the last treatment dose. In addition, male patients&#xD;
             must agree to request that their partners use an additional method of contraception,&#xD;
             such as oral contraceptives, intrauterine device, barrier method of contraception, or&#xD;
             spermicidal jelly. With female partners of childbearing potential or pregnant female&#xD;
             partners, men must remain abstinent or use a condom during the treatment period and&#xD;
             for 60 days after the final dose of mosunetuzumab, 6 months after the final dose of&#xD;
             polatuzumab vedotin, and 60 days after the final dose of tocilizumab, as applicable,&#xD;
             to avoid exposing the embryo. Men must refrain from donating sperm during this same&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. For women of reproductive potential who are not surgically sterile, agreement to use&#xD;
             two adequate methods of contraception, such as oral contraceptives, intrauterine&#xD;
             device, or barrier method of contraception in conjunction with spermicidal jelly for≥&#xD;
             12 months after the last therapeutic drug dose&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Females of childbearing potential (FCBP, defined as a female of childbearing potential&#xD;
             is a sexually mature woman who: 1) has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy; or 2)has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive&#xD;
             months (i.e., has had menses at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months). must&#xD;
             have a negative serum pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at least 50 mIU/mL within&#xD;
             10 - 14 days prior to and again within 24 hours of prescribing lenalidomide and must&#xD;
             either commit to continued abstinence from heterosexual intercourse or begin TWO&#xD;
             acceptable methods of birth control, one highly effective method and one additional&#xD;
             effective method AT THE SAME TIME, at least 4 weeks before she starts taking&#xD;
             lenalidomide. FCBP must also agree to ongoing pregnancy testing. Men must agree to use&#xD;
             a latex condom during sexual contact with a female of childbearing potential even if&#xD;
             they have had a successful vasectomy. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is&#xD;
             pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should inform&#xD;
             her treating physician immediately. Women must refrain from donating eggs during this&#xD;
             same period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. All study participants must be registered into the mandatory Revlimid REMS® program&#xD;
             and be willing and able to comply with the requirements of Revlimid REMS® program.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Able to take aspirin (81 or 325 mg) daily as prophylactic anticoagulation (patients&#xD;
             intolerant to ASA may use warfarin or low molecular weight heparin).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known hypersensitivity to any study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior treatment with polatuzumab vedotin&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior treatment with mosunetuzumab or other CD20-directed bispecific antibodies&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior treatment with tafasitamab and/or lenalidomide&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Autologous SCT within 100 days prior to first study treatment administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Prior treatment with CAR-T therapy within 30 days before first study treatment&#xD;
             administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Current eligibility for autologous SCT in patients with R/R DLBCL&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Prior allogeneic SCT&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Prior solid organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions to monoclonal antibody therapy&#xD;
             (or recombinant antibody-related fusion proteins)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Regular treatment with corticosteroids during the 2 weeks prior to the start of Cycle&#xD;
             1, unless administered for indications other than NHL at a dose equivalent to &lt; 20&#xD;
             mg/day prednisone. Treatment with systemic immunosuppressive medications, including,&#xD;
             but not limited to, prednisone (20 mg), azathioprine, methotrexate, thalidomide, and&#xD;
             anti-tumor necrosis factor agents within 2 weeks prior to Day 1 of Cycle 1. The use of&#xD;
             inhaled corticosteroids is permitted The use of mineralocorticoids for management of&#xD;
             orthostatic hypotension is permitted. Single dose of dexamethasone for nausea or B&#xD;
             symptoms is permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Prior systemic treatment with chemotherapy, immunotherapy, targeted and biologic&#xD;
             therapy 4 weeks prior to C1D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Prior treatment with radiotherapy within 2 weeks prior to C1D1. If patients have&#xD;
             received radiotherapy within 4 weeks prior to the initiation of study treatment,&#xD;
             patients must have at least one measurable lesion outside of the radiation field.&#xD;
             Patients who have only one measurable lesion that was previously irradiated but&#xD;
             subsequently progressed are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of prior malignancy within the last 2 years, except for curatively treated&#xD;
             basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin and low- grade in situ carcinoma of the&#xD;
             cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Any serious medical condition or abnormality in clinical laboratory tests that, in the&#xD;
             investigator's judgment, precludes the patient's safe participation in and completion&#xD;
             of the study, or which could affect compliance with the protocol or interpretation of&#xD;
             results including but not limited to uncontrolled hypertension, uncontrolled&#xD;
             congestive heart failure within past 6 months prior to screening (Class 3 (moderate)&#xD;
             or Class 4 (severe) cardiac disease as defined by the New York Heart Association&#xD;
             Functional Classification), uncontrolled or symptomatic arrhythmias with corrected QT&#xD;
             interval (QTc) &gt; 480 msec at screening, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus,&#xD;
             active/symptomatic coronary artery disease, COPD, LVEF less than 40%, renal failure,&#xD;
             uncontrolled autoimmune hemolytic anemia or idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura active&#xD;
             infection, history of invasive fungal infection, moderate to severe hepatic disease&#xD;
             (Child Pugh Class B or C), active hemorrhage, laboratory abnormality, or psychiatric&#xD;
             illness that, in the investigators opinion places the patient at unacceptable risk and&#xD;
             would prevent the subject from signing the informed consent form. Patients with&#xD;
             history of cardiac arrhythmias should have cardiac evaluation and clearance.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Known or suspected history of hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. History of autoimmune disease, including, but not limited to, myasthenia gravis,&#xD;
             myositis, autoimmune hepatitis, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, vascular thrombosis associated with antiphospholipid&#xD;
             syndrome, Wegener granulomatosis, Sjögren syndrome, Guillain-Barré syndrome, multiple&#xD;
             sclerosis, vasculitis, or glomerulonephritis Patients with a history of&#xD;
             autoimmune-related hypothyroidism on a stable dose of thyroid replacement hormone may&#xD;
             be eligible. Patients with controlled Type 1 diabetes mellitus who are on an insulin&#xD;
             regimen are eligible for the study. Patients with a history of disease-related immune&#xD;
             thrombocytopenic purpura, autoimmune hemolytic anemia, or other stable autoimmune&#xD;
             diseases may be eligible after review and approval by the Medical Monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Known active bacterial, viral, fungal, mycobacterial, parasitic, or other infection&#xD;
             (excluding fungal infections of nail beds) or any major episode of infection requiring&#xD;
             treatment with IV antibiotics or hospitalization (relating to the completion of the&#xD;
             course of antibiotics, except if for tumor fever) within 2 weeks prior to the start of&#xD;
             cycle 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients with suspected active or latent tuberculosis (latent tuberculosis needs to be&#xD;
             confirmed by positive Interferon-gamma release assay)&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Known or suspected chronic active Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Known HIV infection. Hepatitis B or C serologic status: subjects who are hepatitis B&#xD;
             core antibody (anti-HBc) positive and who are hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg)&#xD;
             negative will need to have a negative DNA polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and must be&#xD;
             willing to undergo DNA PCR testing during the study to be eligible. Those who are&#xD;
             HBsAg positive or hepatitis B DNA PCR positive will be excluded. Subjects who are&#xD;
             hepatitis C antibody positive will need to have a negative DNA PCR result to be&#xD;
             eligible. Those who are hepatitis C DNA PCR positive will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Vaccination with live vaccines within 28 days prior to start of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. No peripheral neuropathy ≥ grade 2 or = grade 2 with pain&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Pregnant or lactating females.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. All study participants must be registered into the mandatory Revlimid REMS® program,&#xD;
             and be willing and able to comply with the requirements of the REMS® program.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum (-human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin [-hCG]) at screening and must adhere to the scheduled pregnancy testing&#xD;
             as required in the Revlimid REMS® program.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. All patients with known central nervous system involvement with lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Contraindication to any of the required concomitant drugs or supportive treatments or&#xD;
             intolerance to hydration due to preexisting pulmonary or cardiac impairment including&#xD;
             pleural effusion requiring thoracentesis or ascites requiring paracentesis not due to&#xD;
             lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. Patients with active pulmonary embolism or deep vein thrombosis (diagnosed within 30&#xD;
             days of study enrollment).&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. Major surgery within 4 weeks of study entry, or wound that is not healed from prior&#xD;
             surgery or trauma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         31. History of stroke or intracranial hemorrhage within 6 months prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
         32. Active bleeding or history of bleeding diathesis (eg, hemophilia or von Willebrand&#xD;
             disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
         33. Uncontrolled AIHA (autoimmune hemolytic anemia) or ITP (idiopathic thrombocytopenic&#xD;
             purpura).&#xD;
&#xD;
         34. Prothrombin time (PT)/INR or aPTT (in the absence of lupus anticoagulant) &gt;2x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         35. Concurrent participation in another therapeutic clinical trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jason Westin, MD, MS, FACP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jason Westin, MD, MS, FACP</last_name>
    <phone>713-792-3750</phone>
    <email>jwestin@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jason Westin, MD, MS, FACP</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-3750</phone>
      <email>jwestin@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jason Westin, MD, MS, FACP</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>MD Anderson Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

