<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619172</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SC105</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>(AURELIO-05)</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2022-001527-32</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619172</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of SOT101 in Combination With Cetuximab to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety in Patients With Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Open-label, Single-arm, Multicenter Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of SOT101 in Combination With Cetuximab in Patients With RAS Wild-type Colorectal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>SOTIO Biotech AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>SOTIO Biotech</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of the study is to estimate the antitumor efficacy of SOT101 in&#xD;
      combination with cetuximab in RAS wild-type colorectal cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Two safety cohorts will be implemented in a 3+3 dose escalation design. The main cohort will start only after data from safety cohorts are assessed by an internal safety committee.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) according to Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors version 1.1 (RECIST 1.1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR according to RECIST for immune-based therapeutics (iRECIST) (iORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best overall response according to RECIST 1.1 (BOR) and iRECIST (iBOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response according to RECIST 1.1 (DoR) and iRECIST (iDoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical benefit rate according to RECIST 1.1 (CBR) and iRECIST (iCBR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS) according to RECIST 1.1 and iRECIST (iPFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to response according to RECIST 1.1 (TtR) and iRECIST (iTtR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression according to RECIST 1.1 (TtP) and iRECIST (iTtP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-emergent AEs (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>A TEAE is defined as an AE that started or worsened at or after the start of study treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with clinical laboratory test abnormalities (coagulation, hematology, clinical chemistry and urinalysis)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The following laboratory parameters will be assessed:&#xD;
Coagulation: prothrombin time, activated partial thromboplastin time, international normalized ratio, D-dimer, and fibrinogen&#xD;
Hematology: hemoglobin, glycated hemoglobin at screening, hematocrit, red blood cell count, reticulocytes, white blood cell count (with full differentiation), absolute lymphocyte count, and platelet count&#xD;
Clinical chemistry: Na, K, Cl, phosphate, Mg, Ca, albumin, total protein, ALT, AST, bilirubin (direct, total), alkaline phosphatase, lactate dehydrogenase, creatinine clearance calculated by the Cockcroft-Gault formula, creatinine, glucose (preferably fasting), urea or blood urea nitrogen, cholesterol, triglyceride, C-reactive protein, uric acid, amylase, and lipase&#xD;
Urinalysis: pH, glucose, protein, bilirubin, urobilinogen. Microscopic examination (mandated only if clinically indicated): red blood cell count, white blood cell count, epithelial cells, bacteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with vital signs abnormalities</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The following vital signs parameters will be assessed:&#xD;
Blood pressure (systolic and diastolic, after ≥5 minutes of rest), body temperature, and heart rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with electrocardiography abnormalities</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to approximately 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with DLTs</measure>
    <time_frame>Through Cycle 1 (21 days)</time_frame>
    <description>AEs as per NCI CTCAE v5.0 considered DLTs:&#xD;
All G5 events not clearly related to disease progression or any other causes will be considered DLTs&#xD;
Any G3 or higher non-hematologic toxicity regardless of duration will be considered a DLT, with the following exceptions that are not considered DLTs:&#xD;
G3 nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea that can be controlled within 72 hours&#xD;
G3 fatigue that lasts less than 5 days&#xD;
G3 or higher correctable electrolyte abnormalities that last less than 72 hours and are not associated with clinical complications&#xD;
G3 or higher serum amylase or lipase not associated with clinical manifestations of pancreatitis&#xD;
G3 AST or ALT increase or G3 blood bilirubin increase that lasts 5 days or less&#xD;
Hy's law cases will be considered DLTs.&#xD;
Hematologic DLTs will include the following:&#xD;
G4 decreased neutrophil count or decreased platelet count lasting more than 7 days&#xD;
Febrile neutropenia&#xD;
G3 or higher decreased platelet count with bleeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of area under the curve (AUC) of SOT101 and cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of maximum concentration (Cmax) of SOT101 and cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of time to maximum concentration (Tmax) of SOT101 and cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of pre-dose concentration (Ctrough) of SOT101 and cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of terminal elimination half-life (T1/2) of SOT101 and cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of systemic clearance (CL) of SOT101 and cetuximab in single dose and steady state</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of volume of distribution of SOT101 and cetuximab at steady state and during terminal phase (Vss, Vz)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of accumulation ratio (RAUC, RCmax) of SOT101 and cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of Cycle 1 until Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of concentration of SOT101 and cetuximab at various timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of anti-drug antibodies (ADAs) against SOT101</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until 30 (±2) days after the last dose of SOT101</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by occurrence in time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Titer of ADAs against SOT101</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until 30 (±2) days after the last dose of SOT101</time_frame>
    <description>Measured as lowest reactive dilution</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time course of ADAs against SOT101</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until 30 (±2) days after the last dose of SOT101</time_frame>
    <description>Development in time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of ADAs against cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until 30 (±2) days after the last dose of cetuximab</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by occurrence in time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Titer of ADAs against cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until 30 (±2) days after the last dose of cetuximab</time_frame>
    <description>Measured as lowest reactive dilution</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time course of ADAs against cetuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until 30 (±2) days after the last dose of cetuximab</time_frame>
    <description>Development in time</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">64</enrollment>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SOT101 and Cetuximab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be first treated with 9 µg/kg of SOT101 and then proceed to be treated with either 12 µg/kg or 6 µg/kg of SOT101 in combination with cetuximab (depending on the safety evaluation of the first safety cohort). SOT101 treatment will be administered on day 1 (from cycle 2 onwards, ±1 day), day 2 (±1 day), day 8 (±1 day), and day 9 (±1 day) of each 21-day cycle, Cetuximab treatment will be administered on day 1 (from cycle 2 onwards, ±1 day), day 8 (±1 day), and day 15 (±1 day) of each 21-day cycle; on day 1 and day 8, cetuximab infusion will start within 30 minutes after SOT101 administration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SOT101</intervention_name>
    <description>Subcutaneous (SC) injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>SOT101 and Cetuximab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cetuximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous (IV) infusion via peripheral or central venous line</description>
    <arm_group_label>SOT101 and Cetuximab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Type of patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ≥18 years of age on the day of signing informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to understand and sign written informed consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Provides written informed consent for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Life expectancy &gt;6 months Disease characteristics&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced and/or metastatic RAS wild-type&#xD;
             colorectal cancer as confirmed by the investigational site within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             the first administration of study treatment. For the assessment of the RAS mutational&#xD;
             status, a US Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-approved test or an experienced local&#xD;
             laboratory using validated test methods for the detection of K-RAS and N-RAS (exons 2,&#xD;
             3, and 4) mutations must be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. EGFR mutation status should be available from a tumor biopsy taken within 3 months&#xD;
             prior to the first administration of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients who are relapsed/refractory or intolerant to prior treatment with irinotecan-&#xD;
             and oxaliplatin-containing chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Have at least one measurable lesion according to RECIST 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance score 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Must have recovered from all AEs due to previous therapies to grade ≤1 toxicity&#xD;
             (excluding alopecia) Organ function Have adequate organ function as defined below.&#xD;
             Specimens must be collected within 7 days prior to the start of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Hematology:&#xD;
&#xD;
             11.1. Absolute neutrophil count ≥1,500/µL 11.2. Platelets ≥100,000/µL 11.3. Hemoglobin&#xD;
             ≥9.0 g/dL (criteria must be met without packed red blood cell transfusion within the&#xD;
             prior 2 weeks; patients can be on stable dose of erythropoietin [≥3 months])&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Renal function: Creatinine clearance rate ≥50 mL/min as calculated using&#xD;
             Cockcroft-Gault equation&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Hepatic function: ALT/AST ≤2.5× upper limit of normal (ULN) and total bilirubin ≤2×ULN&#xD;
             in patients without liver metastasis (benign hereditary hyperbilirubinemias, e.g.,&#xD;
             Gilbert's syndrome, are permitted if total bilirubin &lt;3 mg/dL). In patients with liver&#xD;
             metastasis, ALT/AST ≤5×ULN is allowed but total bilirubin must be ≤2×ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Prothrombin time and activated partial thromboplastin time ≤1.5×ULN Hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. A locally performed hepatitis B (HBV) test is required during screening. Patients who&#xD;
             are HBV surface antigen positive are eligible if they have received HBV anti-viral&#xD;
             therapy for at least 4 weeks and have undetectable HBV viral load before study entry&#xD;
             (ICF signature). Patients should remain on anti-viral therapy throughout study&#xD;
             treatment and follow local guidelines for HBV anti-viral therapy post completion of&#xD;
             study treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. A locally performed hepatitis C (HCV) test is required during screening. Patients with&#xD;
             history of HCV infection are eligible if HCV viral load is undetectable at screening.&#xD;
             Patients must have completed anti-viral therapy at least 4 weeks before study entry&#xD;
             (ICF signature).&#xD;
&#xD;
             Special requirements for contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. A female patient is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant, not breastfeeding,&#xD;
             and one of the following conditions applies:&#xD;
&#xD;
             17.1. Not a woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP). A WOCBP is defined as fertile,&#xD;
             following menarche and until becoming post-menopausal unless permanently sterile.&#xD;
             Permanent sterilization methods include hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, and&#xD;
             bilateral oophorectomy. A postmenopausal state is defined as no menses for 12 months&#xD;
             without an alternative medical cause. A high follicle stimulating hormone level in the&#xD;
             postmenopausal range may be used to confirm a post-menopausal state in women not using&#xD;
             hormonal contraception or hormonal replacement therapy. However, in the absence of 12&#xD;
             months of amenorrhea, a single follicle stimulating hormone measurement is&#xD;
             insufficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
             17.2. A WOCBP who agrees to use a highly effective contraceptive method during the&#xD;
             treatment period and for at least 60 days after the last dose of cetuximab or at least&#xD;
             30 days after last dose of SOT101, whichever is later.&#xD;
&#xD;
             • WOCBP can only be included after a negative serum pregnancy test at screening within&#xD;
             7 days before day 1 of cycle 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Male patients must agree to use a condom during the treatment period and for at least&#xD;
             60 days after the last dose of cetuximab or at least 30 days after last dose of&#xD;
             SOT101, whichever is later.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prior/concomitant therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Prior exposure to drugs that are agonists of IL-2 or IL-15&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Therapy with cetuximab within 3 months prior to ICF signature or patients who had&#xD;
             progressive disease as best response to prior cetuximab-containing regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior systemic anti-cancer therapies, including investigational agents before study&#xD;
             entry (ICF signature):&#xD;
&#xD;
             3.1. Less than 3 weeks or 5 half lives (whichever shorter) for anti-cancer treatments&#xD;
             3.2. Less than 4 weeks from major surgeries and not recovered adequately from the&#xD;
             procedure and/or any complications from the surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has received prior radiotherapy within 2 weeks of the start of study treatments. A&#xD;
             1-week radiation-free period is permitted for palliative radiation (≤2 weeks of&#xD;
             radiotherapy) to non-central nervous system disease. Patients must have recovered from&#xD;
             all radiation-related toxicities and not require corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Has received a live or live-attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose&#xD;
             of study treatments Prior/concurrent clinical study experience&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational&#xD;
             agent or has used an investigational device within 3 weeks or 5 half lives (whichever&#xD;
             longer) before study entry (ICF signature). Patients who have entered the follow-up&#xD;
             phase of an investigational study may participate as long as it has been 3 weeks or 5&#xD;
             half lives (whichever longer) after the last dose of the previous investigational&#xD;
             agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with known BRAF mutations&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Clinically significant cardiac abnormalities including prior history of any of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
             8.1. Cardiomyopathy, with left ventricular ejection fraction lower than the lower&#xD;
             limit of the institutional normal range at screening 8.2. Congestive heart failure of&#xD;
             New York Heart Association grade ≥2 8.3. History of clinically significant (i.e.,&#xD;
             active) atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease, specifically myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             unstable angina, cerebrovascular accident within 6 months prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study treatments, and any history of coronary heart disease and clinically significant&#xD;
             peripheral and/or carotid artery disease 8.4. Prolongation of QTcF &gt;450 msec; history&#xD;
             or family history of congenital long QT syndrome 8.5. Uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
             requiring medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Uncontrolled hypertension defined as systolic blood pressure &gt;160 mmHg, diastolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &gt;110 mmHg. Patients with uncontrolled hypertension should be medically&#xD;
             managed on a stable regimen to control hypertension prior to study entry (ICF&#xD;
             signature).&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Has a clinical diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving chronic systemic steroid&#xD;
             therapy (in dosing exceeding 10 mg daily of prednisone equivalent) or any other form&#xD;
             of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatments. Systemic steroid pretreatment prior to cetuximab infusion according to&#xD;
             local guidelines is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of or serology positive for HIV. A locally performed HIV test is required&#xD;
             during screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or has required active treatment&#xD;
             within the past 5 years. Patients with basal cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma&#xD;
             in situ (e.g., breast carcinoma, cervical cancer in situ) that have undergone&#xD;
             potentially curative therapy are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Has known active central nervous system metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis.&#xD;
             Patients with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are&#xD;
             radiologically stable, i.e., without evidence of progression for at least 4 weeks&#xD;
             confirmed during screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Has an active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2&#xD;
             years (i.e., with use of disease-modifying agents, corticosteroids, or&#xD;
             immunosuppressive drugs). Replacement therapy (e.g., thyroxine, insulin, or&#xD;
             physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency)&#xD;
             is not considered a form of systemic treatment and is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality&#xD;
             that might confound the results of the study, interfere with the patient's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the study, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the patient to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Has a known psychiatric or substance abuse disorder that would interfere with the&#xD;
             patient's ability to cooperate with the requirements of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. History of hypersensitivity to any component of cetuximab or to compounds of similar&#xD;
             biological or chemical composition of SOT101 and/or the excipients contained in the&#xD;
             study drug formulations&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Richard Kapsa</last_name>
    <phone>(+420) 2241 74448</phone>
    <email>kapsa@sotio.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>December 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 1, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 5, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 5, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 6, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SOT101</keyword>
  <keyword>SO-C101</keyword>
  <keyword>Cetuximab</keyword>
  <keyword>Colorectal cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>AURELIO-05</keyword>
  <keyword>Nanrilkefusp alfa</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

