<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05627258</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000889</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000889-I</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05627258</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of a Human Monoclonal Antibody, VRCHIVMAB0115-00-AB (VRC01.23LS), Administered Intravenously or Subcutaneously to Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>VRC 615: A Phase I, Open-Label, Dose-Escalation Study of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of a Human Monoclonal Antibody, VRC-HIVMAB-0115-AB (VRC01.23LS), Administered Intravenously or Subcutaneously to Healthy Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      HIV causes AIDS, a serious disease that can lead to fatal infections. HIV infection can be&#xD;
      controlled but not cured, nor is there a vaccine to prevent it. Antibodies may offer a&#xD;
      promising new way to prevent HIV infection. Antibodies are proteins that are naturally made&#xD;
      by the body to fight germs. One antibody (VRC01.23LS) has been tested in the lab and was&#xD;
      found to block HIV-like viruses. Researchers want to find out if it is safe to inject&#xD;
      VRC01.23LS into people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test the safety of VRC01.23LS in healthy adults.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy people aged 18 to 60 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be divided into 6 groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some will get 1 dose of VRC01.23LS. They will visit the clinic up to 14 times in 24 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some will get 3 doses, each 12 weeks apart. They will have 25 clinic visits over 48 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For some participants, the drug will be given through a tube attached to a needle inserted&#xD;
      into a vein in the arm. This will take about 30 minutes. Others will receive the drug as an&#xD;
      injection under the skin in a fatty area of the belly, arm, or thigh; each dose may need up&#xD;
      to 3 individual injections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will stay in the clinic up to 8 hours on the days they receive VRC01.23LS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will receive a thermometer and measuring tool. They will check their temperature&#xD;
      daily for 7 days after they receive the study drug. They will measure any redness, swelling,&#xD;
      or bruising at the injection site.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This first-in-human, open-label study will evaluate VRC01.23LS (VRCHIVMAB0115- 00-AB) in a&#xD;
      dose-escalation design to examine safety, tolerability, dose, and pharmacokinetics (PK) in&#xD;
      healthy adults. The primary hypothesis is that subcutaneous (SC) and intravenous (IV)&#xD;
      administrations of VRC01.23LS will be safe and well-tolerated in healthy adults. A secondary&#xD;
      hypothesis is that VRC01.23LS will be detectable in human sera with a definable half-life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Products:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The VRC01.23LS broadly neutralizing monoclonal antibody (bnAb) targets the CD4 binding site&#xD;
      in the HIV-1 envelope, is human in origin, and contains two amino acid modifications within&#xD;
      the C-terminus of the heavy chain constant region designed to improve the antibody half-life&#xD;
      in vivo. VRC01.23LS was developed by the VRC/NIAID/NIH and manufactured under cGMP&#xD;
      regulations a the VRC Pilot Plant operated under contract by the Vaccine Clinical Materials&#xD;
      Program (VCMP), Leidos Biomedical Research, Inc., Frederick. MD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy adults, 18-60 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This open-label study will include 6 groups to evaluate VRC01.23LS administered alone or by&#xD;
      repeat dosing as shown below in the Study Schema. Enrollment will begin with the 5 mg/kg dose&#xD;
      groups, and enrollment for subsequent dose group will proceed after dose-escalation safety&#xD;
      reviews. Assessment of safety will include solicited reactogenicity, clinical observation,&#xD;
      and monitoring of hematological and chemical parameters at clinical visits throughout the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 30, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 29, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 29, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of VRC01.23LS (5 mg/kg SC) administered to healthy adults</measure>
    <time_frame>Through 24 weeks after product administration</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of a single SC dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of VRC01.23LS (20 mg/kg IV) administered to healthy adults</measure>
    <time_frame>Through 24 weeks after product administration</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of a single IV dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of VRC01.23LS (20 mg/kg IV) administered for a total of 3 injections in 12 week intervals to healthy adults</measure>
    <time_frame>Through 24 weeks after last product administration</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of repeat IV dosing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of VRC01.23LS (40 mg/kg IV) administered to healthy adults</measure>
    <time_frame>Through 24 weeks after product administration</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of a single IV dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of VRC01.23LS (5 mg/kg IV) administered to healthy adults</measure>
    <time_frame>Through 24 weeks after product administration</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of a single IV dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of VRC01.23LS (5 mg/kg SC) administered for a total of 3 injections in 12 week intervals to healthy adults</measure>
    <time_frame>Through 24 weeks after the last product administration</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of repeat SC dosing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PK will be evaluated at each dose level and route of administration.</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout the study</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of VRC01.23LS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>5 mg/kg IV single administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>5 mg/kg SC single administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>20 mg/kg IV single administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>40 mg/kg IV single administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>5 mg/kg SC repeat dosing</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>20 mg/kg IV repeat dosing</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>VRC-HIVMAB0115-00-AB</intervention_name>
    <description>VRC01.23LS is a broadly neutralizing monoclonal antibody that targets the CD4 binding site in the HIV-1 envelope, is human in origin, and contains two amino acid modifications within the C-terminus of the heavy chain constant region designed to improve antibody half-life in vivo.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 6</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A subject must meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Willing and able to complete the informed consent process.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to provide proof of identity to the satisfaction of the study clinician&#xD;
             completing the enrollment process.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Available for clinical follow-up through the last study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. 18 to 60 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. In good general health without clinically significant medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Physical examination without clinically significant findings within the 56 days prior&#xD;
             to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate venous access if assigned to an IV group or adequate abdominal subcutaneous&#xD;
             tissue if assigned to SC group.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Willing to have blood samples collected, stored indefinitely, and used for research&#xD;
             purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Laboratory Criteria within 56 days prior to enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. White blood cell count (WBC): 2,500-12,000/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. WBC differential either within institutional normal range or accompanied by the&#xD;
             Principal Investigator (PI) or designee approval.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Platelets: 125,000 - 500,000/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Hemoglobin within institutional normal range or accompanied by PI or designee&#xD;
             approval.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Creatinine: &lt;= 1.1 x Upper Limit of Normal (ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. ALT: &lt;= 1.25 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. AST: &lt;= 1.25 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Negative for HIV infection by an FDA approved method of detection.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Female-Specific Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Agrees to use an effective means of birth control from 21 days prior to enrollment&#xD;
             through the duration of study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Negative Beta-HCG (human chorionic gonadotropin) pregnancy test (urine or serum) on&#xD;
             day of enrollment for women presumed to be of reproductive potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A subject will be excluded if one or more of the following conditions apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Woman who is breast-feeding or planning to become pregnant during study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Weight &gt; 115 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any history of a severe allergic reaction with generalized urticaria, angioedema or&#xD;
             anaphylaxis prior to enrollment that has a reasonable risk of recurrence during the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Hypertension that is not well controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Receipt of any investigational study product within 28 days prior to enrollment (Note:&#xD;
             Emergency Use Authorization of a COVID-19 vaccine is not exclusionary).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receipt of an investigational HIV vaccine or anti-HIV monoclonal antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Receipt of any live attenuated vaccine within 28 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Receipt of any vaccine within 2 weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Bleeding disorder diagnosed by a doctor (e.g., factor deficiency, coagulopathy, or&#xD;
             platelet disorder requiring special precautions) or significant bruising or bleeding&#xD;
             difficulties with IM injections or blood draws.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any other chronic or clinically significant medical condition that in the opinion of&#xD;
             the investigator would jeopardize the safety or rights of the volunteer, including but&#xD;
             not limited to: diabetes mellitus type I, chronic hepatitis; OR clinically significant&#xD;
             forms of: drug or alcohol abuse, asthma, infectious disease, autoimmune disease,&#xD;
             psychiatric disorder, heart disease, or cancer.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lesia K Dropulic, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>VRC Clinic</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 451-8715</phone>
    <email>vaccines@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>VRC Clinic</last_name>
      <phone>301-451-8715</phone>
      <email>vaccines@nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000889-I.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gaudinski MR, Coates EE, Houser KV, Chen GL, Yamshchikov G, Saunders JG, Holman LA, Gordon I, Plummer S, Hendel CS, Conan-Cibotti M, Lorenzo MG, Sitar S, Carlton K, Laurencot C, Bailer RT, Narpala S, McDermott AB, Namboodiri AM, Pandey JP, Schwartz RM, Hu Z, Koup RA, Capparelli E, Graham BS, Mascola JR, Ledgerwood JE; VRC 606 Study Team. Safety and pharmacokinetics of the Fc-modified HIV-1 human monoclonal antibody VRC01LS: A Phase 1 open-label clinical trial in healthy adults. PLoS Med. 2018 Jan 24;15(1):e1002493. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1002493. eCollection 2018 Jan.</citation>
    <PMID>29364886</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gaudinski MR, Houser KV, Doria-Rose NA, Chen GL, Rothwell RSS, Berkowitz N, Costner P, Holman LA, Gordon IJ, Hendel CS, Kaltovich F, Conan-Cibotti M, Gomez Lorenzo M, Carter C, Sitar S, Carlton K, Gall J, Laurencot C, Lin BC, Bailer RT, McDermott AB, Ko SY, Pegu A, Kwon YD, Kwong PD, Namboodiri AM, Pandey JP, Schwartz R, Arnold F, Hu Z, Zhang L, Huang Y, Koup RA, Capparelli EV, Graham BS, Mascola JR, Ledgerwood JE; VRC 605 study team. Safety and pharmacokinetics of broadly neutralising human monoclonal antibody VRC07-523LS in healthy adults: a phase 1 dose-escalation clinical trial. Lancet HIV. 2019 Oct;6(10):e667-e679. doi: 10.1016/S2352-3018(19)30181-X. Epub 2019 Aug 28.</citation>
    <PMID>31473167</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kwon YD, Asokan M, Gorman J, Zhang B, Liu Q, Louder MK, Lin BC, McKee K, Pegu A, Verardi R, Yang ES, Program VP, Carlton K, Doria-Rose NA, Lusso P, Mascola JR, Kwong PD. A matrix of structure-based designs yields improved VRC01-class antibodies for HIV-1 therapy and prevention. MAbs. 2021 Jan-Dec;13(1):1946918. doi: 10.1080/19420862.2021.1946918.</citation>
    <PMID>34328065</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 26, 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 27, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 27, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Immune Response</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>First in Human</keyword>
  <keyword>Broadly Neutralizing</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>.Please refer to protocol Section 9.3.4.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

