<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612074</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022P002884</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612074</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Methemoglobin Concentration in High Dose Inhaled Nitric Oxide</brief_title>
  <official_title>Kinetics of Methemoglobin Concentration in Healthy Subjects Exposed to High Dose Inhaled Nitric Oxide</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to learn about the kinetic of methemoglobin in healthy&#xD;
      subjects breathing high dose inhaled nitric oxide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What are the kinetics of methemoglobin formation at different concentrations of nitric&#xD;
           oxide and oxygen&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What are the kinetics of methemoglobin reduction after nitric oxide discontinuation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be exposed to intermittent high dose inhaled nitric oxide while being&#xD;
      continuously monitored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The current proposed physiologic study is a single center, open-label clinical trial in&#xD;
      healthy subjects. The primary aim is to describe kinetics of methemoglobin (MetHb) formation&#xD;
      and reduction during exposure to high dose inhaled nitric oxide (iNO) in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
      The investigators will also assess the contribution of increased cardiac output in relation&#xD;
      to MetHb formation/reduction and of different inspired oxygen concentrations on the&#xD;
      production of nitrogen dioxide (NO2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol consists of three iNO concentrations (i.e., 200, 250 and 300 parts per&#xD;
      million, ppm) and two different FiO2 levels (i.e. 21% and 80%). The combination of iNO&#xD;
      concentrations and FiO2 levels identifies 6 study cohorts; five different subjects will be&#xD;
      enrolled for each cohort. The maximum number of volunteers enrolled in this clinical trial is&#xD;
      30 spontaneously breathing, awake, healthy subjects, divided in two groups (15&#xD;
      volunteers/group, 2 groups). The first 15 subjects will be exposed to iNO in a mixture of gas&#xD;
      at 21% of FiO2, the second group of 15 patients will receive iNO a mixture of gas at 80% of&#xD;
      FiO2. The maximum number of enrolled volunteers of 15/group is a product of the number of&#xD;
      volunteers exposed to each iNO concentration (5 volunteers/concentration, 3 doses). Each&#xD;
      volunteer will be exposed to a single iNO dosage at 3 times/day for 5 consecutive days. Thus,&#xD;
      a maximum of 450 total iNO treatments will be administered (30 enrolled volunteers, 5 days, 3&#xD;
      treatments/day). On the fifth day of the study, the iNO administration will be performed&#xD;
      during physical exercise that will increase the respiratory rate of the subject, in order to&#xD;
      study the influence of the respiratory rate on the rate of MetHb formation. During each&#xD;
      treatment period, a threshold of MetHb = 10% and/or inspiratory NO2 = 5 ppm (as defined by&#xD;
      the OSHA, https://www.osha.gov/chemicaldata/21, last accessed on Oct 31, 2022) will be used&#xD;
      as stopping criteria for gas inhalation. Also, iNO administration will be stopped at any&#xD;
      time, regardless of the MetHb and NO2 levels, at the discretion of the subject.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Physiologic study in healthy volunteers</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Methemoglobin kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of methemoglobin formation and reduction during and after exposure to high dose inhaled nitric oxide</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nitric Oxide Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of Nitric Oxide metabolites (urinary and plasma) in subjects exposed to high dose iNO.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nitrogen Dioxide</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Inspiratory NO2 concentrations at different inspiratory concentrations of NO and O2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Subjects</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nitric Oxide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>High dose inhaled nitric oxide (200, 250 and 300 ppm) in a nitrogen-oxygen-air mixture, at two different FiO2 levels (0.21 and 0.8) will be delivered intermittently with a dedicated system and a snug-fitting facemask to healthy volunteers three times per day for 5 days. The subjects will be monitored before, during and after the administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Inhaled Nitric Oxide</intervention_name>
    <description>Inhaled nitric oxide (Medical grade, in NO/N2 tanks) will be delivered in a oxygen-air-nitrogen mixture for 30 minutes three times per day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nitric Oxide</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nitric Oxide</other_name>
    <other_name>Gaseous Nitric Oxide</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 - 64 years-old volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index (BMI) 18 - 30 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of current systemic and/or respiratory diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capacity to consent to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of any physical, mental, and/or medical conditions that would make the&#xD;
             proposed studies relatively more hazardous.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic and/or respiratory disease with or without any functional limitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricle ejection fraction &lt; 30%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline MetHb ≥ 3%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other conditions of increased risk for MetHb formation: genetic diseases (e.g.,&#xD;
             glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency, cytochrome b5 reductase deficiency,&#xD;
             sickle cell disease), significant anemia or baseline elevation in MetHb.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of transient ischemic attack or stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active smoking and tobacco chewers. Volunteers may be enrolled if they quit smoking&#xD;
             for more than 1 year and less than 10 pack years total.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any vaping/e-cigarettes use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excess alcohol use: more than ½ L/day of wine consumption or equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of any recreational drugs (including the use of medical marijuana) or use&#xD;
             of recreational drugs over the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy determined by blood pregnancy test detecting presence of human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin (hCG).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than six weeks postpartum.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any current medication uses except oral contraceptives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lower respiratory infection within the last 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Claustrophobia (inability to wear a facemask) or other active psychiatric conditions&#xD;
             or unwillingness to cooperate with the investigators and other medical teams.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in another research study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Facial abnormalities that would preclude proper use of a face mask.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lorenzo Berra, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lorenzo Berra, MD</last_name>
    <phone>617 726 3030</phone>
    <email>lberra@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wiegand SB, Traeger L, Nguyen HK, Rouillard KR, Fischbach A, Zadek F, Ichinose F, Schoenfisch MH, Carroll RW, Bloch DB, Zapol WM. Antimicrobial effects of nitric oxide in murine models of Klebsiella pneumonia. Redox Biol. 2021 Feb;39:101826. doi: 10.1016/j.redox.2020.101826. Epub 2020 Dec 11.</citation>
    <PMID>33352464</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Di Fenza R, Yu B, Carroll RW, Berra L. Chemiluminescence-based Assays for Detection of Nitric Oxide and its Derivatives from Autoxidation and Nitrosated Compounds. J Vis Exp. 2022 Feb 16;(180). doi: 10.3791/63107.</citation>
    <PMID>35253799</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Valsecchi C, Winterton D, Safaee Fakhr B, Collier AY, Nozari A, Ortoleva J, Mukerji S, Gibson LE, Carroll RW, Shaefi S, Pinciroli R, La Vita C, Ackman JB, Hohmann E, Arora P, Barth WH Jr, Kaimal A, Ichinose F, Berra L; DELiverly oF iNO (DELFiNO) Network Collaborators. High-Dose Inhaled Nitric Oxide for the Treatment of Spontaneously Breathing Pregnant Patients With Severe Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pneumonia. Obstet Gynecol. 2022 Aug 1;140(2):195-203. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000004847. Epub 2022 Jul 6.</citation>
    <PMID>35852269</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Safaee Fakhr B, Di Fenza R, Gianni S, Wiegand SB, Miyazaki Y, Araujo Morais CC, Gibson LE, Chang MG, Mueller AL, Rodriguez-Lopez JM, Ackman JB, Arora P, Scott LK, Bloch DB, Zapol WM, Carroll RW, Ichinose F, Berra L; Nitric Oxide Study Investigators. Inhaled high dose nitric oxide is a safe and effective respiratory treatment in spontaneous breathing hospitalized patients with COVID-19 pneumonia. Nitric Oxide. 2021 Nov 1;116:7-13. doi: 10.1016/j.niox.2021.08.003. Epub 2021 Aug 13.</citation>
    <PMID>34400339</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bartley BL, Gardner KJ, Spina S, Hurley BP, Campeau D, Berra L, Yonker LM, Carroll RW. High-Dose Inhaled Nitric Oxide as Adjunct Therapy in Cystic Fibrosis Targeting Burkholderia multivorans. Case Rep Pediatr. 2020 Jun 24;2020:1536714. doi: 10.1155/2020/1536714. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>32685229</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Miller C, Miller M, McMullin B, Regev G, Serghides L, Kain K, Road J, Av-Gay Y. A phase I clinical study of inhaled nitric oxide in healthy adults. J Cyst Fibros. 2012 Jul;11(4):324-31. doi: 10.1016/j.jcf.2012.01.003. Epub 2012 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>22520076</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wiegand SB, Safaee Fakhr B, Carroll RW, Zapol WM, Kacmarek RM, Berra L. Rescue Treatment With High-Dose Gaseous Nitric Oxide in Spontaneously Breathing Patients With Severe Coronavirus Disease 2019. Crit Care Explor. 2020 Nov 16;2(11):e0277. doi: 10.1097/CCE.0000000000000277. eCollection 2020 Nov.</citation>
    <PMID>33225304</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Safaee Fakhr B, Wiegand SB, Pinciroli R, Gianni S, Morais CCA, Ikeda T, Miyazaki Y, Marutani E, Di Fenza R, Larson GM, Parcha V, Gibson LE, Chang MG, Arora P, Carroll RW, Kacmarek RM, Ichinose F, Barth WH Jr, Kaimal A, Hohmann EL, Zapol WM, Berra L. High Concentrations of Nitric Oxide Inhalation Therapy in Pregnant Patients With Severe Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19). Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Dec;136(6):1109-1113. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000004128.</citation>
    <PMID>32852324</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pinciroli R, Traeger L, Fischbach A, Gianni S, Morais CCA, Fakhr BS, Di Fenza R, Robinson D, Carroll R, Zapol WM, Berra L. A Novel Inhalation Mask System to Deliver High Concentrations of Nitric Oxide Gas in Spontaneously Breathing Subjects. J Vis Exp. 2021 May 4;(171). doi: 10.3791/61769.</citation>
    <PMID>34028428</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gianni S, Fenza RD, Morais CCA, Fakhr BS, Mueller AL, Yu B, Carroll RW, Ichinose F, Zapol WM, Berra L. High-Dose Nitric Oxide From Pressurized Cylinders and Nitric Oxide Produced by an Electric Generator From Air. Respir Care. 2022 Feb;67(2):201-208. doi: 10.4187/respcare.09308. Epub 2021 Aug 19.</citation>
    <PMID>34413210</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 14, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lorenzo Berra, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical Director, Respiratory Care</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>nitric oxide</keyword>
  <keyword>methemoglobin</keyword>
  <keyword>nitrogen dioxide</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nitric Oxide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

