<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623774</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IkT-001Pro-501</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623774</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Dose Calibration Study Comparing IkT-001Pro to Imatinib Mesylate 400mg</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Dose Calibration and Dose Equivalence Pharmacokinetic Study in Healthy Volunteers Comparing IkT-001Pro to Imatinib Mesylate 400mg</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Inhibikase Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Inhibikase Therapeutics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study investigates the safety, tolerability and dose equivalence of drug IkT-001Pro in&#xD;
      healthy volunteers (18 to 55 years old) in comparison to imatinib mesylate. This study is&#xD;
      designed in 2 parts. Part A consists of 3 cohorts. In cohort 1 healthy participants will take&#xD;
      a single, oral dose of 400mg IkT-001Pro then will be followed by a single dose of 400mg&#xD;
      Imatinib mesylate after a 7-day washout. Cohort 2 and 3 will follow the same structure as&#xD;
      cohort 1 with a different Ikt-001Pro dose. Part B will be chosen using Part A data by&#xD;
      statistical procedures. Part B will enroll 32 subjects to demonstrate the bioequivalence of&#xD;
      IkT-001Pro (the 'Test') to 400 mg imatinib delivered as imatinib mesylase (the 'Reference').&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Part A, Dose Calibration Cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a crossover design dose calibration study in healthy volunteers to identify a dose of&#xD;
      IkT-001Pro film-coated tablets that would be equivalent to imatinib free base 400 mg&#xD;
      film-coated tablets containing imatinib mesylate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dose calibration cohorts will each consist of eight (8) subjects who will receive a single&#xD;
      dose of IkT-001Pro at 400, 500 or 600 mg and then crossover to a single dose of imatinib 400&#xD;
      mg delivered as imatinib mesylate following a 7-day washout. The three cohorts will have&#xD;
      staggered starting points. The 400 mg IkT-001Pro dose, washout and 400 mg imatinib delivered&#xD;
      as imatinib mesylate will be completed first including full PK analysis. Following review of&#xD;
      the PK data at 400 mg IkT-001Pro, the 500 mg and 600 mg cohorts will be enrolled&#xD;
      approximately simultaneously.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pharmacokinetic plasma samples for all three cohorts will be drawn pre-dose at 0.25, 0.5, 1,&#xD;
      2, 4, 6, 8, 12, 16, 24, 48, 72 and 96 hours after dosing. A 7-day washout period will take&#xD;
      place between dosing of IkT-001Pro and dosing of 400 mg imatinib delivered as imatinib&#xD;
      mesylate. PK plasma samples for the imatinib mesylate arm will be obtained on the same&#xD;
      sampling schedule as the IkT-001Pro arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part B- Dose Equivalence Cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part B will test the bioequivalence of the IkT-001Pro dose chosen in Part A. In this&#xD;
      two-period crossover design dose equivalence study, up to 16 subjects will receive IkT-001Pro&#xD;
      and up to 16 subjects will receive 400 mg imatinib as imatinib mesylate as a single dose. The&#xD;
      dose of IkT-001Pro will be computed from the exposures measured in Part A to estimate the&#xD;
      dose of IkT-001Pro that should be equivalent to 400 mg imatinib delivered as imatinib&#xD;
      mesylate. After a 7-day washout period, the subjects that began on IkT-001Pro will switch to&#xD;
      400 mg imatinib delivered as imatinib mesylate. Similarly, the subjects that began on 400 mg&#xD;
      imatinib delivered as imatinib mesylate will switch to the equivalent dose of IkT-001Pro.&#xD;
      Blood samples for PK assessment will be drawn pre-dose and 0.25, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 12, 16,&#xD;
      24, 48, 72 and 96 hours after dosing for both IkT-001Pro and 400 mg imatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General Methodological Considerations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Dose Calibration and Dose Equivalence cohorts will consist of up to 14 visits over a&#xD;
      period of up to 28 days prior to dosing and 28 days after dosing. The dose-escalation pattern&#xD;
      and timing for IkT-001Pro in Part A or Part B may be modified by the Safety Review Committee&#xD;
      (SRC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects in each cohort of the study will be admitted to the unit approximately 24 hours&#xD;
      prior to the expected time of dosing. They will be confined to the unit for approximately 96&#xD;
      hours in Part A and Part B of the study for each drug product to be administered. Subjects&#xD;
      will not be confined to the unit during the wash-out period. No subject may be discharged&#xD;
      from the unit until the investigator is satisfied that they have no continuing adverse events&#xD;
      that could be related to study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A full breakfast must be given no more than 60 mins prior to dosing in Parts A and B. The&#xD;
      meal must be a high-fat (approximately 50 percent of total caloric content of the meal) and&#xD;
      high-calorie (approximately 800 to 1000 calories) meal. The meal should derive approximately&#xD;
      150, 250, and 500-600 calories from protein, carbohydrate, and fat, respectively. The caloric&#xD;
      breakdown of the meal must be provided in the study report. The single dose of IkT-001Pro or&#xD;
      400 imatinib delivered as imatinib mesylate is to be taken after the meal with a large glass&#xD;
      of water (240 ml or 8 oz).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 16, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a crossover design dose calibration study in healthy volunteers to identify a dose of IkT-001Pro film-coated tablets that would be equivalent to imatinib free base 400 mg film-coated tablets containing imatinib mesylate</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by area under the concentration-time curve for imatinib from time zero to last measurable concentration (AUC(0-last))</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the concentration-time curve for imatinib from time zero to last measurable concentration (AUC0-last)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by area under the concentration-time curve for imatinib from time zero to infinity (AUC0-inf)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the concentration-time curve for imatinib from time zero to infinity (AUC(0-inf))</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by the maximum plasma concentration (Cmax) of imatinib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>The maximum plasma concentration (Cmax) of imatinib</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Incidence and temporal profile of treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) evaluated by type/nature, severity/intensity, seriousness, and relationship to study intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and temporal profile of treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: Proportion of those in each dosing cohort who discontinued the assigned regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of those in each dosing cohort who discontinued the assigned regimen</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by imatinib pharmacokinetic parameters for terminal rate constant</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of lamda-z</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by imatinib pharmacokinetic parameters for terminal half-life</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of terminal half-life t1/2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by imatinib pharmacokinetic parameters for time to maximum concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Time to reach maximum concentration (tmax)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by imatinib pharmacokinetic parameters for dose normalized maximum concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Dose-normalized maximum concentration Cmax/D, where D is the dose in mg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by imatinib pharmacokinetic parameters for dose normalized area under the time concentration curve to last time point</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Dose-normalized AUC(0-t)/D, where D is the dose in mg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure of imatinib after administration of IkT-001Pro and imatinib mesylate, as measured by imatinib pharmacokinetic parameters for dose-normalized area under the time concentration curve from 0 to infinite time</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 through day 12</time_frame>
    <description>Dose-normalized AUC(0-infinity)/D, where D is the dose in mg.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">64</enrollment>
  <condition>CML</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Calibration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Part A, cohorts will consist of 8 subjects who will receive a single dose of Ikt-001Pro and then cross over to a single does of imatinib following a 7 day washout.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Equivalance</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Part B, up to 16 subjects will receive IkT001-Pro and up to 16 subjects will receive 400mg of imatinib mesylate. After a 7 day washout period the subjects will switch to receive the drug they did not previously receive.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Imatinib Mesylate</intervention_name>
    <description>400mg tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Calibration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Equivalance</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IkT-001Pro</intervention_name>
    <description>100mg or 400mg tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Calibration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Equivalance</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject must have all questions about the study answered and must have signed the&#xD;
             informed consent document before any study-specific procedures are performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Healthy ambulatory male and female subjects &gt; 18 to &lt; 55 years of age at the Screening&#xD;
             visit, with no history or evidence of clinically relevant medical disorders as&#xD;
             determined by the Investigator in consultation with the Sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Bodyweight &gt; 50 kg and body mass index (BMI) &gt; 18.0 and &lt; 32.0 kg/m2 at the screening&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Physical examination, clinical laboratory values, vital signs, and electrocardiogram&#xD;
             (ECG) data. Vital signs and clinical laboratory values must be within the normal range&#xD;
             and or deemed not clinically significant by the PI and ECG tracings must be normal at&#xD;
             baseline and/or deemed not clinically significant by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Female subjects must be postmenopausal, permanently sterile (bilateral tubal&#xD;
             occlusion), or of childbearing potential with a negative pregnancy test,&#xD;
             non-breastfeeding, and using two highly effective methods of birth control prior to&#xD;
             screening and through completion of the last follow-up visit. If a subject&#xD;
             discontinues early after receiving a dose of study drug, she must continue this method&#xD;
             of birth control for at least 7 days following the last dose of the study drug. Highly&#xD;
             effective methods of birth control are defined as follows: hormonal (ie, established&#xD;
             use of oral, implantable, injectable, or transdermal hormonal methods of&#xD;
             contraception); placement of an intrauterine device; placement of an intrauterine&#xD;
             system; and mechanical /barrier method of contraception (ie, condom or occlusive cap&#xD;
             [diaphragm or cervical/vault cap] in conjunction with spermicide [foam, gel, film,&#xD;
             cream or suppository]).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Male subjects must agree to practice an acceptable method of highly effective birth&#xD;
             control from the Screening visit, while on study and for 7 days after receiving the&#xD;
             last dose of study drug. Highly effective methods of birth control include sexual&#xD;
             abstinence; vasectomy; or a condom with spermicide (men) in combination with their&#xD;
             partner's highly effective method.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Males must be willing to abstain from sperm donation from the screening visit, while&#xD;
             on study and through 30 days after receiving the last dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any subject with previous exposure to imatinib or known hypersensitivity to imatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinically significant abnormal values for hematology, clinical chemistry or&#xD;
             urinalysis at the screening and admission visits. Abnormalities considered to be&#xD;
             non-clinically significant by the Investigator are acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinically significant abnormal physical examination or 12-lead electrocardiogram&#xD;
             (ECG) at the screening or admission visits. NOTE: QTcF interval of &gt; 450 msec in males&#xD;
             or &gt; 470 msec in females will be the basis for exclusion from the study. ECG may be&#xD;
             repeated for confirmatory purposes if initial values obtained exceed the limits&#xD;
             specified.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinically significant abnormal renal function defined as a creatinine clearance rate&#xD;
             &lt; 90 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Significant history (within six months prior to receiving the study drug) and/or&#xD;
             presence of hepatic, renal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             endocrinological, hematological, dermatological, psychiatric, neurological,&#xD;
             immunologic, ophthalmologic, metabolic, fluid retention and edema, bleeding disorders&#xD;
             including hemorrhage or oncological disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any subject with a history, presence and/or current evidence of serologic positive&#xD;
             result for hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C antibodies, or HIV antibodies 1 or&#xD;
             2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Recent history (within previous six months prior to screening) of alcohol or drug&#xD;
             abuse (as judged by the investigator), or has consumed &gt; 2 alcohol drinks/day during&#xD;
             the last three months prior to screening (one glass is approximately equivalent to:&#xD;
             beer [284 mL], wine [125 mL/4 ounces], or distilled spirits [25 mL/1 ounce]). Subjects&#xD;
             that consume three glasses of alcoholic beverages per day but less than 14 glasses per&#xD;
             week may be enrolled at the discretion of the Investigator. Positive screens for&#xD;
             alcohol or controlled substances at the screening or admission visits will disqualify&#xD;
             a subject from study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any subject who currently uses or has regularly used tobacco or tobacco-containing&#xD;
             products (cigarettes, pipes, etc.) for at least 30 days prior to screening or positive&#xD;
             urine cotinine screen (&gt;300 ng/mL) at the screening or admission visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any subject who has received treatment with an investigational drug during the 30 days&#xD;
             prior to screening. Exposure to an investigational medical device within 30 days of&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Use of agents known to affect drug metabolism: use of any known CYP3A4 inducers and/or&#xD;
             inhibitors or consumed grapefruit juice, grapefruit, Seville oranges or St John's Wort&#xD;
             or products containing these within 14 days prior to first administration of study&#xD;
             drug. Strong inducers of CYP3A4 include dexamethasone, phenytoin, carbamazepine,&#xD;
             rifampin, rifabutin, rifampicin and phenobarbital. Strong inhibitors of CYP3A4 include&#xD;
             ketoconazole, itroconazole, clarythromycin, atazanavir, indinavir, nefazodone,&#xD;
             nelfinavir, ritonavir, saquinavir, telithromycin and voriconazole.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Investigative site personnel or their immediate families (spouse, parent, child or&#xD;
             sibling whether biological or legally adopted).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Any subject unwilling or unable to comply with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Pregnant or nursing women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Anyone who does not meet the requirements for exclusion of certain concomitant&#xD;
             medications as defined in Section 7.5.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janelle Weyer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Celerion</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sydney Kruger</last_name>
    <phone>4109672905</phone>
    <email>Skruger@inhibikase.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Celerion</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tempe</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85283</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrew Islas</last_name>
      <phone>602-437-0097</phone>
      <email>andrew.islas@celerion.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Janelle Weyer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 27, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 27, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

