<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05790369</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CMUH110-REC2-192</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05790369</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Home-Based Ankle Training Program on The Muscle Strength, Balance and Gait Function in the Elderly</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Home-Based Ankle Training Program on The Muscle Strength, Balance and Gait Function in the Elderly</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>China Medical University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>China Medical University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The occurrence of frequent falls influences the independence of the elderly's physical&#xD;
      functions, and the factors related to falls include: weakness in the lower limbs, age, past&#xD;
      injury experiences and so forth. Prolonged inactivity also increases the risk of falls, which&#xD;
      is subsequently prone to bringing about other complications, which enhances the odds of&#xD;
      falling again on the elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the literature, training methods for the lower limbs were for the most part of complex&#xD;
      training, whereas only a few studied on the single part training. In locomotion, the ankle&#xD;
      first touches the ground, needing strong ankle muscular strength to support the body.&#xD;
      Nevertheless, previous studies rarely mentioned whether a single ankle muscular strength&#xD;
      could reduce the risk of falls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Traditionally, the training of ankle muscular strength practically utilizes elastic bands,&#xD;
      and there are plenty of benefits confirmed in the literature. However, it is even harder to&#xD;
      implement the operation in reality, especially in the elderly. To resolve this problem&#xD;
      effectively, a new type of ankle training machine is added to this study. It can be adjusted&#xD;
      to different levels of resistance, provide multi directional training, and allow the subjects&#xD;
      to be trained in a sitting position achieving a stable state. In addition, this machine is&#xD;
      easy to operate for the elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aims of this research are: (1) to propose two different types of ankle training methods&#xD;
      and designed a 6 week training programs, (2) to explore whether the training programs can&#xD;
      improve muscular strength, balance capacity and gait function and (3) compare the training&#xD;
      effects between the two types of ankle training methods. In this study, 60 voluntary old&#xD;
      citizens, aged over 65, will be recruited, and they will be randomly divided into: 30 members&#xD;
      in the Elastic Band Training Group (EBTG) and 30 members in the New Ankle Training Machine&#xD;
      Training Group (NAMTG). During the six week workout plan, the subjects receive on site or&#xD;
      online guidance from professional coaches every two weeks; meanwhile, coaches can affirm&#xD;
      whether the plan is executed properly, confirming the effectiveness of the home training.&#xD;
      Through these two groups of home ankle training programs with different interventional&#xD;
      approaches lasting six weeks, the objective of the intervention is to boost muscular&#xD;
      strength, balance ability as well as gait ability, meanwhile to decline the risk of falls and&#xD;
      to reduce high medical expenses and care labor costs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 8, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 8, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle strength test</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline (before the training) at the completion of 6 weeks training</time_frame>
    <description>Sit-to-stand test, recoding by the time in seconds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postural stability test</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline (before the training) at the completion of 6 weeks training</time_frame>
    <description>One-leg standing with eye-open and eye-closed, recoding by the the center of pressure from a force plate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Y- balance test</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline (before the training) at the completion of 6 weeks training</time_frame>
    <description>Recoding the distance in the anterior, posterio-medial and posterio-lateral in cm.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Gait analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline (before the training) at the completion of 6 weeks training</time_frame>
    <description>Recoding the joint angle in degrees by the IMU sensors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>New ankle machine training group (NAMTG)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>home-based ankle training program consisted of 6 exercises for their general physical fitness and use a device (new ankle machine) to provide progressive resisted exercise for the ankle strength</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Elastic band training group (EBTG)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>home-based ankle training program consisted of 6 exercises for their general physical fitness and use Thera band to provide progressive resisted exercise for the ankle strength</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resistance training (New ankle machine training)</intervention_name>
    <description>A six week workout plan, the subjects receive on site or online guidance from professional coaches every two weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>New ankle machine training group (NAMTG)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resistance training (Elastic band training )</intervention_name>
    <description>A six week workout plan, the subjects receive on site or online guidance from professional coaches every two weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Elastic band training group (EBTG)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy elderly people over 65 years old have no exercise habits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The ability to walk independently or without equipment is at least 10m.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to independently perform activities related to daily life, such as doing&#xD;
             housework, walking, climbing stairs, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elderly people who have a history of minor stroke or upper limb surgery but have not&#xD;
             affected the ankle movement can be included in the scope of the case.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There is a musculoskeletal system disease, or the movement of the limbs is severely&#xD;
             restricted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If there is a history of lower limb surgery, which affects neurological symptoms and&#xD;
             mobility, it is excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclude specific diseases, such as stroke, spinal cord injury,etc., who have obvious&#xD;
             sequelae of movement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participated in other programs including Muscular strength, Balance ability, Gait&#xD;
             function training, etc. in the past 6 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>China Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung City</city>
        <zip>40402</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>China Medical University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hsiu-Chen Lin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ankle strengthening training</keyword>
  <keyword>Muscular strength</keyword>
  <keyword>Balance ability</keyword>
  <keyword>Gait function</keyword>
  <keyword>Elderly</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

