<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05617833</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00301237</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01HD104673-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05617833</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety of Erythropoietin and Melatonin for Very Preterm Infants With Intraventricular Hemorrhage</brief_title>
  <acronym>SCEMPI</acronym>
  <official_title>Safety of Combined Therapy With Erythropoietin and Melatonin for Very Preterm Infants With Intraventricular Hemorrhage (SCEMPI)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Very preterm infants are prone to numerous medical complications with lifelong impact.&#xD;
      Amongst the most serious are severe intraventricular hemorrhage (sIVH) and the subsequent&#xD;
      progression to posthemorrhagic hydrocephalus (PHH). Currently, the only treatment for PHH is&#xD;
      surgery, most commonly with shunts that are prone to malfunction across the lifespan.&#xD;
      Preclinical data show that melatonin (MLT) and erythropoietin (EPO), when administered in a&#xD;
      sustained dosing regimen, can prevent the hallmarks of progression from early postnatal sIVH&#xD;
      to subsequent PHH. The investigators will perform a Phase I, single institution, randomized,&#xD;
      double-blind trial for very preterm infants with sIVH to define a safe combination dose of&#xD;
      MLT and EPO. A maximum of 60 very preterm neonates with sIVH will be enrolled, treated&#xD;
      through 33w6/7d, and followed to 37w6/7d. Neonates will be randomized 3:1 between MLT+EPO and&#xD;
      placebo, with all receiving standard of care. The primary endpoint is a composite serious&#xD;
      adverse event (SAE)/dose limiting toxicity (DLT). The investigators hypothesize that the&#xD;
      MLT+EPO SAE/DLT rate will not be higher than the placebo rate. Secondary outcomes will be&#xD;
      rate of co-morbidities of preterm birth. Exploratory data, collected to guide design of&#xD;
      future clinical trials for efficacy, will include serial neuro-imaging metrics acquired from&#xD;
      clinical images, serial neonatal neurodevelopmental examinations, serum and urine MLT and EPO&#xD;
      levels, and liquid biomarkers. Successful implementation of this initial safety trial will&#xD;
      provide essential data to guide the next stage of clinical trials to test if sustained&#xD;
      MLT+EPO treatment can reduce the need for surgical intervention, and avoid the lifelong&#xD;
      burden of shunted hydrocephalus.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of SAE/DLT including death</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after the conclusion of treatment, up to 38 weeks gestational age</time_frame>
    <description>to test the hypothesis that rate of Serious Adverse Events (SAE)/dose limiting toxicity (DLT) with a cocktail of MLT and EPO in very preterm infants with severe intraventricular hemorrhage (sIVH) will have similar rate of SAE/DLT in subjects treated with placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of EPO plus MLT as assessed by rate of preterm birth related co-morbidities</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after the conclusion of treatment, up to 38 weeks gestational age</time_frame>
    <description>Determine whether treatment with EPO plus MLT alters the rate of preterm birth related co-morbidities compared to concurrent placebo controls.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Intraventricular Hemorrhage of Prematurity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MLT+EPO</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Melatonin 3 mg/mL oral syringe enterally every evening. For neonates weighing less than 1200 g, divide the dose in half and administer each half 30 minutes apart.&#xD;
High dose epoetin alfa epbx recombinant (1000 units/kg) syringe IV every 48 hours for 10 doses.&#xD;
Low dose epoetin alfa-epbx recombinant (400 units/kg) subcutaneously or intravenously three times weekly on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday until age 33-6/7wk.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo oral syringe enterally every evening.&#xD;
Placebo syringe IV every 48 hours for 10 doses.&#xD;
Placebo subcutaneously or intravenously three times weekly on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday until age 33-6/7wk.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MLT+EPO</intervention_name>
    <description>Melatonin component will be a single daily dose of 30 mg/kg enteral administered in the evening. EPO component is a two-stage regimen with high dose EPO (1000 U/kg/dose q 48 hrs ± 2hr IV) for 10 doses followed by maintenance dose EPO (400 U/kg/dose q Monday, Wednesday, Friday IV/SC) to 33-6/7wk. Maintenance EPO dosing will begin on the day closest to completing the high dose series.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MLT+EPO</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo enteral and IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU) inpatients born at &gt;22 and &lt;32 wks gestation (born&#xD;
             after 22w6d and before or on 31-6/7 wk GA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sIVH within the first 21 days from birth, defined as at least unilateral grade III5 on&#xD;
             head ultrasound performed within the past 5 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  expected to survive at least 3 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  absence of a congenital anomaly of metabolic or genetic disorder with expected&#xD;
             survival less than term equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  approval of the primary neonatologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  arterial or venous access&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  appropriate caregiver to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  life expectancy &lt;3 days for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe congenital anomaly or genetic disorder with life expectancy &lt;40 w&#xD;
             post-menstrual age (PMA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  liver failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe hematologic crisis such as disseminated intravascular coagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hydrops fetalis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  polycythemia (hematocrit &lt; 65%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hypertension for age requiring medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical concern or diagnosis of toxoplasmosis, cytomegalovirus, rubella or syphilis&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no appropriate person available or willing to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Hours</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>2 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shenandoah Robinson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jessica Wollett</last_name>
    <phone>667-306-8141</phone>
    <email>jwollet1@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>May 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 3, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 3, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

