<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05620368</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>01/2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05620368</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mindfulness for Mothers of Children With Disabilities</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mindfulness-Based Online Support Program for Mothers of Children With Disabilities</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Silesia in Katowice</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jan Dlugosz University in Czestochowa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of an eight-week&#xD;
      mindfulness-based teleintervention in improving quality of life, parental burnout,&#xD;
      self-compassion, and stress level in mothers of children with disabilities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Parenthood is accompanied by significant mental and physical effort accompanied by different&#xD;
      sources of long-term stress and encumbrance. The results of this research indicate serious&#xD;
      difficulties in the functioning of parents of children with disabilities, such as pain,&#xD;
      emotional and physical discomfort, anxiety, depression, and problems resulting from the&#xD;
      realization of everyday life activities combined with the care of the child. They indicate&#xD;
      how serious this crisis is and how important life constraints it brings to the individual and&#xD;
      the social functioning of the family.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A parent's ability to adapt to stressful situations depends on several variables, including&#xD;
      an individual's psychological strengths, individual and family resources, and the type of&#xD;
      coping strategies utilized. Parental burnout is defined as a syndrome that occurs in response&#xD;
      to chronic parental stress. The risk of parental burnout is related to family functioning. In&#xD;
      the concept of family as an interactional system, &quot;family adaptability is the degree to which&#xD;
      the family is flexible and can regain equilibrium in stressful and challenging situations or&#xD;
      environments&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positive coping styles such as positive perceptions and effective problem-solving skills were&#xD;
      associated with successful family adaptation and resilience. Twenty years ago, the concept of&#xD;
      mindful parenting was introduced as an alternative to traditional discipline-oriented methods&#xD;
      by focusing on the quality of a parent's presence in the parent-child dyad. It focuses on&#xD;
      cultivating mindfulness and attunement with the parent's inner experience while interacting&#xD;
      with the child, and feeling the full range of emotions related to parenting. Mindful&#xD;
      parenting involves cultivating non-judgmental awareness of the unfolding of internal and&#xD;
      external experiences in daily life, practicing emotion regulation skills, learning about&#xD;
      adaptive responses to distress, and developing a self-compassionate attitude toward one's&#xD;
      fallibility, limitations, and suffering.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compassion- and mindfulness-based interventions (CMBIs) hold promise in supporting parental&#xD;
      resilience by enabling adaptive stress appraisal and coping, mindful parenting, and&#xD;
      self-compassion. These interventions also aimed to reduce social isolation by increasing the&#xD;
      capacity for connections. Perceived social support, an aspect of compassionate behavior, is a&#xD;
      potent buffer against stress on health outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the main objective of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of an eight-week&#xD;
      mindfulness-based teleintervention in improving quality of life, parental burnout,&#xD;
      self-compassion, and stress level in mothers of children with disabilities. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that the mindfulness-based teleintervention compared with the control group will&#xD;
      lead to (A) an improvement in positive aspects of mental health, including quality of life,&#xD;
      and self-compassion, and (B) a reduction in psychopathological variables including perceived&#xD;
      stress and parental burnout.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Families in Early Intervention Quality of Life (FEIQoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Families in Early Intervention Quality of Life (FEIQoL) questionnaire will be used for assessing the quality of life. Participants answer 40 items using a five-point Likert scale (1, 'poor' to 5, 'excellent') in the aspects of family life (24 items), and child's functioning (16 items).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental Burnout Measure (PBM-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Parental Burnout will be assessed with the Parental Burnout Measure (PBM-12) measures parental burnout in two dimensions: exhaustion and helplessness. Both dimensions are measured as a sum of 6 items, answered on a 4-point Likert scale (1, 'never' to 4, 'very often'). Fully satisfactory internal reliability indicators (Cronbach's alpha) were reached by all burnout measures - PBM-12 total score (.90), exhaustion subscale (.88), and helplessness sub-scale (.80).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-Compassion Scale (SCS)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>To assess self-compassion we will use a polish adaptation of the Self-Compassion Scale (SCS). Items on the SCS use a five-point Likert scale to measure conformity (1, 'almost never' to 5, 'almost always'). The final SCS score ranges from 26 to 130. A higher score indicates a higher level of self-compassion. This scale has good internal consistency and test-retest reliability (.93).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Stress Scale (PSS-10)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The 10-item Perceived Stress Scale (PSS-10) will be used to measure self-reported stress. This scale includes 10 questions, with answers ranked using a 5-point Likert scale, and assesses stressful experiences and responses to stress over the previous 4 weeks. Scores range from 0 to 56, with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ego Resilience Scale (ER89)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The Ego-Resiliency Scale (ER89) measures the construct of ego-resiliency, which refers to the dynamic capacity of an individual to modify a characteristic level of ego-control, in either direction, as a function of the demand characteristics of the environmental context, so as to preserve or enhance system equilibration. It consists of 14 items, each responded to on a 4-point scale (1 = &quot;does not apply at all&quot;; 2 = &quot;applies slightly, if at all&quot;; 3 = &quot;applies somewhat&quot;; and 4 = &quot;applies very strongly&quot;).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Parental Burnout</condition>
  <condition>Caregiver Burnout</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness-based teleintervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>8-week Mindfulness and Compassionate Living Course (MCLC). The course will be held online (using the Zoom platform) with weekly sessions lasting 2.5 hours each, as well as a day of silent practice (mini-retreat of 4 hours).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The facility provides psychological support for parents as needed and at the request of the parent. Support includes individual support of a psychologist (1h / week), consultation with a teacher (special pedagogue and early school education teacher, 1h / week), individual consultation with observation of a child with a Venetian mirror (1h / week).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness and Compassionate Living Course (MCLC)</intervention_name>
    <description>The course will be held online (using the Zoom platform) with weekly sessions lasting 2.5 hours each, as well as a day of silent practice (mini-retreat of 4 hours) between sessions 6 and 7.&#xD;
On the structural level, every course session consists of four elements: (1) an educational input, (2) mindfulness and compassion exercises (eg, sitting meditation, body scan, mindful walking, self-compassion break), (3) a reflection of one's practice (inquiry), (4) and home assignments.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness-based teleintervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Usual care intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>If necessary, psychological support is organized at the request of the parent.&#xD;
Support includes individual support of a psychologist (1h / week), consultation with a teacher (special pedagogue and early school education teacher, 1h / week), individual consultation with observation of a child with a Venetian mirror (1h / week).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mother of childern with disabilities&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  substance abuse;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  participation in another therapeutic project or individual psychotherapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  antidepressant treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Małgorzata Sekułowicz, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Krystyna Boroń-Krupińska, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sylwia Wrona, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Silesia in Katowice</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wroclaw</city>
        <state>Lower Silesia</state>
        <zip>51-612</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jan Dlugosz University in Czestochowa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Częstochowa</city>
        <state>Upper Silesia</state>
        <zip>42-200</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Silesia in Katowice</name>
      <address>
        <city>Katowice</city>
        <state>Upper Silesi</state>
        <zip>40-007</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zessin U, Dickhauser O, Garbade S. The Relationship Between Self-Compassion and Well-Being: A Meta-Analysis. Appl Psychol Health Well Being. 2015 Nov;7(3):340-64. doi: 10.1111/aphw.12051. Epub 2015 Aug 26.</citation>
    <PMID>26311196</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Allen AB, Leary MR. Self-Compassion, Stress, and Coping. Soc Personal Psychol Compass. 2010 Feb 1;4(2):107-118. doi: 10.1111/j.1751-9004.2009.00246.x.</citation>
    <PMID>20686629</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Neece CL, Chan N, Klein K, Roberts L, Fenning RM. Mindfulness-Based Stress Reduction for Parents of Children with Developmental Delays: Understanding the Experiences of Latino Families. Mindfulness (N Y). 2019 Jun;10(6):1017-1030. doi: 10.1007/s12671-018-1011-3. Epub 2018 Sep 6.</citation>
    <PMID>31191735</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bohadana G, Morrissey S, Paynter J. Self-compassion: A Novel Predictor of Stress and Quality of Life in Parents of Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder. J Autism Dev Disord. 2019 Oct;49(10):4039-4052. doi: 10.1007/s10803-019-04121-x.</citation>
    <PMID>31267283</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bohadana G, Morrissey S, Paynter J. Self-Compassion in Mothers of Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder: A Qualitative Analysis. J Autism Dev Disord. 2021 Apr;51(4):1290-1303. doi: 10.1007/s10803-020-04612-2.</citation>
    <PMID>32656737</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bogels SM, Lehtonen A, Restifo K. Mindful Parenting in Mental Health Care. Mindfulness (N Y). 2010 Jun;1(2):107-120. doi: 10.1007/s12671-010-0014-5. Epub 2010 May 25.</citation>
    <PMID>21125026</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang H, Wang Q, Hu X, Han ZR. Mindfulness and Stress Among Parents of Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder in China. J Autism Dev Disord. 2022 May;52(5):2035-2045. doi: 10.1007/s10803-021-05011-x. Epub 2021 May 29.</citation>
    <PMID>34050845</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cousineau TM, Hobbs LM, Arthur KC. The Role of Compassion and Mindfulness in Building Parental Resilience When Caring for Children With Chronic Conditions: A Conceptual Model. Front Psychol. 2019 Aug 5;10:1602. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01602. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31428005</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Duncan LG, Coatsworth JD, Greenberg MT. A model of mindful parenting: implications for parent-child relationships and prevention research. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. 2009 Sep;12(3):255-70. doi: 10.1007/s10567-009-0046-3.</citation>
    <PMID>19412664</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ettman CK, Abdalla SM, Cohen GH, Sampson L, Vivier PM, Galea S. Prevalence of Depression Symptoms in US Adults Before and During the COVID-19 Pandemic. JAMA Netw Open. 2020 Sep 1;3(9):e2019686. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.19686.</citation>
    <PMID>32876685</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Friis AM, Johnson MH, Cutfield RG, Consedine NS. Kindness Matters: A Randomized Controlled Trial of a Mindful Self-Compassion Intervention Improves Depression, Distress, and HbA1c Among Patients With Diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2016 Nov;39(11):1963-1971. doi: 10.2337/dc16-0416. Epub 2016 Jun 22.</citation>
    <PMID>27335319</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Homan KJ, Sirois FM. Self-compassion and physical health: Exploring the roles of perceived stress and health-promoting behaviors. Health Psychol Open. 2017 Sep 14;4(2):2055102917729542. doi: 10.1177/2055102917729542. eCollection 2017 Jul-Dec.</citation>
    <PMID>29379620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ten Hoopen LW, de Nijs PFA, Duvekot J, Greaves-Lord K, Hillegers MHJ, Brouwer WBF, Hakkaart-van Roijen L. Children with an Autism Spectrum Disorder and Their Caregivers: Capturing Health-Related and Care-Related Quality of Life. J Autism Dev Disord. 2020 Jan;50(1):263-277. doi: 10.1007/s10803-019-04249-w.</citation>
    <PMID>31625009</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuhlthau KA, Luberto CM, Traeger L, Millstein RA, Perez GK, Lindly OJ, Chad-Friedman E, Proszynski J, Park ER. A Virtual Resiliency Intervention for Parents of Children with Autism: A Randomized Pilot Trial. J Autism Dev Disord. 2020 Jul;50(7):2513-2526. doi: 10.1007/s10803-019-03976-4.</citation>
    <PMID>30900195</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Robinson S, Hastings RP, Weiss JA, Pagavathsing J, Lunsky Y. Self-compassion and psychological distress in parents of young people and adults with intellectual and developmental disabilities. J Appl Res Intellect Disabil. 2018 May;31(3):454-458. doi: 10.1111/jar.12423. Epub 2017 Nov 9.</citation>
    <PMID>29119672</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Turnage D, Conner N. Quality of life of parents of children with Autism Spectrum Disorder: An integrative literature review. J Spec Pediatr Nurs. 2022 Oct;27(4):e12391. doi: 10.1111/jspn.12391. Epub 2022 Aug 20.</citation>
    <PMID>35986656</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 17, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 17, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 20, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Błażej Cieślik</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>parental burnout</keyword>
  <keyword>meditation</keyword>
  <keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>self-compassion</keyword>
  <keyword>stress level</keyword>
  <keyword>parents of children with disability</keyword>
  <keyword>autism</keyword>
  <keyword>quality of life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Psychological</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Caregiver Burden</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

