<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619757</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>69HCL22_0547</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619757</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Compliance and Endometriosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Compliance With Medical Treatment for Endometriosis : a Cross-sectional Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospices Civils de Lyon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospices Civils de Lyon</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Endometriosis is defined as the presence of hormone-dependent endometrial tissue outside the&#xD;
      uterine cavity. It is a chronic, painful and often disabling pathology during the normal&#xD;
      activities of daily life. It affects 10% of women of childbearing age. It is therefore a real&#xD;
      public health issue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The latest recommendations from the HAS and the CNGOF now recommend primary medical&#xD;
      management of endometriosis in painful women who do not wish to become pregnant. It should be&#xD;
      remembered that until very recently, the teams resigned themselves to carrying out surgical&#xD;
      interventions in order to support the diagnosis (this is histological and requires a biopsy)&#xD;
      and to treat the patient if possible. Sometimes, this treatment was not possible from the&#xD;
      outset, as the lesions appeared to be inaccessible, and additional hormonal treatment was&#xD;
      therefore required. The current concept is to propose to patients a first hormonal&#xD;
      suppressive treatment before a possible surgery. This therapeutic de-escalation should be&#xD;
      considered in the light of the physiopathology of endometriosis, which is essentially based&#xD;
      on the ovarian cycles, and indirectly on menstruation, which must then be suspended. However,&#xD;
      a good number of patients are initially reluctant to undergo any kind of hormonal therapy,&#xD;
      either because they have had a bad experience with hormonal contraception (intolerance) or&#xD;
      because of a fear related to the possible complications of hormonal therapy with third or&#xD;
      fourth generation pills, for example (thromboembolic risk). There is also a health alert at&#xD;
      present concerning macro progestins in relation to the risk of meningioma. Acceptance of the&#xD;
      principle of instituting amenorrhea in order to relieve patients suffering from endometriosis&#xD;
      requires prior information. In investigator's daily practice, they frequently deplore&#xD;
      non-compliance, which is detrimental to the proper management of the disease. The&#xD;
      effectiveness of hormonal treatment, which will institute a quiescence of hormonal activity,&#xD;
      is not immediate. An analgesic and anti-inflammatory treatment is then added. Investigators&#xD;
      propose to compare the compliance of three drug strategies: analgesics alone, hormone therapy&#xD;
      alone or hormone therapy and analgesics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 21, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance measured by the Morisky Medication Adherence Scales (MMAS-8).</measure>
    <time_frame>10 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>This self-administered questionnaire validated in French has 8 items each scored 0 or 1. A high score indicates high compliance: high compliance (score = 8), average compliance (score of 6 to &lt; 8) and low compliance (score &lt; 6). Patients with a score greater than or equal to 6 will be considered as compliant. This questionnaire has been validated in French.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometriosis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Compliance with medical treatment for endometriosis</intervention_name>
    <description>During their scheduled consultation at the Hôpital Femme Mère Enfant (HFME), women who meet the eligibility criteria will be presented with the study and given the written information note. If they agree to participate, the investigator will give them a QR code redirecting them to the online self-questionnaire.&#xD;
Patients will be included once they log in and complete the questionnaire.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study will include women with painful endometriosis who have never had endometriosis&#xD;
        surgery. In addition, patients must speak and understand French and be over 18 years old.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be a woman with diagnosed painful endometriosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a prescription for medication (analgesics alone, hormone therapy alone or hormone&#xD;
             therapy and analgesics).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speak and understand French&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be a woman over 18 years old until menopause&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Be a woman who has already had surgery for endometriosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Erdogan NOHUZ, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>04.27.85.53.53</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>erdogan.nohuz@chu-lyon.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Service de Gynécologie-Obstétrique, Sénologie et Oncologie, Hôpital Femme Mère Enfant, Hospices Civils de Lyon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bron</city>
        <zip>69500</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erdogan NOHUZ, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>04.27.85.53.53</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>erdogan.nohuz@chu-lyon.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erdogan NOHUZ, Professor</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Endometriosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug treatments</keyword>
  <keyword>Hormonal treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>Compliance</keyword>
  <keyword>Amenorrhea</keyword>
  <keyword>Recommendations</keyword>
  <keyword>Menstruation</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficiency</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometriosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

