<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05796908</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AP-PRO-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05796908</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Aptis PRUJ Prosthesis for the Treatment of Patients With Proximal Radial Ulna Joint Disorders.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Multi-Center, Single-Arm Clinical Trial of the Safety and Effectiveness of the Aptis PRUJ Prosthesis for the Treatment of Patients With Proximal Radial Ulna Joint Disorders.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aptis Medical</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>MCRA</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aptis Medical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Prospective, Multi-Center, Single-Arm Clinical Trial of the safety and effectiveness of the&#xD;
      Aptis PRUJ prosthesis for the treatment of patients with proximal radial ulna joint disorders&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, multi-center, single-arm clinical trial of the safety and&#xD;
      effectiveness of the Aptis PRUJ prosthesis for the treatment of patients with proximal radial&#xD;
      ulna joint disorders. A total of 84 patients will be enrolled in this trial with 9 centers&#xD;
      participating in the US. The total study duration will be approximately 36 months, with an&#xD;
      enrollment period of 12 months, followed by a 24 month follow-up period. Annual visits will&#xD;
      continue until the last patient reaches the 2-year post-operative time point.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sucess</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>A non-inferiority composite primary endpoint for effectiveness and safety, where a subject is considered a success if they meet the following criteria:&#xD;
Mayo Elbow Performance Score, where success is defined as Good or Excellent at 24 months; and&#xD;
Absence of radiographic evidence of periprosthetic osteolysis (radiolucent line &gt;2mm around entire radial stem and ulnar screws), and no screw breakage at 24 months; and&#xD;
Absence of device-related serious adverse events including any revisions and removals through 24 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The following secondary endpoints will evaluate the effectiveness of the investigational device:&#xD;
Pre- vs. Post-operative function assessed via Mayo Elbow Performance Score&#xD;
Mayo Subscores&#xD;
Pain&#xD;
Range of motion&#xD;
Instability&#xD;
Function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in overall health at all follow-up time points assessed via SF-36</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in disability index assessed at all follow-up time points via DASH</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Radiolucencies around radial stem and ulnar screws</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Subsidence of radial component</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Screw breakage</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ulnar variance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Economic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Use of other concomitant medications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Economic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Post-operative recovery time (return to daily activities/work)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Economic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months, 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Post-operative rehabilitation details</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">84</enrollment>
  <condition>Arthritis</condition>
  <condition>Unstable Radial Head</condition>
  <condition>Proximal Radioulnar Joint Instability</condition>
  <condition>Decreased Motion at the Proximal Radioulnar Joint and/or the Radio-humeral Joint</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aptis PRUJ Prothesis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Investigational Aptis PRUJ Prothesis treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aptis PRUJ Prosthesis</intervention_name>
    <description>A prosthetic implant for replacement of the proximal radial ulna joint.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aptis PRUJ Prothesis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In order to be eligible to participate in this study, subjects must meet all of the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patient is skeletally mature and under 85 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patient has a painful, unstable radial head due to degeneration or post-traumatic&#xD;
                  disabilities presenting pain, crepitation, and decreased motion at the&#xD;
                  radiohumeral and/or proximal radioulnar joint and is otherwise&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients willing and able to understand and sign the informed consent. In the&#xD;
                  opinion of the Investigator, the patient has the understanding and willingness to&#xD;
                  comply with all study requirements including the post-operative rehabilitation&#xD;
                  and follow-up visits per protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Inadequate bone stock or soft tissue coverage 2. Patients with severe humeral/ulnar&#xD;
             arthritis, defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Pain at terminal flexion/extension&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Pain throughout ROM with loss of motion in terminal flexion and/or extension 3.&#xD;
                  Patients with an allergy to the implant materials 4. Active systemic infection or&#xD;
                  infection at the site of surgery 5. Physical interference with or by other&#xD;
                  prostheses during implantation or use 6. Have a Body Mass Index (BMI) greater&#xD;
                  than 35 kg/m2 7. Have any mental or psychological disorder that would impair the&#xD;
                  ability to complete the study questionnaires 8. Have significant comorbidities or&#xD;
                  conditions associated with high-risk for surgical or anesthetic survival (e.g.,&#xD;
                  renal failure, peripheral vascular disease, unstable cardiac disease, poorly&#xD;
                  controlled diabetes, immunosuppression, etc.) 9. Have any medical condition or&#xD;
                  other circumstances that might interfere with the ability to return for follow-up&#xD;
                  visits in the judgment of the Investigator, including any systemic illness,&#xD;
                  neuromuscular, neurosensory, or musculoskeletal deficiency that would render the&#xD;
                  subject unable to perform appropriate post-operative rehabilitation 10. Have any&#xD;
                  condition which, in the judgment of the Investigator, would preclude adequate&#xD;
                  evaluation of the device's safety and performance 11. Skin, bone, circulatory&#xD;
                  and/or neurological deficiency at or affecting the implantation site 12.&#xD;
                  Prisoners 13. Patients on chronic corticosteroid or non-steroidal&#xD;
                  anti-inflammatory therapy 14. Women who are pregnant or breast-feeding or are&#xD;
                  planning to become pregnant during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  15. Patients with a documented history of uncontrolled diabetes. 16. Patients&#xD;
                  with known allergies against anesthesia. 17. Patients with a history of or&#xD;
                  current drug and/or alcohol abuse 18. Patients unlikely to cooperate or are&#xD;
                  legally incompetent. 19. Patients with legal involvement, including an active&#xD;
                  claim for workman's compensation, or any other issue that would hinder completion&#xD;
                  of the two-year follow period.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  20. Patients who are participating or have participated in any other study&#xD;
                  involving an investigational drug or device within the past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Intra-operative Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Subjects who meet any of the following intra-operative screening criteria will be&#xD;
                  excluded from participation in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  A proximal radio ulnar joint that cannot be reduced intraoperatively&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Inadequate bone quality that would allow for implant placement&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Not enough radius bone proximally for device implantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John Scheker</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Aptis Medical</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer N Jennings</last_name>
    <phone>12027423861</phone>
    <email>JJennings@mcra.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 10, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PRUJ</keyword>
  <keyword>Disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>radio-humeral joint</keyword>
  <keyword>proximal radioulnar joint</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Joint Instability</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

