<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612399</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY22060101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612399</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Precision Analgesia for Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Precision Perioperative Methadone Use in Adult Cardiac Surgical Patients to Reduce Opioid Use Adverse Effects While Improving Analgesia and Outcomes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kathirvel Subramaniam</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed research is an important extension of an ongoing perioperative personalized&#xD;
      analgesia and intravenous opioid pharmacogenetic research. This research focuses on two of&#xD;
      the most commonly used oral opioid analgesics, oxycodone, and methadone in elderly adults&#xD;
      undergoing cardiac surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiac surgery patients often experience significant acute postoperative pain, and untreated&#xD;
      or undertreated pain has consequences. Each year, 900,000 painful cardiac surgeries occur in&#xD;
      the US alone. Pain associated with cardiac surgery results from surgical incision, sternal&#xD;
      retraction, internal mammary artery harvesting, saphenous vein removal, placement of&#xD;
      mediastinal and chest drains, sternal wires, and release of pro-inflammatory mediators after&#xD;
      tissue injury. One study reported that 49%, 62%, and 78% of patients reported severe pain at&#xD;
      rest, movement, and coughing, respectively after coronary artery bypass surgery (CABG).&#xD;
      Another study showed that 61.4% of patients undergoing cardiac surgery reported moderate to&#xD;
      severe pain. Inadequate pain treatment is common in cardiac surgery due to health care&#xD;
      providers' fears of causing cardiorespiratory compromise. Poor pain control can trigger&#xD;
      sympathoadrenal responses leading to cardiac arrhythmias and myocardial ischemia, restrict&#xD;
      mobility to cause venous thrombosis, impair clearance of secretions leading to pulmonary&#xD;
      complications such as atelectasis and pneumonia, decrease patient satisfaction and predispose&#xD;
      to the development of chronic, persistent surgical pain (CPSP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Improving clinical practice by shifting paradigms: Our research is transformative and will&#xD;
      evolve current reactive clinical practice towards proactive precision methods based on&#xD;
      genetic risks for surgical pain and ORADE in elderly vulnerable population. This is the first&#xD;
      effort to move in the direction of personalizing perioperative opioid use with precise dosing&#xD;
      to improve safety and efficacy in cardiac surgery. Preoperative genotyping-based clinical&#xD;
      decisions are expected to support clinical implementation in real-world settings.&#xD;
      Importantly, investigators will be able to reach beyond the current best-in-class outcomes&#xD;
      with precision multi-dose methadone analgesia based on proactive genetic risk identification&#xD;
      to maximize safety and efficacy of opioids in all cardiac surgical patients and positively&#xD;
      impact socio-economic outcomes in the future. By addressing these critical barriers, this&#xD;
      research will help physicians identify patients at risk and improve the safety and efficacy&#xD;
      of opioids and surgical pain management while preventing OD, misuse, overdose, and deaths.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine Genetic Factors - Opioid Related Adverse Events (RD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately post-surgery during hospital stay</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory depression will be measured with binary yes/no responses obtained either via self-report from the patient or reported by the clinical care staff.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine Genetic Factors - Opioid Related Adverse Events (PONV)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately post-surgery during hospital stay</time_frame>
    <description>Post-operative nausea and vomiting will be measured with binary yes/no responses obtained either via self-report from the patient or reported by the clinical care staff.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine Genetic Factors - Opioid Related Adverse Events (Excessive Sedation)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately post-surgery during hospital stay</time_frame>
    <description>Excessive sedation will be measured with binary yes/no responses obtained either via self-report from the patient or reported by the clinical care staff.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine Genetic Factors - Uncontrolled severe pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately post-surgery during hospital stay</time_frame>
    <description>We postulate that specific CYP2B6, ABCB1, OPRM1, FAAH, and ORM1 genetic variants identify patients at risk for poor pain relief and ORADE with methadone in the immediate post-surgical period. Pain will be measured by the Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) in which 0 = no pain at all and 10 = worst pain imaginable. This will be self-reported responses by the patient.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Analgesia</condition>
  <condition>Cardiac Surgery</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      One Pharmacogenetic (PG) blood sample collection of 1-3mL obtained prior to surgery.&#xD;
      Genotyping will include ABCB1, CYP2B6, OPRM1, FAAH, CYP2D6, ORM1, and CYP3A4. Other relevant&#xD;
      exploratory genes in custom gene panel will include ADRB2, GCH1, TRPA1, COMT, and DRD2&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Elderly cardiac surgical patients over 60 years of age Both genders are included All races&#xD;
        and ethnic groups undergoing elective open cardiac surgery through midline sternotomy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elderly cardiac surgical patients over 60 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Methadone allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Morbid obesity (BMI &gt;40kg/cm2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe sleep apnea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe pulmonary disease requiring oxygen therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preoperative mechanical circulatory support&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergency surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver disease (liver enzymes more than two times normal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  End-stage renal disease requiring dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine more than 2.0mg&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kathirvel Subramaniam, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amy Monroe, MPH, MBA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alisha Maslanka, BS, CCRC</last_name>
    <phone>412-864-6779</phone>
    <email>maslankaaa@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Carly Riedmann, BS</last_name>
    <phone>412-623-4147</phone>
    <email>riedmannca@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UPMC Presbyterian Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kathirvel Subramaniam, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <email>subramaniamk@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Amy Monroe, MPH, MBA</last_name>
      <phone>412-623-6382</phone>
      <email>monroeal@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 6, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 6, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 10, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kathirvel Subramaniam</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Agnosia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

