<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05619575</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLTD5836</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05619575</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acceptance and Performance of the CP1170 Sound Processor in Experienced Adult Cochlear Implant Recipients (POLAR)</brief_title>
  <acronym>POLAR</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pre-market, Open-label, Within Subject Study, of Acceptance and Performance of the CP1170 Sound Processor in Experienced Adult Cochlear Implant Recipients Compared With the CP1150 Sound Processor and Their Current Sound Processor.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cochlear</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Avania</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cochlear</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acceptance and performance of the CP1170 sound processor in experienced adult cochlear&#xD;
      implant recipients compared with the CP1150 sound processor and their current sound&#xD;
      processor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This investigation is planned to investigate the performance and clinical benefits of&#xD;
      features that are new to the CP 1170 Sound Processor. This study will build on the evidence&#xD;
      previously collected on OTE (off the ear) sound processors and ForwardFocus, with particular&#xD;
      focus on the acceptance and satisfaction of the automation of ForwardFocus in the CP1170&#xD;
      Sound Processor and associated components in general.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 20, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Speech perception testing - Speech in Noise using CP1170 sound processor using FF (forwardfocus)</measure>
    <time_frame>One day (in booth testing)</time_frame>
    <description>Paired difference in dB SRT between the CP1170 SCAN 2 FF (Automated ForwardFocus ON) and CP1170 SCAN 2 (ForwardFocus OFF) (65 dB SPL (sound pressure level) S0Nrearhalf 4Talker Babble).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Speech perception testing - Speech in Noise using CP1170 sound processor using FF (forwardfocus)</measure>
    <time_frame>One day (in booth testing)</time_frame>
    <description>Paired difference in dB SRT between the CP1170 SCAN 2 FF (ForwardFocus ON) and CP1170 SCAN 2 (ForwardFocus OFF), (65 dB SPL S0N3 Babble).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Speech perception in quiet with CP1170 and CP1150 Sound Processors</measure>
    <time_frame>One day (in booth testing)</time_frame>
    <description>Paired difference in percentage CNC (consonant-nucleus-consonant) Words correct in quiet (50 dB) between the CP1170 sound processor and CP1150 sound processor (commercial version)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective acceptance and satisfaction between the CP1170 sound processor and the subject's own processor.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Ratings based on the CP1170 Questionnaire after a minimum 2-weeks actual-use of the CP1170 sound processor in the home environment and the subject's own processor.&#xD;
The CP1170 Questionnaire has a 5-point Likert scale for each rating in the questionnaire for at home usage ( with the values ranging from) : 1 = least favourable option to 3 = Neutral to 5 = most favourable option.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective hearing performance between the CP1170 sound processor and the subject's own processor</measure>
    <time_frame>One day</time_frame>
    <description>Paired difference in Global SSQ12 scores after experience with the CP1170 sound processor and own processor.&#xD;
The SSQ-12 is comprised of 12 items using the response format on a scale from 0 to 10, were 0 equals no ability and 10 equals perfect ability. These are divided into three sub-scales and the questions 1-5 are from the speech sub-scale, 6-8 from the spatial, and 9-12 from the qualities sub-scale. The three sub-scales are the average of the questions within. A 'not applicable' option is given for each item.&#xD;
The change from baseline is then calculated and the theoretical score could vary between -10 to +10. The higher the score the better benefit and positive score indicates improved hearing, a negative value an impaired hearing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Hearing Impairment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CP1170 sound processor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Take home use of CP1170 Sound processor for 2 weeks followed by in booth testing of the investigational device.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CP1150 sound processor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In booth testing of CP1150 sound processor.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CP1170 sound processor</intervention_name>
    <description>The CP 1170 sound processor will be used to determine the hearing performance with the new implementation of ForwardFocus in SCAN 2 (SCAN 2 FF), as assessed by speech perception in noise.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CP1170 sound processor</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CP1150 Sound processor</intervention_name>
    <description>Active comparator off the ear sound processor.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CP1150 sound processor</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Post lingually deafened&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Implanted with the CI600 Series (CI612, CI632, CI622, CI624), CI500 Series (CI512,&#xD;
             CI532, CI522); Freedom Series (CI24RE(CA), CI24RE(ST), CI422) or N24 Series (CIC3).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least 6 months experience with a cochlear hearing implant&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At least 3 months experience with any Nucleus sound processor and SCAN program&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to score 30% or more at +15 SNR with CI alone on a sentence in babble test&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Willingness to participate in and to comply with all requirements of the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Fluent speaker in English as determined by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Willing and able to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Additional disabilities that would prevent participation in evaluations&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Unrealistic expectations on the part of the subject, regarding the possible benefits,&#xD;
             risks and limitations that are inherent to the procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Unable or unwilling to comply with the requirements of the clinical investigation as&#xD;
             determined by the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Investigator site personnel directly affiliated with this study and/or their immediate&#xD;
             families; immediate family is defined as a spouse, parent, child, or sibling&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Cochlear employees or employees of Contract Research Organisations or contractors&#xD;
             engaged by Cochlear for the purposes of this investigation, as determined by the&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Current participation, or participation in another interventional clinical study/trial&#xD;
             in the past 30 days, involving an investigational drug or device (unless the other&#xD;
             investigation was/is a Cochlear sponsored investigation and determined by the&#xD;
             investigator or Sponsor to not impact this investigation).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cochlear Macquarie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Macquarie</city>
        <state>Sydney</state>
        <zip>2109</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 18, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 18, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Deafness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

