<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798273</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ErasmusMC-2020-0338</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798273</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>(68^Ga)-GaPSMA-11 PET/MR-imaging of Malignant Intra-axial Brain Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>[68Ga] Ga-PSMA-11 PET/MR-imaging of Malignant Intra-axial Brain Tumors; Primary Assessment of PSMA Expression, Optimization of Compound Delivery and Determination of Theranostic Potential</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Erasmus Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Erasmus Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      PSMA is a transmembrane protein specifically expressed in the vascular endothelium of&#xD;
      malignant brain tumors, most notably glioblastoma and not in healthy brain parenchyma. It has&#xD;
      been shown to be involved in (neo)angiogenesis and endothelial cell invasion. By means of&#xD;
      68Ga-labeled PSMA ligands, investigators are able to non-invasively visualize/quantify PSMA&#xD;
      expression in glioblastoma (neo)vasculature in vivo by means of PET.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim of this study is to confirm PSMA as suitable diagnostic and potential&#xD;
      theranostic target in patients with intra-axial brain tumors by means of&#xD;
      [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-HBEC-CC ([68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11) PET.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary aim is to assess whether uptake is increased with intra-arterial injection in&#xD;
      those tumors that show uptake after intravenous injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Brain tumors have a major impact due to both high morbidity and mortality. Primary brain&#xD;
      tumors (glioma) have a low incidence (5-7:100,000), but the highest loss of life years&#xD;
      compared to other cancer types. Glioblastoma without mutations in the Isocitrate&#xD;
      Dehydrogenase gene (IDHwt), are the most frequent and the most aggressive of all primary&#xD;
      malignant brain tumors. They account for 48% of all the primary malignant brain tumors and&#xD;
      15% of all primary brain tumors. Treatment consists of resection, radiotherapy and systemic&#xD;
      chemotherapy. Nevertheless the current prognosis is still poor with a 1-, 2- and 5-year&#xD;
      survival of respectively 40%, 17% and 6%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary brain tumors (brain metastases) are frequent, occurring in 15% of cancer patients&#xD;
      (incidence 50-70:100,000). The prevalence of brain metastases is rising due to better&#xD;
      extracranial local cancer control with systemic treatment resulting in more surviving&#xD;
      patients with good local tumor control, but with brain metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A recently discovered potential target for (localized) therapy of glioblastoma is PSMA. PSMA&#xD;
      was originally found to be specifically expressed in normal prostate, and overexpressed in&#xD;
      almost all stages of prostate cancer. In recent years, PSMA was also found to be expressed in&#xD;
      tumor-associated (neo)vasculature in many other solid tumors, including glioblastoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PSMA is distinct from other vascular targets, such as vascular endothelial growth factor,&#xD;
      endoglin, or the integrins involved in the general process of angiogenesis, as these latter&#xD;
      are not specific to tumor vasculature. PSMA, in contrast, is not expressed in normal&#xD;
      vasculature and is only minimally expressed in a subset of normal glial cells. PSMA therewith&#xD;
      represents the most specific (neo)vascular target for glioblastoma currently known.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This specificity makes PSMA an ideal target for delivery of a cytotoxic agent or a&#xD;
      radionuclide designed to tumor vasculature destruction. Particularly in intra-axial brain&#xD;
      tumors such as glioblastoma, therapeutic targeting of (neo)vasculature is attractive as it&#xD;
      may be exposed to a therapeutic agent much more readily than the tumor parenchyma itself,&#xD;
      which is protected by the blood-brain barrier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim of this first PSMA-PET study performed in the Netherlands is to confirm PSMA&#xD;
      as suitable diagnostic and theranostic target in patients with intra-axial brain tumors by&#xD;
      means of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-HBEC-CC ([68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11) PET. The secondary aim is to assess whether&#xD;
      uptake is increased with intra-arterial injection in those tumors that show uptake after&#xD;
      intravenous injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible for this non-treatment study are patient, aged &gt;18 years old, with enhancing glioma&#xD;
      or brain metastases scheduled for (re-)resection. Upon informed consent, patients will&#xD;
      undergo intravenous injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11, followed by synchronously combined PET-MR&#xD;
      scans at 45-60 min post-injection to determine [68Ga]Ga-PSMA tumor uptake and dosimetry over&#xD;
      time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the known expression profile of PSMA in glioblastoma, it is expected that&#xD;
      significant tumor-uptake will be seen in 50% of included patients. In case the tumor shows&#xD;
      significant uptake, patients will subsequently undergo local intra-arterial injection of [&#xD;
      68Ga]GaPSMA-11, with an interval of two weeks, performed by a trained neuro-interventional&#xD;
      radiologist, immediately followed by a repeat PET/MRI scan. Tumor uptake values of each of&#xD;
      the scans will be compared to determine the optimal route of administration. [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11&#xD;
      uptake values of the tumor will be compared to the degree of PSMA expression determined by&#xD;
      IHC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the few studies published thus far, we expect significant expression of PSMA to be&#xD;
      present in progressive/recurrent enhancing glioma and brain metastases. We expect approximate&#xD;
      50% positive scans and in these, increased uptake upon intra-arterial injection compared to&#xD;
      intravenous injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this pilot study will aid in the development of future PSMA-targeting chemo-&#xD;
&#xD;
      /radionuclide therapies for malignant brain tumors. Therapeutic PSMA PET imaging studies have&#xD;
      not yet been performed in patients with primary brain tumors, but studies in patients with&#xD;
      (cerebral) metastases from prostate cancer show promising clinical results and acceptable&#xD;
      toxicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>non-randomized, single center, prospective imaging study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>tumor SUV (upon intravenous and intra-arterial injection),</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>tumor SUV (upon intravenous and intra-arterial injection</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SUV tumor-to-background ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>SUV tumor-to-background ratio</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Biodistribution</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>Biodistribution</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>correlation between SUV and the degree of immunohistochemical PSMA staining</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>correlation between SUV and the degree of immunohistochemical PSMA staining</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Brain Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intra-arterial injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>eligible for intra-arterial injection (age &gt;18 years) with enhancing glioma or brain metastases eligible for (re-)resection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>intra-arterial injection</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients will receive an intravenous injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11 (1.5 MBq/kg), followed by a synchronous PET/MRI scan (median duration approximately 50 min) at 45-60 min post-injection.&#xD;
In case of a positive [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-PET signal at the tumor site, patients will return (in 2 weeks) for an intra-arterial injection (i.e., a neuro-interventional procedure) of 68Ga-PSMA-11 (1.5 MBq/kg), followed by a repeat synchronous PET/MRI scan (median duration 50 min) at 45-60 min post-injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>intra-arterial injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>synchronous PET/MRI scan</intervention_name>
    <description>Scan done at (median duration approximately 50 min) at 45-60 min post-injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>intra-arterial injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiopharmacon Contrast agent</intervention_name>
    <description>Type: [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11 dosage: 1.5 MBq/kg</description>
    <arm_group_label>intra-arterial injection of [68Ga]Ga-PSMA-11</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiologically presumed/histologically confirmed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  glioma (grade II-IV) showing enhancement on post-contrast MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  brain metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned for (re-)resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good clinical condition (Karnofsky performance status score &gt;70)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability and willingness to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired renal function: eGFR (MDRD) &lt;30 ml/min/1,73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired liver function :AST and ALT &gt; 2.5 8 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky Performance score of less than 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous other malignancies, except for any previous malignancy which was treated with&#xD;
             curative intent more than 3 years prior to enrollment, and except for adequately&#xD;
             controlled limited basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous carcinoma of the skin or&#xD;
             carcinoma in situ of the cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of cerebrovascular disease (e.g. ischemic stroke, cerebral hemorrhage)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe claustrophobia prohibiting PET/MRI scanning&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A neurologic or psychiatric condition impairing judgement, making adequate informed&#xD;
             consent impossible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition hampering&#xD;
             participation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Contra-indications for PET imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergic reaction to therapeutic radiopharmaceuticals&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contra-indications for MR imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metal implants or fragments of the type which may concentrate radiofrequency fields or&#xD;
             cause tissue damage from twisting in a magnetic field:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  metal plates, wires, screws or rods&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  surgical (brain) clips or staples&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  metallic fragments in or near eyes or blood vessels&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  metallic cardiac valve(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a cardiac implantable electronic device (pacemaker, wires, implantable&#xD;
                  cardioverter-defibrillator (ICD))&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  eye implants&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ear or cochlear implants&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a drug pump implant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a nerve stimulator&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  dental fillings and bridges&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  artificial joints&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  penile implants&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  tubal ligation clips&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  non-removable piercing&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  tattoos containing metal traces&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergic reaction to gadolinium-based contrast agents&#xD;
&#xD;
        Contra-indications for arterial catheterization:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known local infection thrombus or distorted anatomy at the puncture site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe peripheral vascular disease or femoral artery disease, which makes the&#xD;
             femoral approach impossible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe coagulopathy (spontaneous prolonged PT with an INR &gt; 2.5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In case of the use of anticoagulation: an absolute contra-indication to temporarily&#xD;
             stop or bridge the anti-coagulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known severe thrombocytopenia (platelet count 50 x 109/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergic reaction to iodine containing contrast agent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A physical, neurologic or psychological condition preventing the patient to lay still&#xD;
             for the duration of the procedure (± 2h)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sophie EM Veldhuijzen van Zante, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Erasmus Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Laurens Groenendijk</last_name>
    <phone>31 10 7033612</phone>
    <email>l.groenendijk@erasmusmc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laurens Groenendijk</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berkel en Rodenrijs</city>
        <state>Zuid Holland</state>
        <zip>2651GG</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laurens Groenendijk</last_name>
      <phone>+31 10 7033612</phone>
      <email>l.groenendijk@erasmusmc.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 16, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 3, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 3, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 3, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Erasmus Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. S.E.M. Veldhuijzen van Zanten</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Scientific investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Intra-axial brain tumor Malignant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

