<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05794217</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SAN-BB-LEUK-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05794217</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Multi-Site Leukopak Repository Providing Annotated Biospecimens for Approved Investigator-Directed Biomedical Research Initiatives</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multi-Site Leukopak Repository Providing Annotated Biospecimens for Approved Investigator-Directed Biomedical Research Initiatives</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanguine Biosciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanguine Biosciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To collect, preserve, and distribute annotated leukopak biospecimens and associated medical&#xD;
      data to institutionally approved, investigator-directed biomedical research to discover and&#xD;
      develop new treatments, diagnostics, and preventative methods for specific and complex&#xD;
      conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol will be utilized to collect research grade products that are not meant for&#xD;
      transfusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-center study, with up to 20,000 participants enrolled. Participants may&#xD;
      complete up to two visits, a screening visit, and an apheresis visit, during their enrollment&#xD;
      in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The biospecimens collected by apheresis may be processed and stored, delivered frozen, or&#xD;
      delivered unfrozen directly to the requesting researcher. All participant specimens, if&#xD;
      processed, will be stored, and distributed to researchers in an anonymized fashion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following activities will occur during the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sponsor Obtain overall study informed consent. Sanguine will implement a&#xD;
      software-as-a-service (SaaS) provider of electronic signature technology and transaction&#xD;
      management solutions and/or a hardcopy of the informed consent form (ICF). Participants may&#xD;
      electronically sign the ICF and authorization of release of information using an electronic&#xD;
      device. The Sponsor will also provide the participant the option of completing hardcopy&#xD;
      documents if they so desire. In addition to the Principal Investigator (PI), approved study&#xD;
      staff can also administer and sign the ICF and will address all of the participant's queries&#xD;
      regarding the ICF and study design. The informed consent process can take place at the site&#xD;
      location by the on-site staff. In addition to the overall study informed consent, sites may&#xD;
      also administer their own ICF per site-specific procedures, if required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Health information will be collected via self-report and medical record review to obtain a&#xD;
      detailed clinical history of the subject's health. The health information includes but is not&#xD;
      limited to demographic and lifestyle information, height and weight, current medications and&#xD;
      comorbidities, date of diagnosis, condition-related treatment history, current disease&#xD;
      characteristics, diagnostic reports, and family medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apheresis Center Laboratory tests, including, but not limited to, a complete blood count&#xD;
      (CBC) and viral testing for hepatitis C, hepatitis B, and HIV, at a minimum, will be&#xD;
      performed on all prospective donors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apheresis health questionnaire to identify potential health risks and risk of communicable&#xD;
      disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Venous access check completed by an apheresis nurse to qualify donor as having adequate veins&#xD;
      for successful apheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment performed by the apheresis collection center on the day of donation which may&#xD;
      include (but is not limited to the following) Basic health questionnaire to assess donor&#xD;
      suitability for apheresis Mini physical exam including vitals and hemoglobin measurement&#xD;
      Other requirements of the apheresis center as per standard procedure Apheresis cell&#xD;
      collection&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 28, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 28, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 28, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Leukopak</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2022 and September 2024</time_frame>
    <description>The studies collected biospecimens are white blood cells, specifically leukopaks.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20000</enrollment>
  <condition>Rare Diseases</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>This is a non-interventional study</intervention_name>
    <description>This is a non-interventional study</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      The studies collected biospecimens are white blood cells, specifically leukopaks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a multi-center study, with up to 20,000 participants enrolled. Participants may&#xD;
        complete up to two visits, a screening visit, and an apheresis visit, during their&#xD;
        enrollment in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons deemed healthy enough for the procedure and aged 18 to 89 years at the date of&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Minimum weight of 110 lbs. Pulse greater than 50 and less than 110 beats per minute Blood&#xD;
        Pressure diastolic greater than 50 mmHg and less than100 mmHG and systolic is greater than&#xD;
        90 mmHg and less than 180 mmHg Peripheral veinous access is deemed adequate for apheresis&#xD;
        as determined by apheresis staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Negative for Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C, and HIV 1-2 upon testing performed within 30 days,&#xD;
        unless specifically obtaining cell collection based upon this diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        CBC results which fall within site-specific parameters within 30 days of apheresis&#xD;
        procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The participant understands the procedures and requirements of the study by providing&#xD;
        written informed consent, including consent for authorization for protected health&#xD;
        information disclosure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons younger than 18 years of age or older than 89 years of age at the date of&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Presenting with a history of a specific condition determined through medical evaluation to&#xD;
        be incompatible with safely undergoing apheresis Receipt of transfusion of blood products&#xD;
        within 30 days of the study procedure. Receipt of an investigational (unapproved) drug 30&#xD;
        days before the study procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        A confirmable diagnosis of any medical condition that would increase potential procedure&#xD;
        risks. Such medical conditions include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Severe or untreated cardiovascular, kidney, liver, or lung diseases which would preclude&#xD;
        apheresis procedures; Bleeding disorders Conditions associated with chronic anemia Active&#xD;
        systemic infection Use of ACE inhibitors unless they can safely be held for 24 hours prior&#xD;
        to apheresis procedure Pregnancy Has donated a unit of blood within the last 2 months at&#xD;
        the date of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Unable to understand the procedures and requirements of the study in order to provide&#xD;
        written informed consent, including consent for authorization for protected health&#xD;
        information disclosure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Requires a Legally Authorized Representative (LAR) for the study informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanguine Biosciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Waltham</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02451</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sonia Lunar</last_name>
      <phone>855-836-4759</phone>
      <email>slunar@sanguinebio.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Timothy Triche, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rare Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Deidentified data will be shared with researchers via redacted medical records.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

