<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05617417</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BAIBU-MF-OG-UMU-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05617417</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Efficacy of Injectable Platelet-rich Fibrin in the Treatment of the Female Stress Urinary Incontinence</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Efficacy of Locally Administered Autologous Injectable Platelet-rich Fibrin in Women With Stress Urinary Incontinence</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Abant Izzet Baysal University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Abant Izzet Baysal University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We aimed to evaluate the efficacy of locally applied injectable platelet-rich fibrin in women&#xD;
      with stress urinary incontinence. We searched whether there was a decrease in the severity of&#xD;
      urinary incontinence after the injection of platelet-rich fibrin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants will answer questionnaires about urinary incontinence before and after the&#xD;
      injectable platelet-rich fibrin treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Female patients with pure stress urinary incontinence who gave written informed consent after&#xD;
      being informed about the study were included in the study. Two tubes of venous blood samples&#xD;
      taken from the patients were centrifuged and injectable platelet-rich fibrin was prepared.&#xD;
      The obtained autologous material was injected into the patient within one minute after&#xD;
      preparation, without applying a local anesthetic. The injection was given to the anterior&#xD;
      wall of the vagina, approximately 1.5 cm below the urethral meatus, coinciding with the&#xD;
      mid-urethral region, and the dose was applied to three adjacent points. The procedure was&#xD;
      repeated three times at one-month intervals. Before and after the procedure, ICIQ-SF, UDI-6,&#xD;
      and IIQ-7 questionnaires were filled and the severity of urinary incontinence was recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 5, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 26, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Thirty patients with pure stress urinary incontinence were included in the study. Autologously prepared injectable platelet-rich fibrin from the patients was applied locally. The procedure was repeated for the same patient three times with an interval of one month. The severity of urinary incontinence was evaluated and recorded by filling out questionnaires before and after the procedure.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in urinary incontinence severity before and 6 months after injectable platelet-rich fibrin application were evaluated with International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire-Urinary Incontinence Short Form (ICIQ-SF).</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in urinary incontinence severity before and 6 months after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>ICIQ-SF evaluates the severity of urinary incontinence symptoms and their impact on health-related quality of life. It is scored on a scale from 0-21. A higher score indicates greater impairment from incontinence. Stress urinary incontinence grade according to ICIQ-SF: slight (1-5), moderate (6-12), severe (13-18) and very severe (19-21).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in quality of life in patients with urinary incontinence before and 6 months after injectable platelet-rich fibrin application were evaluated with Urogenital Distress Inventory-6 (UDI-6) and Incontinence Impact Questionnaire-7 (IIQ-7).</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in urinary incontinence severity before and 6 months after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>UDI-6 is a short version of a condition-specifc quality of life instrument. Higher scores in UDI-6 indicate higher disability. Total score is from 0 to 100.&#xD;
IIQ-7 is a urinary incontinence-specific psychometric questionnaire. This questionnaire assesses the psychosocial impact of UI in women. Higher scores in UDI-6 indicate higher disability. Total score ranges from 0 to 100.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Urinary Incontinence</condition>
  <condition>Treatment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The women with stress urinary incontinence administered injectable platelet-rich fibrin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Injectable platelet-rich fibrin was prepared by centrifuging venous blood samples from women with stress urinary incontinence. The obtained autologous material was injected into the anterior vaginal wall, approximately 1.5 cm below the urethral meatus, without applying a local anesthetic. The procedure was repeated for the same patient three times with an interval of one month. The severity of urinary incontinence was evaluated by filling out questionnaires before and after the procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Local applied injectable platelet-rich fibrin in women with stress urinary incontinence</intervention_name>
    <description>Injectable platelet-rich fibrin was prepared by centrifuging venous blood taken from women with stress urinary incontinence and applied locally to the anterior vaginal wall of the patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The women with stress urinary incontinence administered injectable platelet-rich fibrin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient who has pure stress urinary incontinence&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient who had previous surgery for stress urinary incontinence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known platelet dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anti-coagulant users&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Critical thrombocytopenia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ülkü Mete Ural</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bolu Abant Izzet Baysal University, Faculty of Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bolu Abant Izzet Baysal University, Faculty of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bolu</city>
        <state>Gölköy</state>
        <zip>14030</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 25, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Abant Izzet Baysal University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ulku Mete Ural</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor Doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Urinary Stress Incontinence</keyword>
  <keyword>Platelet-Rich Fibrin</keyword>
  <keyword>Questionnaire</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence, Stress</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

