<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05793073</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>23Infectio01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05793073</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>AMS Intervention for Early Adaptation of Empirical Antibiotic Therapy in High-risk Neutropenic Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of an Antimicrobial Stewardship Intervention for Early Adaptation of Empirical Antibiotic Therapy in High-risk Neutropenic Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Febrile neutropenia (FN) is a frequent and serious complication in patients with&#xD;
      hematological malignancies undergoing intensive chemotherapy. The growth of antibiotic&#xD;
      resistance is a major threat in high-risk neutropenic patients given that delay in&#xD;
      introduction of appropriate empirical antibiotic therapy (EAT) in this population is&#xD;
      associated with increased morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2013, the 4th European Conference on Infections in Leukaemia (ECIL-4) group published new&#xD;
      guidelines, promoting early adaptation of EAT in stable afebrile patients, regardless of&#xD;
      neutrophil count and expected duration of neutropenia. Despite these evidence-based&#xD;
      guidelines, discontinuation and de-escalation strategies are not widely implemented in&#xD;
      hematology departments. However, recent studies have found that early adaptation of EAT is&#xD;
      safe and feasible and could lead to reduced antibiotic consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In response to growing antibiotic resistance and low adherence to ECIL-4 guidelines in the&#xD;
      hematology department in the center of Nice, the investigators have developed and implemented&#xD;
      a multifaceted AMS intervention. This intervention aimed to improve the quality of febrile&#xD;
      neutropenia management and to promote the adoption of early de-escalation and discontinuation&#xD;
      strategies in high-risk neutropenic patients by our hematology team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this before-after study was to assess the impact of a multifaceted AMS&#xD;
      intervention, promoting early adaptation of empirical antibiotic therapy, on antibiotic&#xD;
      consumption and clinical outcomes in high-risk neutropenic patients. Secondly, the&#xD;
      investigators sought to assess the applicability and adherence to de-escalation and&#xD;
      discontinuation strategies by the hematology team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint was total antibiotic use during hospital stay, expressed as days of&#xD;
      therapy (DOT). DOT was defined as the number of days that a patient received antibiotics&#xD;
      regardless of the dose. Secondary endpoints included length of therapy (LOT), antibiotic-free&#xD;
      days (AFD), 30-day mortality, ICU admission, Clostridium difficile infection and duration of&#xD;
      stay. LOT was defined as the number of days that a patient received systemic antibiotic&#xD;
      therapy, irrespective of the number of different antibiotics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Febrile neutropenia (FN) is a frequent and serious complication in patients with&#xD;
      hematological malignancies undergoing intensive chemotherapy. FN episodes are responsible for&#xD;
      repeated and prolonged antibiotic therapy, leading to an increased risk of bacterial&#xD;
      antibiotic resistance, Clostridium difficile infections, fungal infections and adverse drug&#xD;
      events. The growth of antibiotic resistance is a major threat in high-risk neutropenic&#xD;
      patients given that delay in introduction of appropriate empirical antibiotic therapy (EAT)&#xD;
      in this population is associated with increased morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Excessive and inappropriate antibiotic use are major drivers of the growth of antibiotic&#xD;
      resistance. Antimicrobial stewardship (AMS) interventions have therefore been introduced to&#xD;
      optimize antibiotic use in order to decrease unintended consequences of antibiotic use, such&#xD;
      as growing antibiotic resistance and excessive healthcare costs. AMS interventions often&#xD;
      include various components, such as prescriber education, prospective audit and feedback as&#xD;
      well as clinical decision support at the point-of-care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2013, the 4th European Conference on Infections in Leukaemia (ECIL-4) group published new&#xD;
      guidelines, promoting early adaptation of EAT in stable afebrile patients, regardless of&#xD;
      neutrophil count and expected duration of neutropenia. Despite these evidence-based&#xD;
      guidelines, discontinuation and de-escalation strategies are not widely implemented in&#xD;
      hematology departments. However, recent studies have found that early adaptation of EAT is&#xD;
      safe and feasible and could lead to reduced antibiotic consumption. However, some of these&#xD;
      studies did not use a control group. Furthermore, some of these studies solely investigated&#xD;
      the effets of one aspect of adaptation (i.e. de-escalation or discontinuation) or focused on&#xD;
      specific clinical presentations or patient profiles. One interrupted time series study&#xD;
      investigated the impact of de-escalation and discontinuation strategies on antibiotic&#xD;
      consumption but found no significant difference in total antibiotic consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In response to growing antibiotic resistance and low adherence to ECIL-4 guidelines in the&#xD;
      hematology department in our center, the investigators have developed and implemented a&#xD;
      multifaceted AMS intervention. This intervention aimed to improve the quality of febrile&#xD;
      neutropenia management and to promote the adoption of early de-escalation and discontinuation&#xD;
      strategies in high-risk neutropenic patients by our hematology team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this before-after study was to assess the impact of a multifaceted AMS&#xD;
      intervention, promoting early adaptation of empirical antibiotic therapy, on antibiotic&#xD;
      consumption and clinical outcomes in high-risk neutropenic patients. Secondly, the&#xD;
      investigators sought to assess the applicability and adherence to de-escalation and&#xD;
      discontinuation strategies by the hematology team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population This study was conducted in the hematology department of a 1800-bed&#xD;
      university teaching hospital in Nice, France during two 6-month periods. The hematology&#xD;
      department is divided into two separate units: a 10-bed intensive care unit with laminar air&#xD;
      flow rooms and a 16-bed conventional hospitalization unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During these periods, all patients admitted to the hematology department for intensive&#xD;
      chemotherapy, with chemotherapy-induced neutropenia lasting 7 days or more, who experienced&#xD;
      at least one febrile episode, were eligible for inclusion. Patients were excluded if they&#xD;
      were younger than 18 years old or had chemotherapy-induced neutropenia for less than 7 days&#xD;
      or received corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design and implementation of AMS intervention The pre-intervention spanned from October 2019&#xD;
      to March 2020. During this period, if EAT was effective (i.e patient remained stable and&#xD;
      apyrexia was obtained), no change to antibiotic regimen was made, discontinuation was not&#xD;
      considered and de-escalation was rarely performed. During this period, the discontinuation of&#xD;
      antibiotic therapy was solely determined by neutrophil recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In early 2021, the investigators started to design a persuasive multifaceted AMS&#xD;
      intervention, aimed to optimize the management of high-risk febrile neutropenia. The&#xD;
      implementation of the intervention started on November 2nd 2021 and the implementation phase&#xD;
      lasted one month. This intervention included the development of new local clinical guidelines&#xD;
      in the form of visual decision algorithms, prompting early de-escalation and discontinuation&#xD;
      of EAT, according to clinical and microbiological criteria. These decision algorithms were&#xD;
      subsequently discussed with the hematology medical team and revised until they were agreed&#xD;
      upon by both teams. These visual decision aids were then displayed in all medical offices of&#xD;
      the hematology department. Educational meetings were held with residents and paramedical&#xD;
      staff during the implementation period, providing an opportunity for all stakeholders to ask&#xD;
      questions and to learn about the adaptation guidelines. Additionally, a patient-level review&#xD;
      of all antibiotic prescriptions was conducted twice a week in the presence of the hematology&#xD;
      medical team and the AMS team. Patient-specific recommendations regarding antibiotic therapy&#xD;
      were provided by the AMS team based on clinical and microbiological data. Moreover, the AMS&#xD;
      team offered day-to-day guidance via a specialist hotline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The post-intervention phase started in December 2021 and lasted for the subsequent 6 months,&#xD;
      until May 2022. During this period, clinical outcomes and adherence to clinical algorithms&#xD;
      were prospectively assessed and face-to-face meetings were organized by the AMS team to&#xD;
      provide feedback on progress of the intervention and to discuss opportunities for improvement&#xD;
      with the hematology team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Febrile neutropenia guidelines In November 2021, new clinical guidelines promoting early&#xD;
      adaptation of EAT, based on local microbiological epidemiology, clinical and microbiological&#xD;
      criteria and ECIL-4 guidelines, were introduced.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In line to guidelines, EAT with a beta-lactam agent was started as early as possible after&#xD;
      onset of fever in neutropenic patients. During both periods, carbapenem use was restricted to&#xD;
      patients with prior colonization or infection with ESBL-producing bacteria and in patients&#xD;
      with septic shock. A single injection of aminoglycosides was administered in patients with&#xD;
      sepsis or septic shock. An agent active against resistant Gram-positive (e.g. daptomycin,&#xD;
      vancomycin or linezolid) was added in patients with suspected catheter-related infection,&#xD;
      skin and soft tissue infection or severe mucitis, in patients with prior colonization or&#xD;
      infection with methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) as well as in patients with&#xD;
      septic shock.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Without documented infection, EAT was discontinued after 72 hours in stable patients who had&#xD;
      been afebrile for at least 48 hours, irrespective of neutrophil count or expected duration of&#xD;
      neutropenia. In clinically or microbiologically documented infections, appropriate antibiotic&#xD;
      therapy was continued for at least 7 days and until infection was microbiologically&#xD;
      eradicated and clinical resolution was obtained and fever had resolved for at least 4 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If an anti-resistant Gram-positive agent was started based on focal clinical signs, its&#xD;
      stopping was encouraged in stable patients who had been afebrile for at least 48 hours upon&#xD;
      resolution of focal clinical signs. If EAT with carbapenem was started based on prior&#xD;
      colonization or infection with resistant pathogens and no microbiological documentation was&#xD;
      available, de-escalation was encouraged in stable patients who had been afebrile for at least&#xD;
      48 hours. If carbapenem or anti-resistant Gram-positives therapy was started in the context&#xD;
      of septic shock and the patient had stabilized on treatment, without documented infection, no&#xD;
      particular change was encouraged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection All individual data on the pre-intervention period was retrospectively&#xD;
      collected by the AMS team by manual review of electronic health records (EHRs) while data on&#xD;
      the post-intervention phase was prospectively collected. Data on patient demographics,&#xD;
      comorbidities, hematological malignancies, colonization with multidrug-resistant (MDR)&#xD;
      bacteria (i.e. MRSA or ESBL-producing bacteria), dates and reason for hospital stay, results&#xD;
      of microbiological samples, were collected. All data on antibiotic use were also retrieved&#xD;
      from EHRs and were then double checked for accuracy by the pharmacy department. Clinical&#xD;
      outcomes, such as ICU admission and 30-day mortality, were also collected to assess for&#xD;
      unintended consequences of early adaptation of EAT. The applicability of de-escalation and&#xD;
      discontinuation strategies and clinician adherence to these strategies were also assessed by&#xD;
      the AMS team individually for all FN episodes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint was total antibiotic use during hospital stay, expressed as days of&#xD;
      therapy (DOT). DOT was defined as the number of days that a patient received antibiotics&#xD;
      regardless of the dose. When a patient received more than one antibiotic, more than one DOT&#xD;
      was counted. Secondary endpoints included length of therapy (LOT), antibiotic-free days&#xD;
      (AFD), 30-day mortality, ICU admission, Clostridium difficile infection and duration of stay.&#xD;
      LOT was defined as the number of days that a patient received systemic antibiotic therapy,&#xD;
      irrespective of the number of different antibiotics [24]. AFD were calculated by the&#xD;
      difference between duration of neutropenia of stay and LOT. If duration of neutropenia was&#xD;
      greater than LOT, AFD was measured as 0. The 30-day mortality was defined as death occurring&#xD;
      within 30 days after the onset of neutropenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis Continuous variables are reported as median (interquartile range) and&#xD;
      categorical variables as number (percentage). Continuous variables were compared using the&#xD;
      Student's t-test, or when inappropriate the Mann-Whitney test. Categorical variables were&#xD;
      compared using the Chi-2 test, or when inappropriate the Fisher's exact test. All tests were&#xD;
      two-tailed and p values ≤ 0.05 were considered statistically significant. Univariate and&#xD;
      multivariate logistic regression was performed to identify factors associated with clinician&#xD;
      adherence to de-escalation and discontinuation strategies. Only variables with p values &lt; 0.2&#xD;
      in the univariate analysis were included in the multivariate logistic regression model.&#xD;
      Sample size was calculated using a power of 80% and an α value of 0.05. Based on preliminary&#xD;
      results from our department, the mean DOT was assumed to be 29 days (standard deviation =&#xD;
      13.5 days) and a reduction of DOT by 25 % in the post-intervention period was considered&#xD;
      significant. Based on these assumptions, a sample size of 55 per period was required. The&#xD;
      open-source software R Foundation for Statistical Computing (Vienna, Austria) was used for&#xD;
      statistical analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total antibiotic use during hospital stay, expressed as days of therapy (DOT)</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>DOT was defined as the number of days that a patient received antibiotics regardless of the dose. When a patient received more than one antibiotic, more than one DOT was counted.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total antibiotic use during hospital stay, expressed as days of therapy (LOT)</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>LOT was defined as the number of days that a patient received systemic antibiotic therapy, irrespective of the number of different antibiotics</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibiotic-free days (AFD)</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>AFD were calculated by the difference between duration of neutropenia of stay and LOT. If duration of neutropenia was greater than LOT, AFD was measured as 0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>30-day mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>The 30-day mortality was defined as death occurring within 30 days after the onset of neutropenia. Number of deaths among all hospital stays included during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU admission rate</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of ICU admission among all hospital stays included during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clostridium difficile infection rate</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Clostriudium difficile infection cases among all hospital stays included during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>31 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days during hospitalization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">55</enrollment>
  <condition>Neutropenia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pre-intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Post-intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with febril neutropenia due to intensive chemotherapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients admitted to the hematology department for intensive chemotherapy, with&#xD;
             chemotherapy-induced neutropenia lasting 7 days or more, who experienced at least one&#xD;
             febrile episode, were eligible for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Younger than 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had chemotherapy-induced neutropenia for less than 7 days or received corticosteroids.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Nice</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <zip>06200</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 16, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>antibiotic</keyword>
  <keyword>antimicrobial stewardship</keyword>
  <keyword>hematological malignancy</keyword>
  <keyword>febrile neutropenia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neutropenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

