<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05628766</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SiirtUNIVERSI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05628766</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thiol/Disulphide Homeostasis in Unexplained Infertility</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Role of Thiol/Disulphide Homeostasis in Unexplained Primary Infertile Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Siirt University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Siirt University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim in this study is to determine whether there is a relationship between Thiol /&#xD;
      Disulphide levels in primary infertile patients and comparing them with infertile patients&#xD;
      and the control group. For this purpose, 41 women followed up with the diagnosis of primary&#xD;
      infertility in Siirt Training and Research Hospital between November 2022 and January 2023&#xD;
      will be included in the study. The same number of (n:41) non-infertile control women will be&#xD;
      included. Age, pregnancy history and medical history of both groups will be recorded. FSH,&#xD;
      LH, E2, TSH, and prolactin levels taken routinely in these patients will be examined.&#xD;
      Thiol/disulphide levels in the blood will be checked by taking whole blood from these&#xD;
      patients. In the light of the information thus obtained, the investigator plan to determine&#xD;
      whether there is a relationship between oxidant/antioxidant balance in primary infertile&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Reactive oxygen species (ROS) are products of normal cellular metabolism and consist of&#xD;
      oxygen ions, free radicals and peroxides. Adding an electron to oxygen creates the superoxide&#xD;
      anion radical, which can then be converted to a hydroxyl radical, peroxyl radical, or&#xD;
      hydrogen peroxide. Free radicals try to participate in chemical reactions that free&#xD;
      themselves of their unpaired electrons and result in oxidation. Natural antioxidants found in&#xD;
      the body include catalase, glutathione peroxidase, superoxide dismutase and glutathione&#xD;
      reductase, vitamins C and E, ferritin, and transferrin. Other lifestyle factors such as&#xD;
      smoking, diet, illness, pollution, stress, alcohol, and allergies also contribute to&#xD;
      increased levels of free radicals, suggesting that these factors have a negative impact on&#xD;
      female fertility, potentially through the formation of excessive oxidative stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Excessive accumulation of ROS can damage cells, proteins, DNA and lipids; therefore, ROS&#xD;
      levels are regulated by antioxidant mechanisms in the organism. A shift in the direction of&#xD;
      ROS in this balance is called oxidative stress (OS). ROS produced in the follicle have&#xD;
      important roles in folliculogenesis and ovulation. Granulosa cells produce antioxidants to&#xD;
      protect oocytes from the harmful effects of excess ROS. OS has been implicated as an&#xD;
      etiopathogenetic factor in female infertility. The number of studies examining the role of OS&#xD;
      in the etiopathogenesis of infertility has increased in recent years, and it has been&#xD;
      suggested that increased OS and/or decreased antioxidant defense mechanisms may contribute to&#xD;
      infertility-related conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One of the defense mechanisms against OS in humans is the thiol redox reaction. The thiol&#xD;
      consists of a sulfhydryl group, and under OS conditions these functional groups form&#xD;
      reversible disulfide bridges. These bonds bring about functional and structural changes in&#xD;
      proteins. Disulfide bonds are reduced to thiol groups through antioxidant mechanisms, thereby&#xD;
      providing thiol/disulfide homeostasis. Thus, disulfide bridges are thought to be a marker of&#xD;
      OS, while thiols are suggested to be members of the antioxidant system. Only one side of this&#xD;
      equilibrium has been measured by Ellman (1979), whereas in recent years both sides of the&#xD;
      thiol/disulfide equilibrium can be measured by the Erel and Neselioğlu assay method, allowing&#xD;
      a full assessment of the thiol/disulfide status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dynamic thiol/disulfide homeostasis, a recently identified marker of OS, is thought to have&#xD;
      critical roles in pathological processes in various vital processes such as folliculogenesis&#xD;
      and ovulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      n the literature review, there are studies investigating the relationship between infertility&#xD;
      and oxidant/antioxidants. However, measurements require measuring a large number of&#xD;
      parameters and many separate biomarkers. The thiol/disulfide balance is beneficial in terms&#xD;
      of showing the oxidant/antioxidant balance in total. It was not possible to measure this&#xD;
      balance simultaneously on both sides in the method measuring the thiol/disulfide balance by&#xD;
      Newman in 1979. In recent years, it has become possible to measure the serum Thiol/disulfide&#xD;
      balance bilaterally with the automatic spectrophotometric method described by Erel and&#xD;
      Neşelioğlu. This study aims to investigate whether there is a relationship by measuring the&#xD;
      Total oxidant/antioxidant load with the Thiol/disulfide method in patients with unexplained&#xD;
      infertility, to investigate the relationship between thiol/disulfide homeostasis and impaired&#xD;
      ovulation and fertility, and to analyze the potential pathogenetic mechanism.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 30, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 21, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 21, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measuring the total oxidant/antioxidant load with the Thiol/disulfide method in patients with unexplained infertility</measure>
    <time_frame>&quot;through study completion, an average of 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine whether there is a relationship between oxidant/ antioxidant balance in primary infertile patients by looking at Thiol/disulphide blood levels in both groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Oxidative Stress</condition>
  <condition>Infertility</condition>
  <condition>Antioxidative Stress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Women diagnosed with primary infertility (n:41)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women which followed up with infertility of unknown cause.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group ( n:41)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy women who are not infertile</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>complete blood count</intervention_name>
    <description>Thiol/disulphide levels in the blood will be checked by taking complete blood count</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group ( n:41)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Women diagnosed with primary infertility (n:41)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women between the age of 18-35 diagnosed with infertility of unknown cause.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with primary infertility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients between the age of 18-35&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic liver or kidney failure history&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Coronary artery disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute infection (within 14 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any chronic inflammatory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of autoimmune disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inflammatory bowel disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hormonal contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  alcohol use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with tubal infertility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partner with abnormal spermiogram&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Şerif Aksin, assoc.Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Siirt University Medical Faculty Obstetrics and Gynecology Departmant</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Siirt Üniversity Medical Faculty</name>
      <address>
        <city>Siirt</city>
        <zip>56000</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 21, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 21, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 25, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Siirt University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Serif Aksin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

