<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05797961</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R34MH123337</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05797961</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HIV Self-testing With Online Supervision for Vietnamese MSM</brief_title>
  <official_title>HIV Self-testing With Online Supervision for Vietnamese MSM</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mahidol University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Puerto Rico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>US Military HIV Research Program</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mahidol University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Although global rates of HIV infection have decreased overall, rates among men who have sex&#xD;
      with men (MSM) in Southeast Asia are increasing. A recent review of available global data and&#xD;
      the molecular epidemiology of HIV among MSM in Southeast Asia suggests that targeted&#xD;
      interventions for MSM populations are necessary to reduce HIV incidence in the region. For&#xD;
      example, in Vietnam's urban centers, the HIV epidemic among MSM is growing rapidly, with an&#xD;
      estimated prevalence of 17% in Ho Chi Minh City and an estimated incidence of 5.8% among&#xD;
      young men who have sex with men in Hanoi. Behavioral epidemiology has also been&#xD;
      well-described, with high rates of unprotected sex, multiple concurrent partners, untreated&#xD;
      STIs, and poor engagement in the HIV care continuum, including low rates of HIV testing, all&#xD;
      contributing to high levels of circulating virus among MSM risk networks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HIV rates among MSM in Vietnam have increased sharply since 2006. By 2011, rates had reached&#xD;
      19%, with HCMC accounting for the largest number of infections. MSM, particularly YMSM,&#xD;
      continue to have low rates of HIV testing and poor engagement in HIV care. Studies have&#xD;
      identified various risk factors, including low knowledge and perceived risk, sexual risk and&#xD;
      STIs/HIV, complexity in identity and meaning, substance use and mental health, limited HIV&#xD;
      interventions, and poor engagement in health services. Increasing HIV testing among MSM,&#xD;
      particularly YMSM, is crucial for early detection and enrolment in ART. However, individual&#xD;
      and institutional-level barriers hinder testing, such as poor knowledge, stigma, and poor&#xD;
      repeat testing. Using the internet as an intervention platform can reach and engage MSM who&#xD;
      cannot be reached using conventional health-engagement approaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed study aims to adapt and pilot test an online HIV testing intervention (OHT)&#xD;
      targeted at young men who have sex with men (MSM) in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. The OHT&#xD;
      intervention was developed and successfully implemented among MSM in Thailand, showing&#xD;
      significant impacts on testing rates and linkage to HIV care. The proposed study builds on&#xD;
      longstanding collaborations between HIV researchers from Mahidol University in Thailand and a&#xD;
      local community-based organization that serves YMSM in Vietnam. The findings from the&#xD;
      proposed study will have important implications for assessing the potential for OHT&#xD;
      intervention to overcome profound and longstanding barriers to HIV testing among YMSM in&#xD;
      Vietnam, an outcome that if brought to scale could significantly improve enrolment in ART and&#xD;
      reduce HIV incidence. Innovative strategies to increase testing and improve continuum will be&#xD;
      needed to reduce HIV transmission in Vietnam, where little data is available on uptake of HIV&#xD;
      testing among Vietnamese MSM, and a high proportion of men who have sex with men surveyed&#xD;
      have never been voluntarily tested for HIV. HIV self-testing with online supervision&#xD;
      represents an important strategy to improve scale-up of HIV testing among Vietnamese MSM. The&#xD;
      proposed OHT can overcome the barrier of face-to-face testing and counseling, while ensuring&#xD;
      that Vietnamese YMSM receive real-time guidance and support for self-testing and linkage to&#xD;
      care and treatment, if positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The project's aims are: (1) to conduct a qualitative study with Focus Group Discussions&#xD;
      (FGDs) to identify potential barriers and facilitators to the uptake of OHT among YMSM in&#xD;
      HCMC; (2) to conduct a quantitative study with online survey questionnaires to adapt the&#xD;
      existing Thai OHT intervention for use among YMSM in Vietnam, including translation and&#xD;
      socio-cultural refinement of testing kits, clip video content, online pre-and post-test&#xD;
      counseling, and broader socio-cultural contexts. Data from Aim 1 will be analyzed and used to&#xD;
      design the test kit, the clip video content, and when and how the HIV counselor will conduct&#xD;
      pre-and post-test counseling. Moreover, willingness to engage in OHT as well as factors&#xD;
      related to sustained testing will be collected through an online survey, and (3) to conduct a&#xD;
      pilot study with Randomized Control Trial to demonstrate the feasibility and acceptability of&#xD;
      the adapted OHT intervention, including the use of an HIV rapid diagnostic&#xD;
      antibody/antigen-based self-testing with an HIV counselor through video conferencing. YMSM&#xD;
      recruited through the online survey who indicated an interest in OHT will be randomly&#xD;
      selected to the OHT group or the venue-based testing group (standard of care), using repeated&#xD;
      measures at 6 and 12 months to compare HIV testing rates and behavioral outcomes because of&#xD;
      retention and we need to understand how the socio-cultural factors affecting to OHT&#xD;
      retention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>1:1 randomization to either HIV testing with online supervision or venue testing as usual</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV self-testing with online supervision past 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Past 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who have gone through the intervention (self-tested for HIV with online supervision past 6 months). For the control group, participants will answer a yes/no question if they have tested for HIV in the past 6 months.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV prevalence</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>HIV prevalence at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV incidence/seroconversion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>HIV incidence/seroconversion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HIV self-testing with online supervision</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>HIV self-testing with online supervision</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>venue-based HIV testing</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HIV self-testing with online supervision</intervention_name>
    <description>A pilot study to assess the feasibility of HIV self-testing with online supervision</description>
    <arm_group_label>HIV self-testing with online supervision</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control</intervention_name>
    <description>venue-based HIV testing</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 16-29 years at cohort baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported male gender&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported having had anal sex with another man in the past 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speak, read and write Vietnamese&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vietnamese citizenship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resident of the assessment city (Ho Chi Minh City) for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not consent to HIV self-testing with online supervision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to give contact information for follow-up assessments&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>29 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas E Guadamuz, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mahidol University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Giang M Le, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Hanoi Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thomas E Guadamuz, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+66860844154</phone>
    <email>tguadamu@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lan Anh Do, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+84945217146</phone>
    <email>lananhytcc08@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center for Applied Research on Men and Health (CARMAH)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ho Chi Minh City</city>
        <zip>700000</zip>
        <country>Vietnam</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lan Anh Thi Do</last_name>
      <phone>+84 945217146</phone>
      <email>lananhytcc08@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Vietnam</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 7, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 7, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 9, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

