<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05613556</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ORPYX</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05613556</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Monitoring Physiologic Parameters in Individuals With Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Monitoring Physiologic Parameters in Individuals With Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathy: a Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Orpyx Medical Technologies Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Orpyx Medical Technologies Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary aim of this study is to use the Orpyx® SI Sensory Insole System (Orpyx Medical&#xD;
      Technologies Inc., Calgary AB, Canada) (&quot;Orpyx&quot; or &quot;the Company&quot;) as an adjunct to diabetic&#xD;
      peripheral neuropathy standard of care (SOC), and observe step count, pressure, temperature,&#xD;
      and adherence data through remote patient monitoring (RPM). This will provide insights into&#xD;
      patient engagement and the benefits of offering remote, preventative care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 28, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 23, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency and location of high-pressure plantar areas</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>frequency and location of high-pressure plantar areas</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Foot</condition>
  <condition>Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathy</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Orpyx SI® Sensory Insole System</intervention_name>
    <description>Orpyx SI Sensory Insole System consists of Orpyx Custom Insoles and Orpyx Sensory Technology. The Orpyx Custom Insoles are precisely fabricated for an individual's feet. The Orpyx Sensory Technology, a powered limb overload warning technology, is compatible with the Orpyx Custom Insoles. It is intended for monitoring physiological parameters, such as plantar pressure, motion and temperature, and providing real-time cues for pressure offloading as the patient goes about their daily activities</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The participant population to be studied will be subjects 18 years of age or older who have&#xD;
        been diagnosed with diabetes (Type I or Type II) and neuropathy and who are at moderate to&#xD;
        high risk of foot ulceration based on the International Working Group on the Diabetic Foot&#xD;
        (IWDGF) guidelines.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically diagnosed neuropathy and type 1 or 2 diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Qualification as a &quot;Moderate or High-Risk Participant,&quot; as defined by the&#xD;
             International Working Group on the Diabetic Foot (IWGDF) Guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete healing of any previous foot ulcers, as defined by complete&#xD;
             re-epithelialization of healed ulcer which is confirmed by two medical exams that&#xD;
             occur at least two to three weeks apart (V0 and V1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to walk independently (without use of wheelchair) for 30 steps&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged &gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand all the study and device requirements and have a life expectancy&#xD;
             greater than the study duration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  0.6 &lt; [ABI] &lt; 1.2, capillary refill time &lt; 5 seconds (in the last 12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing and able to wear the Orpyx Sensory Insoles and provided diabetic&#xD;
             footwear during all weight bearing activities (sitting, standing, walking, and wearing&#xD;
             footwear)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Most recent HbA1c level of &lt; 12.0% (in the last 12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject or caregiver is able to see the bottom of their feet and inspect for redness,&#xD;
             callus, and wounds as per standard of care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing to wear the sensory insoles and carry the digital display device&#xD;
             all day, but for a minimum of 4.5 hours a day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing to charge the Orpyx SI Sensory Insoles overnight every night&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active ulcer or presence of other open chronic wound (on foot or other body surface),&#xD;
             regardless of etiology (e.g., vasculitis, neoplasms, or hematological disorders)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Past history of known non-neuropathic foot ulcer (i.e., arterial or venous&#xD;
             insufficiency ulcer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of severe vascular disease (refer to acceptable ABI parameters in section&#xD;
             7.7.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric illnesses or social situations that would limit compliance with the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious underlying balance dysfunction, regardless of etiology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant cardiopulmonary or other systemic disease limiting the participant's&#xD;
             ability to walk at least 30 steps or to stand for an amount of time equal to or&#xD;
             greater than five (5) minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current participation in another clinical investigation of a medical device or a drug;&#xD;
             or participation in such a study within 30 days prior to this study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current osteomyelitis or gangrene of the lower extremity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncorrected plantar Charcot neuroarthropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bunion which would predispose ulcer formation (clinician discretion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extreme equinus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hallux valgus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At the start of V1, the subject does not continue to meet the entrance criteria&#xD;
             (inclusion and exclusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hallux rigidus / limitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that would affect or limit the ability to properly fit both shoes with&#xD;
             the device under study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a history of intercurrent illness or conditions that would compromise the&#xD;
             safety of the subject or their ability to participate in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is in a site of care that is not conducive to ambulation or qualify for remote&#xD;
             patient care (skilled nursing facility, acute care facility)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amputations on the foot which require additive insole modifications (including but not&#xD;
             limited to transmetatarsal, toe or ray amputations which create the need for a toe&#xD;
             filler, or which prevent the subject from wearing the prescribed footwear)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>WAFL Inc / Cutting Edge Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Circleville</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43113</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 5, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 5, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 9, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Neuropathies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

