<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05627583</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EAT study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05627583</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nutritional Rehabilitation and Markers of Severity in Anorexia Nervosa</brief_title>
  <acronym>EAT</acronym>
  <official_title>Τhe Effect of Nutritional rEhabilitation in Patients With Anorexia Nervosa on Markers Associated With Disease severiTy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Harokopio University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eginitio Hospital, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens (NKUA) Medical School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sismanoglio General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institute of Chemical Biology National Hellenic Research Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Attiko Hospital, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens (NKUA) Medical School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Harokopio University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The design of this project is a longitudinal trial in patients with Anorexia Nervosa (AN)&#xD;
      during in-hospital rehabilitation. Τhe structure of the study, the questionnaires and data&#xD;
      protection policy prepared exclusively for our study, have been reviewed and standardised at&#xD;
      Institutional Review Boards (Ethics Committees, IRBs,) in Harokopio University of Athens&#xD;
      (HUA), Eginition Hospital (EH), Attiko Hospital (AH) and Sismanoglio Hospital (SG).&#xD;
&#xD;
      AN is a psychiatric disorder followed by a psychopathologic concerning of body image and very&#xD;
      low body weight due to extreme self-starvation. The exact pathogenesis of AN remains unknown&#xD;
      with neurobiological, gastrointestinal, neuroendocrinological, immunological, and genetic&#xD;
      factors suspected to be implicated. Furthermore, many metabolic traits, biochemical,&#xD;
      biological or/and anthropometrical, are manifested during the maintaining effort of patients&#xD;
      to achieve lower body weight. Self-inflicted starvation is the primary and essential&#xD;
      causation of the pathological outcomes of the disorder. These outcomes involve all biological&#xD;
      systems and organs. The role of the immune system in AN is critical as levels of&#xD;
      pro-inflammatory cytokines are increased and the immune system is dysregulated. Other&#xD;
      contributors to AN pathogenesis have been proposed, such as increased oxidative stress,&#xD;
      dysbiosis of the gut microbiota and altered metabolomic profiles. Treatment options for&#xD;
      patients with AN constitutes outpatient and inpatient care accordingly with the severity of&#xD;
      the disorder. So far, no biomarker has been strongly proposed as an indicator of the&#xD;
      disorder's severity or for assessing the progression of the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to assess and monitor the nutritional rehabilitation of patients&#xD;
      with AN during hospitalization treatment. Throughout the treatment's course, nutrition and&#xD;
      feeding process, vital signs, psychopathology and biological samples will be gathered and&#xD;
      statistical analysis of these data is expected to reveal potential biomarker/s for monitoring&#xD;
      the progression of recovery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Inpatients with AN and non-eating disorders control subjects will be informed about the&#xD;
      project outline, objectives and inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring of AN patients will take place during in-hospital rehabilitation. Physical exam,&#xD;
      lab tests, bioelectrical impedance analysis and psychometric evaluation will take place twice&#xD;
      a month. Plasma and serum will be collected and isolated form blood samples, while stool&#xD;
      samples will be collected for Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) metabolomics analysis and in&#xD;
      StoolFix tubes for DNA isolation from intestinal microbiota. For serum and plasma isolation,&#xD;
      whole blood will be directly and properly drawn into a vacutainer tube and promptly&#xD;
      centrifuged. Then, samples will be stored at -80C until further elaboration. Case record&#xD;
      forms will be carefully checked for missing data and inconsistencies prior to developing a&#xD;
      proper database based on data entry. The highest ethical standards and data protection will&#xD;
      be considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment will include Medical history, Anthropometric measurements, Vital signs, Nutrition,&#xD;
      Subjective Global Assessment-Patient Generated (SGA-PG), Biochemical parameters, Appetite&#xD;
      hormones, Inflammation markers, Oxidative stress markers, Composition of intestinal&#xD;
      microbiota, Psychometric scales-measurements, Eating Attitude Test-26 (EAT-26), Eating&#xD;
      Disorder Examination Questionnaire (EDE-Q), Spielberger State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI),&#xD;
      Beck Depression Inventory (BDI), Body Appreciation Scale (BAS), Sense of Coherence Scale&#xD;
      (SOC), Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) for subjective appetite estimation&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolic recovery in patients with AN</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Month 1, Month 2, Month 3, Month 4, Month 5, Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in metabolite concentrations in gut microbiome. The changes will be evaluated via Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) metabolomics analysis in stool samples collected in different time intervals during in-hospital rehabilitation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Anorexia Nervosa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anorexia Nervosa (AN)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Anorexia Nervosa patients hospitalized for rehabilitation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rehabilitation</intervention_name>
    <description>Hospitalized patients with AN under treatment for rehabilitation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anorexia Nervosa (AN)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        20 Males and females with AN who are hospitalized for rehabilitation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Patients with Anorexia Nervosa according to the DSM-V (American Psychiatric Association,&#xD;
        2013)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Antibiotic treatment before and during the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andriana C. Kaliora</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Harokopio University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andriana C. Kaliora, Dr</last_name>
    <phone>+306976094521</phone>
    <email>akaliora@hua.gr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Charalampia Amerikanou, Dr</last_name>
    <phone>+306947526539</phone>
    <email>amerikanou@windowslive.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kaliora, Andriana C.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <state>Attica</state>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andriana C. Kaliora</last_name>
      <phone>+306976094521</phone>
      <email>akaliora@hua.gr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Harokopio University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andriana C Kaliora</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Prof. in Foods and Human Nutrition</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anorexia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anorexia Nervosa</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

