<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05626712</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CELZ-201-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05626712</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of CELZ-201 in Patients With Recent Onset Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>CREATE-1</acronym>
  <official_title>Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of CELZ-201 in Patients With Recent Onset Type 1 Diabetes (CREATE-1)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Creative Medical Technology Holdings Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Creative Medical Technology Holdings Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The brief purpose of this research study is to learn about the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      intra-arterial administration of CELZ-201 in patients with newly diagnosed Type 1 Diabetes&#xD;
      Mellitus (T1D).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study is a Phase I/IIa randomized, controlled clinical trial to evaluate&#xD;
      CELZ-201 therapy as an intervention for the treatment of recent onset Type 1 Diabetes. The&#xD;
      objective is to determine the safety and efficacy of CELZ-201 administration, based on the&#xD;
      timing and dose of CELZ-201 treatment. Subjects who meet eligibility criteria will be&#xD;
      randomized to treatment or control groups, in a 2:1 ratio. Subjects in the Group I (Treatment&#xD;
      Group, n=12) will receive standard of care for type 1 diabetes and CELZ-201 within 1 month&#xD;
      from enrollment (within 180 days of diagnosis). Subjects in Group II (Control Arm, n=6) and&#xD;
      will receive enhanced standard of care for type 1 diabetes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 7, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study is a two-arm, open label, randomized trial. Subjects who meet eligibility criteria will be randomized to treatment or control groups in a 2:1 ratio.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome to be assessed is tolerability and safety of the CELZ-201 therapy. The incidence of adverse events (grade 2 or above as per CTCAE version 5.0) in both groups at 6 months.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of adverse events (grade 2 or above as per CTCAE version 5.0) in both groups at 12 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of adverse events (grade 2 or above as per CTCAE version 5.0) in both groups at 24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glycosylated HbA1C</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in glycosylated HbA1c (%)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin Requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in exogenous insulin requirement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Islet Autoantibody Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in islet autoantibody levels GAD65 (U/mL), IA2 (U/mL), and ZnT8 (U/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alloreactive Antibody Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in alloreactive antibody levels (U/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C-peptide during a 4-hour MMTT</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in fasting, peak stimulated and AUC C-peptide (ng/mL) during a 4-hour MMTT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CELZ-201 Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will receive a single dose of CELZ-201, in addition to standard of care of care for Type 1 Diabetes treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will receive standard of care for Type 1 Diabetes only.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CELZ-201 Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants in this group will receive a single dose of CELZ-201, in addition to standard of care for Type 1 Diabetes treatment. Perinatal tissue derived cells will be administered at a dose of 1x10^6 cells/kg via an intra-arterial infusion into the dorsal pancreatic artery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CELZ-201 Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Enhanced standard of care for Type 1 Diabetes treatment only.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject must be able to understand and provide signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Males and females, 18-35 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of T1D within 180 days, with stimulated C-peptide peak level &gt;0.6 ng/mL as&#xD;
             assessed by 4-hour MMTT at the time of Visit 0 (screening).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Diagnosed with T1D, according to ADA standard criteria, and confirmed by positivity to&#xD;
             at least two islet autoantibodies, GAD65, IA-2, or ZnT8.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Mentally stable and able to comply with the procedures of the study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects must be willing to comply with &quot;standard-of-care&quot; diabetes management.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects with eGFR &gt;80 ml/min/1.73m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test upon&#xD;
             study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Female (and male) subjects with reproductive potential must agree to use two FDA&#xD;
             approved methods of birth control for the entire duration of the study. Potential&#xD;
             subjects of childbearing potential should agree to use effective contraception for the&#xD;
             entire 2-year period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Adequate venous access to support study required blood draws.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability or unwillingness of a subject to give written informed consent or comply&#xD;
             with study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. BMI&gt;28 kg/m.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. HbA1c &gt; 9%&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with poorly controlled hypertension as defined by systolic blood pressure&#xD;
             &gt;140 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;90 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with any history of cardiac disease, including but not limited to myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, uncompensated heart failure, fluid overload, as well as any clinically&#xD;
             significant abnormality identified on prior cardiac stress test, angiogram evaluation,&#xD;
             or echocardiogram.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with liver disease, portal hypertension, any coagulopathy (including history&#xD;
             of Factor V deficiency) or long-term anti-coagulant therapy (except low-dose aspirin).&#xD;
             Other hepatic conditions including hepatic anatomic abnormalities or variants that&#xD;
             would place the individual at increased risk in the judgment of the investigator are&#xD;
             also considered exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Symptomatic cholecystolithiasis; acute or chronic pancreatitis; or current symptomatic&#xD;
             peptic ulcer disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects with uncontrolled thyroid disease: thyroid stimulating hormone &lt;0.3 mU/L or&#xD;
             &gt;5 mU/L; free T4 &lt;5.0 ug/dL or &gt;11.0 ug/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any of the following laboratory findings: hemoglobin &lt;11.5 g/dL (females) or &lt;13.2&#xD;
             g/dL (males); leukocytes &lt;3,000/μL; neutrophils &lt;1,500/μL; lymphocytes &lt;800/μL;&#xD;
             platelets &lt;100,000/μL; elevation in AST and ALT &gt;2 x ULN (upper limit of normal); LDL&#xD;
             cholesterol &gt;160; Triglycerides &gt;3 x ULN; total bilirubin &gt;1.5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Screening laboratory evidence consistent with significant chronic active infection&#xD;
             (i.e.., hepatitis B and C, tuberculosis, and HIV), and IGRA Tuberculosis (Tb) test&#xD;
             during screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Ongoing acute infections, e.g., acute respiratory tract, urinary tract, or&#xD;
             gastrointestinal tract infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects with eating disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Ongoing or anticipated use of diabetes medications other than insulin.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Current or ongoing use of non-insulin pharmaceuticals that affect glycemic control&#xD;
             within 7 days of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Recent recipient of any licensed or investigational live attenuated vaccine(s) within&#xD;
             6 weeks of randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patients who have participated in previous clinical studies, other than observational&#xD;
             studies, will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Concomitant therapy with immunosuppressive drugs, immunomodulators, or cytotoxic&#xD;
             agents, or previous therapy less than 3 months from randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. History or diagnosis of malignancy with the exception of a history of localized basal&#xD;
             or squamous cell carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Any history of gastroparesis or other severe gastrointestinal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Presence of an allograft.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Diagnosed or self-reported drug or alcohol abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. An individual who has a medical, psychological or social condition that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Principal Investigator, would interfere with safe and proper completion&#xD;
             of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Pregnancy or ongoing breastfeeding for women; unwillingness or inability of both&#xD;
             females and males of childbearing age to use a reliable and effective form of&#xD;
             contraception, for the entire 2-year duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Inability to perform any of the assessments required for endpoint analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Known history of serious allergic reactions, including anaphylaxis to CELZ-201 or its&#xD;
             preparation components. Specifically, patients with a prior history of heparin induced&#xD;
             thrombocytopenia or any other adverse reaction to heparin, will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. The investigator believes that participating in the trial is not in the best interest&#xD;
             of the patient, or the investigator considers patient unsuitable for enrollment (such&#xD;
             as unpredictable risks or subject compliance issues).&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Positive for coronavirus disease (COVID)-19 by PCR or evidence of active infection per&#xD;
             local institutional standards.&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Allergy to iodine contrast or anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. For female subjects: Pregnant, nursing, or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             course of entire duration of the study (approximately little over two years) or&#xD;
             unwillingness to comply with contraceptive requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. For male subjects: Male subjects with a female partner who is planning to become&#xD;
             pregnant with the male subject during the entire course of the study or unwillingness&#xD;
             to comply with contraceptive requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Camillo Ricordi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Miami, Diabetes Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Creative Medical Technology</last_name>
    <phone>(480) 399-2822</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrials@creativemedicaltechnology.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diabetes Research Institute, University of Miami Miller School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Camillo Ricordi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>305-243-6913</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Camillo Ricordi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rodolfo Alejandro, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 7, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 7, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 10, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recent Onset Type 1 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Adult Onset Type 1 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 1 Diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

