<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05611060</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Cameron2022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05611060</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Building Healthy Life Skills Program</brief_title>
  <official_title>Building Healthy Life Skills for Merced County Navigation Center</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Merced</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Merced</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this intervention trial is to learn test whether participation in the Building&#xD;
      Health Life Skills Program leads to improvements in psychological well-being and stress&#xD;
      management skills for people who are experiencing homelessness and housing insecurity. The&#xD;
      main questions it aims to answer are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Will participation in the Building Healthy Life Skills Program lead to better skills in&#xD;
           managing negative emotions?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Will participation in the Building Healthy Life Skills Program lead to improvements in&#xD;
           psychological well-being, sleep quality, and health-related quality of life?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to complete three surveys: one prior to the first session of the&#xD;
      program, one at the end of the program, and one three months later. The surveys include&#xD;
      measures of skills for managing negative emotions, mood states, sleep quality, health-related&#xD;
      quality of life, illness experiences, and history of childhood adversity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Community members who are experiencing homelessness and receiving support services from the&#xD;
      Merced County Navigation Center and who have enrolled in the center's Building Healthy Life&#xD;
      Skills Program will be invited to participate in this intervention evaluation study. The&#xD;
      Building Healthy Life Skills program is a 10-week program designed to provide participants&#xD;
      with an understanding of how abuse, neglect and household dysfunctions during childhood&#xD;
      affect emotional, social, and cognitive well-being; and to provide training in emotion&#xD;
      regulation skills, including adaptive emotional processing and expression, mindfulness, and&#xD;
      cognitive reappraisal. The sessions are two hours in duration and conducted in classroom&#xD;
      style. Open enrollment will be conducted four times a year, serving approximately 60&#xD;
      individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 10, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study utilizes a pretest-posttest design, with surveys completed at baseline immediately prior to the start of the intervention onset, immediately after completion of the intervention, and at follow-up 3 months after the completion of the intervention.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in health-related quality of life as assessed by the SF-12, for which scores range from 0 to 100 with higher scores reflecting better quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life as assessed by the SF 12</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depressive symptoms as assessed by the Center for Epidemiological Studies Depression measure, for which averaged rating scores range from 0 to 3 with higher scores reflecting more depressive symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Center for Epidemiological Studies Depression measure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in stress as assessed by the Perceived Stress Scale, for which averaged rating scores range from 1 to 5 with higher scores reflecting greater stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Perceived Stress Scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rumination as an emotion regulation behavior as assessed by the Rumination and Reflections Questionnaire,for which averaged rating scores range from 1 to t with higher scores reflecting more rumination</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Rumination and Reflections Questionnaire</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in emotional suppression as assessed by the Cortauld Emotional Control Scale (scores range is 1-4, higher scores reflect higher suppression) and the Emotion Regulation Questionnaire (scores range is 1-5, higher scores reflect higher suppression)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Cortauld Emotional Control Scale and the Emotion Regulation Questionnaire</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mindfulness as an emotional regulation tendency as assessed by the Mindful Awareness Attention Scale, for which averaged rating scores range from 1 to 5 with higher scores reflecting greater mindfulness tendencies</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Mindful Awareness Attention Scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cognitive reappraisal as an emotion regulation strategy as assessed by the Emotion Regulation Questionnaire, for which averaged rating scores range from 1 to 5 with higher scores reflecting higher use of cognitive reappraisal</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Emotion Regulation Questionnaire</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in general self-efficacy as assessed by the General Self-Efficacy Survey, for which averaged rating scores range from 1 to 5 with higher scores reflecting higher sense of self-efficacy in managing challenging situations</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the General Self-Efficacy Survey</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in resilience as assessed by the Ego Resilience 89, for which averaged rating scores range from 1 to 5 with higher scores reflecting higher resilience in managing challenging situations</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Ego Resilience 89</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep quality as assessed by the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Inventory, for which averaged rating scores range from 0 to 21 with higher scores reflecting poorer sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Inventory</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in physical health as assessed by self-reported number of sick days in the past month (ranging from 0 to 31) and a the frequency of 17 symptoms each rated 1 to 5 and higher averaged rating scores reflecting higher symptom loads</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline, immediately following completion of the intervention, and 3 months following intervention completion</time_frame>
    <description>Scores on a symptom checklist and number of sick days</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Adverse Childhood Experiences</condition>
  <condition>Housing Problems</condition>
  <condition>Emotion Regulation</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Building Healthy Life Skills Program</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention provides education and training in the long-term mental and physical health consequences of childhood adversity and emotion regulation skills.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are receiving support services from the Merced County Navigation&#xD;
             Center due their current experiences of housing insecurity or homelessness, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have enrolled in the Building Healthy Life Skills program&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals under the age of 18 years and those who cannot speak English or Spanish&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Linda D Cameron, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>209-626-6892</phone>
    <email>lcameron@ucmerced.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marisela Yepez, B.S.</last_name>
    <phone>209-228-2252</phone>
    <email>myepez5@ucmerced.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Merced</name>
      <address>
        <city>Merced</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95343</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Linda D Cameron, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>209-626-6892</phone>
      <email>lcameron@ucmerced.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Marisela Yepez, B.A.</last_name>
      <email>myepez5@ucmerced.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Merced</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Linda Diane Cameron</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We have not decided on the IPD sharing plan at this point in time.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

