<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05622747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UoPAPHHOA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05622747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acute Passive Heating in Healthy Older Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Time Course of Cardiovascular Function, Cognitive Function and Heat Shock Proteins in Response to Acute Passive Heating in Older Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Portsmouth</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Portsmouth</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aging is associated with a decline in cardiovascular health, cognitive function and losses in&#xD;
      muscle strength, with half or more of those over age 65 suffering from two or more&#xD;
      comorbidities (e.g., heart disease, type 2 diabetes). The worldwide population of older&#xD;
      adults is growing rapidly, with one in six people expected to be over age 65 by 2050. This&#xD;
      will place further financial burden from chronic diseases on already stressed healthcare&#xD;
      systems. While studies show that frequent exercise is an effective way for older adults to&#xD;
      maintain or improve cardiovascular and metabolic health, older individuals are less&#xD;
      physically active and do not adhere well to exercise programs, often due to physical or&#xD;
      medical limitations. Therefore, alternative methods for older adults to get the same health&#xD;
      benefits as exercise require further exploration. Recent work has shown a single session of&#xD;
      passive heat therapy could be an alternative way to improve cardiovascular health and&#xD;
      cognitive function in various populations, however, the length of time that these benefits&#xD;
      last is yet to be explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aging is associated with declines in cardiovascular health and cognitive function as well as&#xD;
      chronic inflammation and the development of neurodegenerative conditions such as Alzheimer's&#xD;
      and Parkinson's disease. Additionally, ageing results in a loss of muscle size and strength,&#xD;
      commonly referred to as sarcopenia, leading to increased risk of falls or adverse&#xD;
      exercise-related events. It is well understood that frequent exercise improves cardiovascular&#xD;
      and metabolic health whilst lowering the risk of disease and all-cause mortality, acting as a&#xD;
      treatment for many different health conditions. Despite the evidence of its efficacy, many&#xD;
      individuals struggle with adherence to exercise programmes, particularly older adults and&#xD;
      clinical populations, with many individuals within these populations unable to perform&#xD;
      exercise due to physical limitations or medical contraindications. With one in six people&#xD;
      expected to be over the age of 65 years by 2050 and corresponding increases in&#xD;
      non-communicable diseases (e.g., cancer, diabetes, cardiovascular disease) anticipated from&#xD;
      this aging population, the development of adjunct treatments or alternatives to exercise to&#xD;
      improve general health in older populations is needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent work has shown one such potential solution could be the use of passive heat therapy&#xD;
      (PHT) (e.g., hot water immersion, sauna), which can achieve health benefits comparable to&#xD;
      exercise. Acute PHT induces vascular improvements including increased blood flow, reduced&#xD;
      blood pressure. and macro- and microvascular dilator function in various populations. Acute&#xD;
      PHT has also been shown to increase reaction time, while mixed results have been seen in its&#xD;
      effect on executive function in both young and older populations. The mechanisms for these&#xD;
      improvements, however, are currently unclear, and may be related to increases in nitric oxide&#xD;
      activity or reductions in biomarkers of inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One potential mechanism for the physiological benefits obtained from PHT is the increase of&#xD;
      cytoprotective heat shock proteins (HSP) (specifically HSP27, HSP60, HSP70 and HSP90)&#xD;
      intracellularly (i) and extracellularly (e) in response to increases in deep body&#xD;
      temperature. Increases in the expression of these HSPs have been shown to play a role in&#xD;
      reducing inflammation and protecting the vasculature via increases in endothelial nitric&#xD;
      oxide synthase activity. Increased HSP concentrations may also prevent the accumulation of&#xD;
      harmful biomarkers in the brain that play a role in cognitive decline and development of&#xD;
      neurodegenerative diseases. There is also evidence that increased preoperative levels of both&#xD;
      iHSP70 and eHSP70 are correlated with improved postoperative outcomes following cardiac&#xD;
      surgery. Aging, however, is associated with a reduction in HSP transcription activity in&#xD;
      various tissues, resulting in an impaired heat shock response and development of a&#xD;
      pro-inflammatory state.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous work using acute hot water immersion has shown mixed results, with various studies&#xD;
      showing increases in eHSP70, iHSP70 and iHSP90, while others have reported no change in&#xD;
      expression. Heating stimuli applied in these studies has varied in magnitude, duration and&#xD;
      whole body or not, and measurements of HSPs have taken place at various time points before,&#xD;
      during and after PHT. Therefore, it is possible that upregulation of HSPs may have been&#xD;
      missed, as no time course relationship exists between a single bout of PHT and upregulation&#xD;
      of HSPs. Additionally, the duration for acute vascular and cognitive benefits from PHT and&#xD;
      when function is returned to baseline is yet to be determined. A time course relationship&#xD;
      study to determine the peak HSP response to acute passive heat therapy in older adults would&#xD;
      provide insight into the relationship between acute changes in vascular or cognitive function&#xD;
      and concurrent upregulation of both intracellular and extracellular HSPs, as well as its&#xD;
      potential implications for improved surgical outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brachial artery flow-mediated dilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then 1 hour, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change in brachial artery diameter and return to baseline as assessed by ultrasound</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microvascular function</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then 1 hour, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in microvascular function and return to baseline as assessed via iontophoresis on the forearm with acetylcholine (Ach) and Insulin, Area under the curve is the unit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stroke volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then 1 hour, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in stroke volume and return to baseline measured noninvasively via thoracic impedance. mL/m^2 is the unit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total peripheral resistance</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then 1 hour, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in total peripheral resistance and return to baseline measured noninvasively via thoracic impedance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac output</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then 1 hour, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in cardiac output and return to baseline measured noninvasively via thoracic impedance. L/min is the unit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracellular HSP27 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in iHSP27 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via immunoblotting in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracellular HSP60 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in iHSP60 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via immunoblotting in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracellular HSP70 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in iHSP70 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via immunoblotting in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracellular HSP90 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in iHSP90 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via immunoblotting in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma eHSP27 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in plasma eHSP27 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma eHSP60 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in plasma eHSP60 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma eHSP70 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in plasma eHSP70 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma eHSP90 concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in plasma eHSP90 concentration and return to baseline. Measured via ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reaction time</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in reaction time and return to baseline as assessed using ANAM: Automated Neurophysiological Assessment Metrics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Logical reasoning</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in logical reasoning and return to baseline as assessed using ANAM: Automated Neurophysiological Assessment Metrics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Memory</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in memory function and return to baseline as assessed using ANAM: Automated Neurophysiological Assessment Metrics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cerebral oxygenation</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre hot water immersion, then immediately post, 3 hours, 24 hours and 48 hours post</time_frame>
    <description>Change in cerebral oxygenation and return to baseline. Assessed using Near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS) attached to the forehead</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Passive heating intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1 h hot water immersion (to the clavicle, @40°C, rectal temperature ~38.5°C and &lt;39°C)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Passive heating</intervention_name>
    <description>1 h hot water immersion (to the clavicle, @40°C, rectal temperature ~38.5°C and &lt;39°C)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Passive heating intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female age ≥ 55&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Free from cardiometabolic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index of 18-35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of a normal 12-lead ECG approved by the School Independent Medical Officer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capacity to understand and provide their written, informed consent to participate in&#xD;
             the study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to understand or cooperate with the study protocol due to learning difficulties&#xD;
             or otherwise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any current, or past medical (last five years), history of any cardiovascular,&#xD;
             respiratory, cancer, renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, haematological, lymphatic,&#xD;
             neurological, psychiatric, or any other disease or diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any regular medication for the last five years (not including acute courses of&#xD;
             treatment of less than one month for discrete, resolved conditions).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medications that may influence physiological responses to the passive heating&#xD;
             intervention Uncontrolled hypertension (≥ 150 mmHg systolic and/or ≥ 90 mmHg&#xD;
             diastolic)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index of &gt; 35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent long-term exposure to a hot climate (within the previous three months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current smoker (or have stopped smoking within the previous three months)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Portsmouth</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ant Shepherd</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Lecturer in Physical Activity, Exercise and Health</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Passive heating</keyword>
  <keyword>Endothelial function</keyword>
  <keyword>Heat shock proteins</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive function</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All data will be anonymized and raw data uploaded to the University of Portsmouth repository.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After data has been collected and analyzed it will be available indefinitely.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Available to public at repository website</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

