<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05615194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2023-3190</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05615194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Impact of a Single Dexmedetomidine Bolus on Intraoperative Sevoflurane Consumption (DEXHALE)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Clinical Study to Assess the Impact of a Single Dexmedetomidine Bolus During Induction of General Anesthesia on Intraoperative Sevoflurane Consumption in Elective Laparoscopic Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ciusss de L'Est de l'Île de Montréal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ciusss de L'Est de l'Île de Montréal</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sevoflurane is a volatile agent easy to control thanks to the Minimum Alveolar Concentration&#xD;
      (MAC) allowing its titration for an optimal depth of anesthesia. Growing biomedical evidence&#xD;
      also highlight its anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects protecting against&#xD;
      ischemia-reperfusion injury in cardiac surgery and, potentially, in organ transplant. The&#xD;
      estimated annual contribution of inhalational anesthetic agents represents about 0.01% of&#xD;
      global CO2 production. Alternatives such as total intravenous anesthesia (TIVA) avoid direct&#xD;
      greenhouse emission, but their indirect carbon footprint remains a major problem. For all&#xD;
      these reasons, this research aim to find a way to maintain the use of sevoflurane for its&#xD;
      clinical benefits while reducing its consumption to limit the environmental consequences. The&#xD;
      use of dexmedetomidine could help anesthesiologists to achieve this greener sevoflurane&#xD;
      anesthesia. Dexmedetomidine is a potent, highly selective α-2 adrenergic receptor agonist&#xD;
      described as a unique sedative with analgesic and sympatholytic properties. This new&#xD;
      randomized controlled trial (RCT) will answer the question whether a single bolus of&#xD;
      dexmedetomidine (0.6 mcg.kg-1 on 10 minutes during induction) compared to placebo has a&#xD;
      clinically significant impact on sevoflurane consumption during laparoscopic elective&#xD;
      surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Inhaled gases have been used since the advent of anesthesia due to their analgesic and&#xD;
      dissociative properties. However, these are now part of a growing environmental debate which&#xD;
      leads us to reconsider their systematic use for general anesthesia. Sevoflurane is a volatile&#xD;
      agent easy to monitor using the Minimal Alveolar Concentration (MAC) facilitating its&#xD;
      titration for adequate anesthesia depth. Growing biomedical evidence also highlight its&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects protecting against ischemia-reperfusion injury in&#xD;
      cardiac surgery and, potentially, in organ transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The estimated annual contribution of inhalational anesthetic agents represents about 0.01% of&#xD;
      global CO2 production. This data can be illustrated as a commercial airliner flying 418 times&#xD;
      around the world. Desflurane is gradually abandoned as its greenhouse effect is 25 times more&#xD;
      potent than sevoflurane for an equivalent MAC and fresh gas flow. As low-flow inhalational&#xD;
      techniques and scavenging technologies become the standard of practice, anesthesiologists&#xD;
      still cannot prevent the gas to be released in the atmosphere .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternatives such as total intravenous anesthesia (TIVA) avoid direct greenhouse emission,&#xD;
      but their indirect carbon footprint remains a major problem. Propofol has a high potential&#xD;
      for bioaccumulation. It has high mobility in soil, resists degradation in aquatic environment&#xD;
      and concentrates in adipose tissue of aquatic organism. To control its toxicity, destruction&#xD;
      should be done by incineration over 1000°C. Unfortunately, studies prove that 32-49% of&#xD;
      dispensed propofol is waisted and is mostly disposed unproperly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all these reasons, this research aim to find a way to maintain the use of sevoflurane for&#xD;
      its clinical benefits while reducing its consumption to limit the environmental consequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of dexmedetomidine could help us achieve this greener sevoflurane anesthesia.&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine is a potent, highly selective α-2 adrenergic receptor agonist described as a&#xD;
      unique sedative with analgesic and sympatholytic properties. Currently approved for sedation,&#xD;
      this molecule shows many advantages compared to hypnotic drugs such as propofol. Although&#xD;
      still under investigation, dexmedetomidine would possibly have a lower hazard environmental&#xD;
      score. The use of dexmedetomidine also shows promising results regarding the reduction of&#xD;
      emergence cough and agitation. Decrease in pain and post-operative nausea and vomiting (PONV)&#xD;
      are other benefits of dexmedetomidine providing conditions to promote enhanced recovery after&#xD;
      surgery (ERAS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many investigations have studied impacts of dexmedetomidine as an adjuvant to general&#xD;
      anesthesia for its opioid sparing capacity, and hemodynamics response during laparoscopic&#xD;
      surgeries. Fewer research specifically wondered about sevoflurane dispense outcome. Moreover,&#xD;
      they don't reflect the anesthesia practice of North America and their sample sizes are low.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This new randomized controlled trial (RCT) will answer the question whether a single bolus of&#xD;
      dexmedetomidine (0.6 mcg.kg-1 on 10 minutes during induction) compared to placebo has a&#xD;
      clinically significant impact on sevoflurane consumption during laparoscopic elective&#xD;
      surgery. Opioid requirement, need for vasopressors, post-operative events (PONV, shivering,&#xD;
      critical respiratory event) and time for readiness for Post-Anesthesia Care Unit (PACU) will&#xD;
      also be assessed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 5, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will be 1:1 randomly assign to one of the two following groups: dexmedetomidine 0.6 mcg.kg-1 (group D) or a saline placebo of equivalent volume (group C) to be administered on 10 minutes during induction.&#xD;
The patient presenting all the inclusion criteria and no exclusion criteria for this study will be approached by the anesthesia research team. They will provide explanations on the study as well as a consent form to the patient for him to have time to read it before the surgery. The risk of serious and unexpected adverse reactions to dexmedetomidine will also be disclosed to the patient before his agreement to participate to the study. After his approval, the patient will sign the consent and will be randomized.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>The patient, the anesthesiologist in charge, the surgeon, the PACU staff and the research team evaluating the patient in PACU will be blinded to the randomization group.&#xD;
The syringe containing the dexmedetomidine or the placebo will be prepared by an anesthesiologist or a pharmacist external to the study and identified by a unique number so that the patient's group can be identified if needed. Both solutions are translucent and total volume to be administered on 10 minutes during induction will be of equal volume.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sevoflurane consumption expressed in mL.kg-1.h-1</measure>
    <time_frame>From intubation to end of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the total sevoflurane consumption when using a dexmedetomidine single bolus (group D) of 0.6 mcg.kg-1 on 10 minutes during induction versus placebo (group C). This will be expressed in mL.kg-1.h-1 of surgery.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total intra-operative remifentanil consumption (in mcg.kg-1)</measure>
    <time_frame>From intubation to end of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the total intra-operative remifentanil consumption during anesthesia based on the NoL index (Medasense Ltd., Ramat Gan, Israel)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of time during the intraoperative period for which the NOL index will be above the pain threshold of 25 (in % of surgical time)</measure>
    <time_frame>From intubation to end of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the percentage of time during the intraoperative period for which the NOL index will be above the pain threshold of 25</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total amount of hydromorphone given IV in PACU (in mg)</measure>
    <time_frame>From PACU admission to discharge</time_frame>
    <description>To quantify the total amount of hydromorphone needed in PACU</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intra-operative and postanesthesia care unit (PACU) doses of vasopressors</measure>
    <time_frame>From intubation to PACU discharge</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the intra- and post-operative requirements of phenylephrine, ephedrine, glycopyrrolate and atropine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean end tidal sevoflurane (in %) and MAC needed to maintain the BIS index (Medtronic, Canada) between 40 and 60</measure>
    <time_frame>From intubation to end of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the mean end tidal sevoflurane (EtSevo) and MAC needed to maintain the BIS index between 40 and 60</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total intraoperative time from intubation until end of surgery with BIS index between 40 and 60 (in minutes)</measure>
    <time_frame>From intubation to end of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the % of total intraoperative time from intubation until end of surgery with BIS index between 40 and 60</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time for extubation (in minutes)</measure>
    <time_frame>From sevoflurane discontinuation to extubation</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the time for extubation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time for awakening (in minutes)</measure>
    <time_frame>From sevoflurane discontinuation to when the patient is opening his eyes</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the time for awakening</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative outcomes such as postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV), shivering and critical respiratory event (CRE)</measure>
    <time_frame>From PACU admission to discharge</time_frame>
    <description>To assess postoperative outcomes such as postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV), shivering and critical respiratory event (CRE)&#xD;
A CRE will be defined as the occurrence of one of the following criteria:&#xD;
Upper airway obstruction requiring an intervention&#xD;
Moderate hypoxemia: SpO2 of 90-93% on 2 L.min-1 nasal cannula O2&#xD;
Severe hypoxemia: SpO2 &lt; 90% on 2 L.min-1 nasal cannula O2&#xD;
Signs of respiratory distress or impeding ventilatory failure&#xD;
Patient requiring reintubation in the PACU&#xD;
Clinical evidence or suspicion of pulmonary aspiration after tracheal extubation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total time spent in PACU (in minutes)</measure>
    <time_frame>From PACU admission to discharge</time_frame>
    <description>To compare total time for readiness for discharge from PACU between groups assessed by recovery scores (Aldrete's modified score and Maisonneuve-Rosemont PACU score)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">84</enrollment>
  <condition>Inhalation Anesthesia</condition>
  <condition>Dexmedetomidine</condition>
  <condition>Sevoflurane</condition>
  <condition>Laparoscopy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Normal saline in volume equivalent of dexmedetomidine dose according to patient weight ; Administered via infusion pump (Smith Medical Medfusion® 4000 Syringe Infusion Pump) so that the full dose is delivered over 10 minutes during induction of general anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dexmedetomidine 0.6 mcg/kg (adjusted body weight) ; Administered via infusion pump (Smith Medical Medfusion® 4000 Syringe Infusion Pump) so that the full dose is delivered over 10 minutes during induction of general anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine</intervention_name>
    <description>0.6 mcg/kg in infusion over 10 minutes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dexmedetomidine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Precedex</other_name>
    <other_name>Dexmedetomidine Hydrochloride</other_name>
    <other_name>DIN : 02339366</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Volume equivalent in infusion over 10 minutes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Normal Saline</other_name>
    <other_name>NaCl 0.9%</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA 1-3 patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing laparoscopic surgery of duration time expected under 120 minutes using&#xD;
             general anesthesia with sevoflurane&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fully consented&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18yo&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No allergy to one of the medications used in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe coronary artery disease; ventricular dysfunction, serious cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia (including atrial fibrillation and high-grade atrioventricular block)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to severe renal or hepatic dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to any drug used in the study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal of the patient for participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe PONV&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Olivier Verdonck</last_name>
    <phone>+15142523426</phone>
    <email>overdonck@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Nadia Godin</last_name>
    <phone>+15142523400</phone>
    <phone_ext>3193</phone_ext>
    <email>ngodin.hmr@ssss.gouv.qc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Maisonneuve-Rosemont, CIUSSS de l'Est de l'Ile de Montréal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H1T2M4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Olivier Verdonck, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+15142523426</phone>
      <email>overdonck@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Philippe Richebé, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+15142523426</phone>
      <email>philipperichebe@live.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Olivier Verdonck, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Philippe Richebe, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 13, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 13, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 15, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ciusss de L'Est de l'Île de Montréal</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Olivier Verdonck</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Deputy chief of the Department of Anesthesiology of Maisonneuve-Rosemont Hospital, University of Montreal(UDeM)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Environment</keyword>
  <keyword>kgCO2eq</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Aspiration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

