<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05799196</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HasanuddinU/Ortopedi/001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05799196</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effectiveness of the Microfracture Technique in the Meniscal Healing</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effectiveness of the Microfracture Technique in the Meniscal Healing Rate in Patients With Meniscal Tear Among Indonesian Population</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hasanuddin University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hasanuddin University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Meniscus injuries are a very common cause of knee pain. The meniscus is a semilunar&#xD;
      fibrocartilage structure found on the medial and lateral sides of the knee. The meniscus&#xD;
      serves to absorb impact and protect the articular cartilage during weight-bearing activities,&#xD;
      joint stability, proprioception, and nutrition. This has a significant effect on knee&#xD;
      biomechanics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the menisci are injured, the biomechanics of the knee change so that degenerative&#xD;
      changes occur more frequently in the tibiofemoral compartment. Improvement of tibiofemoral&#xD;
      arthrosis after meniscectomy surgery has been demonstrated in several long-term clinical&#xD;
      studies. With increasing awareness of the importance of the meniscus in knee biomechanics,&#xD;
      various meniscus repair techniques have been developed. In addition, several adjuvants for&#xD;
      healing have been proposed to enhance meniscus healing. However, a study showed the meniscal&#xD;
      repair failure rate increased from 22% to 24% at 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study found the healing rate of meniscus repair, which was accompanied by ACL repair, had a&#xD;
      greater healing rate, 93% vs. 50%. Hemarthrosis that occurs after bony tunneling during ACL&#xD;
      reconstruction provides a fibrin clot and an environment rich in factors that promote healing&#xD;
      of the newly repaired meniscus. The fibrin clot provides the structural foundation for&#xD;
      meniscus healing. Transmission factors, such as fibronectin and growth factors, are also&#xD;
      present.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Microfracture is a common procedure used for the treatment of damage to the articular&#xD;
      cartilage in the knee. This procedure is used to stimulate the production of fibrocartilage&#xD;
      in areas of injured cartilage. Microfractures are performed by creating 1 or more small&#xD;
      channels (1 to 3 mm in size) that pierce the subchondral bone and release bone-forming&#xD;
      components into the joint. Microfractures serve to promote the formation of fibrocartilage&#xD;
      over damaged cartilage. Research in 2016 used an animal model (Capra hircus) to investigate&#xD;
      the effectiveness of the microfracture technique on meniscus tear healing rates. They found&#xD;
      significant healing in meniscal repair accompanied by microfracture technique (65% vs 12%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However there is still not enough research regarding the efficacy of microfracture in&#xD;
      meniscal healing, especially among Indonesian. Therefore, the investigators aim to&#xD;
      investigate its efficacy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>6 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Healing Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Healing Rate, Investigated by MRI and Arthroscopy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Healing Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Healing Rate, Investigated by MRI and Arthroscopy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Outcome assessed with IKDC ScoreFunctional Outcome assessed with IKDC Score. The higher the score, the higher the level of function and the lower the level of symptoms. A score of 100 suggests no limitation with activities of daily living or sports activities and the absence of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Outcome assessed with IKDC Score. The higher the score, the higher the level of function and the lower the level of symptoms. A score of 100 suggests no limitation with activities of daily living or sports activities and the absence of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Microfractures</condition>
  <condition>Meniscus Tear</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Microfracture</arm_group_label>
    <description>The patient with meniscus tear would be performed meniscus repair with additional microfracture</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional</arm_group_label>
    <description>The patient with meniscus tear would be performed meniscus repair</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Microfracture</intervention_name>
    <description>Microfracture was made in the non-weight bearing chondral to provide the release of MSC and growth factor.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Conventional</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Microfracture</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with meniscus tear in Wahidin Sudirohusodo General Hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with meniscus tears&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient underwent meniscus repair surgery using arthroscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have an MRI examination before and after surgery within 6 months post-surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        B. Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with meniscus tears in the white-white area&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient underwent meniscus repair surgery without using arthroscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The patient did not perform an MRI examination before after surgery within 6 months&#xD;
             post-surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Muhammad Sakti, MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Hasanuddin University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Leonard Christianto Singjie, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+6281212609805</phone>
    <email>leonardcs@hotmail.co.id</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hasanuddin University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Makassar</city>
        <state>South Sulawesi</state>
        <country>Indonesia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Leonard Christianto Singjie, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+628121260985</phone>
      <email>leonardcs@hotmail.co.id</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Indonesia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 9, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hasanuddin University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Leonard Christianto Singjie</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>meniscus tear</keyword>
  <keyword>microfracture</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fractures, Stress</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

