<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05624411</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>soh-Med-22-11-03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05624411</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Outcomes of Post-placental Insertion of Cupper T380A and Multiload 375 Contraceptive Devices During Cesarean Section</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Outcomes of Post-placental Insertion of Cupper T380A and Multiload 375 Contraceptive Devices During Cesarean Section</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sohag University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sohag University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Clinical outcomes of post-placental insertion of Cupper T380A and Multiload 375 contraceptive&#xD;
      devices during cesarean section&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      An intrauterine device (IUD) is considered one of the most effective, highly convenient and&#xD;
      cheap methods of contraception[1]. IUD has been endorsed as a first-line contraceptive choice&#xD;
      by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists [2]. However, many complications&#xD;
      have been reported with its use, such as irregular bleeding, expulsion, pelvic pain, and&#xD;
      unexpected pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, extrauterine migration of IUD may result in damage to adjacent organs, bowel&#xD;
      injury or even death [3]. Well-designed studies have elucidated that uterine perforation is&#xD;
      expected in 0.2 to 3.6 per 1000 IUD insertions [4]. In addition, some case reports have shown&#xD;
      IUD displacement into the sigmoid colon and lower urinary tract [5-8].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nearly, fifty percent of malpositioned IUDs are asymptomatic and usually undetected for many&#xD;
      years. Taking into consideration the possible risk of extrauterine migration and its&#xD;
      dangerous sequelas, follow-up examinations are advised for all women after IUD insertion [9].&#xD;
&#xD;
      One of the safe, trusted and most convenient strategies to avoid new unwanted pregnancies is&#xD;
      immediate postpartum IUD placement, within 10 minutes of delivery of the placenta [10].&#xD;
      However, expulsion rates are higher after immediate postpartum IUD insertions in comparison&#xD;
      to delayed postpartum insertions (4-6 weeks postpartum)[11-13] Ultrasonographic assessment is&#xD;
      considered the standard tool for confirming the position of an IUD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2) Aim of the study The aim of the current study is to compare two types of intrauterine&#xD;
      devices, namely Cu T380A IUD and Multiload 375 IUD, inserted immediately post placental, as&#xD;
      regard to expulsion rates, safety, efficacy, side effects, and complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3) Subjects and Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      1) Study type: A randomized comparative clinical trial 4) Methods: This study is a clinical&#xD;
      trial that will include all patients fulfilling the eligibility criteria and presented to the&#xD;
      emergency unit of the department of Obstetrics and Gynecology at Sohag University hospital&#xD;
      (Egyptian tertiary referral hospital) who are requesting immediate postpartum contraception&#xD;
      between November 2022 and September 2023. The attending physician will explain the nature of&#xD;
      the study and all patients included will be asked to sign an informed consent. Participants&#xD;
      were randomly allocated through a computer-generated list into two groups. In the first group&#xD;
      Cu-T380A (Pregna International Ltd) will be inserted while in the second group Multiload 375&#xD;
      (Pregna International Ltd, Mumbai, India) will be inserted, Researchers and participants will&#xD;
      not be masked to the type of IUCD inserted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IUCDs will be inserted high at the fundus through the lower uterine segment incision&#xD;
      immediately after delivery of the placenta using the cylinder provided within the sterile&#xD;
      packaging; the IUCD pushing rod will not be used. Before placement in the uterine cavity,&#xD;
      both IUCD strings were lengthened using 10 cm of Vicryl sutures (polyglactin 910) number 0&#xD;
      which will then threaded through the cylinder to appear at the other end. Following insertion&#xD;
      adjacent to the fundus, the cylinder will be gradually moved downwards across the threads,&#xD;
      passed through the cervix, and removed vaginally after delivery [14], This technique ensures&#xD;
      that the threads are located within the vagina immediately after the operation and prevents&#xD;
      their entanglement within the cervical canal or uterine cavity[14]. The uterine incision will&#xD;
      then be closed in two layers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Transabdominal US will be done to all patients before discharge to ensure adequate position&#xD;
      of the IUD and then Women will be requested to attend follow-up appointment at 6 weeks after&#xD;
      delivery, gynecological examination in addition to transvaginal sonography will be done to&#xD;
      measure top-fundal distance that reflects the position of the IUD. The participants were&#xD;
      instructed to report the pattern of bleeding during the puerperium, the number of sanitary&#xD;
      pads used per day, the presence of blood clots, missed periods, fever, or vaginal discharge.&#xD;
      They were shown how to find the threads and informed to urgently seek medical care if they&#xD;
      could not feel the threads. During the puerperium, the Vicryl suture knot appeared below the&#xD;
      cervix; the threads were shortened to a length of 2 cm from the cervix. Transabdominal and&#xD;
      transvaginal 2D ultrasonography will be used to evaluate IUCD position in each visit.&#xD;
      Complete expulsion was recorded when the longitudinal arm of the IUCD was partially or&#xD;
      totally inside the cervix or vagina. Partial expulsion or displacement was recorded when the&#xD;
      IUCD was more than 10 mm away from the fundus but still totally within the uterine cavity&#xD;
      [15]. Women with severe PID who did not respond to treatment and/or had severe menorrhagia&#xD;
      were candidates for IUCD discontinuation and were prescribed another contraception method if&#xD;
      required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5) Statistical analysis: Data will be expressed as mean ± standard deviation (SD), unless&#xD;
      stated otherwise. Chi-squared test will be used to compare categorical variables and&#xD;
      Student's t-test to compare continuous variables. A p-value of &lt;0.05 will be considered&#xD;
      statistically significant. STATA v14 (StataCorp. 2015. Stata Statistical Software: Release&#xD;
      14. College Station, TX: StataCorp LP) and MedCalc programs and will be used for data&#xD;
      analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6) Study results and impact: The current study may prove or disprove the benefits versus the&#xD;
      risks of intrapartum insertion of different types of IUCDs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 22, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The expulsion rate of Multiload IUCD versus CopperT380A after post-placental insertion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The expulsion rate of Multiload IUCD versus CopperT380A after post-placental insertion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uterine bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>number of bleeding days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uterine bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>pattern of bleeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uterine bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>presence of blood clots</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PID</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>pesence of fever or vaginal discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>perforation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>presence of abdominal pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pregnancy on top of IUCD</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>missed periods , or pregnancy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>IUD (Intrauterine Device) Malposition</condition>
  <condition>IUD; Complications, Infection or Inflammation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <description>post-placental insertion of CU T380A IUD during CS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <description>post-placental insertion of multiload 375 IUD during CS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CU T380A IUD</intervention_name>
    <description>post-placental insertion of intrauterine contraceptive device</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CU T380A</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>multiload 375 IUD</intervention_name>
    <description>post-placental insertion of intrauterine contraceptive device</description>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>multiload 375</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients admitted for delivery at obstetric and gynecology emergency unit of sohag&#xD;
        university hospital which is a tertiary center at sohag city in egypt who requested&#xD;
        postpartum contraception, were invited to participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -(1) All patients admitted for delivery at our department who requested postpartum&#xD;
        contraception, were invited to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        (2) Age (18-45)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (1) Intrauterine infection at time of delivery (chorioamnionitis) (2) postpartum&#xD;
             hemorrhage (3) Uterine anomalies (distorted uterine cavity) (4) History of previous&#xD;
             IUD expulsion (5) Anemic patients with hemoglobin&lt; 10gm/dl (6) pre-labor rupture of&#xD;
             membranes for more than 18 hours (7) Placenta previa.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sohag University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sohag</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bilian X. Chinese experience with intrauterine devices. Contraception. 2007 Jun;75(6 Suppl):S31-4. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2006.12.007. Epub 2007 Feb 16.</citation>
    <PMID>17531613</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hillard PJ. Practical tips for intrauterine devices use in adolescents. J Adolesc Health. 2013 Apr;52(4 Suppl):S40-6. doi: 10.1016/j.jadohealth.2012.09.023.</citation>
    <PMID>23535056</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Behtash N, Akhavan S, Mokhtar S. Pelvic mass due to transmigrated IUD. Acta Med Iran. 2010 Mar-Apr;48(2):125-6.</citation>
    <PMID>21133007</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vasquez P, Schreiber CA. The missing IUD. Contraception. 2010 Aug;82(2):126-8. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2010.02.019. Epub 2010 Apr 2. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>20654751</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ko PC, Lin YH, Lo TS. Intrauterine contraceptive device migration to the lower urinary tract: report of 2 cases. J Minim Invasive Gynecol. 2011 Sep-Oct;18(5):668-70. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2011.05.010.</citation>
    <PMID>21872173</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kus E, Swierczewski A, Pasinski J, Estemberg D, Brzozowska M, Kowalska-Koprek U, Berner-Trabska M, Karowicz-Bilinska A. [Intrauterine contraceptive device in an appendix--a case report]. Ginekol Pol. 2012 Feb;83(2):132-5. Polish.</citation>
    <PMID>22568359</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Taras AR, Kaufman JA. Laparoscopic retrieval of intrauterine device perforating the sigmoid colon. JSLS. 2010 Jul-Sep;14(3):453-5. doi: 10.4293/108680810X12924466006684.</citation>
    <PMID>21333209</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vilallonga R, Rodriguez N, Vilchez M, Armengol M. Translocation of an intrauterine contraceptive device: incidental finding in the rectosigmoid colon. Obstet Gynecol Int. 2010;2010:404160. doi: 10.1155/2010/404160. Epub 2010 Jun 9.</citation>
    <PMID>20613996</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Koltan SO, Tamay AG, Yildirim Y. Chronic cervical perforation by an intrauterine device. J Chin Med Assoc. 2010 Jun;73(6):325-6. doi: 10.1016/S1726-4901(10)70069-1.</citation>
    <PMID>20603091</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists' Committee on Obstetric Practice. Committee Opinion No. 670: Immediate Postpartum Long-Acting Reversible Contraception. Obstet Gynecol. 2016 Aug;128(2):e32-7. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000001587.</citation>
    <PMID>27454734</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Whitaker AK, Chen BA. Society of Family Planning Guidelines: Postplacental insertion of intrauterine devices. Contraception. 2018 Jan;97(1):2-13. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2017.09.014. Epub 2017 Oct 5.</citation>
    <PMID>28987293</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lopez LM, Bernholc A, Hubacher D, Stuart G, Van Vliet HA. Immediate postpartum insertion of intrauterine device for contraception. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015 Jun 26;(6):CD003036. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD003036.pub3.</citation>
    <PMID>26115018</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Averbach SH, Ermias Y, Jeng G, Curtis KM, Whiteman MK, Berry-Bibee E, Jamieson DJ, Marchbanks PA, Tepper NK, Jatlaoui TC. Expulsion of intrauterine devices after postpartum placement by timing of placement, delivery type, and intrauterine device type: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Aug;223(2):177-188. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2020.02.045. Epub 2020 Mar 3.</citation>
    <PMID>32142826</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nelson AL, Chen S, Eden R. Intraoperative placement of the Copper T-380 intrauterine devices in women undergoing elective cesarean delivery: a pilot study. Contraception. 2009 Jul;80(1):81-3. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2009.01.014. Epub 2009 Mar 4.</citation>
    <PMID>19501220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mosley FR, Shahi N, Kurer MA. Elective surgical removal of migrated intrauterine contraceptive devices from within the peritoneal cavity: a comparison between open and laparoscopic removal. JSLS. 2012 Apr-Jun;16(2):236-41. doi: 10.4293/108680812x13427982377265.</citation>
    <PMID>23477171</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 21, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 20, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 20, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sohag University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mahmoud Ahmed Abdelmawgoud</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>postplacental IUD</keyword>
  <keyword>IUD</keyword>
  <keyword>Cupper T380A IUD</keyword>
  <keyword>Multiload 375 IUD</keyword>
  <keyword>iud expulsion</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

