<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05623150</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C20-12</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05623150</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CHronic Hepatopathies Associated With ALcohol Consumption aNd metAbolic Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>CHALNA2</acronym>
  <official_title>CHronic Hepatopathies Associated With ALcohol Consumption aNd metAbolic Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nice</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim is to determine the metabolic factors, host immune factors, and medical imaging data&#xD;
      associated with the development of HepatoCellular Carcinoma (HCC) in patients with&#xD;
      alcohol-related liver disease or dysmetabolic steatosis/Non-Alcoholic SteatoHepatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will include patients with and without cirrhosis in order to identify early&#xD;
      molecular mechanisms involved in the development of HCC especially in non-cirrhotic patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Type and methodology of the research:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within the framework of the usual management of the patient's pathology, a clinico-biological&#xD;
      characterization (dietary and physical activity questionnaires, &quot;performans status&quot;,&#xD;
      anthropometric measurements, usual blood biology characterizing the hepatic, renal and&#xD;
      inflammatory function, the carbohydrate and lipid metabolism, the non invasive test for liver&#xD;
      fibrosis ELF etc.) will be carry out. In order to collect radiomic data, liver imaging&#xD;
      (particularly in case of HCC) will be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A liver biopsy and constitution of a biobank (samples of plasma, sera, DNA and leucocyte&#xD;
      pellets) will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The elements necessary for the classification of possible hepatocellular carcinomas (BCLC&#xD;
      classification) will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anticipated research schedule:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The duration of inclusion in this research will be 10 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The duration of the patient's participation will be from 1 day (if the consent is signed&#xD;
           and the biopsy is performed on the same day) to 2 months (maximum reflection period is 8&#xD;
           weeks between the signature of the consent and the taking of samples).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The total duration of the research (from the first inclusion, to the last visit of the&#xD;
           last participant) will be 10 years and 2 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2032</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2032</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint will be the study of variations in metabolic gene markers (i.e. mRNA of genes implicated in inflammation or metabolism assessed in qPCR, using a housekeeping gene such as glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate dehydrogenase (GAPDH)), in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary endpoint will include variations in other gene markers (e.g. genes implicated in the regeneration, cell deaths and tumor, assessed in qPCR, using a housekeeping gene such as glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate dehydrogenase (GAPDH)) in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3th outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>3th endpoint will include variations in genetic markers (Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms (SNPs)), in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage.&#xD;
The frequency of SNPs will be compared to that found in the UK biobank cohort.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>4th outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>4th endpoint will include variations in epigenetic markers (histone methylation, micro RNA), in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5th outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>5th endpoint will include variations in tissue proteins (including tumor and non tumor tissue), in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage. Western blots will be quantified and compared in an automated way.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6th outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>6th endpoint will include variations in specific markers or markers derived from analysis via platforms (OMICS), in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>7th outcome measure CHALNA2</measure>
    <time_frame>2022-2032</time_frame>
    <description>7th endpoint will include variations in radiomics (radiomics is a method that extracts a large number of features from medical images using data-characterisation algorithms), in patients with and without hepatocellular carcinoma with different levels of severity of liver damage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">710</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</condition>
  <condition>Non-Alcoholic Steatohepatitis</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol-related Liver Disease</condition>
  <condition>Cirrhosis, Liver</condition>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Descriptive study</arm_group_label>
    <description>The patients included in this observational study are patients with hepatic steatosis either related to NAFLD or to alcohol-related liver disease.&#xD;
Patients included in the study may have hepatocellular carcinoma.&#xD;
Thus, 4 groups of patients can be recruited:&#xD;
patients with NAFLD without hepatocellular carcinoma,&#xD;
patients with NAFLD with hepatocellular carcinoma,&#xD;
patients with alcohol-related liver disease without hepatocellular carcinoma, -patients with alcohol-related liver disease with hepatocellular carcinoma.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Liver biopsy</intervention_name>
    <description>Liver biopsy planned as part of routine care. Clinical-biological characterisation with bio collections.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Descriptive study</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      standard liver biopsy (for immunocytochemistry), frozen liver biopsy, frozen serum, frozen&#xD;
      plasma, DNA&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The patients included in this observational study are patients with hepatic steatosis&#xD;
        either related to NAFLD or to alcohol-related liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients included in the study may have hepatocellular carcinoma. Thus, 4 groups of&#xD;
        patients can be recruited: patients with NAFLD without hepatocellular carcinoma, patients&#xD;
        with NAFLD with hepatocellular carcinoma, patients with alcohol-related liver disease&#xD;
        without hepatocellular carcinoma, patients with alcohol-related liver disease with&#xD;
        hepatocellular carcinoma.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria common to all patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Affiliation to French social security.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Male or female ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients able to receive and understand information about the research and to&#xD;
                  give written informed consent duly signed by the patient and the investigator (at&#xD;
                  the latest on the day of inclusion and before any examination necessary for the&#xD;
                  research).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in the NAFLD group with HCC:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Alcohol consumption ≤ 30 g pure alcohol/d (or 210 g pure alcohol/week) for men&#xD;
                  and ≤ 20 g pure alcohol/d (140 g pure alcohol/week) for women.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Decision, less than 3 months old, of liver biopsy of the suspected HCC nodule and&#xD;
                  non-tumour liver tissue performed as a clinical routine.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. No systemic treatment for HCC within 6 months prior to inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in the NAFLD group without HCC:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Alcohol consumption ≤ 30 g pure alcohol/d (or 210 g pure alcohol/week) for men&#xD;
                  and ≤ 20 g pure alcohol/d (140 g pure alcohol/week) for women.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Decision of less than 3 months of a liver biopsy performed as a clinical routine.&#xD;
                  Biopsy will be motivated by liver function disturbance(s) and/or ultrasound&#xD;
                  steatosis given the lack of validated non-invasive tests or the lack of accuracy&#xD;
                  (grey areas) of available non-invasive tests for the diagnosis of&#xD;
                  necro-inflammation and/or fibrosis in some of these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in the alcohol-related liver disease group with HCC:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Alcohol consumption &gt; 30 g pure alcohol/d (or 210 g pure alcohol/week) for men&#xD;
                  and &gt; 20 g pure alcohol/d (140 g pure alcohol/week) or binge drinking&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Decision within 3 months of liver biopsy of suspected HCC nodule and non-tumour&#xD;
                  liver tissue performed as part of clinical routine&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. No systemic treatment for HCC within 6 months prior to inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in the alcohol-related liver disease group without HCC:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Alcohol consumption &gt; 30 g pure alcohol/d (or 210 g pure alcohol/week) for men&#xD;
                  and &gt; 20 g pure alcohol/d (140 g pure alcohol/week) or binge drinking&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Decision of less than 3 months for a liver biopsy to be performed as a clinical&#xD;
                  routine. Biopsy will be motivated by liver balance disturbance(s) and/or&#xD;
                  ultrasound steatosis given the lack of validated non-invasive tests or the lack&#xD;
                  of accuracy (grey areas) of available non-invasive tests for the diagnosis of&#xD;
                  necro-inflammation and/or fibrosis in some of these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Positive HIV serology&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with detectable hepatitis C viral load&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of Hbs antigen&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of autoimmune hepatitis type 1 or 2, primary biliary cholangitis, primary&#xD;
             sclerosing cholangitis, Wilson's disease, genetic haemochromatosis homozygous, alpha1&#xD;
             anti-trypsin deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Long-term use of methotrexate, corticosteroids, anti-Tumor Necrosis Factor&#xD;
             cyclosporine, tacrolimus&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of solid organ transplantation or bone marrow transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Cancerous disease in the process of being treated, except for skin cancer (excluding&#xD;
             melanoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients under legal protection or unable to express their consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rodolphe Anty, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0033492035943</phone>
    <email>anty.r@chu-nice.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>December 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 12, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 21, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rodolphe ANTY</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-Alcoholic Steatohepatitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol-related Liver Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Cirrhosis, Liver</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

