<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05793398</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CD1022</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05793398</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Biomaterial Collection - and Analysis in Cardiac Sarcoidosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pathomechanisms in Patients With Cardiac Sarcoidosis and Other Inflammatory and Familial Cardiomyopathies of Similar Phenotypic Appearance</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Heart Center Leipzig - University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Leipzig Medical Center, Department of Cardiology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Heart and Diabetes Center North Rhine-Westphalia, Erich and Hanna Klessmann Institute for Cardiovascular Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Max Delbrück Center for Molecular Medicine (MDC), Berlin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Heart Center Leipzig - University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cardiac sarcoidosis (CS) is a complex disease that is characterized by the formation of&#xD;
      inflammatory granulomas in the myocardium. The exact underlying pathophysiology of the&#xD;
      disease is not yet fully understood, but it is believed to be related to dysregulation of the&#xD;
      immune system. Despite significant progress in recent years, the disease remains difficult to&#xD;
      diagnose, and there is a high risk of severe complications such as life-threatening cardiac&#xD;
      arrhythmias, severe heart failure, and sudden cardiac death in affected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover, the clinical presentation of CS can be similar to other inflammatory heart diseases&#xD;
      or familial cardiomyopathies. Thus, it is challenging to differentiate between these&#xD;
      diseases, which can lead to a delayed diagnosis and poor prognosis. It is unclear whether&#xD;
      certain genetic variants play a role in the clinical course and prognosis of CS, which&#xD;
      highlights the need for more research in this area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The diagnosis of CS requires cardiac or extracardiac biopsy with granuloma detection, which&#xD;
      is an invasive and complex procedure. Consequently, the disease is thought to be&#xD;
      underdiagnosed, and many affected patients may not receive timely treatment, resulting in&#xD;
      excess mortality. Early diagnosis and immunosuppressive treatment, as well as defibrillator&#xD;
      implantation if necessary, are crucial in delaying disease progression, preventing&#xD;
      complications, and improving prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To better understand the key molecular pathological mechanisms underlying the development and&#xD;
      maintenance of CS, a prospective, multicenter, exploratory study has been initiated. The&#xD;
      project involves the collection, storage, and analysis of biological samples from blood,&#xD;
      myocardium, and lymph nodes of patients with cardiac sarcoidosis or cardiomyopathies that&#xD;
      present clinically and image morphologically similar. The samples will be used for scientific&#xD;
      investigations on disease mechanisms of cardiomyopathies as well as for identification of new&#xD;
      biomarkers in cardiomyopathy diagnostics and for follow-up of therapeutic measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will employ a range of classical biochemical methods such as ELISA, RIA, as well as&#xD;
      more modern methods of molecular biology (single cell sequencing, single nucleus sequencing)&#xD;
      and systems biology (genomics, metabolomics, or proteomics) to identify key molecular&#xD;
      pathological mechanisms in the development and maintenance of CS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, genetic analysis will be performed to investigate cardiomyopathy- and ion&#xD;
      channel-associated genetic variants, which is critical for improving diagnostics and early,&#xD;
      individualized therapy. The study will be conducted on a multicenter basis, with the Heart&#xD;
      Center Leipzig serving as the initiator and lead center and the University Hospital Leipzig&#xD;
      as the second study center. Biochemical and molecular biological analyses will be performed&#xD;
      on behalf of the study management at the Heart Center Leipzig, the University Hospital&#xD;
      Leipzig, and the Erich and Hanna Klessmann Institute for Cardiovascular Research and&#xD;
      Development of the Heart and Diabetes Center NRW and Max Delbrück Center for Molecular&#xD;
      Medicine in Berlin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In conclusion, CS is a complex and challenging disease that requires further research to&#xD;
      better understand its underlying mechanisms and improve diagnostic and therapeutic&#xD;
      strategies. The prospective, multicenter, exploratory study will provide valuable insights&#xD;
      into the disease's key molecular pathological mechanisms and identify new biomarkers for&#xD;
      better diagnostics and individualized therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CD14++CD16+ - monocytes/macrophages in myocardial samples and peripheral blood correlates with disease activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Sarcoidosis leads to a cellular TH1-mediated immune response with formation of non-necrotizing granulomas in affected organs, including the heart. Monocyte/macrophage subpopulations play an important role in the initiation of the TH1 immune response. Detection of specific immune cells such as CD14++CD16+ - monocytes/macrophages in myocardial samples and peripheral blood correlates with disease activity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Specific genetic variants, single nucleotide polymorphisms, and epigenetic markers are associated with an individually increased risk of disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Modern genetic testing methods can detect an individually increased risk of disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac Sarcoidosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Endomyocardial biopsy-positive Cardiac sarcoidosis</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Endomyocardial biopsy-negative non ischemic cardiomyopathy</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        tertiary care clinic patients with suspected inflammatory cardiomyopathy and/or conduction&#xD;
        disorders and/or ventricular arrhythmias, suspected cardiac sarcoidosis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        (a) patients with a history of symptomatic cardiac sarcoidosis/inflammatory cardiomyopathy&#xD;
        or b) patients with newly diagnosed heart failure with cardiac arrhythmias (ventricular&#xD;
        tachycardia, conduction disturbances, etc.) that may indicate sarcoidosis or inflammatory&#xD;
        cardiomyopathy or c) patients with image morphological suspicion of cardiac sarcoidosis or&#xD;
        inflammatory cardiomyopathy (MRI, PET-CT) or (d) patients who require or have received a&#xD;
        ventricular assist device (VAD) or cardiac transplantation due to suspected cardiac&#xD;
        sarcoidosis or inflammatory cardiomyopathy and (e) written informed consent has been&#xD;
        obtained from patients for study participation and consent for analysis of patient samples.&#xD;
        Studies on pseudoanonymized samples will only be performed with appropriately signed&#xD;
        informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with psychiatric illness that impairs business or insight capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with chronic heart failure due to coronary artery disease or valvular&#xD;
             vitiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. severe underlying disease other than sarcoidosis that is likely to result in death&#xD;
             within one year.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hans Ebbinghaus, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0049341865252550</phone>
    <email>Hans.Ebbinghaus@helios-gesundheit.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Borislav Dinov, MD</last_name>
    <email>Borislav.Dinov@helios-gesundheit.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 30, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 30, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 30, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoidosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

