<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05611073</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>JMM-1261</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05611073</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maximizing Visual Outcomes With Eyhance IOLs</brief_title>
  <official_title>Maximizing Visual Outcomes With Eyhance IOLs</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Berkeley Eye Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Berkeley Eye Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a non-interventional prospective, single center, bilateral, non-randomized,&#xD;
      open-label, observational clinical study. All patients will have had bilateral implantation&#xD;
      of an Eyhance IOL at the time of cataract surgery. These patients will then be compared to&#xD;
      assess which patient biometric properties (such as spherical aberration, q value, pupil size,&#xD;
      etc.) lead to an overall increase in near or intermediate vision as well as overall patient&#xD;
      satisfaction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a non-interventional prospective, single center, bilateral, non-randomized,&#xD;
      open-label, observational clinical study. All patients will have had bilateral implantation&#xD;
      of an Eyhance IOL at the time of cataract surgery. These patients will then be assessed in&#xD;
      the 1-6-month post-operative period. Patients will be grouped into two arms: &quot;distance with&#xD;
      minimal intermediate&quot; and &quot;distance with enhanced intermediate/near&quot; based on mean photopic&#xD;
      binocular BCDVA and DCIVA (at 66 cm) of patients with bilateral Eyhance IOLs corrected to&#xD;
      plano sphere. The &quot;distance with minimal intermediate&quot; group is defined by BCDVA of 0.1&#xD;
      logMAR or better but a DCIVA of 0.4 logMAR or worse. The &quot;distance with enhanced&#xD;
      intermediate/near&quot; is defined by BCDVA of 0.1 logMAR or better and a DCIVA of 0.3 logMAR or&#xD;
      better. In addition to binocular BCDVA and DCIVA, monocular measurements will be obtained as&#xD;
      well. The two groups will be compared to assess which patient biometric properties (such as&#xD;
      spherical aberration, q value, pupil size, etc.) lead to an overall increase in near or&#xD;
      intermediate vision as well as overall patient satisfaction. Biometric data will be obtained&#xD;
      from the Zeiss IOL Master 700, Atlas 9000, and the iTrace.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 7, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of two groups categorized by &quot;distance with minimal intermediate&quot; and &quot;distance with enhanced intermediate/near&quot; based on mean photopic binocular BCDVA and DCIVA (at 66 cm) of patients with bilateral Eyhance IOLs corrected to plano sphere.</measure>
    <time_frame>minimum of 3 weeks post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>To compare two groups categorized by &quot;distance with minimal intermediate&quot; and &quot;distance with enhanced intermediate/near&quot; based on mean photopic binocular BCDVA and DCIVA (66 cm) of patients with bilateral Eyhance IOLs targeted corrected at plano sphere.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine if any statistically significant differences in biometric data exists between the two groups including pupil size, spherical aberration, q value.</measure>
    <time_frame>minimum of 3 weeks post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if any statistically significant differences in biometric data exists between the two groups including pupil size, spherical aberration, q value, etc. that may allow for pre-operative recognition of those patients who could have enhanced benefits of the Eyhance IOL. This will require multiple regression analysis given the large number of variables.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of a patient satisfaction survey between the two groups to assess for subjective differences in everyday life. Patient's answers will be on a scale between always and never, where never shows a better patient outcome.</measure>
    <time_frame>minimum of 3 weeks post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of a patient satisfaction survey between the two groups to assess for subjective differences in everyday life to determine if the enhanced vision plays a statistically significant difference in patient's perceived quality of vision or quality of life. Patient's answers will be on a scale between always and never, where never shows a better patient outcome.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">131</enrollment>
  <condition>Pseudophakia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Minimal Intermediate Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with bilateral implantation of Eyhance IOLs. And defined by BCDVA of 0.1 logMAR or better but a DCIVA of 0.4 logMAR or worse.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Enhanced Intermediate/Near Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with bilateral implantation of Eyhance IOLS. And defined by BCDVA of 0.1 logMAR or better and a DCIVA of 0.3 logMAR or better.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Visual Acuity</intervention_name>
    <description>Measurement of distance, intermediate and near visual acuity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Enhanced Intermediate/Near Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Minimal Intermediate Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biometric Data Collection</intervention_name>
    <description>Measurement of biometric data will be obtained from the Zeiss IOL Master 700, Atlas 9000, and the iTrace.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Enhanced Intermediate/Near Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Minimal Intermediate Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Patient Questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will complete a Patient Questionnaire to determine their level of spectacle independence and visual acuity satisfaction.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Enhanced Intermediate/Near Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Distance with Minimal Intermediate Visual Acuity Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with healthy eyes and uncomplicated bilateral implantation of Eyhance IOLs.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults, 40 years of age having already undergone uncomplicated cataract removal by&#xD;
             phacoemulsification with a clear corneal incision in both eyes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Implantation of bilateral Eyhance IOLs (DIB00/DIU***).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to comprehend and willing to sign informed consent and complete all required&#xD;
             testing procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Best Corrected Distance Visual Acuity (BCDVA) projected to be 0.10 logMAR (Minimum&#xD;
             Angle of Resolution) or better.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clear intraocular media.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Minimum of two weeks post YAG capsulotomy to treat PCO&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any corneal abnormality, other than regular corneal astigmatism (as determined by&#xD;
             pre-operative testing) that in the opinion of the investigator would confound the&#xD;
             outcome(s) of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any complication during cataract surgery (capsular tear, vitrectomy, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of or current retinal conditions or predisposition to retinal conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Amblyopia or strabismus in either eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of or current anterior or posterior segment inflammation of any etiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any form of neovascularization on or within the eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Glaucoma (uncontrolled or controlled with medication).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Optic nerve atrophy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with diagnosed degenerative eye disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Postoperative CDVA worse than 0.10 logMAR (20/25 snellen).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who have an acute or chronic disease or illness that would confound the&#xD;
             results of this investigation in the opinion of the investigator (e.g.&#xD;
             immunocompromised, connective tissue disease, clinically significant atopic disease,&#xD;
             etc.).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Morgan Micheletti, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Berkeley Eye Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Berkeley Eye Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77027</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Eyhance</keyword>
  <keyword>Pseudophakia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pseudophakia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

