<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05798117</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CYTB323G12101</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2022-001796-14</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05798117</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Open-label, Study to Assess Safety, Efficacy and Cellular Kinetics of YTB323 in Severe, Refractory Autoimmune Disorders</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Multi-center, Phase 1/2 Study to Assess Safety, Efficacy and Cellular Kinetics of YTB323 in Participants With Severe, Refractory Autoimmune Disorders</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Novartis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is intended to assess safety, efficacy and cellular kinetics of YTB323 treatment in&#xD;
      participants with severe refractory systemic lupus erythematosus.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 28, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 11, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 11, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with AEs and SAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Long term safety follow up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CAR transgene levels by quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR) in blood</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected to assess cellular kinetics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with anti-drug antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected to measure anti-drug antibodies against YTB323.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of T cell activation by YTB323</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected to measure the level of T cell activation by YTB323.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients infused with planned target dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility of the manufacturing process in autoimmune disorders.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in the Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index-2000 (SLEDAI-2K) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>SLEDAI-2K scores are between 0 and 105, a higher score represents a higher disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in British Isles Lupus Activity Group (BILAG) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>BILAG consists of 97 items that covers 9 organ domains. The range is from a to E, A is very active disease and E no disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in Physician's global assessment (PGA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The Physician's Global assessment is a visual analog scale from 0 to 3, 0 represents no activity and 3 represents severe disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in Lupus Low Disease Activity State (LLDAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>LLDAS is a composite measure based on: SLEDAI-2K ≤ 4, with no activity in major organ system (renal, central nervous system, cardiopulmonary, vasculitis, and fever) and no hemolytic anemia or gastrointestinal activity, current, no new lupus disease activity compared with the previous assessment, prednisone (or its equivalent) dose ≤ 7.5 mg/day, PGA (scale 0-3) ≤ 1, well tolerated standard maintenance doses of immunosuppressive lupus therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Remission rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Remission as specified by Definitions Of Remission In Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (DORIS) criteria: Clinical SLEDAI=0, PGA&lt;0.5 (0-3) irrespective of serology.&#xD;
The patient may be on antimalarials, low-dose glucocorticoids (prednisolone ≤5 mg/day), and/or stable immunosuppressive therapy including biologics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Responder Index -4 (SRI-4)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>SRI-4 response is defined as a greater than or equal to 4-point decrease in the Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index (SLEDAI) score, and no new British Isles Lupus Assessment Group (BILAG) 2004 A score, no greater than 2 new BILAG B domain scores compared with baseline, and a less than 0.3-point worsening from baseline in Physician Global Assessment (PGA) (scale 0 to 3).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in British Isles Lupus Assessment Group based Composite Lupus Assessment (BICLA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>BICLA is a composite assessment based on BILAG, SLEDAI-2K PGA and use of restricted or rescue medications, other than defined in the protocol.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Major Clinical Response (MCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>After 6 months and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who achieved MCR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from pre-dose up to 2 years in Urinary protein creatinine ratio (UPCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the value of UPCR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Complete renal response (CRR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who achieved CRR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</condition>
  <condition>Lupus Nephritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>YTB323</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single infusion of YTB323</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>YTB323</intervention_name>
    <description>Single infusion of YTB323</description>
    <arm_group_label>YTB323</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate renal, hepatic, cardiac, hematological and pulmonary function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women with SLE, aged ≥18 years and ≤65 years at screening, fulfilling the 2019&#xD;
             European League Against Rheumatism EULAR/ACR classification criteria for SLE.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be positive for at least one of the following autoantibodies at&#xD;
             screening: antinuclear antibodies (ANA) at a titer of ≥1:80, or anti dsDNA (above the&#xD;
             ULN); or anti-Sm (above the ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active (severe) disease as defined by SLEDAI-2K ≥ 8 (not including the SLEDAI-2K&#xD;
             domains of lupus headache, cerebrovascular accident, organic brain syndrome*) and at&#xD;
             least one of the following significant SLE related organ involvements:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peri/myocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pleuritis or other lung involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other types of serositis such as peritoneal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vasculitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to respond (i.e. having high disease activity as defined in criterion above&#xD;
             despite the following therapy) to two or more standard immunosuppressive therapies&#xD;
             (including one of mycophenolate or cyclophosphamide), unless contraindicated or having&#xD;
             experienced documented adverse events or intolerance related to such immunosuppressive&#xD;
             drugs not allowing their further use, in combination with glucocorticoids and failure&#xD;
             to respond to at least one biological agent (unless contraindicated, the patient&#xD;
             deemed ineligible by the Investigator or not available in a country).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant active, opportunistic, chronic or recurrent infection confirmed&#xD;
             by clinical evidence, imaging, or positive laboratory tests (e.g., blood cultures, PCR&#xD;
             for DNA/RNA, such as COVID-19 etc.) one month prior to or during screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, lung diseases or any other illness that are not&#xD;
             related to SLE that in the opinion of the Investigator would jeopardize the ability of&#xD;
             the patient to tolerate lymphodepletion and CD19 CAR-T cell therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior history of malignancy except for localized basal cell or squamous skin cancer.&#xD;
             Other malignancies for which the patient is judged to be cured by local surgical&#xD;
             therapy, such as head and neck cancer, or stage I breast cancer will be considered on&#xD;
             an individual basis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patients requiring medications prohibited by the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychiatric condition or disability making compliance with treatment or informed&#xD;
             consent impossible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with anti-CD19 therapy, adoptive T cell therapy or any prior gene&#xD;
             therapy product (e.g. CAR-T cell therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bone marrow/hematopoietic stem cell or solid organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants who are pregnant or breastfeeding, or intending to conceive during&#xD;
             the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of&#xD;
             becoming pregnant, unless they are using a highly effective method of contraception&#xD;
             starting from the time of enrollment to at least 12 months after the YTB323 infusion&#xD;
             and until CAR-T cells are no longer present by qPCR on two consecutive tests&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males unwilling to use a condom during intercourse from the time&#xD;
             enrollment for at least 12 months after the YTB323 infusion and until CAR-T cells are&#xD;
             no longer present by qPCR on two consecutive tests&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any acute, severe lupus related flare during screening that needs immediate treatment&#xD;
             and/or makes the immunosuppressive washout impossible; thus, makes the patient&#xD;
             ineligible for CD19 CAR-T therapy as judged by the Investigator, such as acute central&#xD;
             nervous system (CNS) lupus (e.g. psychosis, epilepsy) or catastrophic antiphospholipid&#xD;
             syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant, likely irreversible organ damage related to SLE, e.g. end stage renal&#xD;
             disease, where, in the opinion of the Investigator CD19 CAR-T cell therapy would be&#xD;
             unlikely to benefit the patient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Novartis Pharmaceutical</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-669-6682</phone>
    <email>novartis.email@novartis.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>+41613241111</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <state>Catalunya</state>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 27, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 4, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CAR-T, YTB323, Lupus, SLE, LN, severe refractory SLE</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nephritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lupus Nephritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Novartis is committed to sharing with qualified external researchers, access to patient-level data and supporting clinical documents from eligible studies. These requests are reviewed and approved by an independent review panel on the basis of scientific merit. All data provided is anonymized to respect the privacy of patients who have participated in the trial in line with applicable laws and regulations.&#xD;
This trial data availability is according to the criteria and process described on www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

