<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05629143</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S64556</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05629143</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Primary carE PPi dEprescRibing Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>PEPPER</acronym>
  <official_title>Determining the Optimal Strategy for Stopping Chronic Proton Pump Inhibitor Therapy in Primary Care Patients: Impact of On-demand Use, Adjunctive Therapies and Antacids</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen KU Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen KU Leuven</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Proton pump inibitors (PPIs) is a class of medications that reduce the acid secretion in the&#xD;
      stomach. These medications are very effective to relieve symptoms of acid reflux for a&#xD;
      well-identified group of diseases and conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Over the years, a major rise in use of these drugs has occurred. Convincing analyses reveal&#xD;
      that a large share of this use occurs outside regular indications, at inappropriately&#xD;
      elevated doses and prolonged treatment durations. Moreover, there are increasing concerns&#xD;
      regarding potential adverse effects and the high cost associated with improper PPI use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Guidelines propose to reduce chronic use of PPIs, but to date this has not generated a&#xD;
      reduction in their application in clinical practice. One reason is the occurrence of a period&#xD;
      of 2 weeks of increased acid secretion, with recurrence of symptoms, when these drugs are&#xD;
      stopped after already a few weeks of usage (rebound effect). The best strategy to overcome&#xD;
      this period of increased acid secretion and symptoms has not been established.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PEPPER study will evaluate two different strategies to overcome the period of increased&#xD;
      secretion when trying to interrupt chronic proton pump inhibitor therapy. The investigators&#xD;
      will compare the success of stopping PPIs when these strategies are implemented, compared to&#xD;
      a classical strategy of stopping after intermittent PPI intake. The strategies under&#xD;
      evaluation are a period of non-daily intake of proton pump inhibitors (on-demand) before&#xD;
      stopping, or the use of alternative methods to control gastric acidity and reflux (so-called&#xD;
      alginates).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will evaluate the success rate of stopping chronic PPIs treatment with&#xD;
      these approaches, compared to an interruption with intake of antacids. Patients will be&#xD;
      followed up for 1 year after interruption of PPIs, and the level of symptom control, quality&#xD;
      of life and healthcare costs will be evaluated at intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted in patients from primary care practices with chronic PPIs intake&#xD;
      outside of the established disease indications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 3, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Evaluation of de-prescription strategies for PPIs</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Succes of de-prescription strategy</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of randomized patients achieving successful therapeutic outcome at the end of the follow up period in each treatment group</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of PPI</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome The use of PPI will be reported by the patient at each study visit as adherence to the suggested treatment. As this information is considered as standard of care, this is the value that will be used for the analysis of this first key point that will be used for the assessment of the primary endpoint of the study.&#xD;
During follow up, patients taking at least one dose of PPIs weekly will be consider as active PPI users, and therefore a failure to this key indicator (result &quot;0&quot;). If patients report to have used a dose PPI less than 3 times in a month, this subject will not be consider as clinical relevant users, and therefore the key indicator result is positive and &quot;1&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome Scale title:treatment satisfaction scale Question to assess treatment satisfaction is: &quot;How satisfied or dissatisfied are you with the control of your symptoms with the current treatment?&quot; Minimum and maximum values: seven-point bipolar scale from 'Extremely Satisfied' (score 7) to 'Extremely Dissatisfied' (score 1) Higher scores mean: better outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Willingness to continue with the current treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome To assess willingness to continue to current treatment regimen, the following question will be used: &quot;Would you be willing to continue the current treatment for the next month?&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Economic impact of PPI deprescribing</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Title: Health resource utilisation questionnaire Minimum and maximum values: yes or no questions (1 or 0) regarding use health resource use Higher scores mean: worst outcome as this is related to more expences due to health issues</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Predictor of success - Predictive value of the symptom pattern</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome questionnaire title:esophageal and gastric symptoms questionnaire Min and max values: varies based on the question to presence of a symptom: yes-no questions and the severity of symptoms with higher scores for more severe symptoms.&#xD;
Higher scores means worst outcome as symptoms are more present and more severe.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive value of demographic variables</measure>
    <time_frame>15 month</time_frame>
    <description>Demographic assessment with patients questionnaires</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive value of number of co-morbidities to stop PPIs use</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Co-morbidities assessment via GP via eCRF The investigator will evaluate if increased number of co-morbidities is a predictor for lower likelihood to succeed a the treatment to decrease the use of PPI.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive value of number of previous failed attempts to stop PPIs use</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment via eCRF via GP medical assessment The investigator will evaluate if the number of previous failed attempts to stop PPIs use is a predictor for lower likelihood to succeed a the treatment to decrease the use of PPI.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive value of gastrin level</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Blood sample at baseline and after 1 year follow-up</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive value of the level of patients' motivation to stop PPIs use</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome on motivation during the study title: Motivational visual analogue scale Max-min scores: 100-0 from &quot;extremely motivated&quot; to &quot;no motivation&quot; Higher scores: good outcome The investigator will evaluate if the level of motivation to stop PPIs use is a predictor for likelihood to succeed a the treatment to decrease the use of PPI.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Work productivity impact of PPI deprescribing</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>title: Work productivity impact questionnaire (WPAI) Max-Min scores: yes/no questions (1/0) and number of hours worked per week (scores: 0 to 150) Higer scores= good outcome, as the patients feels good to work and be productive</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants using rescue therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment via questionnaire in ePRO</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">724</enrollment>
  <condition>Heartburn</condition>
  <condition>Dyspepsia</condition>
  <condition>Reflux</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent deprescribing strategy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Classical approach for deprescribing of PPI based on Belgian Guidelines. In this study arm, the patients will keep the intake of their PPI but will decrease the use of PPI using a scheme where the PPI dose in reduced intermittently for one month. After one month in the intermittent deprescribing scheme, the patients will stop the use of PPI.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>On-demand deprescribing strategy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this study arm, the patients will keep the intake of their PPI but will decrease the use of PPI in an on-demand bases for one month. The patient will only take the PPI when strictly needed because of symptoms. After one month in the on-demand PPI use, the patients will stop the use of PPI.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Replacement of PPI with alginate therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this study arm, the patient will stop the intake of the PPI band replace it with the use of an alginate for one month. After one month, the patient will stop the use of alginates.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>de-prescription of PPI via intermittent scheme</intervention_name>
    <description>The patients will decrease their intake of PPIs via a de-prescription intermittent scheme. After one month, patients will stop their intake of PPI.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent deprescribing strategy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>de-prescription of PPI via on-demand scheme</intervention_name>
    <description>The patients will decrease their intake of PPIs via a de-prescription on-demand scheme. After one month, patients will stop their intake of PPI.</description>
    <arm_group_label>On-demand deprescribing strategy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alginate</intervention_name>
    <description>The patients will stop their intake of PPIs and use alginate. After one month, patients will stop their intake of alginates.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Replacement of PPI with alginate therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Eligible patients are those of either gender, above the age of 18, eligible to give&#xD;
        informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Based on indication: Patients on long-term (&gt;12 weeks) chronic (daily) PPI use without&#xD;
             therapy indication are eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Based on dose:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients on a &quot;maintenance&quot; PPI dose are eligible for randomization. Maintenance&#xD;
                  dose is 20 mg of omeprazole, esomeprazole or pantoprazole daily or 15 mg of&#xD;
                  lansoprazole daily or 10 mg of rabeprazole daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients on a &quot;healing&quot; PPI dose (i.e. ≥40 mg esomeprazole, esomeprazole or&#xD;
                  pantoprazole or ≥30 mg of lansoprazole or ≥20 mg or rabeprazole daily) are also&#xD;
                  eligible, but need first to down-titrate their dose to &quot;maintenance&quot; dose before&#xD;
                  they can be considered for randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on short-term (&lt;12 weeks) PPI therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not on chronic PPI use (less than daily intake)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with established long-term indication such as the presence of a grade C, D&#xD;
             oesophagitis, a peptic ulcer, Barrett's oesophagus or Zollinger-Ellison syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic use of Gaviscon® or similar drugs based on magaldrate such as&#xD;
             Riopan® and Gastricalm® (i.e. more than once a week for the last 2 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic use of NSAIDs (i.e. two or more weekly doses).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of gastric or oesophageal surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a major oesophageal disease such as achalasia, oesophageal spasm, or&#xD;
             oesophageal involvement in systemic disease such as scleroderma or dermatomyositis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with drug abuse and/or alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not able to understand or be compliant with the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jan Tack</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <state>Vlaams Brabant</state>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>proton pump inhibitor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyspepsia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heartburn</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>no individual data sharing</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

