<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618288</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ICKES221114</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618288</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of a Mobile Health Breastfeeding Counseling Intervention for Employed Mothers in Kenya</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of a Mobile Health Breastfeeding Counseling Intervention for Employed Mothers in Kenya</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wheaton College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Kenya Medical Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wheaton College</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Exclusive breastfeeding (EBF) is critical for child survival, growth, and maternal health;&#xD;
      however, over half of mothers in low and middle-income countries (LMIC). Mobile health&#xD;
      (mHealth) describes a range of wireless technologies and techniques that seek to increase&#xD;
      patient access to and interaction with preventive health services. This study will develop&#xD;
      and test the feasibility of an mHealth intervention to improve support counseling for&#xD;
      breastfeeding at a large sub-county referral hospital in Naivasha, Kenya.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Exclusive breastfeeding (EBF) is critical for child survival, growth, and maternal health;&#xD;
      however, over half of mothers in low and middle-income countries (LMICs) do not practice EBF&#xD;
      through the recommended six months of infancy. Maternal employment is a significant risk&#xD;
      factor for early cessation of EBF in LMICs. Policies in Kenya seek to support working mothers&#xD;
      to continue practicing EBF after a nationally mandated 12-week maternity leave. However, the&#xD;
      implementation of this policy is limited, and only 17% of formally employed mothers practice&#xD;
      EBF through the recommended six months in Naivasha, Kenya, where a high proportion of mothers&#xD;
      are employed in commercial agriculture and other low-wage industries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mobile health (mHealth) describes a range of wireless technologies and techniques that seek&#xD;
      to increase patient access to and interaction with preventive health services. mHealth&#xD;
      technologies hold untapped potential to support healthcare workers' training and counseling&#xD;
      approaches to support lactation for working mothers, especially when collaboratively&#xD;
      developed with end users.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will develop and test the feasibility of an mHealth intervention to improve&#xD;
      support counseling for breastfeeding at a large sub-county referral hospital in Naivasha,&#xD;
      Kenya. The primary objective of this proposal is to develop mHealth technology to equip and&#xD;
      support healthcare worker breastfeeding counseling, and implement and evaluate its impact. We&#xD;
      hypothesize that a culturally sensitive and technologically appropriate mHealth counseling&#xD;
      intervention will improve EBF rates among infants of employed mothers. This study will be&#xD;
      conducted in three aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before the clinical trial phase of the study begins, we will employ a human-centered design&#xD;
      approach to iteratively develop and test the feasibility of an mHealth intervention to&#xD;
      support breastfeeding counseling for employed mothers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After developing the technology, we will evaluate the impact of the mHealth breastfeeding&#xD;
      counseling intervention on the outcomes of EBF, child morbidity, and worker presenteeism.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overarching goal of this proposal is to develop an mHealth intervention that can&#xD;
      successfully support continued lactation and BF for employed mothers across various sectors&#xD;
      and be disseminated at a national scale in Kenya and other LMIC contexts where employed&#xD;
      mothers face unique challenges to practicing EBF while maintaining employment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mothers will be recruited in the third trimester of pregnancy and followed through 9-months&#xD;
      postpartum. 284 mothers will be randomly assigned to an mHealth counseling intervention or&#xD;
      the Standard of Care (in person counseling at the Naivasha Sub-County Referral Hospital).&#xD;
      there will be 142 mothers in each intervention arm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2025</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomization to mobile health or in-person breastfeeding counseling</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exclusive breastfeeding at 24 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks post-partum</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of mothers who feed only breastmilk to their infants, without other liquids, formula or semi-solid or solid food.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Continued breastfeeding</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks post partum</time_frame>
    <description>Any breastfeeding in the past 24 hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Early initiation of breastfeeding</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 1 hour of childbirth</time_frame>
    <description>Breastfeeding within 1 hour of childbirth</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">284</enrollment>
  <condition>Breastfeeding, Exclusive</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care breastfeeding counseling. The ongoing antenatal, delivery and postnatal breastfeeding and lactation counseling that is provided by the Naivasha sub-County Referral Hospital.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>mobile Health (mHealth)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Simple messaging service counseling intervention with healthcare providers. This arm will involve two-way messaging with healthcare providers Unstructured Supplementary Service Data application that provides session-based interaction with breastfeeding and lactation support content.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>mobile Health Breastfeeding Counseling</intervention_name>
    <description>a phone-based breastfeeding counseling intervention, delivered by labor and delivery nurses, nutritionists, and maternal and child health nurses.</description>
    <arm_group_label>mobile Health (mHealth)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of care breastfeeding counseling</intervention_name>
    <description>The ongoing antenatal, delivery and postnatal breastfeeding and lactation counseling that is provided by the Naivasha sub-County Referral Hospital.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mothers over 18 years who are employed in contract-based labor in sectors that include&#xD;
             education, business, healthcare, commercial agriculture, tourism/food service.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mothers must reside in the greater Naivasha, Kenya area and receive maternal and child&#xD;
             health care at the Naivasha sub-County Referral Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mothers of infants with cleft deformities or other abnormalities that interfere with&#xD;
             breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Scott B Ickes</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wheaton College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Virginia Shaffer, MA</last_name>
    <phone>1-630-752-5623</phone>
    <email>virginia.shaffer@wheaton.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Joyceline Kinyua, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>+254710289926</phone>
    <email>kinyuajoyceline@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only de-identified data will be shared with other researchers. This will include maternal research identification number, education level, martial status, parity, type of employment, child morbidity and breastfeeding status (at 0, 6, 14, 24, and 36 weeks weeks).</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>2 months after the primary data analysis is complete.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Permission of the principal investigator.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

