<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05792839</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Abdominoplasty &amp; hernia</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05792839</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Abdominoplasty With Ventral Hernia Repair Versus Hernioplasty .</brief_title>
  <official_title>Concomitant Abdominoplasty With Ventral Hernia Repair Versus Ventral Hernioplasty . A Randomized Comparative Prospective Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Comparison between hernioplasty alone versus concomitant abdominoplasty with ventral hernia&#xD;
      repair regarding efficacy and post-operative recurrence of hernia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ventral hernias are very common and do present a challenge because of the risk of recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ventral hernias of the abdomen are defined as a non-inguinal, nonhiatal defect in the fascia&#xD;
      of the abdominal wall. Annually, there are about 350,000 ventral hernia operations. The&#xD;
      repair of these abdominal wall defects is a common surgery performed by general surgeons.&#xD;
      Surgery is typically recommended for individuals with acceptable operative risk, symptomatic&#xD;
      hernias, or those at elevated risk of developing complications from a hernia. They can affect&#xD;
      an individual's quality of life and can lead to hospitalizations and even death in some&#xD;
      cases.[1][2][3] Common causes of acquired ventral hernias include previous surgery causing an&#xD;
      incisional hernia, trauma, and repetitive stress on naturally weak points of the abdominal&#xD;
      wall. These naturally occurring weak points in the abdominal wall include the umbilicus,&#xD;
      semilunar line, ostomy sites, bilateral inguinal regions, and esophageal hiatus. Obesity is a&#xD;
      large component of hernias as well because it stretches the fascia of the abdomen causing it&#xD;
      to weaken. Specifically, the action of repetitive weight gain and loss leads to weakening.[4]&#xD;
      Reported recurrence rates after VHR in the literature vary widely and range from 2.7% to 20%&#xD;
      for primary ventral hernia (umbilical and epigastric) to 32-37% for incisional hernia&#xD;
      repairs, depending on the series in question. (5) Abdominoplasty can be performed in&#xD;
      combination with hernia repair in patients with ventral hernias, especially when associated&#xD;
      with large midline ventral hernias, diastasis of recti and the associated laxity and&#xD;
      abdominal shape deformity, represent aesthetic and functional problems for the patients. So,&#xD;
      the surgical treatment of both pathologies at the same time is highly recommended if the&#xD;
      patient's general condition permits. This can be achieved by a comprehensive technique&#xD;
      incorporating abdominoplasty performed by a transverse lower abdominal incision into any of&#xD;
      the hernia repair techniques.(6) The procedure continues to become increasingly popular, and&#xD;
      this is attributed to the increasing rates of obesity and subsequent use of weight loss&#xD;
      surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim(s) of the Research (50 words max):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Is to compare the outcome and efficacy of the combined procedure of (abdominoplasty and&#xD;
      hernioplasty) to hernioplasty alone according to rate of post operative recurrence of hernia&#xD;
      .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Repair of ventral hernia with hernioplasty or abdominoplasty.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison between the two procedures regarding the rate of recurrence within the two patients groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Umbilical ischaemic changes</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Detection of post operative ishaemia and necrosis of umbilicus as a known complication of abdominoplasty procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">52</enrollment>
  <condition>Abdominal Hernia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Concomitant abdominoplasty with ventral hernia repair .</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>We do abdominoplasty with concomitant repair of the hernial defect and abdominal wall muscles in the same setting.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ventral Hernioplasty</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>We do hernioplasty with mesh placement for a surgical treatment for ventral hernia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Abdominoplasty with ventral hernia repair versus ventral hernioplasty.</intervention_name>
    <description>We do surgical treatment for ventral hernia in the form of hernioplasty with surgical mesh placement or by means of abdominoplasty surgical technique.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Concomitant abdominoplasty with ventral hernia repair .</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ventral Hernioplasty</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with age more than 20 years and less than 60 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients having ventral hernias with BM more than 25 kg/m2. Patients with floppy abdomen&#xD;
        Patients with divercation of recti Patients with an (ASA) classification of 3 or less with&#xD;
        no history of DM or other major comorbidities as cardiopulmonary, hepatic, or renal&#xD;
        impairment.Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mark Natey Abdo Barsom</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident at general and laparoscopic surgery department , assiut university hospital.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ventral hernia</keyword>
  <keyword>Abdominoplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Hernioplasty</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hernia, Ventral</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hernia, Abdominal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Internal Hernia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

