<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05793814</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AFCRO-138</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05793814</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assess the Effects of a Limosilactobacillus Supplement on Recurrence of UTI in Healthy Women During a 6-month Period</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study to Assess the Effects of Consumption of a Limosilactobacillus Supplement on Recurrence of Uncomplicated Symptomatic Urinary Tract Infections (UTI) in Healthy Women During a 6-month Period</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Church &amp; Dwight Company, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Church &amp; Dwight Company, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical trial is to assess the efficacy of the probiotic&#xD;
      Limosilactobacillus reuteri 3613 for the decrease or prevent UTI occurrence in women ages&#xD;
      18-65 with a confirmed medical history of recurrent uncomplicated UTIs compared to a Placebo&#xD;
      (the study medication without the probiotic)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Adult women with a confirmed medical history of recurrent uncomplicated UTIs meeting all the&#xD;
      eligibility criteria will be allocated in two study arms: test and placebo. Approximately 65&#xD;
      subjects per group will be enrolled to assure that approximately 50 subjects in each group&#xD;
      complete the study. the study will be conducted in Ireland. The study will last approximately&#xD;
      six month for each subject and will consist of 5 visits. The L. reuteri 3613 will be taken&#xD;
      daily for 6 months and the frequency of UTIs will be assessed to determine the potential for&#xD;
      the probiotic to decrease or prevent UTI occurrence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A Randomized, Double -Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence rate of symptomatic UTI</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate in healthy women who experience recurrent UTIs, the effect of 6 months of daily supplementation of the investigational product on incidence rate of symptomatic UTIs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects experiencing ≥1 symptomatic UTI</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants per product group experiencing ≥1 symptomatic UTI (as determined by urine culture) during the 6-month intervention period (from Baseline Visit [V2] to Final Visit [V5]).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>UTI symptom severity</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in UTI symptom severity of participants with symptomatic UTI between product groups comparing Baseline (Week 0) with scores to scores at V 5 for</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects experiencing different numbers of UTI</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants per product group experiencing 0, 1, 2, 3, or more symptomatic UTI during the 6-month intervention period from V2 to Final V5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total UTI count</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in total number of UTIs per group (probiotic treatment compared to placebo group) during the 6-month intervention period from V2 to Final V5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time for the first UTI</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in time from Day 0 to the first UTI occurrence between product groups, during the 6-month intervention period from Day 0 to V5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vaginal pH change</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in vaginal pH over time from Visit 2 to Visit 5, between product groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life change</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Quality of Life questionnaire using Likert scale over time from Visit 2 to Visit 5, between product groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Time for vaginal presence of the probiotic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate in healthy women who experience recurrent UTIs, the effect of 6 months of daily supplementation of the investigational product on the time it takes for the probiotic to reach the urogenital tract. The probiotic in vaginal samples will be measured visits 2-5.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Vaginal microbiome</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Modulation of the vaginal microbiome analyzed using Shotgun metagenomic sequencing from Baseline (Week 0) to Visit 5 (Week 24) compared between groups.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Vaginal presence of the probiotic</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the proportion of participants with vaginal swabs positive for the probiotic at Baseline (Visit 2) compared to Visit 5 (Week 24, end of intervention) between product groups.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of any Adverse Events (AEs/SAEs).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Vital signs (Blood Pressure, Heart Rate, and Temperature).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Uncomplicated Symptomatic Urinary Tract Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: Limosilactobacillus Supplement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Capsules containing Probiotic taken daily for 6 month</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Capsules containing Microcrystalline cellulose, magnesium stearate taken Daily for 6 month</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Limosilactobacillus reuteri 3613</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily for 6 month</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: Limosilactobacillus Supplement</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Probiotics, Lactobacillus</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily for 6 month</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Be able to give voluntary, written, informed consent to participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Be between 18-65, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Has a BMI between 18.5 to 40 kg/m2, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has a history of recurrent UTIs, defined as ≥ 3 episodes in the past year, of which&#xD;
             two were approximately in the past 6 months immediately prior to their screening visit&#xD;
             (Visit 1), at the discretion of the investigator. At least one episode must be&#xD;
             diagnosed medically and treated by a health care professional, the remaining two may&#xD;
             be self-reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to maintain existing dietary and physical activity patterns throughout the&#xD;
             trial period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing to comply with the trial protocol and consume the investigational product&#xD;
             daily for the duration of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals who are on unstable medications (defined as prescribed medications which&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator may impact the outcomes of the study (defined as&#xD;
             prescribed medications for which participant only takes periodically or 'as needed').&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Individuals with a history of UTIs who have experienced &gt;5 UTIs in the 6 months prior&#xD;
             to their Baseline Visit (Week 0).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants with clinically significant abnormal laboratory results at their&#xD;
             screening visit (from urine culture, urinalysis, and safety blood assessments) which,&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator, would impact the efficacy of the trial or the&#xD;
             safety of the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Individuals who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or wish to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Individuals currently of childbearing potential, but not using an effective method of&#xD;
             contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Individuals who have taken oral antibiotics (or topical antibiotics in their&#xD;
             urogenital area) within the previous 30 days prior to their Baseline Visit (Visit 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Individuals with a current history of drug abuse (self-report) and/or alcohol abuse&#xD;
             (&gt;2 standard alcoholic drinks per day) within the 6 months prior to Baseline Visit&#xD;
             (Visit2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Uses tobacco or smoking-related products (including, but not limited to cigarettes,&#xD;
             cigars, chewing tobacco, e-cigarettes), and nicotine products (e.g., nicotine gum&#xD;
             and/or nicotine patches).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Individuals currently consuming an extremely restrictive diet, or in the previous 3&#xD;
             months prior to their Baseline Visit or planning to consume a restrictive diet during&#xD;
             the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Individuals who are not willing to adhere to dietary/supplement restrictions listed in&#xD;
             the trial protocol (refrain from consumption of probiotic supplements, prebiotics,&#xD;
             cranberry supplements, and D-mannose supplements; limit consumption of yoghurt,&#xD;
             fermented foods, and cranberries to no more than once per week).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Individuals with allergies or sensitivities to ingredients that would preclude intake&#xD;
             of the investigational products.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participants may not be receiving treatment involving experimental drugs. If the&#xD;
             participant has been in a recent experimental trial, these must have been completed&#xD;
             not less than 30 days prior to their Screening Visit (Visit 1) for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Individuals that have a significant acute or chronic coexisting illness such as renal&#xD;
             diseases (renal failure, nephrolithiasis), anatomical urinary tract abnormalities,&#xD;
             intestinal disease, severe uncontrolled metabolic or cardiovascular disease (such as&#xD;
             diabetes or hypertension), anticoagulant therapy, cancer, or HIV, or any condition&#xD;
             which contraindicates, in the investigator's judgement, entry to the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wafaa A Ayad, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6098061950</phone>
    <email>wafaa.ayad@churchdwight.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Oliver Chen, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6098061583</phone>
    <email>oliver.chen@churchdwight.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Church &amp;Dwight., Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Princeton</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08543</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wafaa A Ayad, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>609-806-1950</phone>
      <email>wafaa.ayad@churchdwight.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Oliver Chen, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>609 806 1583</phone>
      <email>oliver.chen@churchdwight.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 2, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

