<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05611255</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RECHMPL20_0461</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05611255</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Two Bladder Catheterization Strategies in Thoracic Surgery Patients With an Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>URICATHOR</acronym>
  <official_title>Comparison of Two Bladder Catheterization Strategies in Thoracic Surgery Patients With an Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS): Systematic Intermittent Catheterization Versus Bladder Scan Guided Catheterization in the Post Anesthesia Care Unit: a Prospective Randomized Double-blind Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Montpellier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Montpellier</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      General anesthesia, thoracic epidural, and morphine inhibit the urination process and promote&#xD;
      postoperative Acute Urinary Retention (AUR) after thoracic surgery. Indwelling bladder&#xD;
      catheterization prevents this risk, but is associated with other complications (urinary tract&#xD;
      infection, delayed mobilization). With the rise of enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS)&#xD;
      protocols, bladder catheterization is being questioned. The current protocol in the&#xD;
      department is to catheterize only patients with a high bladder volume in the post anesthesia&#xD;
      care unit (defined as a bladder volume &gt; 400 ml on bladder scan). Preliminary results from&#xD;
      the &quot;AirLeaks&quot; study show a high rate of early postoperative AUR (approximately 50%). The&#xD;
      investigators believe that a &quot;systematic intermittent catheterization&quot; (SIC) strategy is&#xD;
      superior to the current &quot;bladder scan-guided catheterization in the post anesthesia care&#xD;
      unit&quot; (BSGC) strategy in preventing the risk of postoperative AUR. To their knowledge, no&#xD;
      study has compared these two bladder catheterization strategies in a thoracic accelerated&#xD;
      rehabilitation protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute urinary retention (AUR) is clinically defined by the presence of a bladder globe, with&#xD;
      complete inability to urinate, sometimes associated with severe suprapubic abdominal pain. It&#xD;
      is a urological emergency. An AUR can be complicated by acute renal failure, obstruction&#xD;
      lifting syndrome (polyuria), a vacuo hematuria, or a slammed bladder (characterized by the&#xD;
      presence of a post-void residue).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Systematic intermittent catheterization (SIC) allows monitoring of diuresis during the per-&#xD;
      and post-operative period, and prevents the risk of AUR. It is associated with numerous&#xD;
      disadvantages, such as the risk of infection (nosocomial urinary tract infection,&#xD;
      bacteriuria, candiduria), which doubles after 2 days of catheterization, the risk of trauma&#xD;
      (bleeding from the urethra, hematuria), the delay in mobilization and ambulation, and the&#xD;
      psychological impact on the patients (dependence, agitation, confusion). All of these&#xD;
      complications are potentially at risk of lengthening the average length of stay, and&#xD;
      represent an additional cost for the Health Insurance. Thus, it seems that SIC is an obstacle&#xD;
      to enhance recovery after surgery (ERAS), which is why the investigators have eliminated this&#xD;
      option in our center. However, even recent American protocols for thoracic ERAS consider that&#xD;
      an epidural should be associated with an indwelling catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bladder catheterization strategies are available for patients undergoing lung surgery.&#xD;
      Options include no bladder catheterization, evacuation catheterization, and post anesthesia&#xD;
      care unit catheterization guided by ultrasound or bladder scan measurement of bladder volume.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SIC is a strategy that involves draining urine once, in all patients, after surgery (in the&#xD;
      operating room). Bladder Scan Guided Catheterization in the post anesthesia care unit (BSGC)&#xD;
      is an innovative strategy that consists of a standardized and reproducible assessment of the&#xD;
      bladder volume before discharge from the post anesthesia care unit, and draining urine only&#xD;
      in patients who require it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To their knowledge, no study has compared these two bladder catheterization strategies in a&#xD;
      thoracic ERAS protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that a SIC strategy is superior to an individualized BSGC strategy in&#xD;
      preventing postoperative AUR in thoracic surgery patients entering a ERAS program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The SIC strategy is a novel idea that is not yet widely used in ERAS programs. The&#xD;
      investigators believe that the SIC strategy will significantly decrease the rate of AUR. If&#xD;
      this strategy proves to be superior to our current &quot;bladder scan guided&quot; service protocol, it&#xD;
      could be incorporated into our ERAS program. Knowing the clinical repercussions,&#xD;
      psychological impact, and costs associated with postoperative AUR, the medico-economic&#xD;
      prospects of this study are major.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 8, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 8, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 8, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of acute urinary retention (AUR) within 24 hours postoperatively</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after thoracic surgery</time_frame>
    <description>AUR is defined by the absence of voiding recovery in an unprobed patient, with or without pubic pain (pain may be inhibited by epidural or morphine received), associated with a bladder volume &gt; 400 ml on bladder scan.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of acute urinary retention (AUR) after Day 1 and during the first 5 days after surgery or during the hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>Between Day 1 and Day 5 postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the rate of AUR occurring beyond the 24th postoperative hour between the two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bladder volume drained</measure>
    <time_frame>The first hour after catheter placement</time_frame>
    <description>Bladder volume drained the first hour after catheter placement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total duration of the first bladder catheterization</measure>
    <time_frame>During the first bladder catheterization</time_frame>
    <description>Total duration of the first bladder catheterization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of bladder catheterizations</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of bladder catheterizations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of complications related to catheterization</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Macroscopic hematuria, documented urinary tract infection, suspected urinary tract infection with probabilistic antibiotic treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of complications related to AUR</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative acute renal failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Other postoperative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative hypotension, nausea or vomiting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration before putting in the chair (in hours)</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Duration before putting in the chair (in hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration before standing up (in hours)</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Duration before standing up (in hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Length of hospital stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated cost of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 5 days of post-surgical hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Estimated cost of stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">112</enrollment>
  <condition>Urinary Retention</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Infection</condition>
  <condition>Urinary Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Systematic Intermittent Catheterization (SIC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A bladder catheter will be placed in the operating room, at the end of the operation, in a patient still under general anesthesia. Once the urine has been drained and quantified, the bladder catheter will be removed before the patient is discharged and extubated.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bladder Scan Guided Catheterization (BSGC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>No systematic catheterization will be performed, the indication for catheterization will be guided by bladder-scan volume monitoring.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Systematic Intermittent Catheterization</intervention_name>
    <description>A strategy that consists of draining urine only once, in all patients, after surgery (in the operating room).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Systematic Intermittent Catheterization (SIC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SIC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bladder Scan Guided Catheterization</intervention_name>
    <description>A strategy of standardized and reproducible assessment of bladder volume before discharge from the post anesthesia care unit, and draining urine only in patients who require it.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bladder Scan Guided Catheterization (BSGC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BSGC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing scheduled thoracic surgery at the study center&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be of legal age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be eligible for the enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) protocol in effect in the&#xD;
             department.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-intubated anesthesia with spontaneous ventilation (NIVATS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Already have an indwelling bladder catheter or suprapubic catheter or double J&#xD;
             catheter or other urinary drainage device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urinary tract infection under treatment or bladder catheterization less than one month&#xD;
             old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indication of per- or postoperative bladder catheterization for another reason (e.g.&#xD;
             monitoring of diuresis in chronic renal failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known vesico-sphincter disorder with documented post-void residue&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological bladder (spinal cord injury or stroke sequelae)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented urinary incontinence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic renal failure with a glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 30 ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to bladder catheterization (e.g. stenosis of the urethra)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be under legal protection or incapable of giving consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to obtain written informed consent after a reflection period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not be affiliated to a French social security system or a beneficiary of such a system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Long-term morphine drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy in progress or planned during the study period, Pregnant or nursing women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jérôme PANIEGO, IADE</last_name>
    <phone>0664439476</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>j-paniego@chu-montpellier.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marc MOURAD, MD</last_name>
    <email>m-mourad@chu-montpellier.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Montpellier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34295</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jérôme PANIEGO</last_name>
      <phone>0664439476</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>j-paniego@chu-montpellier.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 10, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 14, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 14, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 18, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Urinary catheter</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute urinary retention</keyword>
  <keyword>Thoracic surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Thoracic epidural</keyword>
  <keyword>Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS)</keyword>
  <keyword>Perioperative medicine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Retention</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

