<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05612646</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CF20208B</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05612646</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Acupressure in Improving Constipation Among Inpatients in Neurology Departments</brief_title>
  <official_title>Taiwan Taichung Veterans General Hospital</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Taichung Veterans General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Taichung Veterans General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      As a form of non-invasive auxiliary care, Traditional Chinese Medicine acupressure can&#xD;
      prevent constipation, reduce medication for constipation, save medical costs, and alleviate&#xD;
      constipation among inpatients in neurology departments, as well as improve patients' general&#xD;
      ease and comfort of defecation, thereby improving their quality of life. It also provides&#xD;
      clinical nursing staff with a more effective, safer, and more comfortable auxiliary method of&#xD;
      preventing constipation, and can be used as a reference for the nursing of such patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Constipation is a common problem among geriatric patients and in neurology&#xD;
      departments. However, using stool softeners and enemas yield only temporary effects and may&#xD;
      even lead to alternating constipation, diarrhea, and metabolic disorders. Because of its&#xD;
      non-invasive nature, Acupressure can be used as adjuvant therapy of integrated traditional&#xD;
      Chinese and western medicine to prevent constipation among inpatients in neurology&#xD;
      departments. It is necessary to verify that Acupressure can be applied to avoid and alleviate&#xD;
      patients' constipation, improve their comfort, and improve their quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To explore the effect of Acupressure in alleviating constipation among inpatients&#xD;
      in neurology departments.Method: A randomized controlled two-group pre-test and post-test&#xD;
      experiment design were adopted in this study; neurology department inpatients were randomly&#xD;
      assigned to either the experimental group, which comprised 64 subjects receiving Acupressure&#xD;
      on three acupoints (Tianshu, ST25: Stomach Meridian 25; Zhongwan CV12: Conception Vessel 12;&#xD;
      Qihai CV6: Meridian Vessel 6) or the control group which comprised 64 subjects receiving&#xD;
      routine nursing and fake Acupressure. The research tools included the Bristol Stool Form and&#xD;
      Constipation Assessment Scale.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 24, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 24, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Assignment A two-group controlled, randomized study, the intervention groups: receiving acupressure on 3 acupoints (Tianshu, ST25: Stomach Meridian 25; Zhongwan CV12: Conception Vessel 12; Qihai CV6: Meridian Vessel 6), control groups: receiving routine nursing and fake acupressure.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Use the random number generator of EXCEL to generate the random number assigned by the computer, and put the serial number in the sealed envelope in sequence. After the patients completed the pre-test, the sealed envelopes were opened in sequence, and the patients were randomly assigned to the experimental group and the routine care group. The study used an assessor blinding design, that is, the data collectors were unaware of the patient group assignments until the end of the study</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The constipation assessment scale scores</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment from the first day to the seventh day after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Constipation Assessment Scale (CAS), a total of 8 questions, 0 points: no, 1 point: yes, but not severe, 2 points. Very serious, the higher the score (0-16 points), the more severe the constipation symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Bristol Stool Form Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment from the first day to the seventh day after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>bach's alpha of The Bristol Stool Form Scale. Classification: Type 1: hard balls (difficult to pass through), Type 2: sausage-like, but with uneven surface Type 3: sausage-like, but with cracks on the surface, Type 4: like sausage or snake Surface is smooth, type 5: soft lumps with smooth broken edges (easy to pass), type 6: fluffy lumps with rough edges, mushy stool, type 7: watery, no solid lumps (completely liquid), type 1 Types 3 and 2 indicate constipation; Types 3 and 4 are ideal stool shapes, especially Type 4 is the easiest to defecate; Types 5 to 7 are likely to have diarrhea</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">128</enrollment>
  <condition>Constipation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>routine nursing and fake acupressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>control groups: receiving routine nursing and fake acupressure to improve constipation for 7 days during hospitalization.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>acupressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patients assigned to the experimental group received acupoint massage designed to improve constipation for 7 days during hospitalization. The selection of acupoints in this study includes &quot;Tianshu (double)&quot; (Tianshu, ST25: Stomach Meridian 25, the 25th point of the stomach meridian), &quot;Zhongwan (single)&quot; (Zhongwan CV12: Conception Vessel 12, the 12th point of the Ren meridian) ), &quot;Qihai Point (Single)&quot; (Qihai CV6: Meridian Vessel 6 Renmai 6th point) 3 points.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acupressure</intervention_name>
    <description>The patients assigned to the experimental group received acupoint massage designed to improve constipation for 7 days during hospitalization. The selection of acupoints in this study includes &quot;Tianshu (double)&quot; (Tianshu, ST25: Stomach Meridian 25, the 25th point of the stomach meridian), &quot;Zhongwan (single)&quot; (Zhongwan CV12: Conception Vessel 12, the 12th point of the Ren meridian) ), &quot;Qihai Point (Single)&quot; (Qihai CV6: Meridian Vessel 6 Renmai 6th point) 3 points.</description>
    <arm_group_label>acupressure</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>routine nursing and fake acupressure</intervention_name>
    <description>control groups: receiving routine nursing and fake acupressure to improve constipation for 7 days during hospitalization.</description>
    <arm_group_label>routine nursing and fake acupressure</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 20 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Established diagnosis of stroke (ischemic, hemorrhagic acute phase)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. NIHSS 1-20 points&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Undiagnosed within three months before admission With intestinal disease and no rectal&#xD;
             resection&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. meeting the diagnostic criteria for functional constipation (Rome IV).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Abdominal surgery or abdominal radiotherapy within three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Abdominal cancer including liver, large intestine, lymph, and pelvic cavity, etc.,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Massive ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. There are implants in the abdominal cavity, such as V-P Shunt, L-P Shunt, CAPD, etc.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hsiao-Chi Nieh, MSC</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Head Nurse</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>1650 Taiwan Boulevard Sect. 4</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung</city>
        <zip>40705</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Abbasi P, Mojalli M, Kianmehr M, Zamani S. Effect of acupressure on constipation in patients undergoing hemodialysis: A randomized double-blind controlled clinical trial. Avicenna J Phytomed. 2019 Jan-Feb;9(1):84-91.</citation>
    <PMID>30788281</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bharucha AE, Lacy BE. Mechanisms, Evaluation, and Management of Chronic Constipation. Gastroenterology. 2020 Apr;158(5):1232-1249.e3. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2019.12.034. Epub 2020 Jan 13.</citation>
    <PMID>31945360</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Birimoglu Okuyan C, Bilgili N. Effect of abdominal massage on constipation and quality of life in older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Med. 2019 Dec;47:102219. doi: 10.1016/j.ctim.2019.102219. Epub 2019 Oct 16.</citation>
    <PMID>31780015</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chen MC, Yang LY, Chen KM, Hsu HF. Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis on Using Acupressure to Promote the Health of Older Adults. J Appl Gerontol. 2020 Oct;39(10):1144-1152. doi: 10.1177/0733464819870027. Epub 2019 Aug 19.</citation>
    <PMID>31426687</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chumpitazi BP, Self MM, Czyzewski DI, Cejka S, Swank PR, Shulman RJ. Bristol Stool Form Scale reliability and agreement decreases when determining Rome III stool form designations. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2016 Mar;28(3):443-8. doi: 10.1111/nmo.12738. Epub 2015 Dec 21.</citation>
    <PMID>26690980</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 25, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 7, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 7, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 9, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>acupressure, constipation,</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

