<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05622097</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HSC-MS-22</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05622097</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Solution Temperature and Fluid Deficit During Hysteroscopy</brief_title>
  <acronym>STOFD</acronym>
  <official_title>The Influence of Solution Temperature on Fluid Deficit During Hysteroscopy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hysteroscopic surgery is widely used for the treatment of gynecological diseases, such as&#xD;
      septum, synechiae, polyp and intrauterine fibroids. The complication rate is estimated as&#xD;
      0.22% and includes uterine perforation, massive bleeding, and fluid overload. Operative&#xD;
      hysteroscopy intravascular absorption (OHIA) syndrome refers to fluid overload complications&#xD;
      from operative hysteroscopies and is considered a major complication. Report describing the&#xD;
      clinical association between irrigation fluid temperature to intravasation rate itself or the&#xD;
      risk of fluid overload are limited mainly to theoretical models. Due to the aforementioned,&#xD;
      we aim to evaluated the role of temperature on absorption of the irrigation solution in&#xD;
      hysteroscopic surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hysteroscopic surgery is widely used for the treatment of gynecological diseases, such as&#xD;
      septum, synechiae, polyp and intrauterine fibroids. Advantages include less invasiveness and&#xD;
      faster recovery compared to traditional laparotomy. The complication rate is estimated as&#xD;
      0.22% and includes uterine perforation, massive bleeding, and fluid overload.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Operative hysteroscopy intravascular absorption (OHIA) syndrome refers to fluid overload&#xD;
      complications from operative hysteroscopies and is considered a major complication. Although&#xD;
      rare, large-scale fluid absorption might lead to symptoms severe enough to require intensive&#xD;
      care including dilutional hyponatremia, hypoosmolality, brain oedema, hypokinetic circulation&#xD;
      and cardiovascular collapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During surgical resection, hydrostatic pressure is usually higher than intravascular&#xD;
      pressures, mainly in the venous bed, allowing intravasation of irrigation solution from the&#xD;
      surgical field to the intravascular space. The greater the difference between these&#xD;
      hydrostatic pressures, the higher the flow rate into the blood and the higher the risk of&#xD;
      fluid overload. Moreover, although it is important to control surgical time and to keep&#xD;
      distension pressure as low as possible, fluid overload may occur before the predicted period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preventive measures, such as low-pressure irrigation, might reduce the extent of fluid&#xD;
      absorption but does not eliminate this complication. Monitoring the extent of absorption&#xD;
      during surgery allows control of the fluid balance in the individual patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Report describing the clinical association between irrigation fluid temperature to&#xD;
      intravasation rate itself or the risk of fluid overload are limited mainly to theoretical&#xD;
      models. Benefits of cold irrigation fluids are reported in studies on transurethral prostatic&#xD;
      resection (TUR) and include shorter procedure duration, improved surgical visualization, less&#xD;
      fluid use and reduced blood loss. The results of studies demonstrating higher complication&#xD;
      rate with hypothermia caused by locally applied cold irrigation solutions are equivocal and&#xD;
      were not demonstrated specifically in hysteroscopic procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The application of warm distension fluid has been recently used in office hysteroscopy in&#xD;
      order to reduce pain severity. A recent meta-analysis including 5 randomized control trials&#xD;
      reported warm saline was linked to a significant reduction in the visual analog scale (VAS)&#xD;
      pain score during the procedure and higher patient satisfaction rate. Nevertheless, warm&#xD;
      irrigation solution might be limiting for longer procedures due to expected expansion of the&#xD;
      vascular system resulting higher fluid deficit in shorter time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the aforementioned, we aim to evaluated the role of temperature on absorption of the&#xD;
      irrigation solution in hysteroscopic surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and Methods This is a prospective study that will be conducted at a single tertiary&#xD;
      medical center. Study population will include all women undergoing hysteroscopic surgery due&#xD;
      to benign indication. Women with known malignancy or hysteroscopic procedures using&#xD;
      alternative solutions (Ringer's lactate, 1.5% glycine, 5% dextrose) will be excluded from the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A TruClear™ hysteroscope will be used with 0.9% saline solution as the expanding media. Three&#xD;
      different temperatures will be randomly assigned to each case including: 17°C, 24°C (room&#xD;
      temperature), and 37°C (body temperature). The distension fluid will be prepared in advance&#xD;
      using cooled standardized refrigerator for the 17°C solution, and heating incubator for the&#xD;
      37°C and room temperature for the 24°C solution. The liquid temperatures will be confirmed by&#xD;
      thermometer before the procedure. Randomization to each arm will be made using computer&#xD;
      randomizer. The time to reach fluid deficit will be measured at the following deficit points:&#xD;
      250 cc, 500 cc, 750 cc, 1000cc, 1500 cc and total deficit. In addition, presurgical and&#xD;
      post-surgical blood samples for sodium level and osmolality will be collected. Immediate&#xD;
      post-surgical pain will be assesses 1 hour following the procedure using the visual analog&#xD;
      scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographic and clinical characteristics will be drawn from women's medical files. Operative&#xD;
      and post-operative data will be collected including: operation indication, operation&#xD;
      duration, operation complications (uterine perforation, bleeding, fluid overload&#xD;
      complications- electrolyte disturbances, osmolality, pulmonary embolism, pulmonary oedema),&#xD;
      post-operative complications (hemorrhage, endometritis, vascular - thromboembolic event,&#xD;
      ileus).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Median time to reach deficit of 500 cc</measure>
    <time_frame>From recruitment until follow up visit 2 weeks post operation</time_frame>
    <description>The difference to reach deficit of 500 cc in each arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual analog scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>To estimate pain post operation on a scale of 1 to 10 while 1 is no pain and 10 is maximal pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Warmed saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>0.9% Saline will be warmed to 37 degrees Celsius</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Room temperature saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>0.9% Saline will be warmed to 24 degrees Celsius</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cooled Saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>0.9% Saline will be cooled to 17 degrees Celsius</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9% Saline warmed to 37 degrees Celsius</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% Saline warmed to 37 degrees Celsius</description>
    <arm_group_label>Warmed saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9% Saline warmed to 24 degrees Celsius</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% Saline warmed to 24 degrees Celsius</description>
    <arm_group_label>Room temperature saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9% Saline cooled to 17 degrees Celsius</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% Saline cooled to 17 degrees Celsius</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cooled Saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - All women undergoing gynecologic hysteroscopic surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with known malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hysteroscopic procedures using alternative solutions (Ringer's lactate, 1.5% glycine,&#xD;
             5% dextrose)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Hysteroscopy is performed only in women with uterus</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aya Mohr-Sasson</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston, TX</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aya Mohr-Sasson</last_name>
    <phone>13462704682</phone>
    <email>aya.mohrsasson@uth.tmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lee EB, Park J, Lim HK, Kim YI, Jin Y, Lee KH. Complications of fluid overload during hysteroscopic surgery: cardiomyopathy and epistaxis - A case report. Anesth Pain Med (Seoul). 2020 Jan 31;15(1):61-65. doi: 10.17085/apm.2020.15.1.61.</citation>
    <PMID>33329791</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Aydeniz B, Gruber IV, Schauf B, Kurek R, Meyer A, Wallwiener D. A multicenter survey of complications associated with 21,676 operative hysteroscopies. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2002 Sep 10;104(2):160-4. doi: 10.1016/s0301-2115(02)00106-9.</citation>
    <PMID>12206931</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang MT, Chang CC, Hsieh MH, Chang CW, Fan Chiang YH, Tsai HC. Operative hysteroscopy intravascular absorption syndrome is more than just the gynecological transurethral resection of the prostate syndrome: A case series and literature review. Taiwan J Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Sep;59(5):748-753. doi: 10.1016/j.tjog.2020.07.022.</citation>
    <PMID>32917330</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hahn RG. Fluid absorption in endoscopic surgery. Br J Anaesth. 2006 Jan;96(1):8-20. doi: 10.1093/bja/aei279. Epub 2005 Nov 29.</citation>
    <PMID>16317031</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tuchschmid S, Bajka M, Szczerba D, Lloyd B, Szekely G, Harders M. Modelling intravasation of liquid distension media in surgical simulators. Med Image Comput Comput Assist Interv. 2007;10(Pt 1):717-24. doi: 10.1007/978-3-540-75757-3_87.</citation>
    <PMID>18051122</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aya Mohr Sasson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

