<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05617261</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HS25658 (B2022:092)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05617261</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Patient Tolerability and Success for Penile and Scrotal Urologic Procedures Under Conscious Sedation: A Prospective Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluating Patient Tolerability and Success for Penile and Scrotal Urologic Procedures Under Conscious Sedation: A Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Manitoba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Manitoba</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this observational study is to evaluate patient reported outcomes and&#xD;
      tolerability of scrotal and penile urologic procedures under the administration of minimal&#xD;
      conscious sedation. This will be assessed at 4-6 weeks post-procedure where patients will be&#xD;
      followed up with a questionnaire assessing how well patients tolerated the procedure and if&#xD;
      patients would opt for conscious sedation again in a similar, future procedure. The&#xD;
      investigators will secondarily be assessing the associated cost savings as compared to having&#xD;
      these procedures performed under general anesthesia at a tertiary care hospital.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current standard of care for the vast majority of urological procedures is the&#xD;
      administration of general anesthesia, spinal anesthesia, or anesthesia-delivered sedation -&#xD;
      requiring the operating room. However, this poses significant challenges associated with&#xD;
      operating room costs, resources, and patient wait times. Given lengthy surgical backlogs,&#xD;
      priority is focused on more acute conditions such as malignancies that require immediate&#xD;
      intervention. Procedures for non-acute conditions, such as penile and scrotal procedures,&#xD;
      have wait times that can exceed six months. Since most treatment for penile and scrotal cases&#xD;
      tends to be surgical intervention, delays in these procedures may significantly negatively&#xD;
      impact patients' sexual health, relationships, mental health, and quality of life. The&#xD;
      ability to perform these procedures outside of the operating room using local anesthesia with&#xD;
      or without conscious sedation may significantly reduce patient wait times and the costs of&#xD;
      surgical intervention. Furthermore, the use of conscious sedation would allow for faster&#xD;
      post-operative recovery, shorter procedural times, and decreased risks/side effects&#xD;
      associated with general anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fields such as plastic surgery have successfully transitioned certain procedures into a&#xD;
      clinic- based setting and the field of urology had also shown a similar interest. The&#xD;
      investigators research team has been at the forefront of this transition - previously&#xD;
      demonstrating the efficacy of distal ureteroscopy under nursing administered conscious&#xD;
      sedation and other common urologic procedures. However, these studies were limited as they&#xD;
      did not examine invasive scrotal and penile procedures, which have an extraordinary impact on&#xD;
      the sexual health of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project will provide evidence on the efficacy and characteristics of successful penile&#xD;
      and scrotal procedures conducted under the administration of local anesthesia with or without&#xD;
      conscious sedation. The findings of this study will help transition additional urological&#xD;
      procedures into a clinic-based setting safely: improving the sexual and mental health of&#xD;
      patients while decreasing cost, wait times, procedure duration, recovery times, and&#xD;
      anesthetic-related complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed study is a prospective study. Eligible patients at the Manitoba Men's Health&#xD;
      Clinic (Winnipeg, MB, Canada) will be approached for potential enrollment. Procedures with or&#xD;
      without conscious sedation are routinely performed at this clinic with volumes of 15-20&#xD;
      procedures performed weekly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be approached individually for potential recruitment into the study. Prior to&#xD;
      their urological procedure, patients will be seen by a member of the research team to&#xD;
      determine if they are willing to participate in the study. These meetings will occur in the&#xD;
      pre-operative waiting room at the Manitoba Men's Health Clinic where a member of the research&#xD;
      team who is involved in the care of that patient, will review the medical chart to ensure the&#xD;
      candidate meets the inclusion and exclusion criteria of the study. After discussing the&#xD;
      study, potential participants will have the opportunity to decide whether they would like to&#xD;
      be involved or not. Those who choose to be involved in the study will have to sign an&#xD;
      informed consent form. Patients may withdraw consent and terminate participation at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each participant will be assigned a study number to track them over time. Electronic data&#xD;
      forms will be used to collect preliminary information for all patients who consent to the&#xD;
      study. Baseline variables for collection will include patient age, sex, BMI, co-morbidities,&#xD;
      medications, smoking/drinking/illicit substance use, and family history of notable diseases.&#xD;
      Clinical variables collected will include procedure side (where applicable), medication dose&#xD;
      used for sedation, quantity and type of local anesthetic, procedural and recovery times,&#xD;
      patient-reported and surgeon-reported visual analogue scale pre-, intra-, and post-operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The statistical tests will include univariable and multivariable analyses. All the variables&#xD;
      defined above in the data collection section will be analyzed to determine if there is an&#xD;
      association between any of these variables and the patient-reported outcomes after the&#xD;
      urological procedure. Normally distributed continuous data will be reported as the mean ± the&#xD;
      standard deviation. Non-normally distributed data will be presented using the median and the&#xD;
      interquartile range. Multivariable adjusted logistic regression analysis will be used to&#xD;
      assess predictors of whether a patient would opt for conscious sedation again as opposed to&#xD;
      general/spinal anesthesia. SPSS Version 24.0 (SPSS Inc, IBM, Chicago, IL) will be used for&#xD;
      data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Personal Health Information Act (PHIA) compliance of the investigators database will be&#xD;
      ensured by preventing unauthorized access and implementing security measures such as password&#xD;
      protecting the electronic database and never permanently storing the database on a mobile&#xD;
      device or flash drive. Data will only be stored on the desktop computer enclosed in the&#xD;
      Manitoba Men's Health Clinic. Database information will only be emailed using a password-&#xD;
      protected, encrypted file. Information presented at meetings and conferences will be de-&#xD;
      identified and anonymous. The Research Ethics Board has approved this study at the University&#xD;
      of Manitoba.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 13, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Standardized questionnaire will be administered to patients 4-6 weeks after their individual procedure.</time_frame>
    <description>Patient tolerability as assessed using a standardized questionnaire administered to patients. Key questions of interest are if patients would opt for conscious sedation for a repeat procedure or general anesthesia, recommend conscious sedation to a friend undergoing a similar procedure, and a scale question with self-reported tolerability ranging from 0-10 with a higher value corresponding to an excellent experience.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Hydrocele</condition>
  <condition>Spermatocele</condition>
  <condition>Varicocele</condition>
  <condition>Epididymal Cyst</condition>
  <condition>Testicular Biopsy</condition>
  <condition>Circumcision</condition>
  <condition>Frenulectomy</condition>
  <condition>Penile Plication</condition>
  <condition>Orchiectomy</condition>
  <condition>Vasectomy Reversal</condition>
  <condition>Testicular Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Penile Diseases</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conscious sedation</intervention_name>
    <description>Conscious sedation is a combination of medications to help you relax (a sedative, for example nitrous gas) and to block out pain (commonly known as freezing, for example lidocaine).</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients undergoing: hydrocelectomy, spermatocelectomy, varicocelectomy, epididymectomy,&#xD;
        testicular biopsy, adult circumcision, frenulectomy, penile plication, orchiectomy, and&#xD;
        vasectomy reversal at the Manitoba Men's Health Clinic (Winnipeg, MB, Canada) will be&#xD;
        approached for potential enrolment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. patients over the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. undergoing one of the previously mentioned procedures under local anesthesia with or&#xD;
             without conscious sedation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. having a minimum follow-up of 4-6 weeks.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Premal Patel, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Surgery. Director, Undergraduate Urologic Medical Education</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Men's Health Clinic Manitoba</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 13, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 13, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Manitoba</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>PremalPatel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Department of Surgery. Director, Undergraduate Urologic Medical Education</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Conscious sedation</keyword>
  <keyword>Local anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>Penile</keyword>
  <keyword>Scrotal</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient reported outcomes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Varicocele</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Testicular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Penile Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Spermatocele</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

