<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05795660</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1736/2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05795660</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Platelet Rich Plasma for the Treatment of Osteochondral Lesions of the Talus</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Platelet Rich Plasma for the Treatment of Osteochondral Lesions of the Talus: Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ministry of Health, Kuwait</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ministry of Health, Kuwait</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Osteochondral lesion of the talus (OCL) results from the detachment of the talar cartilage&#xD;
      which could also be associated with subchondral bone fragmentation due to trauma. OCL can be&#xD;
      managed conservatively by immobilization and weight bearing restriction or surgically to&#xD;
      stimulate the regeneration and the formation of fibrous cartilage including reparative or&#xD;
      replacement approaches. OCL surgical intervention includes bone marrow stimulation or&#xD;
      autologous osteochondral transplantation while the cartilage regeneration was found&#xD;
      unsatisfactory with these interventions. However, introducing platelet rich plasma (PRP) as&#xD;
      an adjacent intervention could enhance the cartilage regeneration in OCL due to the release&#xD;
      of growth factors and bioactive components, which could in turn reduce the need for&#xD;
      replacement interventions and improve the regeneration of the cartilage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The literature was reviewed, and four randomized controlled trials have been found exploring&#xD;
      the effect of PRP in OCL where both ankle function and pain were examined. The results of the&#xD;
      previous studies have proved the effectiveness of PRP in managing OCL as an adjunct to&#xD;
      microfracture surgery in improving ankle function and reducing pain which was superior to the&#xD;
      surgical intervention alone and also superior to the injection of PRP alone. Despite the&#xD;
      promising results, the previous studies were limited to several factors. There was a lack of&#xD;
      blinding which could risk the results to expectation bias, and the follow up period was short&#xD;
      in according to the MCMS, which is needed to monitor the long-term effect of the PRP and to&#xD;
      document any potential adverse effects or relapse in the function. Additionally, all the&#xD;
      previous studies performed blind injection. Additionally, the previous studies have not&#xD;
      controlled the administration of analgesic which could risk the results of the pain effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed study aims to examine the effect of PRP in the management of OCL using&#xD;
      randomized double-blind control trial design to eliminate any expectation bias. Patients will&#xD;
      be followed up for 12 months, and the PRP will be administered intra-operatively. Moreover,&#xD;
      PRP concentration will be standardized. Analgesic will be controlled and documented as a&#xD;
      confounded factor. Additionally, the quality of the repaired tissue and the regeneration of&#xD;
      the hyaline cartilage will be examined using MRI at the end of the follow-up. Therefore, the&#xD;
      study aims to examine the effectiveness of PRP in OCL using randomized controlled trial&#xD;
      design.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>American Orthopedic Foot and Ankle (AOFAS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteochondral Lesions of the Talus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Osteochondral lesions of the talus group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive PRP injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive saline injection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>platelet rich plasma</intervention_name>
    <description>platelet rich plasma injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Osteochondral lesions of the talus group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>platelet rich plasma injection</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of OCL, which will be confirmed with radiographs and magnetic resonance&#xD;
             imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged &gt; or = 18 years &lt; 60 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  complain of ankle pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  posterior OCL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ankle infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  teroid injection within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  surgery of the involved joint with 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  received glucosamine and/or chondroitin sulfate, or anticoagulant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systematic inflammatory condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  substantial venous or lymphatic stasis in the legs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathologies that my confound pain and functional assessment in the ankle (plantar&#xD;
             fasciitis, Achilles tendonitis, sprains, and degenerative joint disease of the foot.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to any of the component of the PRP injection, disabling degenerative joint&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Najla Alsiri, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00965-66820032</phone>
    <email>dr.alsiri@outlook.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.korgroup.org</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ministry of Health, Kuwait</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Meshal Alhadhoud</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Orthopedic Surgery Department</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be available upon request.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

