<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05628779</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL81645.100.22</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05628779</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Edge-to-edge Transcatheter Tricuspid Valve Repair in Patients With Severe Symptomatic Tricuspid Regurgitation</brief_title>
  <acronym>TRACE-NL</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Safety, Efficacy and Cost-effectiveness of Transcatheter Tricuspid Valve Repair in Patients With Severe Tricuspid Regurgitation in the Netherlands.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Antonius Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ZonMw: The Netherlands Organisation for Health Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Antonius Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a national multicenter, open-label, randomized controlled trial to show superiority&#xD;
      of edge-to-edge Transcatheter Tricuspid Valve repair (TTVr) on top of the Standard Of Care&#xD;
      (SOC; heart failure medication) over the SOC alone in patients with symptomatic severe&#xD;
      Tricuspid Regurgitation (TR) in the Netherlands.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tricuspid valve regurgitation (TR) is a common heart valve disease associated with mortality,&#xD;
      heart failure hospitalization (HHF) and a significant negative impact on quality of life&#xD;
      (QoL). The prevalence of moderate or severe TR in the Netherlands is estimated at 0.55% and&#xD;
      becoming more prevalent. Surgery is rarely performed, because in-hospital mortality is high&#xD;
      and there is little evidence for the efficacy. The majority of patients does therefore&#xD;
      entirely dependent on treatment with heart failure medication. However, a subset of these&#xD;
      patients experience (progressive) symptoms of refractory congestive heart failure despite the&#xD;
      SOC with heart failure medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Transcatheter Tricuspid Valve repair (TTVr) offers several new strategies to address severe&#xD;
      TR; one promising technique to treat patients with symptomatic severe TR is edge-to-edge&#xD;
      tricuspid valve (TV) repair through leaflet approximation. Edge-to-edge TTVr may provide an&#xD;
      elegant alternative treatment for many patients, because it is less burdensome due to the&#xD;
      minimally invasive nature. Moreover, multiple single-arm trials already reported promising&#xD;
      outcomes in terms of efficacy and safety, and the technique is very similar to Transcatheter&#xD;
      Mitral Valve repair (TMVr), with yet proven feasibility, efficacy and safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the safety, efficacy and cost-effectiveness of TTVr for&#xD;
      patients with symptomatic severe TR despite the SOC and high/prohibitive surgical risk in the&#xD;
      Netherlands.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 12, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A total of 150 patients will be randomly assigned with a 2:1 allocation to either interventional (n=100) or control group (n=50).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Randomized controlled trial with open-label extension</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hierarchical composite of all-cause mortality, heart failure hospitalization and Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Life is measured with the Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire with a 5 point change as clinically significant (0-100 points, higher score is better outcome)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mortality of any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization for heart failure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hospitalization for acute decompensated heart failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>5 point change is considered clinically significant (0-100 points with higher score is a better outcome), change of 5 points in Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire is considered clinically meaningful</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants without Major Adverse Events (MAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Cardiovascular mortality, myocardial infarction, stroke, major bleeding, device embolisation, new onset renal failure, endocarditis requiring surgery, non-elective cardiovascular surgery for device related adverse events.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in New York Heart Association</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>ranging from 0 to 4 (no limitation to severe limitation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 6-Minute Walk Test</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Distance in meters (higher score is a better outcome)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction tricuspid regurgitation</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6 months and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Echocardiographic assessment of Tricuspid Regurgitation (at least from severe to moderate or less)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-effectiveness as assessed by the Markov model</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare the cost-effectiveness of the intervention group versus the control group based on lifetime horizon by constructing a Markov model with model parameters populated from the trial results as well as other published literature. The model will estimate the incremental cost-effectiveness ratio between the two groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Tricuspid Valve Regurgitation, Nonrheumatic</condition>
  <condition>Cardiac Catheterization</condition>
  <condition>Heart Failure, Right Sided</condition>
  <condition>Valve Regurgitation, Tricuspid</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transcatheter Edge-to-Edge Repair (TEER) on top of the Standard Of Care (SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Transcatheter Edge-to-Edge Repair (TEER) on top of the Standard Of Care (SOC)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Of Care (SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will continue the SOC with heart failure medication following the European Society of Cardiology guideline 2021 recommendations (e.g. diuretics)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TriClip TTVr system (Abbott Vascular)</intervention_name>
    <description>Edge-to-edge leaflet approximation for the tricuspid valve</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcatheter Edge-to-Edge Repair (TEER) on top of the Standard Of Care (SOC)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PASCAL TTVr system (Edwards Lifesciences)</intervention_name>
    <description>Edge-to-edge leaflet approximation for the tricuspid valve</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcatheter Edge-to-Edge Repair (TEER) on top of the Standard Of Care (SOC)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The patient is symptomatic (New York Heart Association Functional Class II, III or&#xD;
             ambulatory class IV) despite Standard Of Care (SOC). The Central Screening Committee&#xD;
             (CSC) will assess whether the patient is receiving SOC. The CSC will also ensure that&#xD;
             in case of the presence of atrial fibrillation, left sided heart valve disease (not&#xD;
             requiring intervention) or coronary artery disease, conditions are first treated&#xD;
             adequately with medication and/or (surgical) intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient suffers from ≥ grade 3 isolated TR as determined by the assessment of a&#xD;
             qualifying transthoracic echocardiogram (TTE) and three-dimensional transesophageal&#xD;
             echocardiogram (3DTEE) and confirmed by the CSC, according to European Association for&#xD;
             Percutaneous Cardiovascular Interventions (Tricuspid Focus Group) consensus document&#xD;
             (in press). Note: If cardiac procedure(s) occur after eligibility was determined, TR&#xD;
             grade will be re-assessed 30 days after the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The cardiac surgeon of the sites' local heart team concurs that the patient is at high&#xD;
             estimated risk for mortality or morbidity with TV surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient is ≥18 years of age at time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The patient must provide written informed consent prior to any trial related&#xD;
             procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Systolic pulmonary artery pressure (sPAP) &gt; 70 mmHg or fixed pre-capillary pulmonary&#xD;
             hypertension as assessed by right heart catheterization. Severe uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension Systolic Blood Pressure (SBP) ≥ 180 mmHg and/or Diastolic Blood Pressure&#xD;
             (DBP) ≥ 110 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any condition that would interfere with a TTVr procedure, such as prior tricuspid&#xD;
             valve repair or tricuspid valve leaflet anatomy which may preclude device implantation&#xD;
             (e.g. calcification in grasping area, a severe coaptation defect of the tricuspid&#xD;
             leaflets (no clip placement possible), pacemaker or Implantable Cardioverter&#xD;
             Defibrillator (ICD) leads that would prevent appropriate placement or visualization of&#xD;
             TTVr devices, Ebstein Anomaly (normal annulus position, but valve leaflets attached to&#xD;
             walls and septum of the right ventricle), tricuspid valve anatomy non evaluable by&#xD;
             echo, known allergy or hypersensitivity to dual antiplatelet therapy AND anticoagulant&#xD;
             therapy or to device materials, femoral venous mass or thrombus or vegetation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Indication for left-sided (e.g. severe aortic stenosis, severe mitral regurgitation)&#xD;
             or pulmonary valve correction within prior 60 days. Note: concomitant mitral valve&#xD;
             disease (e.g. mitral regurgitation) will be treated first and patients will be&#xD;
             reassessed for the trial after 60 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Tricuspid valve stenosis - Defined as a tricuspid valve orifice of ≤ 1.0 cm2 and/or&#xD;
             mean gradient ≥5 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF) ≤20%&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active endocarditis, active rheumatic heart disease, other ongoing infection requiring&#xD;
             antibiotic therapy (enrolment possible 30 days after discontinuation of antibiotics&#xD;
             with no active infection) or leaflets degenerated from rheumatic disease (i.e.&#xD;
             noncompliant, perforated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Myocardial infarction known unstable angina, or percutaneous coronary intervention&#xD;
             within prior 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Hemodynamic instability defined as systemic systolic pressure &lt;90 mmHg with or without&#xD;
             afterload reduction, cardiogenic shock or the need for inotropic support or&#xD;
             hemodynamic support device (e.g. intra-aortic balloon pump).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Cerebrovascular Accident (CVA) within prior 90 days&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Chronic dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Bleeding disorders or hypercoagulable state, inability to use dual antithrombotic&#xD;
             therapy due to contraindication, allergy or hypersensitivity&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Active peptic ulcer or active gastrointestinal (GI) bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Life expectancy of less than 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject currently participating in another clinical trial (not yet completed primary&#xD;
             endpoint) or in another clinical investigation for valvular heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Pregnant or nursing patients or those who plan pregnancy during the course of the&#xD;
             trial. Women of childbearing age are required to have a negative pregnancy test 7 days&#xD;
             prior to baseline visit. Women of childbearing age should be instructed to use safe&#xD;
             contraception or have a sterilized regular partner.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Presence of anatomic or comorbid conditions, or other medical, social or psychological&#xD;
             conditions that, in the eye of the investigator, limits the subject's ability to&#xD;
             participate in the clinical investigation or comply with follow-up requirements, or&#xD;
             impact the scientific soundness of the investigation results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>M.J. Swaans, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ST. Antonius hospital Nieuwegein</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>M.J. Swaans, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31 (0)88 320 0900</phone>
    <email>m.swaans@antoniusziekenhuis.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mike Bosschaert, Drs</last_name>
    <phone>+31 (0)88 320 0900</phone>
    <email>m.bosschaert@antoniusziekenhuis.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Amsterdam UMC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jan Baan, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UMC Groningen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Groningen</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erik Lipsic, MD PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leiden UMC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leiden</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Frank van der kley, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maastricht UMC+</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jindra Vainer, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Antonius Hospital Nieuwegein</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nieuwegein</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martin Swaans, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicolas van Mieghem, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 29, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 23, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 23, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 27, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>St. Antonius Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Martin J. Swaans</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Transcatheter tricuspid valve repair</keyword>
  <keyword>Tricuspid valve regurgitation</keyword>
  <keyword>Tricuspid valve</keyword>
  <keyword>Leaflet approximation devices</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tricuspid Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>At the end of the study, the data will be locally saved at the st. Antonius Hospital and can be made available at request for reuse in other studies.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After publishing the main study articles, raw and modified data can be made available at request</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>These criteria will be made in consultation with the legal advisor of our institution and have not yet been drafted.&#xD;
Specific degrees in the field of research have to be demonstrated, as wel as links with hospitals or research institutes of the researcher/physician (e.g. an employee contract)</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

