<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05618470</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ZZ11-040</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05618470</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang Use in Patients With Blepharospasm</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Clinical Study on Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang Use in Patients With Blepharospasm</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the efficacy and safety of Jing Fang Wu Mei Wan Jiawei Fang in the treatment of&#xD;
      idiopathic blepharospasm using a clinical randomized controlled trial method.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Idiopathic blepharospasm is an idiopathic dysfunction characterized by involuntary spasms of&#xD;
      the eyelids bilaterally that interfere with visual function and cause ocular discomfort. The&#xD;
      incidence has increased each year in recent years, and the disease may present with&#xD;
      persistent eye closure or even functional blindness in advanced stages. In some patients, the&#xD;
      disease may be associated with submandibular dystonia, known as Meige's syndrome. Currently,&#xD;
      the disease is treated symptomatically. Such as oral.These treatments not only have large&#xD;
      side effects, but also make it difficult to relieve the patient of multiple lesions in the&#xD;
      eyes, face and tongue. Chinese medicine has unique advantages in treating this disease,&#xD;
      highlighting the overall diagnosis and solving different parts of the disease in an&#xD;
      integrated manner. Wu Mei Wan is a traditional Chinese medicine prescription, and our team&#xD;
      has been using Wu Mei Wan Jia Wei Fang for the treatment of Meige syndrome since 2009 under&#xD;
      the leadership of Gao Jiansheng, a famous Chinese medicine teacher in the capital, and found&#xD;
      significant therapeutic effects in preliminary clinical observation, but there is a lack of&#xD;
      large sample of randomized controlled clinical studies. In this study, we propose to&#xD;
      systematically observe the efficacy of traditional Chinese medicine in the treatment of&#xD;
      idiopathic blepharospasm by using the traditional sutra formula for idiopathic blepharospasm&#xD;
      as a test group and local botulinum toxin A injection as a control group, and to&#xD;
      scientifically evaluate the efficacy of the Wu Mei Wan Jia Wei Fang in the treatment of&#xD;
      idiopathic blepharospasm.The results were evaluated in order to provide new treatment options&#xD;
      for the clinical management of idiopathic blepharospasm (including Meige syndrome) and to&#xD;
      benefit more patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 12, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The degree of relief of blepharospasm was evaluated by Jankovic Rating Scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>According to the Jankovic Rating Scale (JRS), in terms of severity and frequency, the score ranges from 0 to 4, with the highest score being 8. The higher the score is, the more severe the spasm is.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Blepharospasm Disability Index (BSDI) was used to evaluate the impact of blepharospasm on daily living activities before and after treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>A total of 6 items were included, including walking, reading, driving, shopping, watching television and general activities. Each item was scored from 0 to 4 points and was self-evaluated by the patients. The total score of BSDI was 24 points.The higher the score is, the more severe the spasm is.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Traditional Chinese Medicine（TCM） syndrome scale evaluated the change of systemic syndrome before and after treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>The score for each syndrome is the sum of the highest scores obtained for each diagnosis of the syndrome. The full score is 30 points. Efficacy score = (Total score of pre-treatment symptoms➖Total post-treatment symptom score)/Total score of pre-treatment symptoms×100%. Symptoms basically disappear, reducing by 95 to 100 percent; Obvious effect: symptoms decreased significantly, reaching more than 75%; Effective: symptoms decreased to more than 55%; Ineffective: No or slightly reduced symptoms, only less than 50%..</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>According to whether there are common side effects of botulinum toxin such as ptosis, diplopia, photophobia, dry eye, gastrointestinal tract of exposed keratitis, whether there are gastrointestinal reactions and other side effects that may be related to the Chinese medicine granule preparation in this study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>According to the Jankovic rating scale, the recurrence was determined at 14 days, 42 days, 3 months and 6 months after medication</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>According to the Jankovic rating scale, the recurrence situation at 14 days, 42 days, 3 months and 6 months after medication was determined, and the increase of spasm intensity by 1 grade or more was considered as recurrence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by systemic response, routine blood tests, liver function (ALT), kidney function (BUN, Cr).</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>Systemic reaction (record at any time);&#xD;
Routine blood tests: the detection points were 14 days, 42 days, 3 months and 6 months after the first visit and treatment;&#xD;
Liver function (ALT), kidney function (BUN, Cr) : The detection points were 14 days, 42 days, three months and six months after the first visit and treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Dry Eye Syndromes</condition>
  <condition>Meige Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Blepharospasm</condition>
  <condition>Hyperactivity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will take Wumei pill granule orally.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>botulinum toxin A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this group, Botulinum toxin type A (Lanzhou Biopharmaceutical Co. LTD.) was injected locally around the eye.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang</intervention_name>
    <description>orally administered Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang prescription granules, 1 dose a day, twice a day, once for 14 days, for 42 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>nothing</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>botulinum toxin A</intervention_name>
    <description>Botulinum toxin (Lanzhou Biopharmaceutical Co., LTD.) was injected into the medial side of the upper eyelid, the lateral side of the upper eyelid, the lateral side of the lower eyelid, and the temporal orbicularis oculi muscle of the lateral canthus. The botulinum toxin type A was diluted into 50IU/ML with normal saline and injected with a 1ml skin test syringe (4\ 5-gauge needle), and 2.5IU was injected into each point. A total of 1 injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>botulinum toxin A</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>nothing</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Idiopathic blepharospasm met the diagnostic criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The age ranges from 18 to 80 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Liver Yang deficiency,mixed syndrome of cold and heat.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Signed Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Secondary blepharospasm due to keratoconjunctivitis, trichiasis, and blepharitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Open eyelid disuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. hemifacial spasm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient had undergone eye surgery in the previous 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Allergic to the ingredients in the medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Corneal lenses were worn during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. A woman who is pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Combined with cardiovascular, cerebrovascular,Liver and kidney function, hematopoietic&#xD;
             system serious primary disease, mental patients, combined with stroke patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. At the same time, use drugs that interfere with the evaluation of drug efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Idiopathic blepharospasm is treated with other drugs.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>wei yang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>wei yang</last_name>
    <phone>18600484803</phone>
    <phone_ext>010-68686185</phone_ext>
    <email>506910548@qq.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Eye Hospital, China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences；GuangAnmen Hospital, China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences；XiYuan Hospital, China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>10040</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Xi Chen</last_name>
      <phone>15300307564</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 21, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yang Wei</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Wumeiwan Jiawei Fang</keyword>
  <keyword>Blepharospasm</keyword>
  <keyword>Meige syndrome</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Meige Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Blepharospasm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

