<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05799300</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RoyalSussex</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05799300</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Haemodynamic Effects of Low-dose Spinal Anaesthesia for Hip Fracture Surgery.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Retrospective, Observational, Single-centre, Cohort Database Analysis of the Haemodynamic Effects of Low-dose Spinal Anaesthesia for Hip Fracture Surgery.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Royal Sussex County Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Royal Sussex County Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 65, 000 hip fractures occur in the United Kingdom (UK) each year, and more than&#xD;
      99% are repaired by surgery. Roughly half of patients receive spinal anaesthesia, where a&#xD;
      small amount (usually less than half a teaspoonful) of local anaesthetic is injected into the&#xD;
      lower back, around the nerves that go to and from the hip.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Low blood pressure is very common during surgery (at least &gt; 30%, depending on definition),&#xD;
      and appears to be linked to a greater chance of death within a month after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are 2 main ways of managing low blood pressure during surgery: treatment and&#xD;
      prevention. Treatments (fluids, drugs) have side effects in the older, frailer population&#xD;
      with hip fracture. Prevention involves giving anaesthesia at lower doses. National guidelines&#xD;
      recommend that lower doses are given, but this recommendation is based on historical research&#xD;
      selectively involving younger, fitter people having hip fracture surgery. Importantly, these&#xD;
      studies did not record blood pressure either accurately or often enough.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Anaesthesia Sprint Audit of Practice (ASAP) 2 study suggested that a safe level of low&#xD;
      blood pressure occurs when only 1.5 mls of spinal anaesthesia is given, and the investigator&#xD;
      has been using this amount in Brighton since 2011. Recently, the investigator has reported a&#xD;
      way of transferring vital signs data from anaesthetic monitors to storage computers for&#xD;
      medicolegal purposes (e.g. in Coroner's investigations: approximately 4000 people in the UK&#xD;
      die annually within a month of hip fracture surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, analyzing such observational data should also allow the investigator to describe&#xD;
      accurately how blood pressure changes around the time of surgery, and in patient groups that&#xD;
      are normally excluded from prospective research (e.g. the very old, the very frail, people&#xD;
      with dementia). By comparing this data to published national data from the ASAP 1 study, the&#xD;
      investigator hopes to determine whether lower doses of spinal anaesthesia are linked with a&#xD;
      lower rate of low blood pressure during surgery, potentially improving people's survival and&#xD;
      recovery after hip fracture.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 65, 000 hip fractures occur in the UK each year, and more than 99% are repaired&#xD;
      by surgery. Roughly half of patients receive spinal anaesthesia, where a small amount&#xD;
      (usually ~ 2.5mls) of local anaesthetic is injected into the lower back, around the nerves&#xD;
      that go to and from the hip.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator has found that low blood pressure (hypotension) is very common during&#xD;
      surgery (occurring in at least &gt; 30%, depending on the definition of hypotension), and&#xD;
      appears to be significantly linked to a greater chance of death within a month after surgery&#xD;
      (~3% rise in mortality/5 mmHg fall in SBP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are 2 main ways of managing low blood pressure during surgery: treatment and&#xD;
      prevention. Treatments (fluids, drugs) have side effects in the older, frailer population&#xD;
      with hip fracture, including fluid overload with heart failure, and cardiac/kidney/gut&#xD;
      ischaemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prevention involves giving anaesthesia at lower doses. UK national guidelines recommend that&#xD;
      lower doses are given (&lt; 2mls 0.5% hyperbaric bupivacaine), but this recommendation is based&#xD;
      on historical research selectively involving younger, fitter people having hip fracture&#xD;
      surgery. Importantly, these studies did not record blood pressure either accurately (i.e.&#xD;
      invasively) or often enough (i.e. &gt; every 5 minutes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ASAP 2 study suggested that a safe level of low blood pressure occurs when only 1.44 mls&#xD;
      0.5% hyperbaric/normobaric spinal anaesthesia is administered, and the investigator has been&#xD;
      using this amount (1.5mls) in Brighton since 2011.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, it has become possible to transfer vital signs data from anaesthetic monitors to&#xD;
      storage computers for medicolegal purposes (eg in Coroner's investigations - approximately&#xD;
      4000 people in the UK die annually within a month of hip fracture surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, analyzing such observational medicolegal data should also allow accurate description&#xD;
      of how blood pressure changes around the time of surgery, and in patient groups that are&#xD;
      normally excluded from prospective research (eg the very old, the very frail, people with&#xD;
      dementia). By comparing this data to published national data from the ASAP 1 study, it should&#xD;
      be possible to determine whether lower doses of spinal anaesthesia are linked with a lower&#xD;
      rate of low blood pressure during surgery. By merging individuals' data with that held on the&#xD;
      Brighton Hip Fracture Database, it should be possible to determine whether prevalence (and/or&#xD;
      depth+duration of hypotension) are correlated with outcomes (survival, length of inpatient&#xD;
      stay) after hip fracture repair.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 3, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 24, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 24, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cohort mean (SD) mean non-invasive blood pressure (MAP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Occurring during the 2 hour duration (approximately) of anaesthesia and surgery for each patient</time_frame>
    <description>Taken at 2 minute intervals peri-operatively for each patient</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The cohort prevalence of hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>During anaesthesia and surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Cohort prevalence of hypotension, variably defined as:&#xD;
Fall in systolic blood pressure (SBP) from baseline &gt; 20%;&#xD;
Fall in systolic blood pressure (SBP) from baseline &gt; 30%;&#xD;
Fall in mean arterial pressure (MAP) from baseline &gt; 20%;&#xD;
Fall in mean arterial pressure (MAP) from baseline &gt; 30%;&#xD;
Lowest SBP &lt; 90 millimetres of mercury (mmHg);&#xD;
Lowest SBP &lt; 100 mmHg&#xD;
Lowest MAP &lt; 70 mmHg;&#xD;
Lowest MAP &lt; 55 mmHg.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean depth x duration area under curve product for cohort hypotension after low dose spinal anaesthesia for hip fracture surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>During anaesthesia and surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Mean depth x duration area under curve product for cohort hypotension after low dose spinal anaesthesia for hip fracture surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantification of cohort systolic and mean arterial blood pressure changes before spinal administration</measure>
    <time_frame>During anaesthesia and surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Describing any effects of propofol sedation and local anaesthetic nerve block</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effective cohort duration of spinal anaesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>During anaesthesia and surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Including number of augmentatory anaesthetic interventions required in mean (SD) time from spinal administration to surgical skin closure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlations between individual (a) hypotension (b) hypotension depth/duration product and outcomes (death at 30 days, length of stay in hospital)</measure>
    <time_frame>During anaesthesia and surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Correlations between individual (a) hypotension (b) hypotension depth/duration product and outcomes (death at 30 days, length of stay in hospital)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Hip Fractures</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hip fracture cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>Gender, Age, Racial and Ethnic Origin of Subjects Male and female adults over the age of 18 years; all origins, all races will be included.&#xD;
Inclusion/exclusion criteria as below</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intrathecal anaesthesia</intervention_name>
    <description>Low dose 0.5% hyperbaric bupivacaine (1.3mls, 0.65mg) intrathecal anaesthesia.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hip fracture cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        People undergoing surgical hip fracture repair (hemiarthoplasty, dynamic hip screw,&#xD;
        cortical screws, proximal femoral nail) administered spinal anaesthesia for whom&#xD;
        contemporaneous vital signs (including blood pressure, heart rate, oxygen saturation,&#xD;
        breathing rate) have been stored in an anonymised, double password-protected database held&#xD;
        on secure computers at Princess Royal Hospital, Hayward's Heath (E. Sussex).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults (over 18 years) who have sustained a unilateral hip fracture and received&#xD;
             surgery (hemiarthroplasty, dynamic hip screw, cortical screws, proximal femoral nail)&#xD;
             under low dose spinal anaesthesia (1.3 mls 0.5% hyperbaric bupivacaine) after fascia&#xD;
             iliaca block + sedation, administered by the Chief Investigator (CI) between 3rd&#xD;
             March, 2017 and 1st January, 2020 at the Princess Royal Hospital, Hayward's Heath (E&#xD;
             Sussex).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. For whom crude vital signs data have been stored in pseudo-anonymised electronic form&#xD;
             on secure hospital computers, for medico-legal reference&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. People with hip fracture receiving conservative management during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. People with hip fracture requiring total hip arthroplasty (for whom larger volumes of&#xD;
             spinal anaesthesia are used);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. People with hip fracture administered spinal anaesthesia other than 1.3 mls 0.5%&#xD;
             hyperbaric bupivacaine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. People meeting inclusion criteria for whom vital signs could not be stored&#xD;
             electronically due to equipment failure.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stu White, FRCA BSc MA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Consultant Anaesthetist</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Sussex County Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brighton</city>
        <state>E Sussex</state>
        <zip>BN2 5BE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>National Hip Fracture Database. 2019 Report. https://www.nhfd.co.uk/20/hipfractureR.nsf/docs/2019Report</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>National Hip Fracture Database. Anaesthesia Sprint Audit of Practice (ASAP). 2014. https://www.nhfd.co.uk/20/hipfractureR.nsf/vwContent/asapReport/$file/onlineASAP.pdf</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>White SM, Moppett IK, Griffiths R, Johansen A, Wakeman R, Boulton C, Plant F, Williams A, Pappenheim K, Majeed A, Currie CT, Grocott MP. Secondary analysis of outcomes after 11,085 hip fracture operations from the prospective UK Anaesthesia Sprint Audit of Practice (ASAP-2). Anaesthesia. 2016 May;71(5):506-14. doi: 10.1111/anae.13415. Epub 2016 Mar 4.</citation>
    <PMID>26940645</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Griffiths R, Babu S, Dixon P, Freeman N, Hurford D, Kelleher E, Moppett I, Ray D, Sahota O, Shields M, White S. Guideline for the management of hip fractures 2020: Guideline by the Association of Anaesthetists. Anaesthesia. 2021 Feb;76(2):225-237. doi: 10.1111/anae.15291. Epub 2020 Dec 2.</citation>
    <PMID>33289066</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ben-David B, Frankel R, Arzumonov T, Marchevsky Y, Volpin G. Minidose bupivacaine-fentanyl spinal anesthesia for surgical repair of hip fracture in the aged. Anesthesiology. 2000 Jan;92(1):6-10. doi: 10.1097/00000542-200001000-00007.</citation>
    <PMID>10638892</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Minville V, Fourcade O, Grousset D, Chassery C, Nguyen L, Asehnoune K, Colombani A, Goulmamine L, Samii K. Spinal anesthesia using single injection small-dose bupivacaine versus continuous catheter injection techniques for surgical repair of hip fracture in elderly patients. Anesth Analg. 2006 May;102(5):1559-63. doi: 10.1213/01.ane.0000218421.18723.cf.</citation>
    <PMID>16632842</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>White SM, Pateman J. A method of recording electronic anaesthetic monitor data for research. Anaesthesia. 2017 Feb;72(2):267-269. doi: 10.1111/anae.13794. No abstract available.</citation>
    <PMID>28093744</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>White SM, Rashid N, Chakladar A. An analysis of renal dysfunction in 1511 patients with fractured neck of femur: the implications for peri-operative analgesia. Anaesthesia. 2009 Oct;64(10):1061-5. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2044.2009.06012.x.</citation>
    <PMID>19735395</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2023</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Royal Sussex County Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Stuart White</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant Anaesthetist, Chief Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anaesthesia, spinal</keyword>
  <keyword>Anaesthesia, cardiovascular effects</keyword>
  <keyword>Surgery, hip fracture</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>On application to PI</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>From submission for publication, indefinite</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Oral/written application to PI</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

