<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05610410</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VUmc_2021.0615</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05610410</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Peripheral Microvascular Blood Flow in ANOCA</brief_title>
  <official_title>Relationship Between Regulation of Peripheral and Intracoronary Microvascular Blood Flow in Patients With Ischemia and no Obstructive Coronary Arteries</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Amsterdam UMC, location VUmc</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Maastricht University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Amsterdam UMC, location VUmc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An observational cross-sectional cohort study investigating whether peripheral endothelial&#xD;
      function assessed using Laser speckle contrast analysis and coronary endothelial function&#xD;
      measured with invasive coronary function testing are correlated in patients with angina and&#xD;
      no obstructive coronary arteries.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: Coronary endothelial dysfunction (CED) has been proposed to cause signs and&#xD;
      symptoms of myocardial ischaemia in patients with angina but no obstructive coronary artery&#xD;
      disease (INOCA) and has been proposed to play an important role in the pathophysiology of&#xD;
      heart failure with preserved ejection fraction, as an element of the pro-inflammatory state&#xD;
      causing cardiac functional and structural abnormalities in this syndrome. Research has shown&#xD;
      that patients with coronary microvascular dysfunction (CMD) often present with&#xD;
      echocardiographic signs of diastolic dysfunction combined with higher rates of detectable&#xD;
      cardiac troponin and are at increased risk of developing HFpEF, indicating a major overlap in&#xD;
      the complex pathophysiology underlying these syndromes. CED is associated with an increased&#xD;
      risk of adverse cardiac events and currently can only be detected with invasive coronary&#xD;
      function testing (ICFT).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, it has been suggested that CED is a component of systemic endothelial dysfunction&#xD;
      and is associated with endothelial dysfunction in other microvascular beds. The cutaneous&#xD;
      microcirculation is suitable for microvascular function studies and has been shown to&#xD;
      correlate with muscle microvascular function. The recently developed Laser speckle contrast&#xD;
      analysis (LASCA) technique enables non-invasive monitoring of microvascular blood flow in&#xD;
      superficial microvascular beds. In combination with iontophoresis of acetylcholine,&#xD;
      nitroprusside and insulin, LASCA allows evaluation of peripheral microvascular endothelial&#xD;
      and smooth muscle function. While LASCA is an established technique, the association between&#xD;
      CED diagnosed with ICFT and an abnormal peripheral endothelial function measured by LASCA is&#xD;
      currently unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: The primary objective of the study is to test whether peripheral endothelial&#xD;
      function assessed using Laser speckle contrast analysis and CED measured with ICFT are&#xD;
      correlated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: Observational cross-sectional cohort study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: 51 patients over the age of 18 with signs and symptoms of ischemia with no&#xD;
      obstructive coronary arteries (INOCA) and a clinical indication for ICFT because of&#xD;
      persistent angina without obstructive coronary artery disease and 58 patients with HFpEF and&#xD;
      a clinical indication for ICFT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary study endpoint: The main study end point is the difference in peripheral endothelial&#xD;
      function between patients with and without CED measured with ICFT in the INOCA group and the&#xD;
      HFpEF group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group&#xD;
      relatedness: Study participants do not benefit from participation in this study. The burden&#xD;
      of this study is low. The aim is that study procedures will be performed within 24 hours of&#xD;
      the elective ICFT and study participants do not have to come to the hospital for an&#xD;
      additional visit. The total risks associated with participation are classified as being low,&#xD;
      because the risks for adverse events and serious adverse events from a local and transient&#xD;
      stimulus in skin are minimal. Iontophoresis of acetylcholine, nitroprusside and insulin does&#xD;
      not cause any skin damage and the used dosages are very small and as such, the stimuli do not&#xD;
      cause any systemic effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral endothelial function</measure>
    <time_frame>1-1,5 hour</time_frame>
    <description>Peripheral endothelial function measured with LASCA between ANOCA patients with and without Coronary endothelial dysfunction</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microvascular reactivity measurement methods</measure>
    <time_frame>1-1,5 hour</time_frame>
    <description>The relationship between microvascular reactivity measured using EndoPAT and LASCA in patients with ANOCA or HFpEF.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">109</enrollment>
  <condition>ANOCA</condition>
  <condition>HFpEF - Heart Failure With Preserved Ejection Fraction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with angina and no obstructive coronary arteries</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with HFpEF</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laser speckle contrast analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Peripheral endothelial function assessment using Laser speckle contrast analysis and Peripheral reactive hyperemia assessment using EndoPAT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with HFpEF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with angina and no obstructive coronary arteries</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EndoPAT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study is designed to evaluate INOCA patients with a clinical indication of ICFT&#xD;
        because of persistent angina without obstructive coronary artery disease and HFpEF patients&#xD;
        with a clinical indication of ICFT.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical indication for elective invasive coronary function test (ICFT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suited for one of the study groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Persistent angina, defined as symptoms of angina; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HFpEF, diagnosed according to the ESC 2021 heart failure guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of obstructive CAD, documented before inclusion, defined as&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CCTA - indicative of absence of obstructed coronary arteries, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CAG - &lt;50% diameter stenosis (DS) in the epicardial coronary arteries or&#xD;
                  (fractional flow reserve (FFR) &gt;0.80 or instant wave free ratio (iFR) &gt;0.89)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable or unwilling to undergo ICFT&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Amsterdam UMC, lcoation VUmc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yolande Appelman, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0031204442244|</phone>
      <email>y.appelman@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Etto Eringa, PhD</last_name>
      <email>e.eringa@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 1, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 1, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 1, 2022</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 1, 2022</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2022</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, location VUmc</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Y. Appelman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, PhD, FESC</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

