<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05613933</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHUBX 2021/24</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05613933</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Antibiotic Prophylaxis of Infective Endocarditis for Invasive Dental Procedures in Patients With Prosthetic Heart Valves and/or History of Infective Endocarditis</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROPHETS</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Antibiotic Prophylaxis of Infective Endocarditis Before Invasive Dental Procedures in Patients With Prosthetic Heart Valves and/or History of Infective Endocarditis: a Prospective, Registry-based, Cluster-randomized Trial in Primary Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Bordeaux</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Bordeaux</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Infective endocarditis (IE) continues to cause serious morbidity and mortality. To reduce its&#xD;
      incidence, antibiotic prophylaxis has been recommended before invasive dental procedures in&#xD;
      patients with at risk predispositions. Several studies have examined the effect of antibiotic&#xD;
      prophylaxis on the incidence of IE and have brought conflicting results. The investigators&#xD;
      aim to evaluate the effectiveness of antibiotic prophylaxis before invasive dental procedures&#xD;
      to prevent oral streptococcal infective endocarditis in patients with prosthetic heart valves&#xD;
      and/or history of IE, using a registry-based, cluster-randomized, controlled trial. In&#xD;
      secondary objectives, the investigators aim to analyze changes in dentists' practices.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Conducting a conventional individual-based RCT to demonstrate the efficacy of antibiotic&#xD;
      prophylaxis of IE is unfeasible and unethical but it also seems unacceptable to perpetuate&#xD;
      potentially ineffective and ecologically deleterious antibiotic use. Since the conditions for&#xD;
      an individual RCT are not met, the procedure performed does not directly involve the drug but&#xD;
      rather the practices of the dentists. This trial will be based on the hypothesis that&#xD;
      dentists of health territories (territoires de santé; TDS) allocated to the intervention arm&#xD;
      will increase their prescription of antibiotic prophylaxis in patients with prosthetic heart&#xD;
      valve and/or history of IE. Thus, assuming antibiotic prophylaxis is effective, the&#xD;
      intervention arm should be associated with a decrease in the incidence of oral streptococci&#xD;
      IE as compared to the control arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the intervention arm, dentists will receive information on the study before the start of&#xD;
      the study.Those who consent will receive information with an &quot;antibiotic prophylaxis package&quot;&#xD;
      aimed to improve adherence to current guidelines. These interventions will be periodically&#xD;
      repeated in order to ensure the persistence of their effect over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among included patients, dental procedures will be classified as invasive if they imply&#xD;
      manipulation of the gingival or periapical region of the teeth or a perforation of the oral&#xD;
      mucosa. In these patients, exposure to antibiotic prophylaxis will be identified through the&#xD;
      dispensation of an antibiotic treatment active against oral streptococci in the 21 days&#xD;
      before the dental procedure. At each new invasive procedure, individuals will be followed for&#xD;
      3 months, until the study outcome, hospital admission for valve replacement, or death from&#xD;
      any cause&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A 2-arm, registry-based, cluster RCT, to be conducted in all French Health Territories (Territoires de santé, TDS) of metropolitan France, which will serve as randomization clusters</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnosis of infective endocarditis</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 3 months after an invasive dental procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnosis of infective endocarditis due to oral streptococci that occurs within 3 months after an invasive dental procedure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antibiotic prophylaxis rate</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days before the dental procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Antibiotic prophylaxis rate in dentists according to their randomization arm (Health territories) in all patients regardless of the implantation of prosthetic heart valve and/or history of IE and their dental procedures (invasive or not). The antibiotic prophylaxis will be classified as appropriate (following the recommendation/intervention) or inappropriate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250000</enrollment>
  <condition>Endocarditis, Bacterial</condition>
  <condition>Endocarditis</condition>
  <condition>Endocarditis Acute and Subacute</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the intervention arm, dentists will receive information on the study 8 weeks before the start of the study and will be invited to consent to participate or to opt out</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the clusters randomized to the control arm, no intervention will be performed and no information will be sent to dentists.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Improved practices</intervention_name>
    <description>A package of tools including: antibiotic prophylaxis guidelines reminders, periodic reminders, the Infectious Endocarditis Prevention Card for patients at risk, practical information targeting both dentists and patients, etc…</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All French Health Territories (Territoires de santé, TDS) will be included and each&#xD;
             TDS will contribute as a cluster for randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All dentists working in each TDS will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Among individuals receiving an invasive dental procedure, all patients aged 18 years&#xD;
             or more identified with prosthetic heart valves or recorded with prior infective&#xD;
             endocarditis will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No exclusion criteria for health territories, dentists and patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  However, dental procedures that had been performed less than 6 months after the date&#xD;
             of first implantation of prosthetic heart valve won't be included.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>January 2023</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 15, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 14, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 31, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 31, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Registry based randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <keyword>antibiotic prophylaxy</keyword>
  <keyword>dentist</keyword>
  <keyword>invasive dental procedure</keyword>
  <keyword>infective endocarditis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endocarditis, Bacterial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endocarditis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

