<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on May 09, 2023</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05624398</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Vivity Protocol 001, Rev A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05624398</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Results of Patients With Glaucoma Undergoing Minimally Invasive Glaucoma Surgery in Conjunction With Cataract Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Visual Outcomes and Patient Satisfaction in Subjects With Stable Open-angle Glaucoma Undergoing Concurrent Minimally Invasive Glaucoma Surgery and IOL Implantation With an Extended-depth-of-focus IOL</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vold Vision P.L.L.C</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alcon Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vold Vision P.L.L.C</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to determine how well patients with glaucoma can see following&#xD;
      cataract surgery with a special type of lens called an extended-depth-of-focus (EDOF) lens.&#xD;
      This lens is intended to reduced the patients need for glasses following cataract surgery.&#xD;
      Patients will also undergo a minimally invasive type of glaucoma surgery using a special type&#xD;
      of stent to reduce eye pressure, with the goal of better glaucoma control and the reduction&#xD;
      in the need for medications to control eye pressure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the range of vision and patient reported outcomes in subjects implanted with&#xD;
      Clareon Vivity IOL undergoing concurrent MIGS with the Hydrus Microstent&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 7, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, single-center, single-surgeon, single-arm, descriptive study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Monocular Best Corrected Distance Visual Acuity (DCVA) (4 meters) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Monocular Best Distance Corrected Intermediate Visual Acuity (DCIVA) (66 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Monocular Uncorrected Distance Visual Acuity (UCDVA) (4 meters) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Monocular Uncorrected Intermediate Visual Acuity (UCIVA) (66 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Binocular Best Corrected Distance Visual Acuity (DCVA) (4 meters) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Binocular Best Distance Corrected Intermediate Visual Acuity (DCIVA) (66 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Binocular Uncorrected Distance Visual Acuity (UCDVA) (4 meters) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Binocular Uncorrected Intermediate Visual Acuity (UCIVA) (66 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Refractive Spherical Equivalent</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Average refractive error or residual spectacle prescription remaining following procedure (diopters)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Absolute Prediction Error</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Average prescription remaining compared to preoperative prediction (diopters)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean post-op refractive astigmatism and the distribution of post-op refractive astigmatism at ≤0.25D, ≤0.50D, ≤0.75D, and ≤1.00D</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Examining the distribution or remaining astigmatism in subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Monocular Best Distance Corrected Near Visual Acuity (DCNVA) (40 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Monocular Uncorrected Near Visual Acuity (UCNVA) (40 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Binocular Best Distance Corrected Near Visual Acuity (DCNVA) (40 cm) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Photopic Binocular Best Corrected Distance Low Contrast Visual Acuity (25%) (4 meters) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement using &quot;faded&quot; letters</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Mesopic Binocular Best Corrected Distance Low Contrast Visual Acuity (25%) (4 meters) logMAR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity measurement using &quot;faded&quot; letters</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Vision Questionnaire (QoV)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The QoV is a validated questionnaire designed to determine what if any visual disturbances are present following surgery. It consists of a 30-item instrument with 10 possible symptoms rated in each of 3 scales (frequency, severity, and bothersome). Examples of common visual disturbances include glare and halo. This outcome measure can be graded on a linear scale with a higher score being a worse outcome (more visual disturbances). This questionnaire takes approximately 5 minutes to complete.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>IOL patient satisfaction (IOLSAT) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The IOLSAT is a questionnaire inquiring about the need for eyeglasses, vision without eyeglasses, expectations for needed eyeglasses, and visual satisfaction. It consists of 23 questions, the first 21 based on a Likert scale. Questions 22 asks whether the patient would choose the same lens again and 23 if they would recommend the lens to their family and friends.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean preoperative IOP versus postoperative IOP</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparing intraocular pressure before versus after intervention</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean preoperative medications versus postoperative medications</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparing the amount of preoperative glaucoma medications before versus after intervention</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</condition>
  <condition>Cataract</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects implanted with the Vivity IOL undergoing concurrent implantation of the Hydrus Microstent</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vivity IOL</intervention_name>
    <description>Cataract surgery with implantation of the Vivity IOL along with concurrent implantation of the Hydrus Microstent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hydrus Microstent</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female subjects 45 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A visually significant age-related cataract in both eyes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of mild OAG&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  VF characteristics consistent with glaucoma with mean deviation not worse than&#xD;
                  -6.00 dB and without fixation threatening scotoma AND/OR with nerve abnormalities&#xD;
                  consistent with glaucoma (rim notching, rim thinning, disc hemorrhage, nerve&#xD;
                  fiber layer loss)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Medicated IOP ≤25 mmHg on 1-3 hypotensive medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glaucoma must be judged as stable by investigator based on review of subject medical&#xD;
             records&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stable VF at least 1 year prior to surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stable nerve fiber layer at least 1 year prior to surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  IOP stable on current medication regimen at least 3 months prior to surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shaffer grade of ≥ III in all angle quadrants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Potential of best corrected visual acuity at distance in the investigator's judgement&#xD;
             of at least 0.1 logMAR (20/25) postoperatively&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to comply with follow up visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understands and signs the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both eyes of the subject should undergo surgery within 21 days of each other to ensure&#xD;
             adequate timing for final visit window of 90 days ± 21 days post operatively&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous incisional glaucoma surgery or cilio-ablative surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior laser trabeculoplasty within 90 days of surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pseudoexfoliative, angle closure, uveitic, congenital, traumatic, angle recession, or&#xD;
             neovascular glaucoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate glaucoma with VF mean deviation between -6.00 dB and -12.00 dB&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe and/or progressive glaucoma defined as&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  VF mean deviation worse than -12.00 dB&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Consistent worsening of visual field on review of subject medical records&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Consistent and progressive thinning of nerve fiber layer on review of subject&#xD;
                  medical records&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled IOP on maximum glaucoma medications&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Historically poor IOP control with medical therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe focal notching of the optic nerve rim&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Expectation for future need of incisional glaucoma surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ocular pathology or other medical condition which, in the investigator's judgment&#xD;
             places the subject at increased risk of complications or significant vision loss&#xD;
             during study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ocular pathology that in the investigator's judgment may impact visual acuity&#xD;
             postoperatively, i.e., significant ocular surface disease, corneal scarring,&#xD;
             blepharitis, epiretinal membrane, macular degeneration, history of significant ocular&#xD;
             trauma with sequela, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior refractive surgery e.g., LASIK, RK, PRK, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with significant complications during surgical procedure e.g., broken&#xD;
             capsule, Hydrus Microstent complication, will be exited from the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who experience visually significant complications related to the Hydrus&#xD;
             Microstent during the study period will be exited from the trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vold Vision P.L.L.C.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fayetteville</city>
        <state>Arkansas</state>
        <zip>72764</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael R. M OD</last_name>
      <phone>479-442-8653</phone>
      <email>mmcfarland@voldvision.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2022</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 6, 2022</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2022</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2022</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 5, 2023</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 5, 2023</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 8, 2023</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Glaucoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Cataract</keyword>
  <keyword>Microstent</keyword>
  <keyword>Premium IOL</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The investigators do not plan to share IPD</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

